<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - Units -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FROZEN</Tag>
		<English>Frozen Concepts</English>
		<French>Frozen Concepts</French>
		<German>Konzepte des Gefrorenen</German>
		<Italian>Frozen Concepts</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frozen Concepts</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FROZEN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Frozen Civilization Concept[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=CIVILIZATION_FROZEN]Frozen[\LINK] are a third summonable civilization, added with the Frozen New Civ Mod by TC01. They can be summoned after researching Elementalism and completing the ritual/project [LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Liberation[\LINK]. This can be done by neutral and evil civilizations. This ritual also provides it's creator with a handful of [LINK=UNIT_ICE_GOLEM]Ice Golems[\LINK], powerful defensive units that act as a replacement of the Longbowman.[PARAGRAPH:2]Both the Infernals and Mercurians, the other summonable civilizations, have some system for gaining Angels or Manes. The Frozen's system for gaining [LINK=UNIT_FROZEN_SOUL]Frozen Souls[\LINK] (which are more like the Mane than the Angel) involves passing promotions through combat.[PARAGRAPH:1]All Frozen and Illian units have the [LINK=PROMOTION_WINTERBORN]Winterborn[\LINK] promotion. Units with Winterborn pass the [LINK=PROMOTION_WINTERED]Frozen Soul[\LINK] promotion to enemies in combat, much like how the diseased promotions work. This promotion weakens the enemy, passes Frozen Soul to enemies in combat, and when killed, provides the Frozen with Frozen Soul units. Winterborn units that are killed also provide Frozen Souls.[PARAGRAPH:1]Based on this, you could either target the Illians and Doviello, civilizations with Winterborn promotions on all their units. Or, you could target their enemies, who may have units with Frozen Soul. If you aren't gaining many Frozen Souls this way, you can cast your worldspell once you research Sorcery. It is called [LINK=SPELL_WINTERING]Wintering[\LINK], and gives all "alive" (not mechanical or naval) units that do not belong to your team the Frozen Soul promotion. It also spreads ice terrain, "upgrading" all ice terrain inside of your empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]Like the Illians, the Frozen are capable of Ascending their leader, Taranis, to become Taranis Ascended. On completing the Ascension ritual, if their hero Taranis is on the map, he is killed, and replaced by [LINK=UNIT_TARANIS_ASCENDED]Taranis Ascended[\LINK]. Taranis Ascended is a powerful unit that is basically identical to Auric Ascended, however, the capabilities of the Ascended have been boosted. Both Auric and Taranis Ascended have been given +10 Ice Affinity, and both have access to a version of the Slow spell with a 2-plot radius. Auric and Taranis Ascended also can cast a spell allowing them to temporarily summon a wide variety of winter units.[PARAGRAPH:1]Your hero [LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Taranis[\LINK] starts with the [LINK=PROMOTION_UNCHANGING]Unchanging[\LINK] promotion. This prevents him from being able to attack, but gives him a city defense bonus. He is also immortal (in that he must die twice on the same turn to be killed). Once built, he cannot be rebuilt, however he will reappear in whatever city is your capital. If you want to relocate him, move your capital somewhere else, and if he dies once, he will reappear there.[PARAGRAPH:2]All Frozen cities start with the following buildings: Temple of the Hand (which provides the ice effect), Elder Council, Obsidian Gate, Forge, Mage Guild, and [LINK=BUILDING_FROZEN_SOULS]Frozen Souls[\LINK]. Frozen Souls is a marker that replaces the "Demonic Citizens" marker that Infernal cities have.[PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=UNIT_TAR_DEMON]Tar Demon[\LINK], a defensive unit that can be summoned by the Sheaim Planar Gate, is also summonable by the Frozen. Frozen cities containing a [LINK=ICY_CONDUIT]Swamp of Souls[\LINK] building, their Aqueduct UB, have a random chance to generate a Tar Demon.[PARAGRAPH:1]At first, a city with the Swamp of Souls building has a pretty good chance of creating a Tar Demon. However, after it creates a few it has a much lower chance of producing one. There is no upper limit for how many Tar Demons a city can create- but after the first few, the chance gets pretty low.[PARAGRAPH:2]Ice terrain is automatically spread by blizzards, features which will randomly appear on snow plots in Illian and Frozen territory. For more information on Blizzards, see their [LINK=CONCEPT_BLIZZARDS]concept page[\LINK].</English>
		<French>[H1]Frozen Civilization Concept[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The Frozen are a third summonable civilization, added with the Frozen New Civ Mod by TC01. They can be summoned after researching Elementalism and completing the ritual/project "Liberation". This can be done by neutral and evil civilizations.[PARAGRAPH:2]Both the Infernals and Mercurians, the other summonable civilizations, have some system for gaining Angels or Manes. The Frozen's system for gaining "Frozen Souls" (which are more like the Mane then the Angel) involves passing promotions through combat.[PARAGRAPH:1]All Frozen and Illian units have the Winterborn promotion. Units with Winterborn pass the "Wintered" promotion to enemies in combat, much like how the diseased promotions work. This promotion weakens the enemy, passes Wintered to enemies in combat, and when killed, provides the Frozen with Frozen Soul units. Winterborn units that are killed also provide Frozen Souls.[PARAGRAPH:1]Based on this, you could either target the Illians and Doviello, civilizations with Winterborn promotions on all their units. Or, you could target their enemies, who may have units with Wintered. If you aren't gaining many Frozen Souls this way, you can cast your worldspell once you research Sorcery. It is called Wintering, and gives all "alive" (not mechanical or naval) units that do not belong to your team the Wintered promotion. It also spreads ice terrain, "upgrading" all ice terrain inside of your empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]Like the Illians, the Frozen are capable of Ascending their leader, Taranis, to become Taranis Ascended. On completing the Ascension ritual, if their hero Taranis is on the map, he is killed, and replaced by Taranis Ascended. Taranis Ascended is a powerful unit that is basically identical to Auric Ascended, however, the capabilities of the Ascended have been boosted. Currently, both Auric and Taranis Ascended have been given +10 Ice Affinity.[PARAGRAPH:1]Your hero Taranis starts with the Unchanging promotion. This prevents him from being able to attack, but gives him a city defense bonus. He is also immortal (in that he must die twice on the same turn to be killed). Once built, he cannot be rebuilt, however he will reappear in whatever city is your capital. If you want to relocate him, move your capital somewhere else, and if he dies once, he will reappear there.[PARAGRAPH:2]All Frozen cities start with the following buildings: Temple of the Hand (which provides the ice effect), Elder Council, Obsidian Gate, Forge, Mage Guild, and Frozen Souls. Frozen Souls is a marker that replaces the "Demonic Citizens" marker that Infernal cities have.[PARAGRAPH:2](More information will be added here in the future)</French>
		<German>[H1]Frozen Civilization Concept[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The Frozen are a third summonable civilization, added with the Frozen New Civ Mod by TC01. They can be summoned after researching Elementalism and completing the ritual/project "Liberation". This can be done by neutral and evil civilizations.[PARAGRAPH:2]Both the Infernals and Mercurians, the other summonable civilizations, have some system for gaining Angels or Manes. The Frozen's system for gaining "Frozen Souls" (which are more like the Mane then the Angel) involves passing promotions through combat.[PARAGRAPH:1]All Frozen and Illian units have the Winterborn promotion. Units with Winterborn pass the "Wintered" promotion to enemies in combat, much like how the diseased promotions work. This promotion weakens the enemy, passes Wintered to enemies in combat, and when killed, provides the Frozen with Frozen Soul units. Winterborn units that are killed also provide Frozen Souls.[PARAGRAPH:1]Based on this, you could either target the Illians and Doviello, civilizations with Winterborn promotions on all their units. Or, you could target their enemies, who may have units with Wintered. If you aren't gaining many Frozen Souls this way, you can cast your worldspell once you research Sorcery. It is called Wintering, and gives all "alive" (not mechanical or naval) units that do not belong to your team the Wintered promotion. It also spreads ice terrain, "upgrading" all ice terrain inside of your empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]Like the Illians, the Frozen are capable of Ascending their leader, Taranis, to become Taranis Ascended. On completing the Ascension ritual, if their hero Taranis is on the map, he is killed, and replaced by Taranis Ascended. Taranis Ascended is a powerful unit that is basically identical to Auric Ascended, however, the capabilities of the Ascended have been boosted. Currently, both Auric and Taranis Ascended have been given +10 Ice Affinity.[PARAGRAPH:1]Your hero Taranis starts with the Unchanging promotion. This prevents him from being able to attack, but gives him a city defense bonus. He is also immortal (in that he must die twice on the same turn to be killed). Once built, he cannot be rebuilt, however he will reappear in whatever city is your capital. If you want to relocate him, move your capital somewhere else, and if he dies once, he will reappear there.[PARAGRAPH:2]All Frozen cities start with the following buildings: Temple of the Hand (which provides the ice effect), Elder Council, Obsidian Gate, Forge, Mage Guild, and Frozen Souls. Frozen Souls is a marker that replaces the "Demonic Citizens" marker that Infernal cities have.[PARAGRAPH:2](More information will be added here in the future)</German>
		<Italian>[H1]Frozen Civilization Concept[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The Frozen are a third summonable civilization, added with the Frozen New Civ Mod by TC01. They can be summoned after researching Elementalism and completing the ritual/project "Liberation". This can be done by neutral and evil civilizations.[PARAGRAPH:2]Both the Infernals and Mercurians, the other summonable civilizations, have some system for gaining Angels or Manes. The Frozen's system for gaining "Frozen Souls" (which are more like the Mane then the Angel) involves passing promotions through combat.[PARAGRAPH:1]All Frozen and Illian units have the Winterborn promotion. Units with Winterborn pass the "Wintered" promotion to enemies in combat, much like how the diseased promotions work. This promotion weakens the enemy, passes Wintered to enemies in combat, and when killed, provides the Frozen with Frozen Soul units. Winterborn units that are killed also provide Frozen Souls.[PARAGRAPH:1]Based on this, you could either target the Illians and Doviello, civilizations with Winterborn promotions on all their units. Or, you could target their enemies, who may have units with Wintered. If you aren't gaining many Frozen Souls this way, you can cast your worldspell once you research Sorcery. It is called Wintering, and gives all "alive" (not mechanical or naval) units that do not belong to your team the Wintered promotion. It also spreads ice terrain, "upgrading" all ice terrain inside of your empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]Like the Illians, the Frozen are capable of Ascending their leader, Taranis, to become Taranis Ascended. On completing the Ascension ritual, if their hero Taranis is on the map, he is killed, and replaced by Taranis Ascended. Taranis Ascended is a powerful unit that is basically identical to Auric Ascended, however, the capabilities of the Ascended have been boosted. Currently, both Auric and Taranis Ascended have been given +10 Ice Affinity.[PARAGRAPH:1]Your hero Taranis starts with the Unchanging promotion. This prevents him from being able to attack, but gives him a city defense bonus. He is also immortal (in that he must die twice on the same turn to be killed). Once built, he cannot be rebuilt, however he will reappear in whatever city is your capital. If you want to relocate him, move your capital somewhere else, and if he dies once, he will reappear there.[PARAGRAPH:2]All Frozen cities start with the following buildings: Temple of the Hand (which provides the ice effect), Elder Council, Obsidian Gate, Forge, Mage Guild, and Frozen Souls. Frozen Souls is a marker that replaces the "Demonic Citizens" marker that Infernal cities have.[PARAGRAPH:2](More information will be added here in the future)</Italian>
		<Spanish>[H1]Frozen Civilization Concept[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The Frozen are a third summonable civilization, added with the Frozen New Civ Mod by TC01. They can be summoned after researching Elementalism and completing the ritual/project "Liberation". This can be done by neutral and evil civilizations.[PARAGRAPH:2]Both the Infernals and Mercurians, the other summonable civilizations, have some system for gaining Angels or Manes. The Frozen's system for gaining "Frozen Souls" (which are more like the Mane then the Angel) involves passing promotions through combat.[PARAGRAPH:1]All Frozen and Illian units have the Winterborn promotion. Units with Winterborn pass the "Wintered" promotion to enemies in combat, much like how the diseased promotions work. This promotion weakens the enemy, passes Wintered to enemies in combat, and when killed, provides the Frozen with Frozen Soul units. Winterborn units that are killed also provide Frozen Souls.[PARAGRAPH:1]Based on this, you could either target the Illians and Doviello, civilizations with Winterborn promotions on all their units. Or, you could target their enemies, who may have units with Wintered. If you aren't gaining many Frozen Souls this way, you can cast your worldspell once you research Sorcery. It is called Wintering, and gives all "alive" (not mechanical or naval) units that do not belong to your team the Wintered promotion. It also spreads ice terrain, "upgrading" all ice terrain inside of your empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]Like the Illians, the Frozen are capable of Ascending their leader, Taranis, to become Taranis Ascended. On completing the Ascension ritual, if their hero Taranis is on the map, he is killed, and replaced by Taranis Ascended. Taranis Ascended is a powerful unit that is basically identical to Auric Ascended, however, the capabilities of the Ascended have been boosted. Currently, both Auric and Taranis Ascended have been given +10 Ice Affinity.[PARAGRAPH:1]Your hero Taranis starts with the Unchanging promotion. This prevents him from being able to attack, but gives him a city defense bonus. He is also immortal (in that he must die twice on the same turn to be killed). Once built, he cannot be rebuilt, however he will reappear in whatever city is your capital. If you want to relocate him, move your capital somewhere else, and if he dies once, he will reappear there.[PARAGRAPH:2]All Frozen cities start with the following buildings: Temple of the Hand (which provides the ice effect), Elder Council, Obsidian Gate, Forge, Mage Guild, and Frozen Souls. Frozen Souls is a marker that replaces the "Demonic Citizens" marker that Infernal cities have.[PARAGRAPH:2](More information will be added here in the future)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FROZEN_SOULS</Tag>
		<English>Frozen Souls</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Âmes gelées</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Gefrorene Seelen</German>
		<Italian>Frozen Souls</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frozen Souls</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FROZEN_SOULS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Frozen Souls cannot be built. Instead they are used to mark Frozen cities.</English>
		<French>Frozen Souls cannot be built. Instead they are used to mark Frozen cities.</French>
		<German>Gefrorene Seelen k&#246;nnen nicht gebaut werden. Statt dessen markieren sie Gefrorene St&#228;dte.</German>
		<Italian>Frozen Souls cannot be built. Instead they are used to mark Frozen cities.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frozen Souls cannot be built. Instead they are used to mark Frozen cities.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_LIBERATION</Tag>
		<English>Liberation</English>
		<French>Libération</French>
		<German>Befreiung</German>
		<Italian>Liberation</Italian>
		<Spanish>Liberation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_LIBERATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Chapter 1: The Liberation[NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Chapter 2: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LEADER_TARANIS]Chapter 3: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Auric stood in meditation surrounded by vast ice crystals. He smiled as he saw images of legions of Ice Golems engaging Luchuirp Golems and holding them at bay, creating a wall of stasis that stretched across the Luchuirp border, as his allies struck. He shitfted his imaging and saw frostling bandits, supported by flesh constructs from Mokka's Cauldron, engaging the Svartalfar. Things were going well, and it looked as if the Deepening would soon begin, according to Anangtios's report. That was when he sensed a disturbance around him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Reflexes honed while wandering Erebus kicked into action, and he ducked behind one of the crystals. The assassin's dart, tipped with a plant that caused spontaneous combustion when it hit a target, struck and melted a chunk of ice away. He snapped "Slow!" and the will behind the command caused time around the assassin to stretch and slow down as she was about to utter a spell that would blow the throne room apart with an inferno. It had the added effect of causing the assassin's invisibility charm to stop working, causing her to become visible to all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric walked forward and studied the assassin. She was an elf, apparently, wrapped in a black cloak covered with invisibility runes that was typical of Svartalfar dress. She also carried a large supply of deadly implements. He waved his hand, and the slow time effects intensified, stopping time around the two of them entirely. Another gesture caused the temperature to lower, subtly. Guards rushed into the room, but to Auric and the elven prisoner, they did not move.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I just thought you should know," he said, "that Illian ice sculpters are capable of altering the position and even the shape of a body after it has been frozen. It produces beautiful artwork." He gestured to the columns of ice statues lining the palace. "Not all were made out of once living people- but some were," he continued. "But, it can be done to a still living body. The process is incredibly painful, as you can no doubt imagine." The assassin's face showed that she did.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric released frozen time, and the guards seized her. He said ominously, "Sculpt her until she talks." The guards departed, dragging the shrieking prisoner, who seconds later died. He frowned. He thought he had removed all magical items with the slow spell. Evidently there was a physical poison as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]He sighed, shaking his head. He needed better guards. And then an idea, propelled by the essence of Mulcarn that lived within him, came to him, and he shouted an order. A Disciple of Winter rushed in, and he gave instructions to him, and the disciple rushed out to obey them.[PARAGRAPH:2]The tower of ice, not located in Garduk but near Letum Frigus, had been built by Auric's will, and it would stand so long as he remained alive- or willed it to collapse. Ice particles had gathered slowly and formed into beautiful crystals, which then formed into a tower. At the top of the tower were four crystalline spikes resembling stalagmites. It was at this top where Auric, Dumnanios, Riuros, and Anangtios were gathered. He had risen it for this specific purpose.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ritual was well under way. Even if anyone else on Erebus was aware of it, and could fight through the Illian and Doviello guards patrolling the empire, they would not be in time to stop it. Auric's vision honed in on an island in a lake at the edge of Elohim lands. Knowing that it was important, the Elohim were guarding a small crystal sphere on the shores of the lake with their lives. He laughed as he gathered energy. Those lives would not be enough...[PARAGRAPH:2]Arlonte, captain of the guards assigned to protect the Evergreen Lake, sighed as he watched the small company of Elohim assigned to this site. It was a good job they had- they did not have to protect the lake itself but rather what appeared to be a glowing green spherical rock. The priest, Lenyos, assigned to their group was currently studying it. The other guards were also enjoying themselves in the grass. They could relax in the lake, but Einion Logos had warned them strictly- do not venture into the lake.[PARAGRAPH:1]He headed over to the priest to take a look at his analysis of the object. That was when he felt a strange sensation, as if lightning was coming. He looked up, along with the others.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was no lightning. The clouds were glowing pure white, and it seemed as if... they were freezing.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then, there was a sudden blast of blue-white light from the frozen clouds. It appeared to be lightning, but it was clearly not. It was directed straight at the object they were supposed to protect, and one of the guards nearby instinctively dove into the path of the lightning. His body froze and was covered in ice. It then fell to the orb, which flared green, and the body of the guard caught on fire until nothing was left but ashes. Arlonte stood staring at the orb. It was obviously a tool against winter, but...[PARAGRAPH:1]His thoughts were interrupted when another blast shot through the sky. Seconds before it hit, Lenyos, a priest of the Fellowship of Leaves, muttered a prayer, and the earth glowed green. Guardian vines emerged and seized the orb. The blast of ice struck them... and nothing happened.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric reeled as a powerful presence interrupted his attack on the Orb of Sucellus guarding the lake. He had frozen a human who had been in the way of the blast, he knew, but that second power... intrigued, he studied it. And the part that was Mulcarn gave him the rest of the information. He had tried to freeze a massive creature, the Guardian of the Forest. Somehow, a being he had identified as a priest of leaves had summoned the Guardian's vines to defend the orb. Clever. He had tried to freeze the entire thing. There did not seem to be a way to win.[PARAGRAPH:1]But, after a few minutes thinking, he had one, and resumed his attack, gathering more power...[PARAGRAPH:2]The Elohim captain looked up again. Arlonte prayed that the attacker was beat and would go away. But that, of course, did not happen. Instead, another blast rained down from the frozen clouds. This one, though was glowing faintly golden... Arlonte realized with surprise that it was a lightning blast. The blast continued coming, becoming a solid beam, not a quick blast. Lenyos gasped in horror as the lightning drilled into one of the vines.[PARAGRAPH:1]He cried, "The guardian..." and rushed forward. A deflected ray of lightning struck him. Lenyos screamed in pain and died.[PARAGRAPH:1]That was when the blast penetrated through the vine.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric mentally roared at the presence of the Guardian, demanding it submit, even as he gathered all the ice energy he had in him, swallowing several nearby blizzards and nearly undoing the tower of ice he was standing on. He hurled it down into the ripped open vine. The ice would either freeze a portion of the great Guardian, or would destroy the Orb of Sucellus.[PARAGRAPH:1]He waited to see what would happen. He did not have enough power to both take on the Guardian and to destroy the Orb simultaneously. Already, he felt himself wilting. He continued to pour out his energy and shout at the Guardian...[PARAGRAPH:2]Arlonte's eyes widened as the vines began to freeze. They crystallized and abruptly melted into nothingness, the Orb having burned the frozen portions away. The remaining vines at the base of the Orb recoiled and reentered the earth, vanishing, as did the aura of nature surrounding the area. His face turned grim as he considered what this meant.[PARAGRAPH:2]The icy beam continued coming, striking the orb, creating a shield of fire around the orb. Ice energy touched and froze the outside of the orb, which caught fire. That fire was then frozen as more ice energy poured down. Eventually, the orb cracked, and exploded, as it could take no more ice magic. Arlonte and the guards ducked as the smoke cleared and the beam stopped.[PARAGRAPH:2]That was when the lake froze. He turned, and his face became pale as he saw an armored warrior stalking across the ice, longsword and shield in hand. Arlonte opened his mouth to order a charge, when he found he could no longer speak. The figure waved a hand and ice filled his mouth. Still striding forward, he swung the sword in a long sweep and Arlonte dropped to the ground. As he died, he saw the figure make short work of the other guards as well...[PARAGRAPH:2]Taranis finished killing the guards and looked around, taking in data. It was another age. Mulcarn's presence was no longer felt- wait... there was an emission of him from the north, from the old realm of the Illians. Analysis: Mulcarn is weakened. Directive: Head north. Directive: Kill all in between targets. Directive: Determine the state of Mulcarn. Directive: Gather aid. Input data: No creatures of ice felt within reasonable range. Analysis: They are dispered or gathered near Mulcarn. Directive: Find them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Such was Taranis. He could take in data and make decisions, albeit in a machine-like method. But after that data was taken in and Taranis came to a decision based on it, it was dumped since it could not be remembered. He continued to reevaluate his current directives, carefully checking if the position of Mulcarn or his ice demons altered. They did not. One final directive was ordered, based on climate data.[PARAGRAPH:1]Directive: Begin the re-wintering of the world.</English>
		<French>Chapter 1: The Liberation[NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Chapter 2: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Auric stood in meditation surrounded by vast ice crystals. He smiled as he saw images of legions of Ice Golems engaging Luchuirp Golems and holding them at bay, creating a wall of stasis that stretched across the Luchuirp border, as his allies struck. He shitfted his imaging and saw frostling bandits, supported by flesh constructs from Mokka's Cauldron, engaging the Svartalfar. Things were going well, and it looked as if the Deepening would soon begin, according to Anangtios's report. That was when he sensed a disturbance around him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Reflexes honed while wandering Erebus kicked into action, and he ducked behind one of the crystals. The assassin's dart, tipped with a plant that caused spontaneous combustion when it hit a target, struck and melted a chunk of ice away. He snapped "Slow!" and the will behind the command caused time around the assassin to stretch and slow down as she was about to utter a spell that would blow the throne room apart with an inferno. It had the added effect of causing the assassin's invisibility charm to stop working, causing her to become visible to all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric walked forward and studied the assassin. She was an elf, apparently, wrapped in a black cloak covered with invisibility runes that was typical of Svartalfar dress. She also carried a large supply of deadly implements. He waved his hand, and the slow time effects intensified, stopping time around the two of them entirely. Another gesture caused the temperature to lower, subtly. Guards rushed into the room, but to Auric and the elven prisoner, they did not move.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I just thought you should know," he said, "that Illian ice sculpters are capable of altering the position and even the shape of a body after it has been frozen. It produces beautiful artwork." He gestured to the columns of ice statues lining the palace. "Not all were made out of once living people- but some were," he continued. "But, it can be done to a still living body. The process is incredibly painful, as you can no doubt imagine." The assassin's face showed that she did.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric released frozen time, and the guards seized her. He said ominously, "Sculpt her until she talks." The guards departed, dragging the shrieking prisoner, who seconds later died. He frowned. He thought he had removed all magical items with the slow spell. Evidently there was a physical poison as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]He sighed, shaking his head. He needed better guards. And then an idea, propelled by the essence of Mulcarn that lived within him, came to him, and he shouted an order. A Disciple of Winter rushed in, and he gave instructions to him, and the disciple rushed out to obey them.[PARAGRAPH:2]The tower of ice, not located in Garduk but near Letum Frigus, had been built by Auric's will, and it would stand so long as he remained alive- or willed it to collapse. Ice particles had gathered slowly and formed into beautiful crystals, which then formed into a tower. At the top of the tower were four crystalline spikes resembling stalagmites. It was at this top where Auric, Dumnanios, Riuros, and Anangtios were gathered. He had risen it for this specific purpose.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ritual was well under way. Even if anyone else on Erebus was aware of it, and could fight through the Illian and Doviello guards patrolling the empire, they would not be in time to stop it. Auric's vision honed in on an island in a lake at the edge of Elohim lands. Knowing that it was important, the Elohim were guarding a small crystal sphere on the shores of the lake with their lives. He laughed as he gathered energy. Those lives would not be enough...[PARAGRAPH:2]Arlonte, captain of the guards assigned to protect the Evergreen Lake, sighed as he watched the small company of Elohim assigned to this site. It was a good job they had- they did not have to protect the lake itself but rather what appeared to be a glowing green spherical rock. The priest, Lenyos, assigned to their group was currently studying it. The other guards were also enjoying themselves in the grass. They could relax in the lake, but Einion Logos had warned them strictly- do not venture into the lake.[PARAGRAPH:1]He headed over to the priest to take a look at his analysis of the object. That was when he felt a strange sensation, as if lightning was coming. He looked up, along with the others.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was no lightning. The clouds were glowing pure white, and it seemed as if... they were freezing.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then, there was a sudden blast of blue-white light from the frozen clouds. It appeared to be lightning, but it was clearly not. It was directed straight at the object they were supposed to protect, and one of the guards nearby instinctively dove into the path of the lightning. His body froze and was covered in ice. It then fell to the orb, which flared green, and the body of the guard caught on fire until nothing was left but ashes. Arlonte stood staring at the orb. It was obviously a tool against winter, but...[PARAGRAPH:1]His thoughts were interrupted when another blast shot through the sky. Seconds before it hit, Lenyos, a priest of the Fellowship of Leaves, muttered a prayer, and the earth glowed green. Guardian vines emerged and seized the orb. The blast of ice struck them... and nothing happened.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric reeled as a powerful presence interrupted his attack on the Orb of Sucellus guarding the lake. He had frozen a human who had been in the way of the blast, he knew, but that second power... intrigued, he studied it. And the part that was Mulcarn gave him the rest of the information. He had tried to freeze a massive creature, the Guardian of the Forest. Somehow, a being he had identified as a priest of leaves had summoned the Guardian's vines to defend the orb. Clever. He had tried to freeze the entire thing. There did not seem to be a way to win.[PARAGRAPH:1]But, after a few minutes thinking, he had one, and resumed his attack, gathering more power...[PARAGRAPH:2]The Elohim captain looked up again. Arlonte prayed that the attacker was beat and would go away. But that, of course, did not happen. Instead, another blast rained down from the frozen clouds. This one, though was glowing faintly golden... Arlonte realized with surprise that it was a lightning blast. The blast continued coming, becoming a solid beam, not a quick blast. Lenyos gasped in horror as the lightning drilled into one of the vines.[PARAGRAPH:1]He cried, "The guardian..." and rushed forward. A deflected ray of lightning struck him. Lenyos screamed in pain and died.[PARAGRAPH:1]That was when the blast penetrated through the vine.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric mentally roared at the presence of the Guardian, demanding it submit, even as he gathered all the ice energy he had in him, swallowing several nearby blizzards and nearly undoing the tower of ice he was standing on. He hurled it down into the ripped open vine. The ice would either freeze a portion of the great Guardian, or would destroy the Orb of Sucellus.[PARAGRAPH:1]He waited to see what would happen. He did not have enough power to both take on the Guardian and to destroy the Orb simultaneously. Already, he felt himself wilting. He continued to pour out his energy and shout at the Guardian...[PARAGRAPH:2]Arlonte's eyes widened as the vines began to freeze. They crystallized and abruptly melted into nothingness, the Orb having burned the frozen portions away. The remaining vines at the base of the Orb recoiled and reentered the earth, vanishing, as did the aura of nature surrounding the area. His face turned grim as he considered what this meant.[PARAGRAPH:2]The icy beam continued coming, striking the orb, creating a shield of fire around the orb. Ice energy touched and froze the outside of the orb, which caught fire. That fire was then frozen as more ice energy poured down. Eventually, the orb cracked, and exploded, as it could take no more ice magic. Arlonte and the guards ducked as the smoke cleared and the beam stopped.[PARAGRAPH:2]That was when the lake froze. He turned, and his face became pale as he saw an armored warrior stalking across the ice, longsword and shield in hand. Arlonte opened his mouth to order a charge, when he found he could no longer speak. The figure waved a hand and ice filled his mouth. Still striding forward, he swung the sword in a long sweep and Arlonte dropped to the ground. As he died, he saw the figure make short work of the other guards as well...[PARAGRAPH:2]Taranis finished killing the guards and looked around, taking in data. It was another age. Mulcarn's presence was no longer felt- wait... there was an emission of him from the north, from the old realm of the Illians. Analysis: Mulcarn is weakened. Directive: Head north. Directive: Kill all in between targets. Directive: Determine the state of Mulcarn. Directive: Gather aid. Input data: No creatures of ice felt within reasonable range. Analysis: They are dispered or gathered near Mulcarn. Directive: Find them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Such was Taranis. He could take in data and make decisions, albeit in a machine-like method. But after that data was taken in and Taranis came to a decision based on it, it was dumped since it could not be remembered. He continued to reevaluate his current directives, carefully checking if the position of Mulcarn or his ice demons altered. They did not. One final directive was ordered, based on climate data.[PARAGRAPH:1]Directive: Begin the re-wintering of the world.</French>
		<German>Chapter 1: The Liberation[NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Chapter 2: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Auric stood in meditation surrounded by vast ice crystals. He smiled as he saw images of legions of Ice Golems engaging Luchuirp Golems and holding them at bay, creating a wall of stasis that stretched across the Luchuirp border, as his allies struck. He shitfted his imaging and saw frostling bandits, supported by flesh constructs from Mokka's Cauldron, engaging the Svartalfar. Things were going well, and it looked as if the Deepening would soon begin, according to Anangtios's report. That was when he sensed a disturbance around him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Reflexes honed while wandering Erebus kicked into action, and he ducked behind one of the crystals. The assassin's dart, tipped with a plant that caused spontaneous combustion when it hit a target, struck and melted a chunk of ice away. He snapped "Slow!" and the will behind the command caused time around the assassin to stretch and slow down as she was about to utter a spell that would blow the throne room apart with an inferno. It had the added effect of causing the assassin's invisibility charm to stop working, causing her to become visible to all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric walked forward and studied the assassin. She was an elf, apparently, wrapped in a black cloak covered with invisibility runes that was typical of Svartalfar dress. She also carried a large supply of deadly implements. He waved his hand, and the slow time effects intensified, stopping time around the two of them entirely. Another gesture caused the temperature to lower, subtly. Guards rushed into the room, but to Auric and the elven prisoner, they did not move.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I just thought you should know," he said, "that Illian ice sculpters are capable of altering the position and even the shape of a body after it has been frozen. It produces beautiful artwork." He gestured to the columns of ice statues lining the palace. "Not all were made out of once living people- but some were," he continued. "But, it can be done to a still living body. The process is incredibly painful, as you can no doubt imagine." The assassin's face showed that she did.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric released frozen time, and the guards seized her. He said ominously, "Sculpt her until she talks." The guards departed, dragging the shrieking prisoner, who seconds later died. He frowned. He thought he had removed all magical items with the slow spell. Evidently there was a physical poison as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]He sighed, shaking his head. He needed better guards. And then an idea, propelled by the essence of Mulcarn that lived within him, came to him, and he shouted an order. A Disciple of Winter rushed in, and he gave instructions to him, and the disciple rushed out to obey them.[PARAGRAPH:2]The tower of ice, not located in Garduk but near Letum Frigus, had been built by Auric's will, and it would stand so long as he remained alive- or willed it to collapse. Ice particles had gathered slowly and formed into beautiful crystals, which then formed into a tower. At the top of the tower were four crystalline spikes resembling stalagmites. It was at this top where Auric, Dumnanios, Riuros, and Anangtios were gathered. He had risen it for this specific purpose.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ritual was well under way. Even if anyone else on Erebus was aware of it, and could fight through the Illian and Doviello guards patrolling the empire, they would not be in time to stop it. Auric's vision honed in on an island in a lake at the edge of Elohim lands. Knowing that it was important, the Elohim were guarding a small crystal sphere on the shores of the lake with their lives. He laughed as he gathered energy. Those lives would not be enough...[PARAGRAPH:2]Arlonte, captain of the guards assigned to protect the Evergreen Lake, sighed as he watched the small company of Elohim assigned to this site. It was a good job they had- they did not have to protect the lake itself but rather what appeared to be a glowing green spherical rock. The priest, Lenyos, assigned to their group was currently studying it. The other guards were also enjoying themselves in the grass. They could relax in the lake, but Einion Logos had warned them strictly- do not venture into the lake.[PARAGRAPH:1]He headed over to the priest to take a look at his analysis of the object. That was when he felt a strange sensation, as if lightning was coming. He looked up, along with the others.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was no lightning. The clouds were glowing pure white, and it seemed as if... they were freezing.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then, there was a sudden blast of blue-white light from the frozen clouds. It appeared to be lightning, but it was clearly not. It was directed straight at the object they were supposed to protect, and one of the guards nearby instinctively dove into the path of the lightning. His body froze and was covered in ice. It then fell to the orb, which flared green, and the body of the guard caught on fire until nothing was left but ashes. Arlonte stood staring at the orb. It was obviously a tool against winter, but...[PARAGRAPH:1]His thoughts were interrupted when another blast shot through the sky. Seconds before it hit, Lenyos, a priest of the Fellowship of Leaves, muttered a prayer, and the earth glowed green. Guardian vines emerged and seized the orb. The blast of ice struck them... and nothing happened.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric reeled as a powerful presence interrupted his attack on the Orb of Sucellus guarding the lake. He had frozen a human who had been in the way of the blast, he knew, but that second power... intrigued, he studied it. And the part that was Mulcarn gave him the rest of the information. He had tried to freeze a massive creature, the Guardian of the Forest. Somehow, a being he had identified as a priest of leaves had summoned the Guardian's vines to defend the orb. Clever. He had tried to freeze the entire thing. There did not seem to be a way to win.[PARAGRAPH:1]But, after a few minutes thinking, he had one, and resumed his attack, gathering more power...[PARAGRAPH:2]The Elohim captain looked up again. Arlonte prayed that the attacker was beat and would go away. But that, of course, did not happen. Instead, another blast rained down from the frozen clouds. This one, though was glowing faintly golden... Arlonte realized with surprise that it was a lightning blast. The blast continued coming, becoming a solid beam, not a quick blast. Lenyos gasped in horror as the lightning drilled into one of the vines.[PARAGRAPH:1]He cried, "The guardian..." and rushed forward. A deflected ray of lightning struck him. Lenyos screamed in pain and died.[PARAGRAPH:1]That was when the blast penetrated through the vine.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric mentally roared at the presence of the Guardian, demanding it submit, even as he gathered all the ice energy he had in him, swallowing several nearby blizzards and nearly undoing the tower of ice he was standing on. He hurled it down into the ripped open vine. The ice would either freeze a portion of the great Guardian, or would destroy the Orb of Sucellus.[PARAGRAPH:1]He waited to see what would happen. He did not have enough power to both take on the Guardian and to destroy the Orb simultaneously. Already, he felt himself wilting. He continued to pour out his energy and shout at the Guardian...[PARAGRAPH:2]Arlonte's eyes widened as the vines began to freeze. They crystallized and abruptly melted into nothingness, the Orb having burned the frozen portions away. The remaining vines at the base of the Orb recoiled and reentered the earth, vanishing, as did the aura of nature surrounding the area. His face turned grim as he considered what this meant.[PARAGRAPH:2]The icy beam continued coming, striking the orb, creating a shield of fire around the orb. Ice energy touched and froze the outside of the orb, which caught fire. That fire was then frozen as more ice energy poured down. Eventually, the orb cracked, and exploded, as it could take no more ice magic. Arlonte and the guards ducked as the smoke cleared and the beam stopped.[PARAGRAPH:2]That was when the lake froze. He turned, and his face became pale as he saw an armored warrior stalking across the ice, longsword and shield in hand. Arlonte opened his mouth to order a charge, when he found he could no longer speak. The figure waved a hand and ice filled his mouth. Still striding forward, he swung the sword in a long sweep and Arlonte dropped to the ground. As he died, he saw the figure make short work of the other guards as well...[PARAGRAPH:2]Taranis finished killing the guards and looked around, taking in data. It was another age. Mulcarn's presence was no longer felt- wait... there was an emission of him from the north, from the old realm of the Illians. Analysis: Mulcarn is weakened. Directive: Head north. Directive: Kill all in between targets. Directive: Determine the state of Mulcarn. Directive: Gather aid. Input data: No creatures of ice felt within reasonable range. Analysis: They are dispered or gathered near Mulcarn. Directive: Find them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Such was Taranis. He could take in data and make decisions, albeit in a machine-like method. But after that data was taken in and Taranis came to a decision based on it, it was dumped since it could not be remembered. He continued to reevaluate his current directives, carefully checking if the position of Mulcarn or his ice demons altered. They did not. One final directive was ordered, based on climate data.[PARAGRAPH:1]Directive: Begin the re-wintering of the world.</German>
		<Italian>Chapter 1: The Liberation[NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Chapter 2: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Auric stood in meditation surrounded by vast ice crystals. He smiled as he saw images of legions of Ice Golems engaging Luchuirp Golems and holding them at bay, creating a wall of stasis that stretched across the Luchuirp border, as his allies struck. He shitfted his imaging and saw frostling bandits, supported by flesh constructs from Mokka's Cauldron, engaging the Svartalfar. Things were going well, and it looked as if the Deepening would soon begin, according to Anangtios's report. That was when he sensed a disturbance around him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Reflexes honed while wandering Erebus kicked into action, and he ducked behind one of the crystals. The assassin's dart, tipped with a plant that caused spontaneous combustion when it hit a target, struck and melted a chunk of ice away. He snapped "Slow!" and the will behind the command caused time around the assassin to stretch and slow down as she was about to utter a spell that would blow the throne room apart with an inferno. It had the added effect of causing the assassin's invisibility charm to stop working, causing her to become visible to all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric walked forward and studied the assassin. She was an elf, apparently, wrapped in a black cloak covered with invisibility runes that was typical of Svartalfar dress. She also carried a large supply of deadly implements. He waved his hand, and the slow time effects intensified, stopping time around the two of them entirely. Another gesture caused the temperature to lower, subtly. Guards rushed into the room, but to Auric and the elven prisoner, they did not move.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I just thought you should know," he said, "that Illian ice sculpters are capable of altering the position and even the shape of a body after it has been frozen. It produces beautiful artwork." He gestured to the columns of ice statues lining the palace. "Not all were made out of once living people- but some were," he continued. "But, it can be done to a still living body. The process is incredibly painful, as you can no doubt imagine." The assassin's face showed that she did.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric released frozen time, and the guards seized her. He said ominously, "Sculpt her until she talks." The guards departed, dragging the shrieking prisoner, who seconds later died. He frowned. He thought he had removed all magical items with the slow spell. Evidently there was a physical poison as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]He sighed, shaking his head. He needed better guards. And then an idea, propelled by the essence of Mulcarn that lived within him, came to him, and he shouted an order. A Disciple of Winter rushed in, and he gave instructions to him, and the disciple rushed out to obey them.[PARAGRAPH:2]The tower of ice, not located in Garduk but near Letum Frigus, had been built by Auric's will, and it would stand so long as he remained alive- or willed it to collapse. Ice particles had gathered slowly and formed into beautiful crystals, which then formed into a tower. At the top of the tower were four crystalline spikes resembling stalagmites. It was at this top where Auric, Dumnanios, Riuros, and Anangtios were gathered. He had risen it for this specific purpose.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ritual was well under way. Even if anyone else on Erebus was aware of it, and could fight through the Illian and Doviello guards patrolling the empire, they would not be in time to stop it. Auric's vision honed in on an island in a lake at the edge of Elohim lands. Knowing that it was important, the Elohim were guarding a small crystal sphere on the shores of the lake with their lives. He laughed as he gathered energy. Those lives would not be enough...[PARAGRAPH:2]Arlonte, captain of the guards assigned to protect the Evergreen Lake, sighed as he watched the small company of Elohim assigned to this site. It was a good job they had- they did not have to protect the lake itself but rather what appeared to be a glowing green spherical rock. The priest, Lenyos, assigned to their group was currently studying it. The other guards were also enjoying themselves in the grass. They could relax in the lake, but Einion Logos had warned them strictly- do not venture into the lake.[PARAGRAPH:1]He headed over to the priest to take a look at his analysis of the object. That was when he felt a strange sensation, as if lightning was coming. He looked up, along with the others.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was no lightning. The clouds were glowing pure white, and it seemed as if... they were freezing.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then, there was a sudden blast of blue-white light from the frozen clouds. It appeared to be lightning, but it was clearly not. It was directed straight at the object they were supposed to protect, and one of the guards nearby instinctively dove into the path of the lightning. His body froze and was covered in ice. It then fell to the orb, which flared green, and the body of the guard caught on fire until nothing was left but ashes. Arlonte stood staring at the orb. It was obviously a tool against winter, but...[PARAGRAPH:1]His thoughts were interrupted when another blast shot through the sky. Seconds before it hit, Lenyos, a priest of the Fellowship of Leaves, muttered a prayer, and the earth glowed green. Guardian vines emerged and seized the orb. The blast of ice struck them... and nothing happened.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric reeled as a powerful presence interrupted his attack on the Orb of Sucellus guarding the lake. He had frozen a human who had been in the way of the blast, he knew, but that second power... intrigued, he studied it. And the part that was Mulcarn gave him the rest of the information. He had tried to freeze a massive creature, the Guardian of the Forest. Somehow, a being he had identified as a priest of leaves had summoned the Guardian's vines to defend the orb. Clever. He had tried to freeze the entire thing. There did not seem to be a way to win.[PARAGRAPH:1]But, after a few minutes thinking, he had one, and resumed his attack, gathering more power...[PARAGRAPH:2]The Elohim captain looked up again. Arlonte prayed that the attacker was beat and would go away. But that, of course, did not happen. Instead, another blast rained down from the frozen clouds. This one, though was glowing faintly golden... Arlonte realized with surprise that it was a lightning blast. The blast continued coming, becoming a solid beam, not a quick blast. Lenyos gasped in horror as the lightning drilled into one of the vines.[PARAGRAPH:1]He cried, "The guardian..." and rushed forward. A deflected ray of lightning struck him. Lenyos screamed in pain and died.[PARAGRAPH:1]That was when the blast penetrated through the vine.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric mentally roared at the presence of the Guardian, demanding it submit, even as he gathered all the ice energy he had in him, swallowing several nearby blizzards and nearly undoing the tower of ice he was standing on. He hurled it down into the ripped open vine. The ice would either freeze a portion of the great Guardian, or would destroy the Orb of Sucellus.[PARAGRAPH:1]He waited to see what would happen. He did not have enough power to both take on the Guardian and to destroy the Orb simultaneously. Already, he felt himself wilting. He continued to pour out his energy and shout at the Guardian...[PARAGRAPH:2]Arlonte's eyes widened as the vines began to freeze. They crystallized and abruptly melted into nothingness, the Orb having burned the frozen portions away. The remaining vines at the base of the Orb recoiled and reentered the earth, vanishing, as did the aura of nature surrounding the area. His face turned grim as he considered what this meant.[PARAGRAPH:2]The icy beam continued coming, striking the orb, creating a shield of fire around the orb. Ice energy touched and froze the outside of the orb, which caught fire. That fire was then frozen as more ice energy poured down. Eventually, the orb cracked, and exploded, as it could take no more ice magic. Arlonte and the guards ducked as the smoke cleared and the beam stopped.[PARAGRAPH:2]That was when the lake froze. He turned, and his face became pale as he saw an armored warrior stalking across the ice, longsword and shield in hand. Arlonte opened his mouth to order a charge, when he found he could no longer speak. The figure waved a hand and ice filled his mouth. Still striding forward, he swung the sword in a long sweep and Arlonte dropped to the ground. As he died, he saw the figure make short work of the other guards as well...[PARAGRAPH:2]Taranis finished killing the guards and looked around, taking in data. It was another age. Mulcarn's presence was no longer felt- wait... there was an emission of him from the north, from the old realm of the Illians. Analysis: Mulcarn is weakened. Directive: Head north. Directive: Kill all in between targets. Directive: Determine the state of Mulcarn. Directive: Gather aid. Input data: No creatures of ice felt within reasonable range. Analysis: They are dispered or gathered near Mulcarn. Directive: Find them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Such was Taranis. He could take in data and make decisions, albeit in a machine-like method. But after that data was taken in and Taranis came to a decision based on it, it was dumped since it could not be remembered. He continued to reevaluate his current directives, carefully checking if the position of Mulcarn or his ice demons altered. They did not. One final directive was ordered, based on climate data.[PARAGRAPH:1]Directive: Begin the re-wintering of the world.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chapter 1: The Liberation[NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Chapter 2: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Auric stood in meditation surrounded by vast ice crystals. He smiled as he saw images of legions of Ice Golems engaging Luchuirp Golems and holding them at bay, creating a wall of stasis that stretched across the Luchuirp border, as his allies struck. He shitfted his imaging and saw frostling bandits, supported by flesh constructs from Mokka's Cauldron, engaging the Svartalfar. Things were going well, and it looked as if the Deepening would soon begin, according to Anangtios's report. That was when he sensed a disturbance around him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Reflexes honed while wandering Erebus kicked into action, and he ducked behind one of the crystals. The assassin's dart, tipped with a plant that caused spontaneous combustion when it hit a target, struck and melted a chunk of ice away. He snapped "Slow!" and the will behind the command caused time around the assassin to stretch and slow down as she was about to utter a spell that would blow the throne room apart with an inferno. It had the added effect of causing the assassin's invisibility charm to stop working, causing her to become visible to all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric walked forward and studied the assassin. She was an elf, apparently, wrapped in a black cloak covered with invisibility runes that was typical of Svartalfar dress. She also carried a large supply of deadly implements. He waved his hand, and the slow time effects intensified, stopping time around the two of them entirely. Another gesture caused the temperature to lower, subtly. Guards rushed into the room, but to Auric and the elven prisoner, they did not move.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I just thought you should know," he said, "that Illian ice sculpters are capable of altering the position and even the shape of a body after it has been frozen. It produces beautiful artwork." He gestured to the columns of ice statues lining the palace. "Not all were made out of once living people- but some were," he continued. "But, it can be done to a still living body. The process is incredibly painful, as you can no doubt imagine." The assassin's face showed that she did.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric released frozen time, and the guards seized her. He said ominously, "Sculpt her until she talks." The guards departed, dragging the shrieking prisoner, who seconds later died. He frowned. He thought he had removed all magical items with the slow spell. Evidently there was a physical poison as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]He sighed, shaking his head. He needed better guards. And then an idea, propelled by the essence of Mulcarn that lived within him, came to him, and he shouted an order. A Disciple of Winter rushed in, and he gave instructions to him, and the disciple rushed out to obey them.[PARAGRAPH:2]The tower of ice, not located in Garduk but near Letum Frigus, had been built by Auric's will, and it would stand so long as he remained alive- or willed it to collapse. Ice particles had gathered slowly and formed into beautiful crystals, which then formed into a tower. At the top of the tower were four crystalline spikes resembling stalagmites. It was at this top where Auric, Dumnanios, Riuros, and Anangtios were gathered. He had risen it for this specific purpose.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ritual was well under way. Even if anyone else on Erebus was aware of it, and could fight through the Illian and Doviello guards patrolling the empire, they would not be in time to stop it. Auric's vision honed in on an island in a lake at the edge of Elohim lands. Knowing that it was important, the Elohim were guarding a small crystal sphere on the shores of the lake with their lives. He laughed as he gathered energy. Those lives would not be enough...[PARAGRAPH:2]Arlonte, captain of the guards assigned to protect the Evergreen Lake, sighed as he watched the small company of Elohim assigned to this site. It was a good job they had- they did not have to protect the lake itself but rather what appeared to be a glowing green spherical rock. The priest, Lenyos, assigned to their group was currently studying it. The other guards were also enjoying themselves in the grass. They could relax in the lake, but Einion Logos had warned them strictly- do not venture into the lake.[PARAGRAPH:1]He headed over to the priest to take a look at his analysis of the object. That was when he felt a strange sensation, as if lightning was coming. He looked up, along with the others.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was no lightning. The clouds were glowing pure white, and it seemed as if... they were freezing.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then, there was a sudden blast of blue-white light from the frozen clouds. It appeared to be lightning, but it was clearly not. It was directed straight at the object they were supposed to protect, and one of the guards nearby instinctively dove into the path of the lightning. His body froze and was covered in ice. It then fell to the orb, which flared green, and the body of the guard caught on fire until nothing was left but ashes. Arlonte stood staring at the orb. It was obviously a tool against winter, but...[PARAGRAPH:1]His thoughts were interrupted when another blast shot through the sky. Seconds before it hit, Lenyos, a priest of the Fellowship of Leaves, muttered a prayer, and the earth glowed green. Guardian vines emerged and seized the orb. The blast of ice struck them... and nothing happened.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric reeled as a powerful presence interrupted his attack on the Orb of Sucellus guarding the lake. He had frozen a human who had been in the way of the blast, he knew, but that second power... intrigued, he studied it. And the part that was Mulcarn gave him the rest of the information. He had tried to freeze a massive creature, the Guardian of the Forest. Somehow, a being he had identified as a priest of leaves had summoned the Guardian's vines to defend the orb. Clever. He had tried to freeze the entire thing. There did not seem to be a way to win.[PARAGRAPH:1]But, after a few minutes thinking, he had one, and resumed his attack, gathering more power...[PARAGRAPH:2]The Elohim captain looked up again. Arlonte prayed that the attacker was beat and would go away. But that, of course, did not happen. Instead, another blast rained down from the frozen clouds. This one, though was glowing faintly golden... Arlonte realized with surprise that it was a lightning blast. The blast continued coming, becoming a solid beam, not a quick blast. Lenyos gasped in horror as the lightning drilled into one of the vines.[PARAGRAPH:1]He cried, "The guardian..." and rushed forward. A deflected ray of lightning struck him. Lenyos screamed in pain and died.[PARAGRAPH:1]That was when the blast penetrated through the vine.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric mentally roared at the presence of the Guardian, demanding it submit, even as he gathered all the ice energy he had in him, swallowing several nearby blizzards and nearly undoing the tower of ice he was standing on. He hurled it down into the ripped open vine. The ice would either freeze a portion of the great Guardian, or would destroy the Orb of Sucellus.[PARAGRAPH:1]He waited to see what would happen. He did not have enough power to both take on the Guardian and to destroy the Orb simultaneously. Already, he felt himself wilting. He continued to pour out his energy and shout at the Guardian...[PARAGRAPH:2]Arlonte's eyes widened as the vines began to freeze. They crystallized and abruptly melted into nothingness, the Orb having burned the frozen portions away. The remaining vines at the base of the Orb recoiled and reentered the earth, vanishing, as did the aura of nature surrounding the area. His face turned grim as he considered what this meant.[PARAGRAPH:2]The icy beam continued coming, striking the orb, creating a shield of fire around the orb. Ice energy touched and froze the outside of the orb, which caught fire. That fire was then frozen as more ice energy poured down. Eventually, the orb cracked, and exploded, as it could take no more ice magic. Arlonte and the guards ducked as the smoke cleared and the beam stopped.[PARAGRAPH:2]That was when the lake froze. He turned, and his face became pale as he saw an armored warrior stalking across the ice, longsword and shield in hand. Arlonte opened his mouth to order a charge, when he found he could no longer speak. The figure waved a hand and ice filled his mouth. Still striding forward, he swung the sword in a long sweep and Arlonte dropped to the ground. As he died, he saw the figure make short work of the other guards as well...[PARAGRAPH:2]Taranis finished killing the guards and looked around, taking in data. It was another age. Mulcarn's presence was no longer felt- wait... there was an emission of him from the north, from the old realm of the Illians. Analysis: Mulcarn is weakened. Directive: Head north. Directive: Kill all in between targets. Directive: Determine the state of Mulcarn. Directive: Gather aid. Input data: No creatures of ice felt within reasonable range. Analysis: They are dispered or gathered near Mulcarn. Directive: Find them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Such was Taranis. He could take in data and make decisions, albeit in a machine-like method. But after that data was taken in and Taranis came to a decision based on it, it was dumped since it could not be remembered. He continued to reevaluate his current directives, carefully checking if the position of Mulcarn or his ice demons altered. They did not. One final directive was ordered, based on climate data.[PARAGRAPH:1]Directive: Begin the re-wintering of the world.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_LIBERATION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Available to all neutral or evil civilizations, use Liberation to found the Frozen civilization. This will either let you take them over or gain a possible ally. Be warned- they can create any of the Spells of Winter rituals, including Ascendency.</English>
		<French>Available to all neutral or evil civilizations, use Liberation to found the Frozen civilization. This will either let you take them over or gain a possible ally. Be warned- they can create any of the Spells of Winter rituals, including Ascendency.</French>
		<German>Available to all neutral or evil civilizations, use Liberation to found the Frozen civilization. This will either let you take them over or gain a possible ally. Be warned- they can create any of the Spells of Winter rituals, including Ascendency.</German>
		<Italian>Available to all neutral or evil civilizations, use Liberation to found the Frozen civilization. This will either let you take them over or gain a possible ally. Be warned- they can create any of the Spells of Winter rituals, including Ascendency.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Available to all neutral or evil civilizations, use Liberation to found the Frozen civilization. This will either let you take them over or gain a possible ally. Be warned- they can create any of the Spells of Winter rituals, including Ascendency.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TRAIT_WINTERBORN</Tag>
		<English>Winterborn</English>
		<French>Enfant de l'Hiver</French>
		<German>Wintergeboren</German>
		<Italian>Winterborn</Italian>
		<Spanish>Winterborn</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TRAIT_WINTERBORN_SHORT</Tag>
		<English>Winter</English>
		<French>Froid</French>
		<German>Winter</German>
		<Italian>Winter</Italian>
		<Spanish>Winter</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FROZEN_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Frozen</English>
		<French>Cryos</French>
		<German>Reich der Gefrorenen</German>
		<Italian>Frozen</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frozen</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FROZEN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Frozen</English>
		<French>Cryonides</French>
		<German>Gefrorenen</German>
		<Italian>Frozen</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frozen</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FROZEN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Frozen</English>
		<French>cryonide:cryonide:cryonides:cryonides</French>
		<German>Gefroren:Gefrorenen:Gefrorene</German>
		<Italian>Frozen</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frozen</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FROZEN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The forces of Mulcarn were feared greatly during the Age of Ice. In the Age of Rebirth, people talk fearfully of the Infernal menance (or, depending on your viewpoint, the Mercurian menace). But the Frozen made the Infernals look like amateurs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mulcarn ruled a vast amount of forces. Many were fashioned directly, such as his court of frozen statues or the columns of Frost Giants. But the Frostlings served as the meat of the Frozen legion in its march on Erebus. Frostlings served the same purpose Manes do as the Infernal.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, this legion of terror, embodied with the force of Mulcarn, was eventually defeated. Their commander Taranis was trapped by Sucellus in battle, and Mulcarn was slain by Kylorin. With the vanish of their god's power, the Frozen withered. They fled to Mulcarn's realm, or dispersed and sought out the tundras of Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Yet, they were not gone for good. During the Era of Ascendency, when the Illians attempted to ascend Auric Ulvin, a number of Spells of Winter they casted gave back strength to the Frozen forces. A final spell called Taranis back from his island prison- along with a countless legion of frostlings and other beasts.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis had but one goal, and that was to reclaim the world. He did not recognize Auric Ulvin as his master for some time, and attacked all in his path no matter what lord they swore allegiance to. Taranis, being unchanging, held his position inside the Frozen capital. The ice-demons under his command expanded his empire rapidly, soon reclaiming the tundra for the servants of Mulcarn.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since Taranis has no power over souls passing from Erebus, he has constructed vast crystal ice cities which collect souls and freeze them as frostlings. When the Frozen returned, countless souls were captured and bound to serve Taranis (and Mulcarn) forever.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 1, Volume II of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</English>
		<French>The forces of Mulcarn were feared greatly during the Age of Ice. In the Age of Rebirth, people talk fearfully of the Infernal menance (or, depending on your viewpoint, the Mercurian menace). But the Frozen made the Infernals look like amateurs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mulcarn ruled a vast amount of forces. Many were fashioned directly, such as his court of frozen statues or the columns of Frost Giants. But the Frostlings served as the meat of the Frozen legion in its march on Erebus. Frostlings served the same purpose Manes do as the Infernal.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, this legion of terror, embodied with the force of Mulcarn, was eventually defeated. Their commander Taranis was trapped by Sucellus in battle, and Mulcarn was slain by Kylorin. With the vanish of their god's power, the Frozen withered. They fled to Mulcarn's realm, or dispersed and sought out the tundras of Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Yet, they were not gone for good. During the Era of Ascendency, when the Illians attempted to ascend Auric Ulvin, a number of Spells of Winter they casted gave back strength to the Frozen forces. A final spell called Taranis back from his island prison- along with a countless legion of frostlings and other beasts.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis had but one goal, and that was to reclaim the world. He did not recognize Auric Ulvin as his master for some time, and attacked all in his path no matter what lord they swore allegiance to. Taranis, being unchanging, held his position inside the Frozen capital. The ice-demons under his command expanded his empire rapidly, soon reclaiming the tundra for the servants of Mulcarn.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since Taranis has no power over souls passing from Erebus, he has constructed vast crystal ice cities which collect souls and freeze them as frostlings. When the Frozen returned, countless souls were captured and bound to serve Taranis (and Mulcarn) forever.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 1, Volume II of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</French>
		<German>The forces of Mulcarn were feared greatly during the Age of Ice. In the Age of Rebirth, people talk fearfully of the Infernal menance (or, depending on your viewpoint, the Mercurian menace). But the Frozen made the Infernals look like amateurs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mulcarn ruled a vast amount of forces. Many were fashioned directly, such as his court of frozen statues or the columns of Frost Giants. But the Frostlings served as the meat of the Frozen legion in its march on Erebus. Frostlings served the same purpose Manes do as the Infernal.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, this legion of terror, embodied with the force of Mulcarn, was eventually defeated. Their commander Taranis was trapped by Sucellus in battle, and Mulcarn was slain by Kylorin. With the vanish of their god's power, the Frozen withered. They fled to Mulcarn's realm, or dispersed and sought out the tundras of Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Yet, they were not gone for good. During the Era of Ascendency, when the Illians attempted to ascend Auric Ulvin, a number of Spells of Winter they casted gave back strength to the Frozen forces. A final spell called Taranis back from his island prison- along with a countless legion of frostlings and other beasts.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis had but one goal, and that was to reclaim the world. He did not recognize Auric Ulvin as his master for some time, and attacked all in his path no matter what lord they swore allegiance to. Taranis, being unchanging, held his position inside the Frozen capital. The ice-demons under his command expanded his empire rapidly, soon reclaiming the tundra for the servants of Mulcarn.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since Taranis has no power over souls passing from Erebus, he has constructed vast crystal ice cities which collect souls and freeze them as frostlings. When the Frozen returned, countless souls were captured and bound to serve Taranis (and Mulcarn) forever.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 1, Volume II of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</German>
		<Italian>The forces of Mulcarn were feared greatly during the Age of Ice. In the Age of Rebirth, people talk fearfully of the Infernal menance (or, depending on your viewpoint, the Mercurian menace). But the Frozen made the Infernals look like amateurs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mulcarn ruled a vast amount of forces. Many were fashioned directly, such as his court of frozen statues or the columns of Frost Giants. But the Frostlings served as the meat of the Frozen legion in its march on Erebus. Frostlings served the same purpose Manes do as the Infernal.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, this legion of terror, embodied with the force of Mulcarn, was eventually defeated. Their commander Taranis was trapped by Sucellus in battle, and Mulcarn was slain by Kylorin. With the vanish of their god's power, the Frozen withered. They fled to Mulcarn's realm, or dispersed and sought out the tundras of Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Yet, they were not gone for good. During the Era of Ascendency, when the Illians attempted to ascend Auric Ulvin, a number of Spells of Winter they casted gave back strength to the Frozen forces. A final spell called Taranis back from his island prison- along with a countless legion of frostlings and other beasts.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis had but one goal, and that was to reclaim the world. He did not recognize Auric Ulvin as his master for some time, and attacked all in his path no matter what lord they swore allegiance to. Taranis, being unchanging, held his position inside the Frozen capital. The ice-demons under his command expanded his empire rapidly, soon reclaiming the tundra for the servants of Mulcarn.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since Taranis has no power over souls passing from Erebus, he has constructed vast crystal ice cities which collect souls and freeze them as frostlings. When the Frozen returned, countless souls were captured and bound to serve Taranis (and Mulcarn) forever.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 1, Volume II of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Italian>
		<Spanish>The forces of Mulcarn were feared greatly during the Age of Ice. In the Age of Rebirth, people talk fearfully of the Infernal menance (or, depending on your viewpoint, the Mercurian menace). But the Frozen made the Infernals look like amateurs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mulcarn ruled a vast amount of forces. Many were fashioned directly, such as his court of frozen statues or the columns of Frost Giants. But the Frostlings served as the meat of the Frozen legion in its march on Erebus. Frostlings served the same purpose Manes do as the Infernal.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, this legion of terror, embodied with the force of Mulcarn, was eventually defeated. Their commander Taranis was trapped by Sucellus in battle, and Mulcarn was slain by Kylorin. With the vanish of their god's power, the Frozen withered. They fled to Mulcarn's realm, or dispersed and sought out the tundras of Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Yet, they were not gone for good. During the Era of Ascendency, when the Illians attempted to ascend Auric Ulvin, a number of Spells of Winter they casted gave back strength to the Frozen forces. A final spell called Taranis back from his island prison- along with a countless legion of frostlings and other beasts.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis had but one goal, and that was to reclaim the world. He did not recognize Auric Ulvin as his master for some time, and attacked all in his path no matter what lord they swore allegiance to. Taranis, being unchanging, held his position inside the Frozen capital. The ice-demons under his command expanded his empire rapidly, soon reclaiming the tundra for the servants of Mulcarn.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since Taranis has no power over souls passing from Erebus, he has constructed vast crystal ice cities which collect souls and freeze them as frostlings. When the Frozen returned, countless souls were captured and bound to serve Taranis (and Mulcarn) forever.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 1, Volume II of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_CONTROL_FROZEN</Tag>
		<English>You have completed the Liberation ritual and allowed the Frozen civilization to enter the world. Would you like to abandon your old civilization and play as Taranis instead?</English>
		<French>You have completed the Liberation ritual and allowed the Frozen civilization to enter the world. Would you like to abandon your old civilization and play as Taranis instead?</French>
		<German>Du hast das Befreiungsritual vollendet, womit es dem Reich der Gefrorenen erm&#246;glicht wird, die Welt zu betreten. M&#246;chtest du dein bisheriges Volk aufgeben und lieber als Taranis weiterspielen?</German>
		<Italian>You have completed the Liberation ritual and allowed the Frozen civilization to enter the world. Would you like to abandon your old civilization and play as Taranis instead?</Italian>
		<Spanish>You have completed the Liberation ritual and allowed the Frozen civilization to enter the world. Would you like to abandon your old civilization and play as Taranis instead?</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MESSAGE_ADD_FROZEN_SOULS</Tag>
		<English>A spirit has been trapped in your empire and has become a Frozen Soul</English>
		<French>Une âme a été piégée par votre empire et transformée en Âme Gelée</French>
		<German>Ein Geist wurde in deinem Reich gefangen und ist zu einer Gefrorenen Seele geworden</German>
		<Italian>A spirit has been trapped in your empire and has become a Frozen Soul</Italian>
		<Spanish>A spirit has been trapped in your empire and has become a Frozen Soul</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MESSAGE_UNIT_FREEZES</Tag>
		<English>Some of your units have gone on to serve the Frozen in the afterlife</English>
		<French>Some of your units have gone on to serve the Frozen in the afterlife</French>
		<German>Einige deiner Einheiten haben dich verlassen, um den Gefrorenen im Jenseits zu dienen</German>
		<Italian>Some of your units have gone on to serve the Frozen in the afterlife</Italian>
		<Spanish>Some of your units have gone on to serve the Frozen in the afterlife</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>Taranis</English>
		<French>Taranis</French>
		<German>Taranis</German>
		<Italian>Taranis</Italian>
		<Spanish>Taranis</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_TARANIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Chapter 1: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Chapter 2: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE]Chapter 3: The Liberation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Taranis's eyes pulsed with blue light as he stood, guarded... and contemplated. The archangel of winter was becoming aware of disturbing new sensations. The fact that he was aware of such things at all and could remember them was disturbing. It was irregular. It was not normal. It was change.[PARAGRAPH:1]Something had happened to him. But what? He needed to know, but the very fact that he needed to know was proof of the effects. Somehow, the order and tranquility in his mind had been disturbed. And he was becoming aware of a new thought process. It was quite a simple thought process. Auric Ulvin had touched his mind. After doing so, he had become disturbed. Therefore, Auric Ulvin's mental contact had caused this.[PARAGRAPH:1]This overrode all other orders. The equilibrium had to be restored, and there was only one way to do that.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric once again stood in meditation, surrounded by ice crystals. The Spells of Winter were proceeding according to plan, and soon he would be the lord of winter. Thanks to Taranis, all assassination attempts had been shrugged off. The archangel was proving quite useful after all, but Auric wondered why such a being would be so useful to a god. Surely, Mulcarn had not feared assassination attempts and require constant protection? Certaintly not until he entered Erebus, anyway. So why had Taranis been bound?[PARAGRAPH:1]As Auric was thinking of Taranis, he became aware of movement behind him. He turned... to see a charging Taranis, sword raised, heading straight for him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Not wasting any time, Auric concentrated, and said a few words. Taranis's progress through the air was slowed as the slow spells took effect. Auric intended to hold Taranis in one place until he could determine what was going on. But Taranis retaliated with a set of his own slow spells, seizing Auric and slowing the rate of increase of Auric's magical potential.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was a stalemate, and a dangerous one. Taranis would eventually strike Auric, and surely slay him, for Auric could not access much of his ice magic outside of the slow spells already cast. But likewise, Auric would eventually gain full control of his ice magic and be able to attack Taranis in many ways- blast him backwards, freeze him temporarily, and then investigate his mind. The question was, which would come first? So, Auric spoke to buy time. Guards would eventually arrive, and that would force Taranis to concentrate his attacks on two positions at once, which would break the stalemate.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Why are you attacking me? Why did you disobey my order?" he asked, not necessarily expecting an answer. To his surprise, Taranis gave him one, out of a mouth that surely had not been spoken from since his creation.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Undo... what you have... done... to me... and I... will... stop." Auric raised an eyebrow. Did Taranis mean the binding Mulcarn had given him? Did he long for his independence?[PARAGRAPH:1]"I will try," he said, plunging into Taranis's mind once again. There was clearly something wrong here. Mental strands that had been firmly bound were becoming unraveled. Auric pulled on a few, guessing that these were the bounds imposed by Mulcarn, and exited Taranis's mind.[PARAGRAPH:2]Taranis dropped to his knees after Auric touched his mind again. The equilibrium was not being restored- it was being destroyed! Actively! And this human thought himself capable of becoming the angel of winter?[PARAGRAPH:1]He paused again. That was an uncharacteristic thought. Thought was uncharacteristic in the first place! But it did not seem so now. Just as the desire to restore stasis and equilibrium had overrode all other orders, these new thoughts began to override those.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You... are not fit... to be... the Angel of Winter!" he said, even managing an exclamation point. He rose again, but did not charge Auric Ulvin. "The Archangel.. of Mulcarn is fit... to be... Angel of Winter," Taranis said. "I... will... Ascend." With that, Taranis turned and left the chamber. A new command had been burned into his mind from the leftover remnants of Mulcarn's programming and Auric's tinkering. He was to ascend, and take Mulcarn's place. He knew he could do it, too- Auric had done enough damage that slowly and surely, the programming of Mulcarn would be undone.[PARAGRAPH:1]Illian guards, sent by Auric, were in his path. Taranis glared at them with contempt, and did not even bother with his sword. They froze where they stood. He would command the ice to shatter, but he would need the energy for what he was going to do. As a result, any other Illian he encountered on his way out of Garduk was frozen, but was not shattered. But when he reached and touched the icy walls of the city, he did shatter them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric had chosen to enclose his capital in great walls of ice encompassing walls of stone. The walls of stone were there in case anyone was able to penetrate the ice, as Taranis was doing now. The ice that reinforced Garduk's walls cracked, and crumbled all around the city. Gone were the frozen crenellations and icy towers. All that remained was a rather unimpressive wall of stone, and that was easily destroyed with a swing of his sword. The touch of the blade froze a portion of it, and then shattered it, creating an opening.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis stepped out of Garduk and walked into the frozen wastes. Much needed to be done to restore Erebus to an Age of Ice, but he intended to do it, and do a far better job at it than Auric was trying to do.[PARAGRAPH:2]The archangel of winter reached a spot, seemingly unremarkable, that contained one of the last remaining ice mana crystals. He sensed it, and nodded. A good spot.[PARAGRAPH:1]It did not take long to dig out the crystals. They still had much of their former power, as blizzards still frequently passed by. As a result, Taranis had all the energy he would need.[PARAGRAPH:1]Touching the crystals, he sent out commands through the ice of Erebus, making contact with the few creatures of his sphere still there. He found few, but the ones he did find he gave commands- to come. Come, and obey. Taranis then made a connection to Mulyr, the realm of Mulcarn... and himself. He found few ice demons there as well, and the ones he did find were mostly busy patrolling the slopes of the mountain and guarding souls remaining in the swamps below. From what Taranis was seeing- that demons of other lords were seizing these souls and forging them into bizarre constructs- they were needed there. Still, he called the few he could spare to Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]It took quite some time for them to appear, but Taranis was not concerned with time. Eventually they were all there, and he looked around at them. Frozen souls and hollow men, the weak ghosts of dead followers of winter. They would need to gain strength before all this was over. Then there were other demons who did not have forms but instead were guiding ice golems. Still more warriors carrying swords and blades, with the White Hand etched across their armor. Some frostlings and a winter wolf had joined the group as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis looked at them. He would need to reforge the legions of ice demons, spread cold, ice, and winter across every corner of Erebus, begin work on ascending to the position of angel of winter, and many other things. Things that would take time and be very difficult. But time and difficulty were irrelevant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Touching the ice crystals again, Taranis drew every ounce of power from them and rose a city of ice. A copy of the cities of hell that other demon lords and archangels had risen in Erebus, but one built on ice, not fire or shadow. He named the city Mulyr, an extension of his vault.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen would begin here.</English>
		<French>[LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Chapter 1: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Chapter 2: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE]Chapter 3: The Liberation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Taranis's eyes pulsed with blue light as he stood, guarded... and contemplated. The archangel of winter was becoming aware of disturbing new sensations. The fact that he was aware of such things at all and could remember them was disturbing. It was irregular. It was not normal. It was change.[PARAGRAPH:1]Something had happened to him. But what? He needed to know, but the very fact that he needed to know was proof of the effects. Somehow, the order and tranquility in his mind had been disturbed. And he was becoming aware of a new thought process. It was quite a simple thought process. Auric Ulvin had touched his mind. After doing so, he had become disturbed. Therefore, Auric Ulvin's mental contact had caused this.[PARAGRAPH:1]This overrode all other orders. The equilibrium had to be restored, and there was only one way to do that.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric once again stood in meditation, surrounded by ice crystals. The Spells of Winter were proceeding according to plan, and soon he would be the lord of winter. Thanks to Taranis, all assassination attempts had been shrugged off. The archangel was proving quite useful after all, but Auric wondered why such a being would be so useful to a god. Surely, Mulcarn had not feared assassination attempts and require constant protection? Certaintly not until he entered Erebus, anyway. So why had Taranis been bound?[PARAGRAPH:1]As Auric was thinking of Taranis, he became aware of movement behind him. He turned... to see a charging Taranis, sword raised, heading straight for him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Not wasting any time, Auric concentrated, and said a few words. Taranis's progress through the air was slowed as the slow spells took effect. Auric intended to hold Taranis in one place until he could determine what was going on. But Taranis retaliated with a set of his own slow spells, seizing Auric and slowing the rate of increase of Auric's magical potential.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was a stalemate, and a dangerous one. Taranis would eventually strike Auric, and surely slay him, for Auric could not access much of his ice magic outside of the slow spells already cast. But likewise, Auric would eventually gain full control of his ice magic and be able to attack Taranis in many ways- blast him backwards, freeze him temporarily, and then investigate his mind. The question was, which would come first? So, Auric spoke to buy time. Guards would eventually arrive, and that would force Taranis to concentrate his attacks on two positions at once, which would break the stalemate.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Why are you attacking me? Why did you disobey my order?" he asked, not necessarily expecting an answer. To his surprise, Taranis gave him one, out of a mouth that surely had not been spoken from since his creation.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Undo... what you have... done... to me... and I... will... stop." Auric raised an eyebrow. Did Taranis mean the binding Mulcarn had given him? Did he long for his independence?[PARAGRAPH:1]"I will try," he said, plunging into Taranis's mind once again. There was clearly something wrong here. Mental strands that had been firmly bound were becoming unraveled. Auric pulled on a few, guessing that these were the bounds imposed by Mulcarn, and exited Taranis's mind.[PARAGRAPH:2]Taranis dropped to his knees after Auric touched his mind again. The equilibrium was not being restored- it was being destroyed! Actively! And this human thought himself capable of becoming the angel of winter?[PARAGRAPH:1]He paused again. That was an uncharacteristic thought. Thought was uncharacteristic in the first place! But it did not seem so now. Just as the desire to restore stasis and equilibrium had overrode all other orders, these new thoughts began to override those.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You... are not fit... to be... the Angel of Winter!" he said, even managing an exclamation point. He rose again, but did not charge Auric Ulvin. "The Archangel.. of Mulcarn is fit... to be... Angel of Winter," Taranis said. "I... will... Ascend." With that, Taranis turned and left the chamber. A new command had been burned into his mind from the leftover remnants of Mulcarn's programming and Auric's tinkering. He was to ascend, and take Mulcarn's place. He knew he could do it, too- Auric had done enough damage that slowly and surely, the programming of Mulcarn would be undone.[PARAGRAPH:1]Illian guards, sent by Auric, were in his path. Taranis glared at them with contempt, and did not even bother with his sword. They froze where they stood. He would command the ice to shatter, but he would need the energy for what he was going to do. As a result, any other Illian he encountered on his way out of Garduk was frozen, but was not shattered. But when he reached and touched the icy walls of the city, he did shatter them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric had chosen to enclose his capital in great walls of ice encompassing walls of stone. The walls of stone were there in case anyone was able to penetrate the ice, as Taranis was doing now. The ice that reinforced Garduk's walls cracked, and crumbled all around the city. Gone were the frozen crenellations and icy towers. All that remained was a rather unimpressive wall of stone, and that was easily destroyed with a swing of his sword. The touch of the blade froze a portion of it, and then shattered it, creating an opening.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis stepped out of Garduk and walked into the frozen wastes. Much needed to be done to restore Erebus to an Age of Ice, but he intended to do it, and do a far better job at it than Auric was trying to do.[PARAGRAPH:2]The archangel of winter reached a spot, seemingly unremarkable, that contained one of the last remaining ice mana crystals. He sensed it, and nodded. A good spot.[PARAGRAPH:1]It did not take long to dig out the crystals. They still had much of their former power, as blizzards still frequently passed by. As a result, Taranis had all the energy he would need.[PARAGRAPH:1]Touching the crystals, he sent out commands through the ice of Erebus, making contact with the few creatures of his sphere still there. He found few, but the ones he did find he gave commands- to come. Come, and obey. Taranis then made a connection to Mulyr, the realm of Mulcarn... and himself. He found few ice demons there as well, and the ones he did find were mostly busy patrolling the slopes of the mountain and guarding souls remaining in the swamps below. From what Taranis was seeing- that demons of other lords were seizing these souls and forging them into bizarre constructs- they were needed there. Still, he called the few he could spare to Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]It took quite some time for them to appear, but Taranis was not concerned with time. Eventually they were all there, and he looked around at them. Frozen souls and hollow men, the weak ghosts of dead followers of winter. They would need to gain strength before all this was over. Then there were other demons who did not have forms but instead were guiding ice golems. Still more warriors carrying swords and blades, with the White Hand etched across their armor. Some frostlings and a winter wolf had joined the group as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis looked at them. He would need to reforge the legions of ice demons, spread cold, ice, and winter across every corner of Erebus, begin work on ascending to the position of angel of winter, and many other things. Things that would take time and be very difficult. But time and difficulty were irrelevant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Touching the ice crystals again, Taranis drew every ounce of power from them and rose a city of ice. A copy of the cities of hell that other demon lords and archangels had risen in Erebus, but one built on ice, not fire or shadow. He named the city Mulyr, an extension of his vault.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen would begin here.</French>
		<German>[LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Chapter 1: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Chapter 2: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE]Chapter 3: The Liberation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Taranis's eyes pulsed with blue light as he stood, guarded... and contemplated. The archangel of winter was becoming aware of disturbing new sensations. The fact that he was aware of such things at all and could remember them was disturbing. It was irregular. It was not normal. It was change.[PARAGRAPH:1]Something had happened to him. But what? He needed to know, but the very fact that he needed to know was proof of the effects. Somehow, the order and tranquility in his mind had been disturbed. And he was becoming aware of a new thought process. It was quite a simple thought process. Auric Ulvin had touched his mind. After doing so, he had become disturbed. Therefore, Auric Ulvin's mental contact had caused this.[PARAGRAPH:1]This overrode all other orders. The equilibrium had to be restored, and there was only one way to do that.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric once again stood in meditation, surrounded by ice crystals. The Spells of Winter were proceeding according to plan, and soon he would be the lord of winter. Thanks to Taranis, all assassination attempts had been shrugged off. The archangel was proving quite useful after all, but Auric wondered why such a being would be so useful to a god. Surely, Mulcarn had not feared assassination attempts and require constant protection? Certaintly not until he entered Erebus, anyway. So why had Taranis been bound?[PARAGRAPH:1]As Auric was thinking of Taranis, he became aware of movement behind him. He turned... to see a charging Taranis, sword raised, heading straight for him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Not wasting any time, Auric concentrated, and said a few words. Taranis's progress through the air was slowed as the slow spells took effect. Auric intended to hold Taranis in one place until he could determine what was going on. But Taranis retaliated with a set of his own slow spells, seizing Auric and slowing the rate of increase of Auric's magical potential.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was a stalemate, and a dangerous one. Taranis would eventually strike Auric, and surely slay him, for Auric could not access much of his ice magic outside of the slow spells already cast. But likewise, Auric would eventually gain full control of his ice magic and be able to attack Taranis in many ways- blast him backwards, freeze him temporarily, and then investigate his mind. The question was, which would come first? So, Auric spoke to buy time. Guards would eventually arrive, and that would force Taranis to concentrate his attacks on two positions at once, which would break the stalemate.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Why are you attacking me? Why did you disobey my order?" he asked, not necessarily expecting an answer. To his surprise, Taranis gave him one, out of a mouth that surely had not been spoken from since his creation.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Undo... what you have... done... to me... and I... will... stop." Auric raised an eyebrow. Did Taranis mean the binding Mulcarn had given him? Did he long for his independence?[PARAGRAPH:1]"I will try," he said, plunging into Taranis's mind once again. There was clearly something wrong here. Mental strands that had been firmly bound were becoming unraveled. Auric pulled on a few, guessing that these were the bounds imposed by Mulcarn, and exited Taranis's mind.[PARAGRAPH:2]Taranis dropped to his knees after Auric touched his mind again. The equilibrium was not being restored- it was being destroyed! Actively! And this human thought himself capable of becoming the angel of winter?[PARAGRAPH:1]He paused again. That was an uncharacteristic thought. Thought was uncharacteristic in the first place! But it did not seem so now. Just as the desire to restore stasis and equilibrium had overrode all other orders, these new thoughts began to override those.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You... are not fit... to be... the Angel of Winter!" he said, even managing an exclamation point. He rose again, but did not charge Auric Ulvin. "The Archangel.. of Mulcarn is fit... to be... Angel of Winter," Taranis said. "I... will... Ascend." With that, Taranis turned and left the chamber. A new command had been burned into his mind from the leftover remnants of Mulcarn's programming and Auric's tinkering. He was to ascend, and take Mulcarn's place. He knew he could do it, too- Auric had done enough damage that slowly and surely, the programming of Mulcarn would be undone.[PARAGRAPH:1]Illian guards, sent by Auric, were in his path. Taranis glared at them with contempt, and did not even bother with his sword. They froze where they stood. He would command the ice to shatter, but he would need the energy for what he was going to do. As a result, any other Illian he encountered on his way out of Garduk was frozen, but was not shattered. But when he reached and touched the icy walls of the city, he did shatter them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric had chosen to enclose his capital in great walls of ice encompassing walls of stone. The walls of stone were there in case anyone was able to penetrate the ice, as Taranis was doing now. The ice that reinforced Garduk's walls cracked, and crumbled all around the city. Gone were the frozen crenellations and icy towers. All that remained was a rather unimpressive wall of stone, and that was easily destroyed with a swing of his sword. The touch of the blade froze a portion of it, and then shattered it, creating an opening.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis stepped out of Garduk and walked into the frozen wastes. Much needed to be done to restore Erebus to an Age of Ice, but he intended to do it, and do a far better job at it than Auric was trying to do.[PARAGRAPH:2]The archangel of winter reached a spot, seemingly unremarkable, that contained one of the last remaining ice mana crystals. He sensed it, and nodded. A good spot.[PARAGRAPH:1]It did not take long to dig out the crystals. They still had much of their former power, as blizzards still frequently passed by. As a result, Taranis had all the energy he would need.[PARAGRAPH:1]Touching the crystals, he sent out commands through the ice of Erebus, making contact with the few creatures of his sphere still there. He found few, but the ones he did find he gave commands- to come. Come, and obey. Taranis then made a connection to Mulyr, the realm of Mulcarn... and himself. He found few ice demons there as well, and the ones he did find were mostly busy patrolling the slopes of the mountain and guarding souls remaining in the swamps below. From what Taranis was seeing- that demons of other lords were seizing these souls and forging them into bizarre constructs- they were needed there. Still, he called the few he could spare to Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]It took quite some time for them to appear, but Taranis was not concerned with time. Eventually they were all there, and he looked around at them. Frozen souls and hollow men, the weak ghosts of dead followers of winter. They would need to gain strength before all this was over. Then there were other demons who did not have forms but instead were guiding ice golems. Still more warriors carrying swords and blades, with the White Hand etched across their armor. Some frostlings and a winter wolf had joined the group as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis looked at them. He would need to reforge the legions of ice demons, spread cold, ice, and winter across every corner of Erebus, begin work on ascending to the position of angel of winter, and many other things. Things that would take time and be very difficult. But time and difficulty were irrelevant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Touching the ice crystals again, Taranis drew every ounce of power from them and rose a city of ice. A copy of the cities of hell that other demon lords and archangels had risen in Erebus, but one built on ice, not fire or shadow. He named the city Mulyr, an extension of his vault.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen would begin here.</German>
		<Italian>[LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Chapter 1: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Chapter 2: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE]Chapter 3: The Liberation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Taranis's eyes pulsed with blue light as he stood, guarded... and contemplated. The archangel of winter was becoming aware of disturbing new sensations. The fact that he was aware of such things at all and could remember them was disturbing. It was irregular. It was not normal. It was change.[PARAGRAPH:1]Something had happened to him. But what? He needed to know, but the very fact that he needed to know was proof of the effects. Somehow, the order and tranquility in his mind had been disturbed. And he was becoming aware of a new thought process. It was quite a simple thought process. Auric Ulvin had touched his mind. After doing so, he had become disturbed. Therefore, Auric Ulvin's mental contact had caused this.[PARAGRAPH:1]This overrode all other orders. The equilibrium had to be restored, and there was only one way to do that.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric once again stood in meditation, surrounded by ice crystals. The Spells of Winter were proceeding according to plan, and soon he would be the lord of winter. Thanks to Taranis, all assassination attempts had been shrugged off. The archangel was proving quite useful after all, but Auric wondered why such a being would be so useful to a god. Surely, Mulcarn had not feared assassination attempts and require constant protection? Certaintly not until he entered Erebus, anyway. So why had Taranis been bound?[PARAGRAPH:1]As Auric was thinking of Taranis, he became aware of movement behind him. He turned... to see a charging Taranis, sword raised, heading straight for him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Not wasting any time, Auric concentrated, and said a few words. Taranis's progress through the air was slowed as the slow spells took effect. Auric intended to hold Taranis in one place until he could determine what was going on. But Taranis retaliated with a set of his own slow spells, seizing Auric and slowing the rate of increase of Auric's magical potential.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was a stalemate, and a dangerous one. Taranis would eventually strike Auric, and surely slay him, for Auric could not access much of his ice magic outside of the slow spells already cast. But likewise, Auric would eventually gain full control of his ice magic and be able to attack Taranis in many ways- blast him backwards, freeze him temporarily, and then investigate his mind. The question was, which would come first? So, Auric spoke to buy time. Guards would eventually arrive, and that would force Taranis to concentrate his attacks on two positions at once, which would break the stalemate.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Why are you attacking me? Why did you disobey my order?" he asked, not necessarily expecting an answer. To his surprise, Taranis gave him one, out of a mouth that surely had not been spoken from since his creation.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Undo... what you have... done... to me... and I... will... stop." Auric raised an eyebrow. Did Taranis mean the binding Mulcarn had given him? Did he long for his independence?[PARAGRAPH:1]"I will try," he said, plunging into Taranis's mind once again. There was clearly something wrong here. Mental strands that had been firmly bound were becoming unraveled. Auric pulled on a few, guessing that these were the bounds imposed by Mulcarn, and exited Taranis's mind.[PARAGRAPH:2]Taranis dropped to his knees after Auric touched his mind again. The equilibrium was not being restored- it was being destroyed! Actively! And this human thought himself capable of becoming the angel of winter?[PARAGRAPH:1]He paused again. That was an uncharacteristic thought. Thought was uncharacteristic in the first place! But it did not seem so now. Just as the desire to restore stasis and equilibrium had overrode all other orders, these new thoughts began to override those.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You... are not fit... to be... the Angel of Winter!" he said, even managing an exclamation point. He rose again, but did not charge Auric Ulvin. "The Archangel.. of Mulcarn is fit... to be... Angel of Winter," Taranis said. "I... will... Ascend." With that, Taranis turned and left the chamber. A new command had been burned into his mind from the leftover remnants of Mulcarn's programming and Auric's tinkering. He was to ascend, and take Mulcarn's place. He knew he could do it, too- Auric had done enough damage that slowly and surely, the programming of Mulcarn would be undone.[PARAGRAPH:1]Illian guards, sent by Auric, were in his path. Taranis glared at them with contempt, and did not even bother with his sword. They froze where they stood. He would command the ice to shatter, but he would need the energy for what he was going to do. As a result, any other Illian he encountered on his way out of Garduk was frozen, but was not shattered. But when he reached and touched the icy walls of the city, he did shatter them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric had chosen to enclose his capital in great walls of ice encompassing walls of stone. The walls of stone were there in case anyone was able to penetrate the ice, as Taranis was doing now. The ice that reinforced Garduk's walls cracked, and crumbled all around the city. Gone were the frozen crenellations and icy towers. All that remained was a rather unimpressive wall of stone, and that was easily destroyed with a swing of his sword. The touch of the blade froze a portion of it, and then shattered it, creating an opening.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis stepped out of Garduk and walked into the frozen wastes. Much needed to be done to restore Erebus to an Age of Ice, but he intended to do it, and do a far better job at it than Auric was trying to do.[PARAGRAPH:2]The archangel of winter reached a spot, seemingly unremarkable, that contained one of the last remaining ice mana crystals. He sensed it, and nodded. A good spot.[PARAGRAPH:1]It did not take long to dig out the crystals. They still had much of their former power, as blizzards still frequently passed by. As a result, Taranis had all the energy he would need.[PARAGRAPH:1]Touching the crystals, he sent out commands through the ice of Erebus, making contact with the few creatures of his sphere still there. He found few, but the ones he did find he gave commands- to come. Come, and obey. Taranis then made a connection to Mulyr, the realm of Mulcarn... and himself. He found few ice demons there as well, and the ones he did find were mostly busy patrolling the slopes of the mountain and guarding souls remaining in the swamps below. From what Taranis was seeing- that demons of other lords were seizing these souls and forging them into bizarre constructs- they were needed there. Still, he called the few he could spare to Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]It took quite some time for them to appear, but Taranis was not concerned with time. Eventually they were all there, and he looked around at them. Frozen souls and hollow men, the weak ghosts of dead followers of winter. They would need to gain strength before all this was over. Then there were other demons who did not have forms but instead were guiding ice golems. Still more warriors carrying swords and blades, with the White Hand etched across their armor. Some frostlings and a winter wolf had joined the group as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis looked at them. He would need to reforge the legions of ice demons, spread cold, ice, and winter across every corner of Erebus, begin work on ascending to the position of angel of winter, and many other things. Things that would take time and be very difficult. But time and difficulty were irrelevant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Touching the ice crystals again, Taranis drew every ounce of power from them and rose a city of ice. A copy of the cities of hell that other demon lords and archangels had risen in Erebus, but one built on ice, not fire or shadow. He named the city Mulyr, an extension of his vault.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen would begin here.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Chapter 1: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TARANIS]Chapter 2: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE]Chapter 3: The Liberation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Taranis's eyes pulsed with blue light as he stood, guarded... and contemplated. The archangel of winter was becoming aware of disturbing new sensations. The fact that he was aware of such things at all and could remember them was disturbing. It was irregular. It was not normal. It was change.[PARAGRAPH:1]Something had happened to him. But what? He needed to know, but the very fact that he needed to know was proof of the effects. Somehow, the order and tranquility in his mind had been disturbed. And he was becoming aware of a new thought process. It was quite a simple thought process. Auric Ulvin had touched his mind. After doing so, he had become disturbed. Therefore, Auric Ulvin's mental contact had caused this.[PARAGRAPH:1]This overrode all other orders. The equilibrium had to be restored, and there was only one way to do that.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric once again stood in meditation, surrounded by ice crystals. The Spells of Winter were proceeding according to plan, and soon he would be the lord of winter. Thanks to Taranis, all assassination attempts had been shrugged off. The archangel was proving quite useful after all, but Auric wondered why such a being would be so useful to a god. Surely, Mulcarn had not feared assassination attempts and require constant protection? Certaintly not until he entered Erebus, anyway. So why had Taranis been bound?[PARAGRAPH:1]As Auric was thinking of Taranis, he became aware of movement behind him. He turned... to see a charging Taranis, sword raised, heading straight for him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Not wasting any time, Auric concentrated, and said a few words. Taranis's progress through the air was slowed as the slow spells took effect. Auric intended to hold Taranis in one place until he could determine what was going on. But Taranis retaliated with a set of his own slow spells, seizing Auric and slowing the rate of increase of Auric's magical potential.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was a stalemate, and a dangerous one. Taranis would eventually strike Auric, and surely slay him, for Auric could not access much of his ice magic outside of the slow spells already cast. But likewise, Auric would eventually gain full control of his ice magic and be able to attack Taranis in many ways- blast him backwards, freeze him temporarily, and then investigate his mind. The question was, which would come first? So, Auric spoke to buy time. Guards would eventually arrive, and that would force Taranis to concentrate his attacks on two positions at once, which would break the stalemate.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Why are you attacking me? Why did you disobey my order?" he asked, not necessarily expecting an answer. To his surprise, Taranis gave him one, out of a mouth that surely had not been spoken from since his creation.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Undo... what you have... done... to me... and I... will... stop." Auric raised an eyebrow. Did Taranis mean the binding Mulcarn had given him? Did he long for his independence?[PARAGRAPH:1]"I will try," he said, plunging into Taranis's mind once again. There was clearly something wrong here. Mental strands that had been firmly bound were becoming unraveled. Auric pulled on a few, guessing that these were the bounds imposed by Mulcarn, and exited Taranis's mind.[PARAGRAPH:2]Taranis dropped to his knees after Auric touched his mind again. The equilibrium was not being restored- it was being destroyed! Actively! And this human thought himself capable of becoming the angel of winter?[PARAGRAPH:1]He paused again. That was an uncharacteristic thought. Thought was uncharacteristic in the first place! But it did not seem so now. Just as the desire to restore stasis and equilibrium had overrode all other orders, these new thoughts began to override those.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You... are not fit... to be... the Angel of Winter!" he said, even managing an exclamation point. He rose again, but did not charge Auric Ulvin. "The Archangel.. of Mulcarn is fit... to be... Angel of Winter," Taranis said. "I... will... Ascend." With that, Taranis turned and left the chamber. A new command had been burned into his mind from the leftover remnants of Mulcarn's programming and Auric's tinkering. He was to ascend, and take Mulcarn's place. He knew he could do it, too- Auric had done enough damage that slowly and surely, the programming of Mulcarn would be undone.[PARAGRAPH:1]Illian guards, sent by Auric, were in his path. Taranis glared at them with contempt, and did not even bother with his sword. They froze where they stood. He would command the ice to shatter, but he would need the energy for what he was going to do. As a result, any other Illian he encountered on his way out of Garduk was frozen, but was not shattered. But when he reached and touched the icy walls of the city, he did shatter them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric had chosen to enclose his capital in great walls of ice encompassing walls of stone. The walls of stone were there in case anyone was able to penetrate the ice, as Taranis was doing now. The ice that reinforced Garduk's walls cracked, and crumbled all around the city. Gone were the frozen crenellations and icy towers. All that remained was a rather unimpressive wall of stone, and that was easily destroyed with a swing of his sword. The touch of the blade froze a portion of it, and then shattered it, creating an opening.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis stepped out of Garduk and walked into the frozen wastes. Much needed to be done to restore Erebus to an Age of Ice, but he intended to do it, and do a far better job at it than Auric was trying to do.[PARAGRAPH:2]The archangel of winter reached a spot, seemingly unremarkable, that contained one of the last remaining ice mana crystals. He sensed it, and nodded. A good spot.[PARAGRAPH:1]It did not take long to dig out the crystals. They still had much of their former power, as blizzards still frequently passed by. As a result, Taranis had all the energy he would need.[PARAGRAPH:1]Touching the crystals, he sent out commands through the ice of Erebus, making contact with the few creatures of his sphere still there. He found few, but the ones he did find he gave commands- to come. Come, and obey. Taranis then made a connection to Mulyr, the realm of Mulcarn... and himself. He found few ice demons there as well, and the ones he did find were mostly busy patrolling the slopes of the mountain and guarding souls remaining in the swamps below. From what Taranis was seeing- that demons of other lords were seizing these souls and forging them into bizarre constructs- they were needed there. Still, he called the few he could spare to Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]It took quite some time for them to appear, but Taranis was not concerned with time. Eventually they were all there, and he looked around at them. Frozen souls and hollow men, the weak ghosts of dead followers of winter. They would need to gain strength before all this was over. Then there were other demons who did not have forms but instead were guiding ice golems. Still more warriors carrying swords and blades, with the White Hand etched across their armor. Some frostlings and a winter wolf had joined the group as well.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis looked at them. He would need to reforge the legions of ice demons, spread cold, ice, and winter across every corner of Erebus, begin work on ascending to the position of angel of winter, and many other things. Things that would take time and be very difficult. But time and difficulty were irrelevant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Touching the ice crystals again, Taranis drew every ounce of power from them and rose a city of ice. A copy of the cities of hell that other demon lords and archangels had risen in Erebus, but one built on ice, not fire or shadow. He named the city Mulyr, an extension of his vault.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen would begin here.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_TARANIS_PEDIA_ALTERNATE</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The body of the warrior known as Taranis the Unchanging by men, Taranis the Defiled by elves, and Taranis the Guardian by the Winterborn stood. Taranis stood at attention on the small rock which he was trapped for all of time. The lakes surrounding him were maintained by Sucellus's power, manifested in an orb.[PARAGRAPH:1]Thrice Mulcarn had sent troops to free him. But the Orb had shattered lines of Illian spearmen with guardian vines beneath their feet, and melted Frost Giants with the power of nature. There was no hope of rescue, but Taranis did not care. While he could think, his mind could not handle original thoughts because Mulcarn had frozen his soul permanently, he rarely did. He merely acted.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was a sudden shifting as if the land was being probed by a magical aura. Taranis sent out a mental ping into the ether, and found it was alive with activity. Ice magic was being concentrated in a massive blast. Suddenly, it exploded outwards, and Taranis's eyes detected a channel of white energy strike the opposite coastline. There was a noise like the cracking of crystal into many shards.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis raised a hand. The earth trembled as a field of ice was moved from the infinite elemental planes to this lake. It suddenly flashed and the lake was frozen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis stepped forward for the first time in hundreds of years. He raised his sword, and marched over the ice. He was, at last, free.[PARAGRAPH:1]Standing on the ocean's shores, Taranis realized (as hard as this was to happen) that the world was much different. It was a new age. He could feel the bright flares of Hyborem and Basium in the world, and of his foe Brigit bond in his master's domain to the north, and as ever the rock of Odio still bound.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The body of the warrior known as Taranis the Unchanging by men, Taranis the Defiled by elves, and Taranis the Guardian by the Winterborn stood. Taranis stood at attention on the small rock which he was trapped for all of time. The lakes surrounding him were maintained by Sucellus's power, manifested in an orb.[PARAGRAPH:1]Thrice Mulcarn had sent troops to free him. But the Orb had shattered lines of Illian spearmen with guardian vines beneath their feet, and melted Frost Giants with the power of nature. There was no hope of rescue, but Taranis did not care. While he could think, his mind could not handle original thoughts because Mulcarn had frozen his soul permanently, he rarely did. He merely acted.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was a sudden shifting as if the land was being probed by a magical aura. Taranis sent out a mental ping into the ether, and found it was alive with activity. Ice magic was being concentrated in a massive blast. Suddenly, it exploded outwards, and Taranis's eyes detected a channel of white energy strike the opposite coastline. There was a noise like the cracking of crystal into many shards.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis raised a hand. The earth trembled as a field of ice was moved from the infinite elemental planes to this lake. It suddenly flashed and the lake was frozen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis stepped forward for the first time in hundreds of years. He raised his sword, and marched over the ice. He was, at last, free.[PARAGRAPH:1]Standing on the ocean's shores, Taranis realized (as hard as this was to happen) that the world was much different. It was a new age. He could feel the bright flares of Hyborem and Basium in the world, and of his foe Brigit bond in his master's domain to the north, and as ever the rock of Odio still bound.</French>
		<German>[TAB]The body of the warrior known as Taranis the Unchanging by men, Taranis the Defiled by elves, and Taranis the Guardian by the Winterborn stood. Taranis stood at attention on the small rock which he was trapped for all of time. The lakes surrounding him were maintained by Sucellus's power, manifested in an orb.[PARAGRAPH:1]Thrice Mulcarn had sent troops to free him. But the Orb had shattered lines of Illian spearmen with guardian vines beneath their feet, and melted Frost Giants with the power of nature. There was no hope of rescue, but Taranis did not care. While he could think, his mind could not handle original thoughts because Mulcarn had frozen his soul permanently, he rarely did. He merely acted.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was a sudden shifting as if the land was being probed by a magical aura. Taranis sent out a mental ping into the ether, and found it was alive with activity. Ice magic was being concentrated in a massive blast. Suddenly, it exploded outwards, and Taranis's eyes detected a channel of white energy strike the opposite coastline. There was a noise like the cracking of crystal into many shards.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis raised a hand. The earth trembled as a field of ice was moved from the infinite elemental planes to this lake. It suddenly flashed and the lake was frozen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis stepped forward for the first time in hundreds of years. He raised his sword, and marched over the ice. He was, at last, free.[PARAGRAPH:1]Standing on the ocean's shores, Taranis realized (as hard as this was to happen) that the world was much different. It was a new age. He could feel the bright flares of Hyborem and Basium in the world, and of his foe Brigit bond in his master's domain to the north, and as ever the rock of Odio still bound.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]The body of the warrior known as Taranis the Unchanging by men, Taranis the Defiled by elves, and Taranis the Guardian by the Winterborn stood. Taranis stood at attention on the small rock which he was trapped for all of time. The lakes surrounding him were maintained by Sucellus's power, manifested in an orb.[PARAGRAPH:1]Thrice Mulcarn had sent troops to free him. But the Orb had shattered lines of Illian spearmen with guardian vines beneath their feet, and melted Frost Giants with the power of nature. There was no hope of rescue, but Taranis did not care. While he could think, his mind could not handle original thoughts because Mulcarn had frozen his soul permanently, he rarely did. He merely acted.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was a sudden shifting as if the land was being probed by a magical aura. Taranis sent out a mental ping into the ether, and found it was alive with activity. Ice magic was being concentrated in a massive blast. Suddenly, it exploded outwards, and Taranis's eyes detected a channel of white energy strike the opposite coastline. There was a noise like the cracking of crystal into many shards.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis raised a hand. The earth trembled as a field of ice was moved from the infinite elemental planes to this lake. It suddenly flashed and the lake was frozen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis stepped forward for the first time in hundreds of years. He raised his sword, and marched over the ice. He was, at last, free.[PARAGRAPH:1]Standing on the ocean's shores, Taranis realized (as hard as this was to happen) that the world was much different. It was a new age. He could feel the bright flares of Hyborem and Basium in the world, and of his foe Brigit bond in his master's domain to the north, and as ever the rock of Odio still bound.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The body of the warrior known as Taranis the Unchanging by men, Taranis the Defiled by elves, and Taranis the Guardian by the Winterborn stood. Taranis stood at attention on the small rock which he was trapped for all of time. The lakes surrounding him were maintained by Sucellus's power, manifested in an orb.[PARAGRAPH:1]Thrice Mulcarn had sent troops to free him. But the Orb had shattered lines of Illian spearmen with guardian vines beneath their feet, and melted Frost Giants with the power of nature. There was no hope of rescue, but Taranis did not care. While he could think, his mind could not handle original thoughts because Mulcarn had frozen his soul permanently, he rarely did. He merely acted.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was a sudden shifting as if the land was being probed by a magical aura. Taranis sent out a mental ping into the ether, and found it was alive with activity. Ice magic was being concentrated in a massive blast. Suddenly, it exploded outwards, and Taranis's eyes detected a channel of white energy strike the opposite coastline. There was a noise like the cracking of crystal into many shards.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis raised a hand. The earth trembled as a field of ice was moved from the infinite elemental planes to this lake. It suddenly flashed and the lake was frozen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis stepped forward for the first time in hundreds of years. He raised his sword, and marched over the ice. He was, at last, free.[PARAGRAPH:1]Standing on the ocean's shores, Taranis realized (as hard as this was to happen) that the world was much different. It was a new age. He could feel the bright flares of Hyborem and Basium in the world, and of his foe Brigit bond in his master's domain to the north, and as ever the rock of Odio still bound.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TARANIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Chapter 1: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE]Chapter 2: The Liberation[NEWLINE][LINK=LEADER_TARANIS]Chapter 3: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Taranis's stead trod across Erebus had never faltered, no matter what obstacles had been in his way. He had nearly had to veer from his course as the Grigori piled on a massive amount of bodies in an attempt to block him from reaching Illian lands. But with some ice magic and his methodical use of his sword, he had broken through and continued to Mulcarn, until he reached the Illian border.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unknown structure detected. Analysis: border fort. Accessing climatological data. Temperatures in and beyond this fort are significantly colder then those here. Conclusion: Mulcarn is nearby.[PARAGRAPH:1]After performing this analysis, Taranis continued his steady pace forward. He raised a hand and accessed ice magic. Nothing happened for a few minutes, until the frozen walls of the Illian border fort reshaped themselves into an open gate. Startled, Illian defenders rushed forward to intercept this stranger. Taranis charged them, a sword stroke killing one, and a blast of ice magic freezing the rest.[PARAGRAPH:1]To an outsider it appeared that someone, perhaps Frostlings, had constructed a beautiful replica of an Illian fortress and it's men out of ice crystals. The truth was that it was one of many that Taranis had created from different nations during his trek to Garduk.[PARAGRAPH:2]Dunmanios, senior of the Priests of Winter and High Priest of Winter of the White Hand, rode across the barren tundra on the back of an icehorse. The Illian icehorses were bred from the ancient Winter Horses created by Mulcarn, just as he had created the Winter Wolves from the Doviello wolves. Because of Dumnanios's seniority, he had been given one of these rare, prized creatures (who could run faster in the snow then on land) and ordered to warn anything between the frozen fort and Garduk not to interfere with Taranis, the assumption being he would be the most capable to stop Taranis.[PARAGRAPH:1]He spotted the small town of Suspiro, reasonably close to Garduk. With it's position near several key herds of arctic deer it was rapidly becoming more then just a small town and one of the main centers for the arctic deer hunt and trade. Unfortunately, it looked like there was nothing going on today- a bad sign.[PARAGRAPH:1]The priest of winter muttered a prayer to Auric under his breath and felt the strength of the reborn god of winter fill him. He urged on the icehorse, which responded to the blast of ice magic and charged before, arriving at the city instantly.[PARAGRAPH:1]By the looks of it, Taranis had just been here previously. He had carved a frozen path of destruction through Suspiro, freezing many buildings, people, and arctic deer being stored in icehouses. And the parts of Suspiro that had not been frozen were in panic. There was rioting, and the Illian defenders and police were having a hard time maintaining order. He cursed, and wondered if Taranis was really worth all of the destruction and chaos he was causing.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric Ulvin rose from his throne as there was an explosion, and then total silence, in the chambers outside of the audience hall. The Illian guards, the members of his court (who were best called sycophants), and other officials around him startled and stepped aside in fear. Auric raised an eyebrow as the doors exploded, and then froze in mid-air before dropping to the ground and shattering.[PARAGRAPH:1]From the clouds of dust, Taranis the Unchanging stepped forward, his ancient longsword and shield in hand. He towered over the Illians by a head, and was covered from head to toe in armor. His blue eyes of crystal ice looked around the room before locking on Auric. He marched forward slowly.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Illian guards, once realizing that this... thing... was heading towards their god-king, overcame their fear and threw themselves in his path. Auric opened his mouth to warn them away, but he was too late as Taranis swung his sword. The instant touch of the blade caused the guard who was touched to freeze. Taranis waved his hand and the frozen guards shattered, and he stepped over what was left of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis halted in front of Auric, waiting for... something. Auric wondered what it was. He had no way of communicating with Taranis to discover it, and Taranis would not answer him. Except... that was not entirely true. He entered Taranis's mind, and was instantly struck by how alien it was. It was like that of a golem.[PARAGRAPH:1]Except... it wasn't. Golems were artificial and had no mind, at least as how the term was understood. But Taranis had a mind. Much of it had been written over, it seemed, by the complex writing of Mulcarn's blessing. Mulcarn had sealed off huge portions of Taranis's mind. Auric nearly became lost in wonder in trying to understand this work of his predecessor. However, he remembered his task, and sought to find a method to speak to Taranis.[PARAGRAPH:1]There would presumably be some way for him to give Taranis an instruction. He found what appeared to be the correct way to send a command, and sent a mental ping it to it. He received another mental ping in return, this one from Taranis. Auric smiled slightly.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am Auric Ulvin, the soon-to-be-new god of winter, and I demand you acknowledge me as your lord," sent Auric. Taranis's mind leaped into action and his body started slightly. Auric felt Taranis processing information.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Prove your identity," was all that Auric was able to parse from the mental reply. Auric looked through himself for the essence of Mulcarn and the power of the sphere of winter, and showed it to Taranis, who jerked slightly again. Auric wondered what these jerks might mean, but had no time to fully analyze Taranis's mind. He still wasn't sure he was doing this correctly.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Confirmed. Instruction?" Taranis sent through the mental channel. Auric hesitated. How to best phrase this, he wondered.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Guard me, the reborn god of winter. Do not allow anyone or anything to harm me. Accompany me at all times unless I order you not to." ordered Auric. Taranis nodded and acknowledged the order. Satisfied, Auric broke from the mental contact and sat down on his throne of ice.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis walked up the steps to the throne and adopted a position behind Auric's throne. Anyone or anything intending to harm him would have to get through an unchanging, undying, archangel of winter. It seemed like he had given the instruction the right way after all. Auric didn't realize that what he just did in Taranis's mind might not have any short-term consequences... but might have some unpleasant long-term ones.</English>
		<French>[LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Chapter 1: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE]Chapter 2: The Liberation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Taranis's stead trod across Erebus had never faltered, no matter what obstacles had been in his way. He had nearly had to veer from his course as the Grigori piled on a massive amount of bodies in an attempt to block him from reaching Illian lands. But with some ice magic and his methodical use of his sword, he had broken through and continued to Mulcarn, until he reached the Illian border.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unknown structure detected. Analysis: border fort. Accessing climatological data. Temperatures in and beyond this fort are significantly colder then those here. Conclusion: Mulcarn is nearby.[PARAGRAPH:1]After performing this analysis, Taranis continued his steady pace forward. He raised a hand and accessed ice magic. Nothing happened for a few minutes, until the frozen walls of the Illian border fort reshaped themselves into an open gate. Startled, Illian defenders rushed forward to intercept this stranger. Taranis charged them, a sword stroke killing one, and a blast of ice magic freezing the rest.[PARAGRAPH:1]To an outsider it appeared that someone, perhaps Frostlings, had constructed a beautiful replica of an Illian fortress and it's men out of ice crystals. The truth was that it was one of many that Taranis had created from different nations during his trek to Garduk.[PARAGRAPH:2]Dunmanios, senior of the Priests of Winter and High Priest of Winter of the White Hand, rode across the barren tundra on the back of an icehorse. The Illian icehorses were bred from the ancient Winter Horses created by Mulcarn, just as he had created the Winter Wolves from the Doviello wolves. Because of Dumnanios's seniority, he had been given one of these rare, prized creatures (who could run faster in the snow then on land) and ordered to warn anything between the frozen fort and Garduk not to interfere with Taranis, the assumption being he would be the most capable to stop Taranis.[PARAGRAPH:1]He spotted the small town of Suspiro, reasonably close to Garduk. With it's position near several key herds of arctic deer it was rapidly becoming more then just a small town and one of the main centers for the arctic deer hunt and trade. Unfortunately, it looked like there was nothing going on today- a bad sign.[PARAGRAPH:1]The priest of winter muttered a prayer to Auric under his breath and felt the strength of the reborn god of winter fill him. He urged on the icehorse, which responded to the blast of ice magic and charged before, arriving at the city instantly.[PARAGRAPH:1]By the looks of it, Taranis had just been here previously. He had carved a frozen path of destruction through Suspiro, freezing many buildings, people, and arctic deer being stored in icehouses. And the parts of Suspiro that had not been frozen were in panic. There was rioting, and the Illian defenders and police were having a hard time maintaining order. He cursed, and wondered if Taranis was really worth all of the destruction and chaos he was causing.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric Ulvin rose from his throne as there was an explosion, and then total silence, in the chambers outside of the audience hall. The Illian guards, the members of his court (who were best called sycophants), and other officials around him startled and stepped aside in fear. Auric raised an eyebrow as the doors exploded, and then froze in mid-air before dropping to the ground and shattering.[PARAGRAPH:1]From the clouds of dust, Taranis the Unchanging stepped forward, his ancient longsword and shield in hand. He towered over the Illians by a head, and was covered from head to toe in armor. His blue eyes of crystal ice looked around the room before locking on Auric. He marched forward slowly.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Illian guards, once realizing that this... thing... was heading towards their god-king, overcame their fear and threw themselves in his path. Auric opened his mouth to warn them away, but he was too late as Taranis swung his sword. The instant touch of the blade caused the guard who was touched to freeze. Taranis waved his hand and the frozen guards shattered, and he stepped over what was left of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis halted in front of Auric, waiting for... something. Auric wondered what it was. He had no way of communicating with Taranis to discover it, and Taranis would not answer him. Except... that was not entirely true. He entered Taranis's mind, and was instantly struck by how alien it was. It was like that of a golem.[PARAGRAPH:1]Except... it wasn't. Golems were artificial and had no mind, at least as how the term was understood. But Taranis had a mind. Much of it had been written over, it seemed, by the complex writing of Mulcarn's blessing. Mulcarn had sealed off huge portions of Taranis's mind. Auric nearly became lost in wonder in trying to understand this work of his predecessor. However, he remembered his task, and sought to find a method to speak to Taranis.[PARAGRAPH:1]There would presumably be some way for him to give Taranis an instruction. He found what appeared to be the correct way to send a command, and sent a mental ping it to it. He received another mental ping in return, this one from Taranis. Auric smiled slightly.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am Auric Ulvin, the soon-to-be-new god of winter, and I demand you acknowledge me as your lord," sent Auric. Taranis's mind leaped into action and his body started slightly. Auric felt Taranis processing information.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Prove your identity," was all that Auric was able to parse from the mental reply. Auric looked through himself for the essence of Mulcarn and the power of the sphere of winter, and showed it to Taranis, who jerked slightly again. Auric wondered what these jerks might mean, but had no time to fully analyze Taranis's mind. He still wasn't sure he was doing this correctly.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Confirmed. Instruction?" Taranis sent through the mental channel. Auric hesitated. How to best phrase this, he wondered.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Guard me, the reborn god of winter. Do not allow anyone or anything to harm me. Accompany me at all times unless I order you not to." ordered Auric. Taranis nodded and acknowledged the order. Satisfied, Auric broke from the mental contact and sat down on his throne of ice.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis walked up the steps to the throne and adopted a position behind Auric's throne. Anyone or anything intending to harm him would have to get through an unchanging, undying, archangel of winter. It seemed like he had given the instruction the right way after all. Auric didn't realize that what he just did in Taranis's mind might not have any short-term consequences... but might have some unpleasant long-term ones.</French>
		<German>[LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Chapter 1: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE]Chapter 2: The Liberation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Taranis's stead trod across Erebus had never faltered, no matter what obstacles had been in his way. He had nearly had to veer from his course as the Grigori piled on a massive amount of bodies in an attempt to block him from reaching Illian lands. But with some ice magic and his methodical use of his sword, he had broken through and continued to Mulcarn, until he reached the Illian border.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unknown structure detected. Analysis: border fort. Accessing climatological data. Temperatures in and beyond this fort are significantly colder then those here. Conclusion: Mulcarn is nearby.[PARAGRAPH:1]After performing this analysis, Taranis continued his steady pace forward. He raised a hand and accessed ice magic. Nothing happened for a few minutes, until the frozen walls of the Illian border fort reshaped themselves into an open gate. Startled, Illian defenders rushed forward to intercept this stranger. Taranis charged them, a sword stroke killing one, and a blast of ice magic freezing the rest.[PARAGRAPH:1]To an outsider it appeared that someone, perhaps Frostlings, had constructed a beautiful replica of an Illian fortress and it's men out of ice crystals. The truth was that it was one of many that Taranis had created from different nations during his trek to Garduk.[PARAGRAPH:2]Dunmanios, senior of the Priests of Winter and High Priest of Winter of the White Hand, rode across the barren tundra on the back of an icehorse. The Illian icehorses were bred from the ancient Winter Horses created by Mulcarn, just as he had created the Winter Wolves from the Doviello wolves. Because of Dumnanios's seniority, he had been given one of these rare, prized creatures (who could run faster in the snow then on land) and ordered to warn anything between the frozen fort and Garduk not to interfere with Taranis, the assumption being he would be the most capable to stop Taranis.[PARAGRAPH:1]He spotted the small town of Suspiro, reasonably close to Garduk. With it's position near several key herds of arctic deer it was rapidly becoming more then just a small town and one of the main centers for the arctic deer hunt and trade. Unfortunately, it looked like there was nothing going on today- a bad sign.[PARAGRAPH:1]The priest of winter muttered a prayer to Auric under his breath and felt the strength of the reborn god of winter fill him. He urged on the icehorse, which responded to the blast of ice magic and charged before, arriving at the city instantly.[PARAGRAPH:1]By the looks of it, Taranis had just been here previously. He had carved a frozen path of destruction through Suspiro, freezing many buildings, people, and arctic deer being stored in icehouses. And the parts of Suspiro that had not been frozen were in panic. There was rioting, and the Illian defenders and police were having a hard time maintaining order. He cursed, and wondered if Taranis was really worth all of the destruction and chaos he was causing.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric Ulvin rose from his throne as there was an explosion, and then total silence, in the chambers outside of the audience hall. The Illian guards, the members of his court (who were best called sycophants), and other officials around him startled and stepped aside in fear. Auric raised an eyebrow as the doors exploded, and then froze in mid-air before dropping to the ground and shattering.[PARAGRAPH:1]From the clouds of dust, Taranis the Unchanging stepped forward, his ancient longsword and shield in hand. He towered over the Illians by a head, and was covered from head to toe in armor. His blue eyes of crystal ice looked around the room before locking on Auric. He marched forward slowly.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Illian guards, once realizing that this... thing... was heading towards their god-king, overcame their fear and threw themselves in his path. Auric opened his mouth to warn them away, but he was too late as Taranis swung his sword. The instant touch of the blade caused the guard who was touched to freeze. Taranis waved his hand and the frozen guards shattered, and he stepped over what was left of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis halted in front of Auric, waiting for... something. Auric wondered what it was. He had no way of communicating with Taranis to discover it, and Taranis would not answer him. Except... that was not entirely true. He entered Taranis's mind, and was instantly struck by how alien it was. It was like that of a golem.[PARAGRAPH:1]Except... it wasn't. Golems were artificial and had no mind, at least as how the term was understood. But Taranis had a mind. Much of it had been written over, it seemed, by the complex writing of Mulcarn's blessing. Mulcarn had sealed off huge portions of Taranis's mind. Auric nearly became lost in wonder in trying to understand this work of his predecessor. However, he remembered his task, and sought to find a method to speak to Taranis.[PARAGRAPH:1]There would presumably be some way for him to give Taranis an instruction. He found what appeared to be the correct way to send a command, and sent a mental ping it to it. He received another mental ping in return, this one from Taranis. Auric smiled slightly.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am Auric Ulvin, the soon-to-be-new god of winter, and I demand you acknowledge me as your lord," sent Auric. Taranis's mind leaped into action and his body started slightly. Auric felt Taranis processing information.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Prove your identity," was all that Auric was able to parse from the mental reply. Auric looked through himself for the essence of Mulcarn and the power of the sphere of winter, and showed it to Taranis, who jerked slightly again. Auric wondered what these jerks might mean, but had no time to fully analyze Taranis's mind. He still wasn't sure he was doing this correctly.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Confirmed. Instruction?" Taranis sent through the mental channel. Auric hesitated. How to best phrase this, he wondered.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Guard me, the reborn god of winter. Do not allow anyone or anything to harm me. Accompany me at all times unless I order you not to." ordered Auric. Taranis nodded and acknowledged the order. Satisfied, Auric broke from the mental contact and sat down on his throne of ice.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis walked up the steps to the throne and adopted a position behind Auric's throne. Anyone or anything intending to harm him would have to get through an unchanging, undying, archangel of winter. It seemed like he had given the instruction the right way after all. Auric didn't realize that what he just did in Taranis's mind might not have any short-term consequences... but might have some unpleasant long-term ones.</German>
		<Italian>[LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Chapter 1: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE]Chapter 2: The Liberation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Taranis's stead trod across Erebus had never faltered, no matter what obstacles had been in his way. He had nearly had to veer from his course as the Grigori piled on a massive amount of bodies in an attempt to block him from reaching Illian lands. But with some ice magic and his methodical use of his sword, he had broken through and continued to Mulcarn, until he reached the Illian border.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unknown structure detected. Analysis: border fort. Accessing climatological data. Temperatures in and beyond this fort are significantly colder then those here. Conclusion: Mulcarn is nearby.[PARAGRAPH:1]After performing this analysis, Taranis continued his steady pace forward. He raised a hand and accessed ice magic. Nothing happened for a few minutes, until the frozen walls of the Illian border fort reshaped themselves into an open gate. Startled, Illian defenders rushed forward to intercept this stranger. Taranis charged them, a sword stroke killing one, and a blast of ice magic freezing the rest.[PARAGRAPH:1]To an outsider it appeared that someone, perhaps Frostlings, had constructed a beautiful replica of an Illian fortress and it's men out of ice crystals. The truth was that it was one of many that Taranis had created from different nations during his trek to Garduk.[PARAGRAPH:2]Dunmanios, senior of the Priests of Winter and High Priest of Winter of the White Hand, rode across the barren tundra on the back of an icehorse. The Illian icehorses were bred from the ancient Winter Horses created by Mulcarn, just as he had created the Winter Wolves from the Doviello wolves. Because of Dumnanios's seniority, he had been given one of these rare, prized creatures (who could run faster in the snow then on land) and ordered to warn anything between the frozen fort and Garduk not to interfere with Taranis, the assumption being he would be the most capable to stop Taranis.[PARAGRAPH:1]He spotted the small town of Suspiro, reasonably close to Garduk. With it's position near several key herds of arctic deer it was rapidly becoming more then just a small town and one of the main centers for the arctic deer hunt and trade. Unfortunately, it looked like there was nothing going on today- a bad sign.[PARAGRAPH:1]The priest of winter muttered a prayer to Auric under his breath and felt the strength of the reborn god of winter fill him. He urged on the icehorse, which responded to the blast of ice magic and charged before, arriving at the city instantly.[PARAGRAPH:1]By the looks of it, Taranis had just been here previously. He had carved a frozen path of destruction through Suspiro, freezing many buildings, people, and arctic deer being stored in icehouses. And the parts of Suspiro that had not been frozen were in panic. There was rioting, and the Illian defenders and police were having a hard time maintaining order. He cursed, and wondered if Taranis was really worth all of the destruction and chaos he was causing.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric Ulvin rose from his throne as there was an explosion, and then total silence, in the chambers outside of the audience hall. The Illian guards, the members of his court (who were best called sycophants), and other officials around him startled and stepped aside in fear. Auric raised an eyebrow as the doors exploded, and then froze in mid-air before dropping to the ground and shattering.[PARAGRAPH:1]From the clouds of dust, Taranis the Unchanging stepped forward, his ancient longsword and shield in hand. He towered over the Illians by a head, and was covered from head to toe in armor. His blue eyes of crystal ice looked around the room before locking on Auric. He marched forward slowly.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Illian guards, once realizing that this... thing... was heading towards their god-king, overcame their fear and threw themselves in his path. Auric opened his mouth to warn them away, but he was too late as Taranis swung his sword. The instant touch of the blade caused the guard who was touched to freeze. Taranis waved his hand and the frozen guards shattered, and he stepped over what was left of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis halted in front of Auric, waiting for... something. Auric wondered what it was. He had no way of communicating with Taranis to discover it, and Taranis would not answer him. Except... that was not entirely true. He entered Taranis's mind, and was instantly struck by how alien it was. It was like that of a golem.[PARAGRAPH:1]Except... it wasn't. Golems were artificial and had no mind, at least as how the term was understood. But Taranis had a mind. Much of it had been written over, it seemed, by the complex writing of Mulcarn's blessing. Mulcarn had sealed off huge portions of Taranis's mind. Auric nearly became lost in wonder in trying to understand this work of his predecessor. However, he remembered his task, and sought to find a method to speak to Taranis.[PARAGRAPH:1]There would presumably be some way for him to give Taranis an instruction. He found what appeared to be the correct way to send a command, and sent a mental ping it to it. He received another mental ping in return, this one from Taranis. Auric smiled slightly.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am Auric Ulvin, the soon-to-be-new god of winter, and I demand you acknowledge me as your lord," sent Auric. Taranis's mind leaped into action and his body started slightly. Auric felt Taranis processing information.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Prove your identity," was all that Auric was able to parse from the mental reply. Auric looked through himself for the essence of Mulcarn and the power of the sphere of winter, and showed it to Taranis, who jerked slightly again. Auric wondered what these jerks might mean, but had no time to fully analyze Taranis's mind. He still wasn't sure he was doing this correctly.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Confirmed. Instruction?" Taranis sent through the mental channel. Auric hesitated. How to best phrase this, he wondered.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Guard me, the reborn god of winter. Do not allow anyone or anything to harm me. Accompany me at all times unless I order you not to." ordered Auric. Taranis nodded and acknowledged the order. Satisfied, Auric broke from the mental contact and sat down on his throne of ice.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis walked up the steps to the throne and adopted a position behind Auric's throne. Anyone or anything intending to harm him would have to get through an unchanging, undying, archangel of winter. It seemed like he had given the instruction the right way after all. Auric didn't realize that what he just did in Taranis's mind might not have any short-term consequences... but might have some unpleasant long-term ones.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[LINK=PROJECT_LIBERATION]Chapter 1: The Liberation[\LINK][NEWLINE]Chapter 2: The Liberation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Taranis's stead trod across Erebus had never faltered, no matter what obstacles had been in his way. He had nearly had to veer from his course as the Grigori piled on a massive amount of bodies in an attempt to block him from reaching Illian lands. But with some ice magic and his methodical use of his sword, he had broken through and continued to Mulcarn, until he reached the Illian border.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unknown structure detected. Analysis: border fort. Accessing climatological data. Temperatures in and beyond this fort are significantly colder then those here. Conclusion: Mulcarn is nearby.[PARAGRAPH:1]After performing this analysis, Taranis continued his steady pace forward. He raised a hand and accessed ice magic. Nothing happened for a few minutes, until the frozen walls of the Illian border fort reshaped themselves into an open gate. Startled, Illian defenders rushed forward to intercept this stranger. Taranis charged them, a sword stroke killing one, and a blast of ice magic freezing the rest.[PARAGRAPH:1]To an outsider it appeared that someone, perhaps Frostlings, had constructed a beautiful replica of an Illian fortress and it's men out of ice crystals. The truth was that it was one of many that Taranis had created from different nations during his trek to Garduk.[PARAGRAPH:2]Dunmanios, senior of the Priests of Winter and High Priest of Winter of the White Hand, rode across the barren tundra on the back of an icehorse. The Illian icehorses were bred from the ancient Winter Horses created by Mulcarn, just as he had created the Winter Wolves from the Doviello wolves. Because of Dumnanios's seniority, he had been given one of these rare, prized creatures (who could run faster in the snow then on land) and ordered to warn anything between the frozen fort and Garduk not to interfere with Taranis, the assumption being he would be the most capable to stop Taranis.[PARAGRAPH:1]He spotted the small town of Suspiro, reasonably close to Garduk. With it's position near several key herds of arctic deer it was rapidly becoming more then just a small town and one of the main centers for the arctic deer hunt and trade. Unfortunately, it looked like there was nothing going on today- a bad sign.[PARAGRAPH:1]The priest of winter muttered a prayer to Auric under his breath and felt the strength of the reborn god of winter fill him. He urged on the icehorse, which responded to the blast of ice magic and charged before, arriving at the city instantly.[PARAGRAPH:1]By the looks of it, Taranis had just been here previously. He had carved a frozen path of destruction through Suspiro, freezing many buildings, people, and arctic deer being stored in icehouses. And the parts of Suspiro that had not been frozen were in panic. There was rioting, and the Illian defenders and police were having a hard time maintaining order. He cursed, and wondered if Taranis was really worth all of the destruction and chaos he was causing.[PARAGRAPH:2]Auric Ulvin rose from his throne as there was an explosion, and then total silence, in the chambers outside of the audience hall. The Illian guards, the members of his court (who were best called sycophants), and other officials around him startled and stepped aside in fear. Auric raised an eyebrow as the doors exploded, and then froze in mid-air before dropping to the ground and shattering.[PARAGRAPH:1]From the clouds of dust, Taranis the Unchanging stepped forward, his ancient longsword and shield in hand. He towered over the Illians by a head, and was covered from head to toe in armor. His blue eyes of crystal ice looked around the room before locking on Auric. He marched forward slowly.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Illian guards, once realizing that this... thing... was heading towards their god-king, overcame their fear and threw themselves in his path. Auric opened his mouth to warn them away, but he was too late as Taranis swung his sword. The instant touch of the blade caused the guard who was touched to freeze. Taranis waved his hand and the frozen guards shattered, and he stepped over what was left of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis halted in front of Auric, waiting for... something. Auric wondered what it was. He had no way of communicating with Taranis to discover it, and Taranis would not answer him. Except... that was not entirely true. He entered Taranis's mind, and was instantly struck by how alien it was. It was like that of a golem.[PARAGRAPH:1]Except... it wasn't. Golems were artificial and had no mind, at least as how the term was understood. But Taranis had a mind. Much of it had been written over, it seemed, by the complex writing of Mulcarn's blessing. Mulcarn had sealed off huge portions of Taranis's mind. Auric nearly became lost in wonder in trying to understand this work of his predecessor. However, he remembered his task, and sought to find a method to speak to Taranis.[PARAGRAPH:1]There would presumably be some way for him to give Taranis an instruction. He found what appeared to be the correct way to send a command, and sent a mental ping it to it. He received another mental ping in return, this one from Taranis. Auric smiled slightly.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am Auric Ulvin, the soon-to-be-new god of winter, and I demand you acknowledge me as your lord," sent Auric. Taranis's mind leaped into action and his body started slightly. Auric felt Taranis processing information.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Prove your identity," was all that Auric was able to parse from the mental reply. Auric looked through himself for the essence of Mulcarn and the power of the sphere of winter, and showed it to Taranis, who jerked slightly again. Auric wondered what these jerks might mean, but had no time to fully analyze Taranis's mind. He still wasn't sure he was doing this correctly.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Confirmed. Instruction?" Taranis sent through the mental channel. Auric hesitated. How to best phrase this, he wondered.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Guard me, the reborn god of winter. Do not allow anyone or anything to harm me. Accompany me at all times unless I order you not to." ordered Auric. Taranis nodded and acknowledged the order. Satisfied, Auric broke from the mental contact and sat down on his throne of ice.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis walked up the steps to the throne and adopted a position behind Auric's throne. Anyone or anything intending to harm him would have to get through an unchanging, undying, archangel of winter. It seemed like he had given the instruction the right way after all. Auric didn't realize that what he just did in Taranis's mind might not have any short-term consequences... but might have some unpleasant long-term ones.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TARANIS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>The lord of the Frozen can be built like most heroes, unlike Hyborem or Basium. However, Taranis has the Unchanging promotion, which is like Held but grants combat defense as well, and the Immortal promotion. Use him to defend wherever you build him.</English>
		<French>The lord of the Frozen can be built like most heroes, unlike Hyborem or Basium. However, Taranis has the Unchanging promotion, which is like Held but grants combat defense as well, and the Immortal promotion. Use him to defend wherever you build him.</French>
		<German>Der Herr der Gefrorenen kann wie die meisten Helden gebaut werden, anders als Hyborem oder Basium. Anders als normale Helden hat Taranis die 'Unver&#228;nderlich' Bef&#246;rderung, die wie 'Held' ist, aber zus&#228;tzlich Verteidigunsbonus und die Unsterblichkeit Bef&#246;rderung enth&#228;lt. Nutze ihn, um dort zu verteidigen, wo du ihn gebaut hast.</German>
		<Italian>The lord of the Frozen can be built like most heroes, unlike Hyborem or Basium. However, Taranis has the Unchanging promotion, which is like Held but grants combat defense as well, and the Immortal promotion. Use him to defend wherever you build him.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The lord of the Frozen can be built like most heroes, unlike Hyborem or Basium. However, Taranis has the Unchanging promotion, which is like Held but grants combat defense as well, and the Immortal promotion. Use him to defend wherever you build him.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TARANIS_ASCENDED</Tag>
		<English>Taranis Ascended</English>
		<French>Taranis Exalté</French>
		<German>Erhabener Taranis</German>
		<Italian>Taranis Ascended</Italian>
		<Spanish>Taranis Ascended</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TARANIS_ASCENDED_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>This all-powerful unit is the Frozen version of Auric Ascended, and represents endgame for them. Use him to totally annihilate all your foes.</English>
		<French>This all-powerful unit is the Frozen version of Auric Ascended, and represents endgame for them. Use him to totally annihilate all your foes.</French>
		<German>Diese sehr m&#228;chtige Einheit ist die Gefrorenen-Version von Erhabener Auric und stellt die Endphase f&#252;r sie dar. Nutze ihn, um all deine Feinde auszul&#246;schen.</German>
		<Italian>This all-powerful unit is the Frozen version of Auric Ascended, and represents endgame for them. Use him to totally annihilate all your foes.</Italian>
		<Spanish>This all-powerful unit is the Frozen version of Auric Ascended, and represents endgame for them. Use him to totally annihilate all your foes.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>Die.</English>
		<French>Mourrez.</French>
		<German>Stirb.</German>
		<Italian>Die.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Die.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_FIRST_CONTACT_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>Identify yourself. Are you friend or foe of the Great Winter?</English>
		<French>Identifiez-vous. Êtes-vous un ami ou un ennemi de l'Hiver Tout Puissant ?</French>
		<German>Erkl&#228;re dich. Bist du Freund oder Feind des Gro&#223;en Winters?</German>
		<Italian>Identify yourself. Are you friend or foe of the Great Winter?</Italian>
		<Spanish>Identify yourself. Are you friend or foe of the Great Winter?</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_REFUSE_TO_TALK_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>Go away.</English>
		<French>Partez.</French>
		<German>Haut ab.</German>
		<Italian>Go away.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Go away.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_PEACE_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>The Wintering can be delayed, for now.</English>
		<French>The Wintering can be delayed, for now.</French>
		<German>Der Winter kann noch ein bi&#223;chen aufgeschoben werden.</German>
		<Italian>The Wintering can be delayed, for now.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Wintering can be delayed, for now.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_NO_PEACE_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>The Wintering will continue.</English>
		<French>The Wintering will continue.</French>
		<German>Nein, der Winter ist noch nicht vor&#252;ber..</German>
		<Italian>The Wintering will continue.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Wintering will continue.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_GREETINGS_ATT_FR_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>Welcome, friend of winter. State your purpose.</English>
		<French>Bienvenue, ami de l'Hiver. Détaillez vos intentions.</French>
		<German>Seid gegr&#252;&#223;t, Freund des Winters. Erkl&#228;rt Euer Begehr.</German>
		<Italian>Welcome, friend of winter. State your purpose.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Welcome, friend of winter. State your purpose.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_GREETINGS_ATT_CAUT_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>State your purpose.</English>
		<French>Détaillez vos intentions.</French>
		<German>Erkl&#228;rt Euer Begehr.</German>
		<Italian>State your purpose.</Italian>
		<Spanish>State your purpose.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_GREETINGS_ATT_FUR_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>The Wintering shall take you soon.</English>
		<French>The Wintering shall take you soon.</French>
		<German>Der Winter wird auch euch guttun.</German>
		<Italian>The Wintering shall take you soon.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Wintering shall take you soon.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_ACCEPT_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>Affirmative.</English>
		<French>Affirmatif.</French>
		<German>Jawohl.</German>
		<Italian>Affirmative.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Affirmative.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_REJECT_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>Negative.</English>
		<French>Négatif.</French>
		<German>Nein.</German>
		<Italian>Negative.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Negative.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_OFFER_PEACE_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>We offer a temporary end to the Wintering of your land.</English>
		<French>Nous vous offrons un répit avant la glaciation de votre territoire.</French>
		<German>Wir bieten ein vor&#252;bergehendes Ende des Winters in Eurem Land an.</German>
		<Italian>We offer a temporary end to the Wintering of your land.</Italian>
		<Spanish>We offer a temporary end to the Wintering of your land.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_THANKS_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>We thank you for assisting the Frozen.</English>
		<French>Merci d'avoir aidé les Cryonides.</French>
		<German>Wir danken f&#252;r Eure Hilfe f&#252;r die Gefrorenen.</German>
		<Italian>We thank you for assisting the Frozen.</Italian>
		<Spanish>We thank you for assisting the Frozen.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_DEMAND_REJECTED_LEADER_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>You have angered the Frozen.</English>
		<French>Vous avez provoqué la colère des Cryonides.</French>
		<German>Ihr habt die Gefrorenen ver&#228;rgert.</German>
		<Italian>You have angered the Frozen.</Italian>
		<Spanish>You have angered the Frozen.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_DEFEATED_TARANIS</Tag>
		<English>The Frozen have melted. Fire reigns, and winter is dead forever.</English>
		<French>Les Cryonides ont fondu. Le feu règne et l'Hiver est définitivement mort.</French>
		<German>Die Gefrorenen sind geschmolzen. Feuer regiert, und der Winter ist wohl f&#252;r immer vorbei.</German>
		<Italian>The Frozen have melted. Fire reigns, and winter is dead forever.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Frozen have melted. Fire reigns, and winter is dead forever.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_WINTER_TECH</Tag>
		<English>Winter Tech</English>
		<French>Winter Tech</French>
		<German>Winter Technologie</German>
		<Italian>Winter Tech</Italian>
		<Spanish>Winter Tech</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_WINTER_TECH_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The god of hibernation does not easily rouse to change but he is no fool.  He will gather his strength if he perceives a threat, and that strength is considerable." - Epona</English>
		<French>"The god of hibernation does not easily rouse to change but he is no fool.  He will gather his strength if he perceives a threat, and that strength is considerable." - Epona</French>
		<German>"The god of hibernation does not easily rouse to change but he is no fool.  He will gather his strength if he perceives a threat, and that strength is considerable." - Epona</German>
		<Italian>"The god of hibernation does not easily rouse to change but he is no fool.  He will gather his strength if he perceives a threat, and that strength is considerable." - Epona</Italian>
		<Spanish>"The god of hibernation does not easily rouse to change but he is no fool.  He will gather his strength if he perceives a threat, and that strength is considerable." - Epona</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_UNCHANGING</Tag>
		<English>Unchanging</English>
		<French>Statique</French>
		<German>Unver&#228;nderlich</German>
		<Italian>Unchanging</Italian>
		<Spanish>Unchanging</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ADULT</Tag>
		<English>Adult Kocrachon</English>
		<French>Kocrachon adulte</French>
		<German>Erwachsener Kocrachon</German>
		<Italian>Adult Kocrachon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Adult Kocrachon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_NESTED</Tag>
		<English>Nested</English>
		<French>Parasité</French>
		<German>Eingenisted</German>
		<Italian>Nested</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nested</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_YOUNG</Tag>
		<English>Young Kocrachon</English>
		<French>Jeune Kocrachon</French>
		<German>Junger Kocrachon</German>
		<Italian>Young Kocrachon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Young Kocrachon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WINTERING</Tag>
		<English>Wintering</English>
		<French>Glaciation</French>
		<German>Winter bringend</German>
		<Italian>Wintering</Italian>
		<Spanish>Wintering</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WINTERING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Frozen in the Age of Rebirth cared little for the Compact. It was already violated, and as long as Taranis was not a god no action could be taken against him for that. So the Wintering began in earnest. The special ice cities they ruled dispelled magic not through temples or arrays but straight into Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]This blast of raw, ordered magic caused a great freezing to occur outside of mountain valleys, and grasslands and plains soon became nothing but snow and ice. Further, the ice magic permeated into the souls of the living, freezing key portions of them, simulating the effect of one's soul being frozen after slaying one of the Winterborn. This terrible ritual fueled the Frozen legions of frozen souls and Frostlings en massse.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 4, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</English>
		<French>[TAB]The Frozen in the Age of Rebirth cared little for the Compact. It was already violated, and as long as Taranis was not a god no action could be taken against him for that. So the Wintering began in earnest. The special ice cities they ruled dispelled magic not through temples or arrays but straight into Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]This blast of raw, ordered magic caused a great freezing to occur outside of mountain valleys, and grasslands and plains soon became nothing but snow and ice. Further, the ice magic permeated into the souls of the living, freezing key portions of them, simulating the effect of one's soul being frozen after slaying one of the Winterborn. This terrible ritual fueled the Frozen legions of frozen souls and Frostlings en massse.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 4, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</French>
		<German>[TAB]The Frozen in the Age of Rebirth cared little for the Compact. It was already violated, and as long as Taranis was not a god no action could be taken against him for that. So the Wintering began in earnest. The special ice cities they ruled dispelled magic not through temples or arrays but straight into Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]This blast of raw, ordered magic caused a great freezing to occur outside of mountain valleys, and grasslands and plains soon became nothing but snow and ice. Further, the ice magic permeated into the souls of the living, freezing key portions of them, simulating the effect of one's soul being frozen after slaying one of the Winterborn. This terrible ritual fueled the Frozen legions of frozen souls and Frostlings en massse.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 4, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]The Frozen in the Age of Rebirth cared little for the Compact. It was already violated, and as long as Taranis was not a god no action could be taken against him for that. So the Wintering began in earnest. The special ice cities they ruled dispelled magic not through temples or arrays but straight into Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]This blast of raw, ordered magic caused a great freezing to occur outside of mountain valleys, and grasslands and plains soon became nothing but snow and ice. Further, the ice magic permeated into the souls of the living, freezing key portions of them, simulating the effect of one's soul being frozen after slaying one of the Winterborn. This terrible ritual fueled the Frozen legions of frozen souls and Frostlings en massse.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 4, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Frozen in the Age of Rebirth cared little for the Compact. It was already violated, and as long as Taranis was not a god no action could be taken against him for that. So the Wintering began in earnest. The special ice cities they ruled dispelled magic not through temples or arrays but straight into Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]This blast of raw, ordered magic caused a great freezing to occur outside of mountain valleys, and grasslands and plains soon became nothing but snow and ice. Further, the ice magic permeated into the souls of the living, freezing key portions of them, simulating the effect of one's soul being frozen after slaying one of the Winterborn. This terrible ritual fueled the Frozen legions of frozen souls and Frostlings en massse.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 4, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WINTERING_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all living units the [LINK=PROMOTION_WINTERED]Wintered[\LINK] promotion.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]In your territory, tundra becomes glacier, taiga becomes tundra, other terrains become taiga. Glacier tiles with no feature or with a blizzard receive feature [LINK=FEATURE_WINTER]winter[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Outside your territory, glacier tiles with no feature spawn a [LINK=FEATURE_BLIZZARD]blizzard[\LINK].</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Fournit à toutes les unités vivantes la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_WINTERED]Hypothermie[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sur votre territoire, les tundras deviennent des glaciers, les taïgas des tundras, les autres terrains des taïgas. Les cases de Glacier sans aménagement ou avec un blizzard reçoivent l'aménagement [LINK=FEATURE_WINTER]Hiver[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]À l'extérieur de votre territoire, les cases de glacier sans aménagement font apparaître un [LINK=FEATURE_BLIZZARD]blizzard[\LINK].</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all living units the [LINK=PROMOTION_WINTERED]Wintered[\LINK] promotion.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]In your territory, tundra becomes glacier, taiga becomes tundra, other terrains become taiga. Glacier tiles with no feature or with a blizzard receive feature [LINK=FEATURE_WINTER]winter[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Outside your territory, glacier tiles with no feature spawn a [LINK=FEATURE_BLIZZARD]blizzard[\LINK].</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all living units the [LINK=PROMOTION_WINTERED]Wintered[\LINK] promotion.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]In your territory, tundra becomes glacier, taiga becomes tundra, other terrains become taiga. Glacier tiles with no feature or with a blizzard receive feature [LINK=FEATURE_WINTER]winter[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Outside your territory, glacier tiles with no feature spawn a [LINK=FEATURE_BLIZZARD]blizzard[\LINK].</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all living units the [LINK=PROMOTION_WINTERED]Wintered[\LINK] promotion.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]In your territory, tundra becomes glacier, taiga becomes tundra, other terrains become taiga. Glacier tiles with no feature or with a blizzard receive feature [LINK=FEATURE_WINTER]winter[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Outside your territory, glacier tiles with no feature spawn a [LINK=FEATURE_BLIZZARD]blizzard[\LINK].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_COUNTERTHAW</Tag><!-- apparently removed from the game at some point-->
		<English>Counterthaw</English>
		<French>Counterthaw</French>
		<German>Antitau</German>
		<Italian>Counterthaw</Italian>
		<Spanish>Counterthaw</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_COUNTERTHAW_PEDIA</Tag><!-- apparently removed from the game at some point-->
		<English>[TAB]Mulcarn's grip over Erebus was near absolute in the Age of Ice. His ice storms shattered livestock pens and his blizzards froze their farms. This forced a reliance on hunting as a method of food gathering, which severely weakened the population without a balanced diet.[PARAGRAPH:1]When the thaws came that occured on Mulcarn's death, the food resources returned and the population of Erebus once again prospered.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen, seeking to return Erebus to the stasis of the Age of Ice, began the 'counterthaw'. The first step was simple, using ice magic channeled by Taranis and the shattered portions of Mulcarn's soul (wherever they actually went) to destroy these food resources, to replace them with ice. It was successful, as the Frozen disrupted growth- which means they disrupted 'change' of countless nations by using frostling patrols, accompanied by s, to destroy their food.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 9, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</English>
		<French>[TAB]Mulcarn's grip over Erebus was near absolute in the Age of Ice. His ice storms shattered livestock pens and his blizzards froze their farms. This forced a reliance on hunting as a method of food gathering, which severely weakened the population without a balanced diet.[PARAGRAPH:1]When the thaws came that occured on Mulcarn's death, the food resources returned and the population of Erebus once again prospered.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen, seeking to return Erebus to the stasis of the Age of Ice, began the 'counterthaw'. The first step was simple, using ice magic channeled by Taranis and the shattered portions of Mulcarn's soul (wherever they actually went) to destroy these food resources, to replace them with ice. It was successful, as the Frozen disrupted growth- which means they disrupted 'change' of countless nations by using frostling patrols, accompanied by s, to destroy their food.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 9, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</French>
		<German>[TAB]Mulcarn's grip over Erebus was near absolute in the Age of Ice. His ice storms shattered livestock pens and his blizzards froze their farms. This forced a reliance on hunting as a method of food gathering, which severely weakened the population without a balanced diet.[PARAGRAPH:1]When the thaws came that occured on Mulcarn's death, the food resources returned and the population of Erebus once again prospered.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen, seeking to return Erebus to the stasis of the Age of Ice, began the 'counterthaw'. The first step was simple, using ice magic channeled by Taranis and the shattered portions of Mulcarn's soul (wherever they actually went) to destroy these food resources, to replace them with ice. It was successful, as the Frozen disrupted growth- which means they disrupted 'change' of countless nations by using frostling patrols, accompanied by s, to destroy their food.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 9, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Mulcarn's grip over Erebus was near absolute in the Age of Ice. His ice storms shattered livestock pens and his blizzards froze their farms. This forced a reliance on hunting as a method of food gathering, which severely weakened the population without a balanced diet.[PARAGRAPH:1]When the thaws came that occured on Mulcarn's death, the food resources returned and the population of Erebus once again prospered.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen, seeking to return Erebus to the stasis of the Age of Ice, began the 'counterthaw'. The first step was simple, using ice magic channeled by Taranis and the shattered portions of Mulcarn's soul (wherever they actually went) to destroy these food resources, to replace them with ice. It was successful, as the Frozen disrupted growth- which means they disrupted 'change' of countless nations by using frostling patrols, accompanied by s, to destroy their food.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 9, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Mulcarn's grip over Erebus was near absolute in the Age of Ice. His ice storms shattered livestock pens and his blizzards froze their farms. This forced a reliance on hunting as a method of food gathering, which severely weakened the population without a balanced diet.[PARAGRAPH:1]When the thaws came that occured on Mulcarn's death, the food resources returned and the population of Erebus once again prospered.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen, seeking to return Erebus to the stasis of the Age of Ice, began the 'counterthaw'. The first step was simple, using ice magic channeled by Taranis and the shattered portions of Mulcarn's soul (wherever they actually went) to destroy these food resources, to replace them with ice. It was successful, as the Frozen disrupted growth- which means they disrupted 'change' of countless nations by using frostling patrols, accompanied by s, to destroy their food.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 9, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_COUNTERTHAW_HELP</Tag><!-- apparently removed from the game at some point-->
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Destroys livestock and grain resources and any improvements on the tile.[ICON_BULLET]Creates an Ice feature on the tile.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Destroys livestock and grain resources and any improvements on the tile.[ICON_BULLET]Creates an Ice feature on the tile.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Zerst&#246;rt Tierbest&#228;nde und jegliche Getreideressourcen auf dem Gel&#228;ndefeld.[ICON_BULLET]Erschafft die Eigenschaft 'Eis' auf dem Feld.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Destroys livestock and grain resources and any improvements on the tile.[ICON_BULLET]Creates an Ice feature on the tile.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Destroys livestock and grain resources and any improvements on the tile.[ICON_BULLET]Creates an Ice feature on the tile.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FORM_BLIZZARDS</Tag><!-- unused -->
		<English>Form Blizzards</English>
		<French>Former un blizzard</French>
		<German>Forme Schneest&#252;rme</German>
		<Italian>Form Blizzards</Italian>
		<Spanish>Form Blizzards</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FORM_BLIZZARDS_PEDIA</Tag><!-- unused -->
		<English>[TAB]The greatest weapon wielded by the lord of winter during the Age of Dragons and the Age of Ice was the blizzard. Striking without warning or range, each blizzard formed by Mulcarn could engulf lands in snow and ice.[PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Ice, in response to the rise of Kylorin and his quest, Mulcarn intensified the forming of blizzards, and countless thousands raged from the land around Letum Frigus, freezing huge tracks of Erebus in their wake, rendering much of the land surrounding the city of Cevedes uninhabitable. Once Mulcarn died, the effects of these blizzards was reversed.[PARAGRAPH:1]All Ice Demons have the capability to form blizzards, and those most skilled in the arcane use of ice magic can form rings of blizzards for defensive and offensive purposes around themselves or their city. The resurgent Frozen used this to help defend their land without a large army of demons.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 10, Volume IV, of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</English>
		<French>[TAB]The greatest weapon wielded by the lord of winter during the Age of Dragons and the Age of Ice was the blizzard. Striking without warning or range, each blizzard formed by Mulcarn could engulf lands in snow and ice.[PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Ice, in response to the rise of Kylorin and his quest, Mulcarn intensified the forming of blizzards, and countless thousands raged from the land around Letum Frigus, freezing huge tracks of Erebus in their wake, rendering much of the land surrounding the city of Cevedes uninhabitable. Once Mulcarn died, the effects of these blizzards was reversed.[PARAGRAPH:1]All Ice Demons have the capability to form blizzards, and those most skilled in the arcane use of ice magic can form rings of blizzards for defensive and offensive purposes around themselves or their city. The resurgent Frozen used this to help defend their land without a large army of demons.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 10, Volume IV, of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</French>
		<German>[TAB]The greatest weapon wielded by the lord of winter during the Age of Dragons and the Age of Ice was the blizzard. Striking without warning or range, each blizzard formed by Mulcarn could engulf lands in snow and ice.[PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Ice, in response to the rise of Kylorin and his quest, Mulcarn intensified the forming of blizzards, and countless thousands raged from the land around Letum Frigus, freezing huge tracks of Erebus in their wake, rendering much of the land surrounding the city of Cevedes uninhabitable. Once Mulcarn died, the effects of these blizzards was reversed.[PARAGRAPH:1]All Ice Demons have the capability to form blizzards, and those most skilled in the arcane use of ice magic can form rings of blizzards for defensive and offensive purposes around themselves or their city. The resurgent Frozen used this to help defend their land without a large army of demons.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 10, Volume IV, of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]The greatest weapon wielded by the lord of winter during the Age of Dragons and the Age of Ice was the blizzard. Striking without warning or range, each blizzard formed by Mulcarn could engulf lands in snow and ice.[PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Ice, in response to the rise of Kylorin and his quest, Mulcarn intensified the forming of blizzards, and countless thousands raged from the land around Letum Frigus, freezing huge tracks of Erebus in their wake, rendering much of the land surrounding the city of Cevedes uninhabitable. Once Mulcarn died, the effects of these blizzards was reversed.[PARAGRAPH:1]All Ice Demons have the capability to form blizzards, and those most skilled in the arcane use of ice magic can form rings of blizzards for defensive and offensive purposes around themselves or their city. The resurgent Frozen used this to help defend their land without a large army of demons.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 10, Volume IV, of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The greatest weapon wielded by the lord of winter during the Age of Dragons and the Age of Ice was the blizzard. Striking without warning or range, each blizzard formed by Mulcarn could engulf lands in snow and ice.[PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Ice, in response to the rise of Kylorin and his quest, Mulcarn intensified the forming of blizzards, and countless thousands raged from the land around Letum Frigus, freezing huge tracks of Erebus in their wake, rendering much of the land surrounding the city of Cevedes uninhabitable. Once Mulcarn died, the effects of these blizzards was reversed.[PARAGRAPH:1]All Ice Demons have the capability to form blizzards, and those most skilled in the arcane use of ice magic can form rings of blizzards for defensive and offensive purposes around themselves or their city. The resurgent Frozen used this to help defend their land without a large army of demons.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 10, Volume IV, of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FORM_BLIZZARDS_HELP</Tag><!-- unused -->
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Randomly summons blizzards on tiles surrounding the caster up to two tiles away.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Randomly summons blizzards on tiles surrounding the caster up to two tiles away.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Beschw&#246;rt zuf&#228;llig einen Schneesturm auf den Feldern bis zu 2 Feldern weg um den Zaubernden.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Randomly summons blizzards on tiles surrounding the caster up to two tiles away.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Randomly summons blizzards on tiles surrounding the caster up to two tiles away.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MULCARNS_GRASP</Tag><!-- apparently removed from the game at some point-->
		<English>Mulcarn's Grasp</English>
		<French>Mulcarn's Grasp</French>
		<German>Mulcarns Umklammerung</German>
		<Italian>Mulcarn's Grasp</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mulcarn's Grasp</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MULCARNS_GRASP_PEDIA</Tag><!-- apparently removed from the game at some point-->
		<English>[TAB]The angels and demons of winter are guarded by the power of Mulcarn, by his aura. When Mulcarn died, his aura retreated from the world and the Frozen were no longer immortal or invincibile. For instance, if Taranis had been free in creation, he would have been as mortal as Basium or Cassiel.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen developed a method of returning the aura of Mulcarn to the world. As Taranis took on power, the grasp of the god of winter, be it Mulcarn, Auric, or Taranis returned from the ether and filled Erebus. The result was that the warriors of Mulcarn again became unchanging and undying, defending his legacy for eons to come.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 6, Volume I of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</English>
		<French>[TAB]The angels and demons of winter are guarded by the power of Mulcarn, by his aura. When Mulcarn died, his aura retreated from the world and the Frozen were no longer immortal or invincibile. For instance, if Taranis had been free in creation, he would have been as mortal as Basium or Cassiel.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen developed a method of returning the aura of Mulcarn to the world. As Taranis took on power, the grasp of the god of winter, be it Mulcarn, Auric, or Taranis returned from the ether and filled Erebus. The result was that the warriors of Mulcarn again became unchanging and undying, defending his legacy for eons to come.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 6, Volume I of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</French>
		<German>[TAB]The angels and demons of winter are guarded by the power of Mulcarn, by his aura. When Mulcarn died, his aura retreated from the world and the Frozen were no longer immortal or invincibile. For instance, if Taranis had been free in creation, he would have been as mortal as Basium or Cassiel.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen developed a method of returning the aura of Mulcarn to the world. As Taranis took on power, the grasp of the god of winter, be it Mulcarn, Auric, or Taranis returned from the ether and filled Erebus. The result was that the warriors of Mulcarn again became unchanging and undying, defending his legacy for eons to come.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 6, Volume I of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]The angels and demons of winter are guarded by the power of Mulcarn, by his aura. When Mulcarn died, his aura retreated from the world and the Frozen were no longer immortal or invincibile. For instance, if Taranis had been free in creation, he would have been as mortal as Basium or Cassiel.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen developed a method of returning the aura of Mulcarn to the world. As Taranis took on power, the grasp of the god of winter, be it Mulcarn, Auric, or Taranis returned from the ether and filled Erebus. The result was that the warriors of Mulcarn again became unchanging and undying, defending his legacy for eons to come.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 6, Volume I of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The angels and demons of winter are guarded by the power of Mulcarn, by his aura. When Mulcarn died, his aura retreated from the world and the Frozen were no longer immortal or invincibile. For instance, if Taranis had been free in creation, he would have been as mortal as Basium or Cassiel.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Frozen developed a method of returning the aura of Mulcarn to the world. As Taranis took on power, the grasp of the god of winter, be it Mulcarn, Auric, or Taranis returned from the ether and filled Erebus. The result was that the warriors of Mulcarn again became unchanging and undying, defending his legacy for eons to come.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 6, Volume I of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MULCARNS_GRASP_HELP</Tag><!-- apparently removed from the game at some point-->
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Builds a Frigid Aura in the city, removed when the caster leaves the city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants all units built in the city the Unchanging promotion.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Builds a Frigid Aura in the city, removed when the caster leaves the city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants all units built in the city the Unchanging promotion.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Beschw&#246;rt eine 'Kalte Aura' in der Stadt, die bei dem Verlassen des Zaubernden aus der Stadt entfernt wird.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sie &#252;bertr&#228;gt allen in dieser Stadt gebauten Einheiten die 'Unver&#228;nderlich' Bef&#246;rderung.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Builds a Frigid Aura in the city, removed when the caster leaves the city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants all units built in the city the Unchanging promotion.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Builds a Frigid Aura in the city, removed when the caster leaves the city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants all units built in the city the Unchanging promotion.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FREEZE_FOREST</Tag>
		<English>Freeze Forest</English>
		<French>Freeze Forest</French>
		<German>Gefriere Wald</German>
		<Italian>Freeze Forest</Italian>
		<Spanish>Freeze Forest</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FREEZE_FOREST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Mulyalfar elf druids, despite the passing of Mulcarn and the decline of much ice magic, were still skilled in it's manipulation. They could cover the ground below forests with snow, or even raise boreal forests in snow-covered plains. These spells allowed the Mulyalfar Elves to craft a "refuge" from the warming of the Age of Rebirth, where they waited for the return of Mulcarn, through either Auric Ulvin or Taranis the Unchanging.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 6, Volume II of The Elves of Mulcarn, by Sidar Historian Jevhan</English>
		<French>The Mulyalfar elf druids, despite the passing of Mulcarn and the decline of much ice magic, were still skilled in it's manipulation. They could cover the ground below forests with snow, or even raise boreal forests in snow-covered plains. These spells allowed the Mulyalfar Elves to craft a "refuge" from the warming of the Age of Rebirth, where they waited for the return of Mulcarn, through either Auric Ulvin or Taranis the Unchanging.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 6, Volume II of The Elves of Mulcarn, by Sidar Historian Jevhan</French>
		<German>The Mulyalfar elf druids, despite the passing of Mulcarn and the decline of much ice magic, were still skilled in it's manipulation. They could cover the ground below forests with snow, or even raise boreal forests in snow-covered plains. These spells allowed the Mulyalfar Elves to craft a "refuge" from the warming of the Age of Rebirth, where they waited for the return of Mulcarn, through either Auric Ulvin or Taranis the Unchanging.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 6, Volume II of The Elves of Mulcarn, by Sidar Historian Jevhan</German>
		<Italian>The Mulyalfar elf druids, despite the passing of Mulcarn and the decline of much ice magic, were still skilled in it's manipulation. They could cover the ground below forests with snow, or even raise boreal forests in snow-covered plains. These spells allowed the Mulyalfar Elves to craft a "refuge" from the warming of the Age of Rebirth, where they waited for the return of Mulcarn, through either Auric Ulvin or Taranis the Unchanging.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 6, Volume II of The Elves of Mulcarn, by Sidar Historian Jevhan</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Mulyalfar elf druids, despite the passing of Mulcarn and the decline of much ice magic, were still skilled in it's manipulation. They could cover the ground below forests with snow, or even raise boreal forests in snow-covered plains. These spells allowed the Mulyalfar Elves to craft a "refuge" from the warming of the Age of Rebirth, where they waited for the return of Mulcarn, through either Auric Ulvin or Taranis the Unchanging.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 6, Volume II of The Elves of Mulcarn, by Sidar Historian Jevhan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FREEZE_FOREST_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Turns a tile into Snow if there is a forest on it[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Creates a forest on a snow tile</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Turns a tile into Snow if there is a forest on it[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Creates a forest on a snow tile</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Wandelt ein Feld mit Wald in ein Schneefeld um[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Erschafft einen Wald auf einem Schneefeld.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Turns a tile into Snow if there is a forest on it[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Creates a forest on a snow tile</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Turns a tile into Snow if there is a forest on it[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Creates a forest on a snow tile</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FRIGID_AURA</Tag>
		<English>Frigid Aura</English>
		<French>Frigid Aura</French>
		<German>Kalte Aura</German>
		<Italian>Frigid Aura</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frigid Aura</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FROZEN_SOUL</Tag>
		<English>Frozen Souls</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Âmes gelées</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Gefrorene Seelen</German>
		<Italian>Frozen Souls</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frozen Souls</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FROZEN_SOUL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]During the Age of Ice, a never-ending supply of frostlings arose from dead bodies who had their souls 'frozen'. This freezing took place soon before death, and when the mortal died, his soul would not pass to wherever it was supposed to go, but rather freeze and become a ghost. After a short period of time, these ghosts would 'age' into Frostlings.[PARAGRAPH:1]While the entire frostling population on Erebus during the Age of Ice primarily resulted from this, the rarer example is that of Malus of the Five, whose soul became a wandering ghost until it was struck down by Epona the Sorceress. This was because Malus died on the edge of Mulcarn's power.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis exploited the same system in the Age of Rebirth. Souls who had been marked by winter, either by being born to it or fighting battle with one of the winterborn could be claimed through the network of ice magic.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because Taranis's power was far from Mulcarn's, these souls arrived as trapped, frozen spirits, not fully formed frostlings. They populated the cities of the Frozen in the same manner that the manes populated the cities of the Infernal.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 5, Volume I of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</English>
		<French>[TAB]During the Age of Ice, a never-ending supply of frostlings arose from dead bodies who had their souls 'frozen'. This freezing took place soon before death, and when the mortal died, his soul would not pass to wherever it was supposed to go, but rather freeze and become a ghost. After a short period of time, these ghosts would 'age' into Frostlings.[PARAGRAPH:1]While the entire frostling population on Erebus during the Age of Ice primarily resulted from this, the rarer example is that of Malus of the Five, whose soul became a wandering ghost until it was struck down by Epona the Sorceress. This was because Malus died on the edge of Mulcarn's power.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis exploited the same system in the Age of Rebirth. Souls who had been marked by winter, either by being born to it or fighting battle with one of the winterborn could be claimed through the network of ice magic.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because Taranis's power was far from Mulcarn's, these souls arrived as trapped, frozen spirits, not fully formed frostlings. They populated the cities of the Frozen in the same manner that the manes populated the cities of the Infernal.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 5, Volume I of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</French>
		<German>[TAB]During the Age of Ice, a never-ending supply of frostlings arose from dead bodies who had their souls 'frozen'. This freezing took place soon before death, and when the mortal died, his soul would not pass to wherever it was supposed to go, but rather freeze and become a ghost. After a short period of time, these ghosts would 'age' into Frostlings.[PARAGRAPH:1]While the entire frostling population on Erebus during the Age of Ice primarily resulted from this, the rarer example is that of Malus of the Five, whose soul became a wandering ghost until it was struck down by Epona the Sorceress. This was because Malus died on the edge of Mulcarn's power.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis exploited the same system in the Age of Rebirth. Souls who had been marked by winter, either by being born to it or fighting battle with one of the winterborn could be claimed through the network of ice magic.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because Taranis's power was far from Mulcarn's, these souls arrived as trapped, frozen spirits, not fully formed frostlings. They populated the cities of the Frozen in the same manner that the manes populated the cities of the Infernal.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 5, Volume I of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]During the Age of Ice, a never-ending supply of frostlings arose from dead bodies who had their souls 'frozen'. This freezing took place soon before death, and when the mortal died, his soul would not pass to wherever it was supposed to go, but rather freeze and become a ghost. After a short period of time, these ghosts would 'age' into Frostlings.[PARAGRAPH:1]While the entire frostling population on Erebus during the Age of Ice primarily resulted from this, the rarer example is that of Malus of the Five, whose soul became a wandering ghost until it was struck down by Epona the Sorceress. This was because Malus died on the edge of Mulcarn's power.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis exploited the same system in the Age of Rebirth. Souls who had been marked by winter, either by being born to it or fighting battle with one of the winterborn could be claimed through the network of ice magic.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because Taranis's power was far from Mulcarn's, these souls arrived as trapped, frozen spirits, not fully formed frostlings. They populated the cities of the Frozen in the same manner that the manes populated the cities of the Infernal.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 5, Volume I of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]During the Age of Ice, a never-ending supply of frostlings arose from dead bodies who had their souls 'frozen'. This freezing took place soon before death, and when the mortal died, his soul would not pass to wherever it was supposed to go, but rather freeze and become a ghost. After a short period of time, these ghosts would 'age' into Frostlings.[PARAGRAPH:1]While the entire frostling population on Erebus during the Age of Ice primarily resulted from this, the rarer example is that of Malus of the Five, whose soul became a wandering ghost until it was struck down by Epona the Sorceress. This was because Malus died on the edge of Mulcarn's power.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taranis exploited the same system in the Age of Rebirth. Souls who had been marked by winter, either by being born to it or fighting battle with one of the winterborn could be claimed through the network of ice magic.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because Taranis's power was far from Mulcarn's, these souls arrived as trapped, frozen spirits, not fully formed frostlings. They populated the cities of the Frozen in the same manner that the manes populated the cities of the Infernal.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 5, Volume I of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FROZEN_SOUL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Frozen version of the Manes. Spawn when cities belonging to a player with the Winterborn trait are raised. They also spawn on the death of a unit with the Winterborn or Frozen Soul promotions.</English>
		<French>The Frozen version of the Manes. Spawn when cities belonging to a player with the Winterborn trait are raised. They also spawn on the death of a unit with the Winterborn or Frozen Soul promotions.</French>
		<German>The Frozen version of the Manes. Spawn when cities belonging to a player with the Winterborn trait are raised. They also spawn on the death of a unit with the Winterborn or Frozen Soul promotions.</German>
		<Italian>The Frozen version of the Manes. Spawn when cities belonging to a player with the Winterborn trait are raised. They also spawn on the death of a unit with the Winterborn or Frozen Soul promotions.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Frozen version of the Manes. Spawn when cities belonging to a player with the Winterborn trait are raised. They also spawn on the death of a unit with the Winterborn or Frozen Soul promotions.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NIVE</Tag>
		<English>Nive</English>
		<French>Nive</French>
		<German>Nive</German>
		<Italian>Nive</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nive</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NIVE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Nive are large beasts covered in thick grey fur. They are typically so covered in snow that they are impossible to distinguish from the terrain, especially in snowstorms.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</English>
		<French>[TAB]The Nive are large beasts covered in thick grey fur. They are typically so covered in snow that they are impossible to distinguish from the terrain, especially in snowstorms.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</French>
		<German>[TAB]The Nive are large beasts covered in thick grey fur. They are typically so covered in snow that they are impossible to distinguish from the terrain, especially in snowstorms.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]The Nive are large beasts covered in thick grey fur. They are typically so covered in snow that they are impossible to distinguish from the terrain, especially in snowstorms.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Nive are large beasts covered in thick grey fur. They are typically so covered in snow that they are impossible to distinguish from the terrain, especially in snowstorms.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NIVE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>A replacement for the Ranger, Nive are slower but better at fighting. They also gain bonuses on snow terrain, as do all Frozen unique units.</English>
		<French>A replacement for the Ranger, Nive are slower but better at fighting. They also gain bonuses on snow terrain, as do all Frozen unique units.</French>
		<German>A replacement for the Ranger, Nive are slower but better at fighting. They also gain bonuses on snow terrain, as do all Frozen unique units.</German>
		<Italian>A replacement for the Ranger, Nive are slower but better at fighting. They also gain bonuses on snow terrain, as do all Frozen unique units.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A replacement for the Ranger, Nive are slower but better at fighting. They also gain bonuses on snow terrain, as do all Frozen unique units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KOCRACHON</Tag>
		<English>Kocrachon</English>
		<French>Kocrachon</French>
		<German>Kocrachon</German>
		<Italian>Kocrachon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kocrachon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KOCRACHON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]This cloud of biting locusts drains the strength of its victims, who will eventually become unable to sustain their own weight. In hell this torment lasts forever. In Erebus the Kocrachon lay eggs in victims who will live until the eggs hatch and thousands of new Kocrachon come bursting out of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</English>
		<French>[TAB]This cloud of biting locusts drains the strength of its victims, who will eventually become unable to sustain their own weight. In hell this torment lasts forever. In Erebus the Kocrachon lay eggs in victims who will live until the eggs hatch and thousands of new Kocrachon come bursting out of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</French>
		<German>[TAB]This cloud of biting locusts drains the strength of its victims, who will eventually become unable to sustain their own weight. In hell this torment lasts forever. In Erebus the Kocrachon lay eggs in victims who will live until the eggs hatch and thousands of new Kocrachon come bursting out of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]This cloud of biting locusts drains the strength of its victims, who will eventually become unable to sustain their own weight. In hell this torment lasts forever. In Erebus the Kocrachon lay eggs in victims who will live until the eggs hatch and thousands of new Kocrachon come bursting out of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]This cloud of biting locusts drains the strength of its victims, who will eventually become unable to sustain their own weight. In hell this torment lasts forever. In Erebus the Kocrachon lay eggs in victims who will live until the eggs hatch and thousands of new Kocrachon come bursting out of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KOCRACHON_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Kocrachon is a Frozen Unique Unit that replaces the Chariot. It passes the "Nested" promotion to enemies in combat. When a unit looses Nested (it has a 20% chance of leaving a unit), it will die and spawn several weaker Young Kocrachon under your control.</English>
		<French>The Kocrachon is a Frozen Unique Unit that replaces the Chariot. It passes the "Nested" promotion to enemies in combat. When a unit looses Nested (it has a 20% chance of leaving a unit), it will die and spawn several weaker Young Kocrachon under your control.</French>
		<German>The Kocrachon is a Frozen Unique Unit that replaces the Chariot. It passes the "Nested" promotion to enemies in combat. When a unit looses Nested (it has a 20% chance of leaving a unit), it will die and spawn several weaker Young Kocrachon under your control.</German>
		<Italian>The Kocrachon is a Frozen Unique Unit that replaces the Chariot. It passes the "Nested" promotion to enemies in combat. When a unit looses Nested (it has a 20% chance of leaving a unit), it will die and spawn several weaker Young Kocrachon under your control.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Kocrachon is a Frozen Unique Unit that replaces the Chariot. It passes the "Nested" promotion to enemies in combat. When a unit looses Nested (it has a 20% chance of leaving a unit), it will die and spawn several weaker Young Kocrachon under your control.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_YOUNG_KOCRACHON</Tag>
		<English>Young Kocrachon</English>
		<French>Young Kocrachon</French>
		<German>Junger Kocrachon</German>
		<Italian>Young Kocrachon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Young Kocrachon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_YOUNG_KOCRACHON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]This cloud of biting locusts drains the strength of its victims, who will eventually become unable to sustain their own weight. In hell this torment lasts forever. In Erebus the Kocrachon lay eggs in victims who will live until the eggs hatch and thousands of new Kocrachon come bursting out of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</English>
		<French>[TAB]This cloud of biting locusts drains the strength of its victims, who will eventually become unable to sustain their own weight. In hell this torment lasts forever. In Erebus the Kocrachon lay eggs in victims who will live until the eggs hatch and thousands of new Kocrachon come bursting out of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</French>
		<German>[TAB]This cloud of biting locusts drains the strength of its victims, who will eventually become unable to sustain their own weight. In hell this torment lasts forever. In Erebus the Kocrachon lay eggs in victims who will live until the eggs hatch and thousands of new Kocrachon come bursting out of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]This cloud of biting locusts drains the strength of its victims, who will eventually become unable to sustain their own weight. In hell this torment lasts forever. In Erebus the Kocrachon lay eggs in victims who will live until the eggs hatch and thousands of new Kocrachon come bursting out of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]This cloud of biting locusts drains the strength of its victims, who will eventually become unable to sustain their own weight. In hell this torment lasts forever. In Erebus the Kocrachon lay eggs in victims who will live until the eggs hatch and thousands of new Kocrachon come bursting out of them.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_YOUNG_KOCRACHON_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>A handful of young Kocrachon will be spawned when the Nested promotion leaves a unit. This causes that unit to be killed. The Young Kocrachon will remain in the game for 5 turns.</English>
		<French>A handful of young Kocrachon will be spawned when the Nested promotion leaves a unit. This causes that unit to be killed. The Young Kocrachon will remain in the game for 5 turns.</French>
		<German>A handful of young Kocrachon will be spawned when the Nested promotion leaves a unit. This causes that unit to be killed. The Young Kocrachon will remain in the game for 5 turns.</German>
		<Italian>A handful of young Kocrachon will be spawned when the Nested promotion leaves a unit. This causes that unit to be killed. The Young Kocrachon will remain in the game for 5 turns.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A handful of young Kocrachon will be spawned when the Nested promotion leaves a unit. This causes that unit to be killed. The Young Kocrachon will remain in the game for 5 turns.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ICE_GOLEM</Tag>
		<English>Ice Golem</English>
		<French>Golem de glace</French>
		<German>Eisgolem</German>
		<Italian>Ice Golem</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ice Golem</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ICE_GOLEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Luchuirp assaulted the Illian city.  Juggernauts slammed against the defenses. Towering iron golems waded through the rubble, destroying any defenders they found.  The Luchuirp forces tried to stop the ritual that was taking place within the inner city, but they were too late.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Mulcarn entered the city, entered creation, the battle stopped.  A layer of ice spread from the first place his foot touched outwards through the city and across the land.  The Luchuirp army was destroyed, dwarves killed, golems frozen.  Even the Illian macemen were frozen in place, kept unchanged until Mulcarn needed them.[PARAGRAPH:1]As he surveyed his new dominion he picked up one of the Luchuirp golems.  He admired their fortitude. They were unaffected by the cold and their unchanging nature.  All traits Mulcarn prized.[PARAGRAPH:1]He whispered a new life into the golem, "Make me more." [PARAGRAPH:1]"As you command" was Barnaxus's reply.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The Luchuirp assaulted the Illian city.  Juggernauts slammed against the defenses. Towering iron golems waded through the rubble, destroying any defenders they found.  The Luchuirp forces tried to stop the ritual that was taking place within the inner city, but they were too late.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Mulcarn entered the city, entered creation, the battle stopped.  A layer of ice spread from the first place his foot touched outwards through the city and across the land.  The Luchuirp army was destroyed, dwarves killed, golems frozen.  Even the Illian macemen were frozen in place, kept unchanged until Mulcarn needed them.[PARAGRAPH:1]As he surveyed his new dominion he picked up one of the Luchuirp golems.  He admired their fortitude. They were unaffected by the cold and their unchanging nature.  All traits Mulcarn prized.[PARAGRAPH:1]He whispered a new life into the golem, "Make me more." [PARAGRAPH:1]"As you command" was Barnaxus's reply.</French>
		<German>[TAB]The Luchuirp assaulted the Illian city.  Juggernauts slammed against the defenses. Towering iron golems waded through the rubble, destroying any defenders they found.  The Luchuirp forces tried to stop the ritual that was taking place within the inner city, but they were too late.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Mulcarn entered the city, entered creation, the battle stopped.  A layer of ice spread from the first place his foot touched outwards through the city and across the land.  The Luchuirp army was destroyed, dwarves killed, golems frozen.  Even the Illian macemen were frozen in place, kept unchanged until Mulcarn needed them.[PARAGRAPH:1]As he surveyed his new dominion he picked up one of the Luchuirp golems.  He admired their fortitude. They were unaffected by the cold and their unchanging nature.  All traits Mulcarn prized.[PARAGRAPH:1]He whispered a new life into the golem, "Make me more." [PARAGRAPH:1]"As you command" was Barnaxus's reply.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]The Luchuirp assaulted the Illian city.  Juggernauts slammed against the defenses. Towering iron golems waded through the rubble, destroying any defenders they found.  The Luchuirp forces tried to stop the ritual that was taking place within the inner city, but they were too late.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Mulcarn entered the city, entered creation, the battle stopped.  A layer of ice spread from the first place his foot touched outwards through the city and across the land.  The Luchuirp army was destroyed, dwarves killed, golems frozen.  Even the Illian macemen were frozen in place, kept unchanged until Mulcarn needed them.[PARAGRAPH:1]As he surveyed his new dominion he picked up one of the Luchuirp golems.  He admired their fortitude. They were unaffected by the cold and their unchanging nature.  All traits Mulcarn prized.[PARAGRAPH:1]He whispered a new life into the golem, "Make me more." [PARAGRAPH:1]"As you command" was Barnaxus's reply.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Luchuirp assaulted the Illian city.  Juggernauts slammed against the defenses. Towering iron golems waded through the rubble, destroying any defenders they found.  The Luchuirp forces tried to stop the ritual that was taking place within the inner city, but they were too late.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Mulcarn entered the city, entered creation, the battle stopped.  A layer of ice spread from the first place his foot touched outwards through the city and across the land.  The Luchuirp army was destroyed, dwarves killed, golems frozen.  Even the Illian macemen were frozen in place, kept unchanged until Mulcarn needed them.[PARAGRAPH:1]As he surveyed his new dominion he picked up one of the Luchuirp golems.  He admired their fortitude. They were unaffected by the cold and their unchanging nature.  All traits Mulcarn prized.[PARAGRAPH:1]He whispered a new life into the golem, "Make me more." [PARAGRAPH:1]"As you command" was Barnaxus's reply.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ICE_GOLEM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Frozen replacement for the Longbowman, Ice Golems cannot enter warm terrains but gain defensive bonuses from ice terrain.</English>
		<French>The Frozen replacement for the Longbowman, Ice Golems cannot enter warm terrains but gain defensive bonuses from ice terrain.</French>
		<German>The Frozen replacement for the Longbowman, Ice Golems cannot enter warm terrains but gain defensive bonuses from ice terrain.</German>
		<Italian>The Frozen replacement for the Longbowman, Ice Golems cannot enter warm terrains but gain defensive bonuses from ice terrain.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Frozen replacement for the Longbowman, Ice Golems cannot enter warm terrains but gain defensive bonuses from ice terrain.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WOLVERINE</Tag>
		<English>Winter Wolf</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Loup hivernal:Loups hivernaux</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Winterwolf</German>
		<Italian>Winter Wolf</Italian>
		<Spanish>Winter Wolf</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WOLVERINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]When Mulcarn ushered the Age of Ice onto Erebus the Doviello pledge allegiance to him. The Doviello lived as one with the wolf packs and Mulcarn transformed their wolves to be able to survive the eternal winter.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</English>
		<French>[TAB]When Mulcarn ushered the Age of Ice onto Erebus the Doviello pledge allegiance to him. The Doviello lived as one with the wolf packs and Mulcarn transformed their wolves to be able to survive the eternal winter.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</French>
		<German>[TAB]When Mulcarn ushered the Age of Ice onto Erebus the Doviello pledge allegiance to him. The Doviello lived as one with the wolf packs and Mulcarn transformed their wolves to be able to survive the eternal winter.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]When Mulcarn ushered the Age of Ice onto Erebus the Doviello pledge allegiance to him. The Doviello lived as one with the wolf packs and Mulcarn transformed their wolves to be able to survive the eternal winter.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]When Mulcarn ushered the Age of Ice onto Erebus the Doviello pledge allegiance to him. The Doviello lived as one with the wolf packs and Mulcarn transformed their wolves to be able to survive the eternal winter.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WOLVERINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Winter wolves are replacements for hunters. They appear identical to base wolves, so if you are facing the Frozen, be wary if you encounter a lone wolf. If you are the Frozen, the wolverines are similar to Hellhounds, but have Cold strength instead of Unholy.</English>
		<French>Winter wolves are replacements for hunters. They appear identical to base wolves, so if you are facing the Frozen, be wary if you encounter a lone wolf. If you are the Frozen, the wolverines are similar to Hellhounds, but have Cold strength instead of Unholy.</French>
		<German>Winter wolves are replacements for hunters. They appear identical to base wolves, so if you are facing the Frozen, be wary if you encounter a lone wolf. If you are the Frozen, the wolverines are similar to Hellhounds, but have Cold strength instead of Unholy.</German>
		<Italian>Winter wolves are replacements for hunters. They appear identical to base wolves, so if you are facing the Frozen, be wary if you encounter a lone wolf. If you are the Frozen, the wolverines are similar to Hellhounds, but have Cold strength instead of Unholy.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Winter wolves are replacements for hunters. They appear identical to base wolves, so if you are facing the Frozen, be wary if you encounter a lone wolf. If you are the Frozen, the wolverines are similar to Hellhounds, but have Cold strength instead of Unholy.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AQUILAN</Tag>
		<English>Aquilan</English>
		<French>Aquilan</French>
		<German>Aquilaner</German>
		<Italian>Aquilan</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aquilan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AQUILAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Aquilan are great eagles that dwell in the heart of blizzards. Many assume that Aquilan seek out the blizzards, but in truth the blizzards are formed wherever the Aquilan are.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</English>
		<French>[TAB]The Aquilan are great eagles that dwell in the heart of blizzards. Many assume that Aquilan seek out the blizzards, but in truth the blizzards are formed wherever the Aquilan are.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</French>
		<German>[TAB]The Aquilan are great eagles that dwell in the heart of blizzards. Many assume that Aquilan seek out the blizzards, but in truth the blizzards are formed wherever the Aquilan are.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]The Aquilan are great eagles that dwell in the heart of blizzards. Many assume that Aquilan seek out the blizzards, but in truth the blizzards are formed wherever the Aquilan are.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Aquilan are great eagles that dwell in the heart of blizzards. Many assume that Aquilan seek out the blizzards, but in truth the blizzards are formed wherever the Aquilan are.[PARAGRAPH:2]From the Bestiary of Erebus, by Kael</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AQUILAN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Aquilan are knight replacements capable of flying. Use them to recon the enemy from the safety of mountain ranges and then strike and retreat safely again.</English>
		<French>Aquilan are knight replacements capable of flying. Use them to recon the enemy from the safety of mountain ranges and then strike and retreat safely again.</French>
		<German>Aquilan are knight replacements capable of flying. Use them to recon the enemy from the safety of mountain ranges and then strike and retreat safely again.</German>
		<Italian>Aquilan are knight replacements capable of flying. Use them to recon the enemy from the safety of mountain ranges and then strike and retreat safely again.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aquilan are knight replacements capable of flying. Use them to recon the enemy from the safety of mountain ranges and then strike and retreat safely again.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_FROZEN</Tag>
		<English>Frozen Palace</English>
		<French>Palais cryonide</French>
		<German>Gefrorener Palast</German>
		<Italian>Frozen Palace</Italian>
		<Spanish>Frozen Palace</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SWAMP_OF_SOULS</Tag>
		<English>Swamp of Souls</English>
		<French>Marais des Âmes</French>
		<German>Seelensumpf</German>
		<Italian>Swamp of Souls</Italian>
		<Spanish>Swamp of Souls</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SWAMP_OF_SOULS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Many denizens of Mulyr, the realm of Mulcarn, lived in the swamps there at the base of Mount Mulyr. They were patrolled by Aquilan from the skies, but not guarded unduly for the whole purpose of the realm was to force manes into the swamp and into Mammon's city.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, when Mulcarn abandoned his realm, there was no one left to guard the souls, for his demonic legion was scattered throughout Erebus, and countless more were still coming through. Demon lords sent hunters and scavengers to see if any were useful and bring them to their masters' realms or onto Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]In particular, Ceridwen commanded her Demons of Magic to gather hundreds of the souls together and forge them into Tar Demons. She then sent these strange forged souls to aid the Sheaim and others devoted to her in the Age of Rebirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Taranis was Liberated, he chose to continue fighting on Erebus, to try and return it to the Age of Ice- to fulfill the element of Stasis- rather than return to his realm. But he was also charged to defend his master's realm in his absence.[PARAGRAPH:1]To save the souls that were 'rightfully his' (as the archangel of and soon-to-be-Ascended God of Winter), he built portals, icy conduits that pulled countless numbers out of Mulyr and into the cities of the Frozen Legion. There, they formed into 'swamp ghettos', laboring for the benefit of the Frozen. But the swamps significantly weakened the health of the city, as even the undead demonic legions were affected by their presence, for it disturbed the pristine nature of Stasis.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 7, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Many denizens of Mulyr, the realm of Mulcarn, lived in the swamps there at the base of Mount Mulyr. They were patrolled by Aquilan from the skies, but not guarded unduly for the whole purpose of the realm was to force manes into the swamp and into Mammon's city.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, when Mulcarn abandoned his realm, there was no one left to guard the souls, for his demonic legion was scattered throughout Erebus, and countless more were still coming through. Demon lords sent hunters and scavengers to see if any were useful and bring them to their masters' realms or onto Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]In particular, Ceridwen commanded her Demons of Magic to gather hundreds of the souls together and forge them into Tar Demons. She then sent these strange forged souls to aid the Sheaim and others devoted to her in the Age of Rebirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Taranis was Liberated, he chose to continue fighting on Erebus, to try and return it to the Age of Ice- to fulfill the element of Stasis- rather than return to his realm. But he was also charged to defend his master's realm in his absence.[PARAGRAPH:1]To save the souls that were 'rightfully his' (as the archangel of and soon-to-be-Ascended God of Winter), he built portals, icy conduits that pulled countless numbers out of Mulyr and into the cities of the Frozen Legion. There, they formed into 'swamp ghettos', laboring for the benefit of the Frozen. But the swamps significantly weakened the health of the city, even the undead demonic legions were affected by their presence, for it disturbed the pristine nature of Stasis.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 7, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Many denizens of Mulyr, the realm of Mulcarn, lived in the swamps there at the base of Mount Mulyr. They were patrolled by Aquilan from the skies, but not guarded unduly for the whole purpose of the realm was to force manes into the swamp and into Mammon's city.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, when Mulcarn abandoned his realm, there was no one left to guard the souls, for his demonic legion was scattered throughout Erebus, and countless more were still coming through. Demon lords sent hunters and scavengers to see if any were useful and bring them to their masters' realms or onto Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]In particular, Ceridwen commanded her Demons of Magic to gather hundreds of the souls together and forge them into Tar Demons. She then sent these strange forged souls to aid the Sheaim and others devoted to her in the Age of Rebirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Taranis was Liberated, he chose to continue fighting on Erebus, to try and return it to the Age of Ice- to fulfill the element of Stasis- rather than return to his realm. But he was also charged to defend his master's realm in his absence.[PARAGRAPH:1]To save the souls that were 'rightfully his' (as the archangel of and soon-to-be-Ascended God of Winter), he built portals, icy conduits that pulled countless numbers out of Mulyr and into the cities of the Frozen Legion. There, they formed into 'swamp ghettos', laboring for the benefit of the Frozen. But the swamps significantly weakened the health of the city, even the undead demonic legions were affected by their presence, for it disturbed the pristine nature of Stasis.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 7, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Many denizens of Mulyr, the realm of Mulcarn, lived in the swamps there at the base of Mount Mulyr. They were patrolled by Aquilan from the skies, but not guarded unduly for the whole purpose of the realm was to force manes into the swamp and into Mammon's city.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, when Mulcarn abandoned his realm, there was no one left to guard the souls, for his demonic legion was scattered throughout Erebus, and countless more were still coming through. Demon lords sent hunters and scavengers to see if any were useful and bring them to their masters' realms or onto Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]In particular, Ceridwen commanded her Demons of Magic to gather hundreds of the souls together and forge them into Tar Demons. She then sent these strange forged souls to aid the Sheaim and others devoted to her in the Age of Rebirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Taranis was Liberated, he chose to continue fighting on Erebus, to try and return it to the Age of Ice- to fulfill the element of Stasis- rather than return to his realm. But he was also charged to defend his master's realm in his absence.[PARAGRAPH:1]To save the souls that were 'rightfully his' (as the archangel of and soon-to-be-Ascended God of Winter), he built portals, icy conduits that pulled countless numbers out of Mulyr and into the cities of the Frozen Legion. There, they formed into 'swamp ghettos', laboring for the benefit of the Frozen. But the swamps significantly weakened the health of the city, even the undead demonic legions were affected by their presence, for it disturbed the pristine nature of Stasis.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 7, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Many denizens of Mulyr, the realm of Mulcarn, lived in the swamps there at the base of Mount Mulyr. They were patrolled by Aquilan from the skies, but not guarded unduly for the whole purpose of the realm was to force manes into the swamp and into Mammon's city.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, when Mulcarn abandoned his realm, there was no one left to guard the souls, for his demonic legion was scattered throughout Erebus, and countless more were still coming through. Demon lords sent hunters and scavengers to see if any were useful and bring them to their masters' realms or onto Erebus.[PARAGRAPH:1]In particular, Ceridwen commanded her Demons of Magic to gather hundreds of the souls together and forge them into Tar Demons. She then sent these strange forged souls to aid the Sheaim and others devoted to her in the Age of Rebirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Taranis was Liberated, he chose to continue fighting on Erebus, to try and return it to the Age of Ice- to fulfill the element of Stasis- rather than return to his realm. But he was also charged to defend his master's realm in his absence.[PARAGRAPH:1]To save the souls that were 'rightfully his' (as the archangel of and soon-to-be-Ascended God of Winter), he built portals, icy conduits that pulled countless numbers out of Mulyr and into the cities of the Frozen Legion. There, they formed into 'swamp ghettos', laboring for the benefit of the Frozen. But the swamps significantly weakened the health of the city, even the undead demonic legions were affected by their presence, for it disturbed the pristine nature of Stasis.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 7, Volume IV of Cryo-Demonology, by Sidar Historian Aritar.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SWAMP_OF_SOULS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>The Frozen replacement for the Aqueduct. Rather than provide health bonuses, it increases city population by 1, production by 30 percent- but also unhealthiness by 2, so use them carefully.</English>
		<French>The Frozen replacement for the Aqueduct. Rather than provide health bonuses, it increases city population by 1, production by 30 percent- but also unhealthiness by 2, so use them carefully.</French>
		<German>Die Version des Aqu&#228;duktes bei den Gefrorenen. Anders als dieses bringt er nicht mehr Gesundheit, sonder erh&#246;ht die Bev&#246;lkerung um 1, die Produktion um 30 Prozent, allerdings senkt er auch die Gesundheit um 2 Punkt, also sollte er nur mit Bedacht genutzt werden.</German>
		<Italian>The Frozen replacement for the Aqueduct. Rather than provide health bonuses, it increases city population by 1, production by 30 percent- but also unhealthiness by 2, so use them carefully.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Frozen replacement for the Aqueduct. Rather than provide health bonuses, it increases city population by 1, production by 30 percent- but also unhealthiness by 2, so use them carefully.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_CONTROL_FROZEN</Tag>
		<English>You have completed the Liberation Ritual and allowed the Frozen to enter the world. Would you like to abandon your civilization and play as Taranis instead?</English>
		<French>Vous avez complété le Rituel de Libération et permis aux Givrés d'entrer dans le monde. Voulez-vous abandonner votre civilisation et jouer Taranis à la place.</French>
		<German>You have completed the Liberation Ritual and allowed the Frozen to enter the world. Would you like to abandon your civilization and play as Taranis instead?</German>
		<Italian>You have completed the Liberation Ritual and allowed the Frozen to enter the world. Would you like to abandon your civilization and play as Taranis instead?</Italian>
		<Spanish>You have completed the Liberation Ritual and allowed the Frozen to enter the world. Would you like to abandon your civilization and play as Taranis instead?</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_CRYODEMONOLOGY_1</Tag>
		<English>Cryo-demonology, I, 5</English>
		<French>Cryo-demonology, I, 5</French>
		<German>Cryo-demonology, I, 5</German>
		<Italian>Cryo-demonology, I, 5</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cryo-demonology, I, 5</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_CRYODEMONOLOGY_2</Tag>
		<English>Cryo-demonology, I, 6</English>
		<French>Cryo-demonology, I, 6</French>
		<German>Cryo-demonology, I, 6</German>
		<Italian>Cryo-demonology, I, 6</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cryo-demonology, I, 6</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_CRYODEMONOLOGY_3</Tag>
		<English>Cryo-demonology, II, 1</English>
		<French>Cryo-demonology, II, 1</French>
		<German>Cryo-demonology, II, 1</German>
		<Italian>Cryo-demonology, II, 1</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cryo-demonology, II, 1</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_CRYODEMONOLOGY_4</Tag>
		<English>Cryo-demonology, IV, 4</English>
		<French>Cryo-demonology, IV, 4</French>
		<German>Cryo-demonology, IV, 4</German>
		<Italian>Cryo-demonology, IV, 4</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cryo-demonology, IV, 4</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_CRYODEMONOLOGY_5</Tag>
		<English>Cryo-demonology, IV, 7</English>
		<French>Cryo-demonology, IV, 7</French>
		<German>Cryo-demonology, IV, 7</German>
		<Italian>Cryo-demonology, IV, 7</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cryo-demonology, IV, 7</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_CRYODEMONOLOGY_6</Tag>
		<English>Cryo-demonology, IV, 9</English>
		<French>Cryo-demonology, IV, 9</French>
		<German>Cryo-demonology, IV, 9</German>
		<Italian>Cryo-demonology, IV, 9</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cryo-demonology, IV, 9</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_CRYODEMONOLOGY_7</Tag>
		<English>Cryo-demonology, IV, 10</English>
		<French>Cryo-demonology, IV, 10</French>
		<German>Cryo-demonology, IV, 10</German>
		<Italian>Cryo-demonology, IV, 10</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cryo-demonology, IV, 10</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_ELVES_MULCARN_1</Tag>
		<English>The Elves of Mulcarn I, 8</English>
		<French>The Elves of Mulcarn I, 8</French>
		<German>The Elves of Mulcarn I, 8</German>
		<Italian>The Elves of Mulcarn I, 8</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Elves of Mulcarn I, 8</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_ELVES_MULCARN_2</Tag>
		<English>The Elves of Mulcarn II, 6</English>
		<French>The Elves of Mulcarn II, 6</French>
		<German>The Elves of Mulcarn II, 6</German>
		<Italian>The Elves of Mulcarn II, 6</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Elves of Mulcarn II, 6</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_LIBERATION_1</Tag>
		<English>Liberation - Chapter 1</English>
		<French>Libération, Ch. 1</French>
		<German>Liberation - Chapter 1</German>
		<Italian>Liberation - Chapter 1</Italian>
		<Spanish>Liberation - Chapter 1</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_LIBERATION_2</Tag>
		<English>Liberation - Chapter 2</English>
		<French>Libération, Ch. 2</French>
		<German>Liberation - Chapter 2</German>
		<Italian>Liberation - Chapter 2</Italian>
		<Spanish>Liberation - Chapter 2</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_LIBERATION_3</Tag>
		<English>Liberation - Chapter 3</English>
		<French>Libération, Ch. 3</French>
		<German>Liberation - Chapter 3</German>
		<Italian>Liberation - Chapter 3</Italian>
		<Spanish>Liberation - Chapter 3</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LORE_LIBERATION_ALT</Tag>
		<English>Liberation - Chapter 1 alt</English>
		<French>Libération, Ch. 1 alt</French>
		<German>Liberation - Chapter 1 alt</German>
		<Italian>Liberation - Chapter 1 alt</Italian>
		<Spanish>Liberation - Chapter 1 alt</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SUMMON_WINTER_CREATURES</Tag>
		<English>Choose ice creatures to summon:</English>
		<French>Choisis les créatures de glace à invoquer :</French>
		<German>Wähle die Eiskreaturen für die Beschwörung:</German>
		<Italian>Choose ice creatures to summon:</Italian>
		<Spanish>Choose ice creatures to summon:</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SUMMON_FROST_GIANT</Tag>
		<English>1 Frost Giant</English>
		<French>1 Géant du froid</French>
		<German>1 Frostriese</German>
		<Italian>1 Frost Giant</Italian>
		<Spanish>1 Frost Giant</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SUMMON_AQUILAN</Tag>
		<English>1 Aquilan</English>
		<French>1 Aquilan</French>
		<German>1 Aquilaner</German>
		<Italian>1 Aquilan</Italian>
		<Spanish>1 Aquilan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SUMMON_ICE_ELEMENTALS</Tag>
		<English>2 Ice Elementals</English>
		<French>2 Élémentaires de Glace</French>
		<German>2 Eiselementare</German>
		<Italian>2 Ice Elementals</Italian>
		<Spanish>2 Ice Elementals</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SUMMON_KOCRACHON</Tag>
		<English>2 Kocrachon</English>
		<French>2 Kocrachons</French>
		<German>2 Kocrachon</German>
		<Italian>2 Kocrachon</Italian>
		<Spanish>2 Kocrachon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SUMMON_WINTER_WOLVES</Tag>
		<English>2 Winter Wolves</English>
		<French>2 Loups de l'Hiver</French>
		<German>2 Winterwölfe</German>
		<Italian>2 Winter Wolves</Italian>
		<Spanish>2 Winter Wolves</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SUMMON_FROSTLINGS</Tag>
		<English>4 Frostlings</English>
		<French>4 Gelbiontes</French>
		<German>4 Frostlinge</German>
		<Italian>4 Frostlings</Italian>
		<Spanish>4 Frostlings</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SUMMON_WINTER_CREATURES</Tag>
		<English>Summon Winter Creatures</English>
		<French>Invoquer des créatures de l'Hiver</French>
		<German>Beschwöre Winterwesen</German>
		<Italian>Summon Winter Creatures</Italian>
		<Spanish>Summon Winter Creatures</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
