<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZAD_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Khazad</English>
		<French>khazador:khazadore:khazadors:khazadores</French>
		<German>Khazadisch</German>
		<Italian>Khazad</Italian>
		<Spanish>Khazad</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZAD_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Khazad</English>
		<French>Khazad</French>
		<German>Reich der Khazad</German>
		<Italian>Khazad</Italian>
		<Spanish>Khazad</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZAD_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Khazad</English>
		<French>Khazadors</French>
		<German>Khazad</German>
		<Italian>Khazad</Italian>
		<Spanish>Khazad</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZAD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Dwarven siege is unmatched, and their production can be extraordinary. They cannot train arcane units, however, and require a large amount of gold per city to reach their full potential.[PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Magic the dwarves were not the united nation that they would become in the Age of Winter. Scattered tribes of mountain peoples, they were skilled craftsmen and engineers but had little interest in the areas beyond their lands. Amiable and welcoming, they made perfect targets for the con-men and tricksters of other kingdoms. The greatest works of their smiths and their shapers were traded for trinkets and baubles, or worse, mere illusions that vanished when their creators were gone. The dwarves couldn't win redress from the local lords through strength of arms or force of argument. They had no great armies, and the neighboring rulers pointed out that the dwarves had, after all, agreed to the bargains.[PARAGRAPH:1]This abuse bred distrust of both foreigners and all forms of illusion and magic. It also pushed them underground. Their formerly welcoming cities built along mountain passes were slowly abandoned for safer under-hill communities. The tribes grew closer, and gradually out of many a single unified civilization was formed, the Khazad. The dwarves began to ask themselves why they ever even bothered with outsiders.[PARAGRAPH:1]Towards the end of the Age of Magic, few dwarves were seen by other races, and it was later said that deep in their under-hill holds, they didn't notice the Age of Winter for three generations. Though this is almost certainly an exaggeration, while the kingdoms of men and elves withered under Mulcarn's onslaught the dwarves grew slowly but steadily. Then one day their gatherers returned from the surface with reports of lush vegetation returning, and snow melting.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros Fir led one group of Khazad out of their cavernous homes, to form cities and trade with the new kingdoms of men and of elves. He does not revere tradition as most dwarves do; rather, he pioneered arts new to his people: negotiation, appraisal, marketing. He pursues trading partners with zeal, by force if necessary, always determined to advance the Khazad's fortunes. Remembering the insults they were subjected to in generations past the Khazad are determined that they be secure as they venture out into the world. Not just the security of high walls and stout hammers, but of brimming coffers and judicious merchants.[PARAGRAPH:1]While his goals draw him outward, what is unknown outside of a few dwarven circles is that internecine conflict helped push him and his followers to the surface. Both he and Arturus Thorne want the best for their people, but they are committed to different visions of achieving it. The limits of underground expansion were reached in ages past, and so both leaders must use the wider world to prove their vision for the Khazad in the age of rebirth.</English>
		<French>Les capacités de siège des nains sont sans égal, et leur production peut-être extraordinaire. Cependant, ils ne peuvent pas entraîner d'unités arcaniques et nécessitent de grandes quantités d'or par ville pour atteindre leur plein potentiel.[PARAGRAPH:1]Durant l'Âge de la Magie les nains n'étaient pas la grande nation unie qu'ils deviendraient durant l'Âge de Glace. Tribus éparses de montagnards, ils étaient des artisans et des ingénieurs talentueux, mais ne s'intéressaient pas à ce qui se trouvait au-dela de leurs terres. Aimables et accueillants, ils faisaient des cibles parfaites pour les arnaqueurs et les filous des autres royaumes. Les plus grandes &#156;uvres de leurs forges et de leurs sculpteurs étaient échangées contre des babioles et des verroteries, ou pire, de simples illusions qui disparaissaient une fois leurs créateurs partis. Les nains ne pouvaient obtenir de compensation des seigneurs locaux par les armes ou par la persuasion. Ils n'avaient pas de grandes armées, et les dirigeants alentours mentionnaient que les nains avaient, après tout, accepté les trocs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ces abus firent naître une méfiance à la fois des étrangers et de toutes les formes d'illusions et de magie. Ils les poussèrent également à se réfugier sous terre. Leurs villes originelles et accueillantes construites le long des cols montagneux furent lentement abandonnées pour des communautés souterraines plus sûres. Les tribus se rapprochèrent, et graduellement, issue de nombreuses tribus une civilisation unique et unifiée émergea, les Khazadors. Les nains commencèrent à se demander pourquoi ils devraient même tolérer les étrangers.[PARAGRAPH:1]Vers la fin de l'Âge de la Magie, peu de nains étaient vus par les autres races, et il fut dit plus tard que profondément enfoncés dans leurs forteresses souterraines les nains ne remarquèrent pas l'Âge de Glace avant trois générations. Bien que ce soit certainement exagéré, tandis que les royaumes humains et elfiques dépérissaient sous le joug de Mulcarn les nains eux croissaient lentement mais sûrement. Puis un jour leurs cueilleurs revinrent de la surface en parlant du rtour de végétation luxuriante et de fonte de neige.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros Fir conduisit un groupe de Khazadors hors de leurs maisons caverneuses, pour former des villeset commercer avec les nouveaux royaumes des hommes et des elfes. Il ne suit pas la tradition de la plupart des nains; au lieu de cela, il introduisit des arts nouveaux pour son peuple : négociation, évaluation, commercialisation. Il cherche des partenaires commerciaux avec zèle, parfois par la force, toujours déterminé à faire furctifier la fortune des Khazadors. Se souvenant des insultes dont les générations passées ont été les victimes, les khazadors sont déterminés à se maintenir en sécurité tandis qu'ils s'ouvrent au monde. Pas seulement la sécurité de hauts murs et de marteaux vigoureux, mais aussi celle de coffres pleins à ras bord et de marchands judicieux.[PARAGRAPH:1]Bien que son but l'ait conduit à la surface, ce que personne ne sait hormis quelques cercles nains est qu'un conflit fraticide l'a poussé ainsi que des fidèles à la surface. Lui et Arturus Thorne veulent tous deux le meilleur pour leur peuple, mais ils sont divisés sur la façon d'y parvenir. Les limites de l'expansion souterraine ont été atteintes dans les âges passés, et chacun des chefs doit utiliser le vaste monde pour éprouver sa vision des khazadors à l'Âge de la Renaissance.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Belagerungen der Zwerge sind unübertrefflich und ihre Produktionsleistung kann außergewöhnliche Höhen erreichen. Sie können jedoch keine Magiekundigen Einheiten aufstellen und benötigen eine große Menge Gold pro Stadt, um ihr volles Leistungsvermögen entfalten zu können.[PARAGRAPH:1]Während des Zeitalters der Magie waren die Zwerge nicht die geeinte Nation, zu der sie im Zeitalter des Winters werden würden. Sie waren verstreut lebende Bergvölker mit sehr fähigen Handwerkern und Ingenieuren, aber sie hatten nur wenig Interesse an den Gebieten jenseits ihrer eigenen. Da sie liebenswürdig und gastfreundlich waren, waren sie beliebte Ziele von Gaunern und Betrügern aus anderen Königreichen. Die besten Arbeiten aus ihren Schmieden und Fräsen tauschten sie gegen allerlei Tand und billigen Schmuck oder, noch schlimmer, gegen bloße Illusionen, die sich auflösten, wenn deren Erschaffer weitergezogen waren. Selbst mit Waffengewalt oder zwingenden Beweisen konnten die Zwerge von den Provinzfürsten keine Entschädigung erhalten. Sie hatten keine großen Armeen zur Verfügung und die benachbarten Anführer verwiesen darauf, dass die Zwerge diesen Handeln immerhin zugestimmt hätten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Diese Ungerechtigkeit gebar Misstrauen gegenüber Fremden und jeglichen Formen der Illusion und der Magie. Außerdem trieb sie die Zwerge unter die Erde. Ihre früher einladenden Städte, die entlang der Gebirgspässe errichtet worden waren, wurden nach und nach zugunsten von sichereren unterirdischen Gemeinschaften verlassen. Die Stämme wuchsen zusammen und langsam bildete sich aus vielen Gemeinden eine einzige vereinte Nation, die Khazad. Und die Zwerge begannen sich zu fragen, weshalb sie sich jemals mit Außenstehenden abgegeben hatten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Gegen Ende des Zeitalters der Magie wurden nur noch wenige Zwerge von anderen Rassen gesichtet und viel später wurde erzählt, dass die Zwerge, tief in ihren unterirdischen Festungen, das Zeitalter des Eises erst nach drei Generationen bemerkt hätten. Obwohl das mit Sicherheit eine Übertreibung ist, wuchs die Gesellschaft der Zwerge langsam aber stetig, während die Königreiche der Menschen und Elfen unter Mulcarns Ansturm vergingen. Bis eines Tages ihre Sammler mit Berichten über saftige Vegetation und das Schmelzen des Schnees von der Oberfläche zurückkehrten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros Fir führte eine Gruppe der Khazad aus ihren Höhlenbehausungen heraus, um neue Städte zu gründen und Handel mit den neuen Reichen der Menschen und Elfen zu treiben. Er ist kein Sklave der Traditionen, wie es die meisten Zwerge sind, sondern bereitete den Weg für Fähigkeiten, die seinem Volk unbekannt waren: Verhandlungsgeschick, Begutachtung und Vermarktung. Er überzeugt seine Handelspartner mit Eifer, auch mit Gewalt, falls nötig, und ist immer darauf bedacht, den Reichtum der Khazad zu mehren. Obwohl sie sich an die Ungerechtigkeiten erinnern, die vergangene Generationen erdulden mussten, sind die Khazad davon überzeugt, dass sie nun selbstsicher durch die Welt reisen können. Und zwar nicht nur mit der Selbstsicherheit von hohen Mauern und starken Hämmern, sondern auch mit jener von überlaufenden Schatzkammern und umsichtigen Kaufleuten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Vordergründig führten seine Ziele Kandros Fir nach draußen, aber, was außerhalb bestimmter zwergischer Kreise nicht bekannt ist, auch ein mörderischer Konflikt zwang ihn und seine Anhänger, an die Oberfläche zu gehen. Er und Arturus Thorne wollen nur das Beste für ihr Volk, aber sie hatten unterschiedliche Ansichten darüber, wie das zu erreichen sei. Die Grenzen der Ausbreitung im Untergrund wurden schon vor langer Zeit erreicht und nun müssen beide Anführer Gebrauch von der weiten Welt machen, um die Tauglichkeit ihrer Vorstellungen für die weitere Entwicklung der Khazad im Zeitalter der Wiedergeburt unter Beweis stellen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Le capacità d'assedio dei nani sono senza pari, e la loro produzione può essere straordinaria. Tuttavia non possono addestrare unità arcane, e richiedono grandi quantita di oro per città per raggiungere il loro pieno potenziale.[PARAGRAPH:1]Durante l'Era della Magia i nani non erano ancora una grande nazione unita, lo sarebberò diventati durante l'Era del Ghiaccio. Queste tribù sparse del popolo delle montagne erano degli abili artigiani e ingenieri che avevano scarso interesse per le zone che erano fuori dalle loro terre. Gentili e accoglienti erano il bersaglio perfetto per i truffatori e imbroglioni degli altri regni. Le più grandi creazioni dei loro fabbri e scultori furono scambiate per ninnoli e gingilli, o peggio, semplici illusioni che svanivano una volta che il loro creatore se ne era andato. I nani non potevano ottenere un risarcimento dai signori locali attraverso la forza delle armi o la forza delle loro argomentazioni. Non possedevano grandi eserciti, e i governanti vicini gli ricordavano che i nani avevano, dopotutto, accettato quegli scambi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Questi abusi generarono nei nani una diffidenza sia per gli stranieri che per ogni forma di illusione e magia. Tutto ciò li spinse ad andare ancor più sotto terra. Le loro precedentemente accoglienti città costruite lungo i passi di montagna furono lentamente abbandonate per comunità sotteranee più sicure. Le tribù crebberò sempre più vicine, e gradualmente si unificarono in una grande civiltà unita, i Khazad. I nani iniziarono a domandarsi perché mai avevano perso tempo con gli estranei.[PARAGRAPH:1]Verso la fine dell'Era della Magia pochi erano i nani visti dalle altre razze, e si disse in seguito che nelle loro profonde città sotteranee loro non notarono l'arrivo dell'Era del Ghiaccio per tre generazioni. Sebbene tale affermazione è quasi sicuramente un'esaggerazione, mentre i regni degli uomini e degli elfi avvizivano sotto l'assalto di Mulcarn i nani si sviluppavano lentamente ma costantemente. Poi un giorno i loro raccoglitori tornarono dalla superficie portando notizie del ritorno di una lussureggiante vegetazione, e dello sciogliemento delle nevi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros Fir guidò un gruppo di Khazad fuori dalle loro case sotteranee, per fondare città e commerciare con i nuovi regni degli uomini e degli elfi. Lui non rispettava le tradizioni come la maggior parte dei nani faceva; anzi, lui sperimentava arti nuove al suo popolo: la negoziazione, la valutazione e il marketing. Cercava partner commerciali con zelo, pure con la forza se necessario, sempre determinato ad aumentare le ricchezze dei Khazad. Ricordando gli insulti subiti dalle generazioni passate i Khazad sono risoluti nello stare al sicuro quando vanno in giro per il mondo. Non solo per quanto riguarda la sicurezza data da alte mura e robusti martelli, ma anche quella data da casse piene d'oro e da commercianti onesti.[PARAGRAPH:1]Anche se i suoi obiettivi lo spingono verso l'esterno, una cosa conosciuta solo all'interno di poche cerchie di nani è che fu un conflitto interno che favorì l'uscita sua e dei suoi seguaci sulla superfice. SIa lui che Arturus Thorne vogliono il meglio per il loro popolo, ma seguono strade e filosofie diverse per ottenere tale risultato. I limiti dell'espansione sotteranea furono raggiunti nelle ere passate, e cosi entrambi i leader devono usare il resto del mondo per dimostrare la loro visione dei Khazad nell'Era della Rinascita.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Dwarven siege is unmatched, and their production can be extraordinary. They cannot train arcane units, however, and require a large amount of gold per city to reach their full potential.[PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Magic the dwarves were not the united nation that they would become in the Age of Winter. Scattered tribes of mountain peoples, they were skilled craftsmen and engineers but had little interest in the areas beyond their lands. Amiable and welcoming, they made perfect targets for the con-men and tricksters of other kingdoms. The greatest works of their smiths and their shapers were traded for trinkets and baubles, or worse, mere illusions that vanished when their creators were gone. The dwarves couldn't win redress from the local lords through strength of arms or force of argument. They had no great armies, and the neighboring rulers pointed out that the dwarves had, after all, agreed to the bargains.[PARAGRAPH:1]This abuse bred distrust of both foreigners and all forms of illusion and magic. It also pushed them underground. Their formerly welcoming cities built along mountain passes were slowly abandoned for safer under-hill communities. The tribes grew closer, and gradually out of many a single unified civilization was formed, the Khazad. The dwarves began to ask themselves why they ever even bothered with outsiders.[PARAGRAPH:1]Towards the end of the Age of Magic, few dwarves were seen by other races, and it was later said that deep in their under-hill holds, they didn't notice the Age of Winter for three generations. Though this is almost certainly an exaggeration, while the kingdoms of men and elves withered under Mulcarn's onslaught the dwarves grew slowly but steadily. Then one day their gatherers returned from the surface with reports of lush vegetation returning, and snow melting.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros Fir led one group of Khazad out of their cavernous homes, to form cities and trade with the new kingdoms of men and of elves. He does not revere tradition as most dwarves do; rather, he pioneered arts new to his people: negotiation, appraisal, marketing. He pursues trading partners with zeal, by force if necessary, always determined to advance the Khazad's fortunes. Remembering the insults they were subjected to in generations past the Khazad are determined that they be secure as they venture out into the world. Not just the security of high walls and stout hammers, but of brimming coffers and judicious merchants.[PARAGRAPH:1]While his goals draw him outward, what is unknown outside of a few dwarven circles is that internecine conflict helped push him and his followers to the surface. Both he and Arturus Thorne want the best for their people, but they are committed to different visions of achieving it. The limits of underground expansion were reached in ages past, and so both leaders must use the wider world to prove their vision for the Khazad in the age of rebirth.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHAZAD_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategy: The Khazad are all about money. The more they have per city in their empire the bigger the bonus. Each Khazad city will have a [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT]Dwarven Vault[\LINK] building of various levels in it that represents this bonus. Regardless of the strategy used with the Khazad, players would do well to watch their gold amount and make sure their city expansion doesn't drop their vaults to low. They can relax a bit once they achieve Overflowing status, as their bonuses won't go up past that. Runes of Kilmorph is the best religion for making lots of money, and it should also be noted that the Khazad have better siege weapons than the other civilizations although they can't build any spellcaster units beyond adepts.</English>
		<French>Les Khazadors sont cupides. Plus ils ont d'or par ville, meilleur est le bonus. Chaque ville khazadore possède une [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT]Chambre Forte Naine[\LINK] dont le niveau représente ce bonus. Indépendamment de la stratégie utilisée avec les Khazadors, les joueurs doivent prêter attention à leur trésorerie et s'assurer que leur expansion ne vide pas trop les chambres fortes. Ils peuvent se détendre une fois atteint l'état "Débordante", car leur bonus n'ira pas plus haut. Les Runes de Kilmorph sont la meilleure religion pour se faire plein d'argent, et l'on doit aussi noter que les Khazadors ont les meilleures armes de sièges bien qu'ils ne puissent produire de lanceurs de sorts meilleurs que les adeptes.</French>
		<German>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategie: Bei den Khazad dreht sich alles um Geld. Je mehr sie pro Stadt in ihrem Reich haben, desto größer der Bonus. Jede Stadt der Khazad wird ein Zwergengewölbe verschiedener Art haben, das diesen Bonus repräsentiert. Egal, welche Strategie mit den Khazad verfolgt wird, werden ihre Spieler gut daran tun, ihren Goldbetrag zu überwachen, und sicher zu gehen, dass ihre Stadt-Ausbreitung die Gewölbe nicht zu niedrig werden lässt. Sie können sich ein bisschen entspannen, sobald sie einmal den Überfüllt-Status erreichen, da der Bonus dann nicht mehr weiter steigt. Die Runen von Kilmorph ist die beste Religion, um viel Geld zu machen, und es sollte auch erwähnt werden, dass die Khazad bessere Belagerungswaffen als die anderen Zivilisationen haben, jedoch können sie zaubernde Einheiten, die über Adepten hinausragen, nicht erstellen.</German>
		<Italian>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategia: I Khazad si basano completamente sui soldi. Quanti più ne hanno per città del loro impero maggiore è il bonus che ottengono. Ogni città Khazad ha l'edificio Camera Blindata Nanica, che possiede vari livelli e fornisce bonus, o malus, a seconda di quale è. Indifferentemente da quale strategia si usa con i Khazad i giocatori farebbero bene a tenere sott'occhio la loro quantità d'oro e assicurarsi che la creazione di nuove città non faccia calare troppo il livello delle Camere Blindate Naniche. Possono rilassarsi un pò una volta raggiunto il livello Strapiena, in quanto è il livello massimo e i bonus rimangoo quelli. Le Rune di Kilmorph è la religione migliore per fare un sacco di soldi, e ci si deve ricordare che i Khazad hanno armi d'assedio migliori di quelle delle altre civiltà, anche se non possono addestrare unità arcane oltre agli adepti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Estrategia: Los Khazad están hechos para el dinero.  Cuanto más tengan por ciudad, mayor será la bonificación.  Cada ciudad Khazad tendrá una Cámara Acorazada Enana de varios niveles que representan esa bonificación.  Independientemente de la estrategia usada con los Khazad, los jugadores harían bien en prestar atención a sus cantidades de oro y asegurarse de que su expansión no vacíe las cámaras. Se podrán relajar un poco una vez alcancen un estado de Desbordamiento, pues las bonificaciones no crecerán más desde ahí. Las Runas de Kilmorph es la mejor religión para hacer montones de dinero, y tambié tener en cuenta que los Khazad tienen mejores armas de asedio que las demás civilizaciones, aunque no pueden construir ninguna unidad lanzaconjuros a parte de los adeptos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ARTURUS</Tag>
		<English>Arturus Thorne</English>
		<French>Arturus Thorne</French>
		<German>Arturus Thorne</German>
		<Italian>Arturus Thorne</Italian>
		<Spanish>Arturus Thorne</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ARTURUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]"Riders!" The cries of the watchmen came far too late to save his camp, for the next sound Arturus Thorne heard was the thunder of hoofbeats around him. He was to his feet in an instant, with his great axe in hand, but most of his company needed far more time to ready their weapons.[PARAGRAPH:1]The horsemen dropped nets on the dwarven watchmen as they rode past into their camp. One managed to free himself with his handaxe, but his comrades were kept busy trying to avoid being trampled as more horses poured into the camp.[PARAGRAPH:1]The King's honor guard, famed for their lightning reflexes, had managed to ready their halberds and were forming ranks around the Arturus in the center of the camp. There were not many of them, but their weapons stopped the cavalry charge. "Thunder Company!" Arturus yelled, "Arm yourselves!" Given a few more minutes to load their weapons the main dwarven force could surely turn the tide of the ambush.[PARAGRAPH:1]A whirring sound heralded the raiders' new tactics. The riders circled the dwarven lines, loosing a swarm of bolas towards the guard and their polearms. Such a tactic would have been a mere annoyance were the Dwarves not badly outnumbered. In moments time the guard was felled and the rest of the company was held at lance point.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus cursed his ill luck. A shortcut through these hills had cut their travel time in half, but meant they spent days near Hippus lands. He had hoped to compensate by traveling light and moving fast, but he saw his mistake clearly now. No one outruns the Hippus.[PARAGRAPH:1]The leader of the raiders rode up to Arturus, pacing his horse back and forth, lance pointed menacingly. He was a tall man, with pitch black hair. His face was obscured by a mask, but he pulled it away to reveal a mouth fixed permanently into a snarl by an old scar. "The crazy Clown King paid us for some dwarven slaves, but your treasure is our spoils. Show us what's in the cart, old dwarf."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus hatched a desperate plan. "I warn you, human, I am the high priest for the ancient dwarven gods. If you do not free my people, you will not see morning." He pulled the tarp away from cart, revealing a tall stone column, covered with carvings. Carefully he folded the tarp, setting it down on the ground. He stumbled in the dark as he arose, bumping into one of his young charges and palming a small pouch from his belt.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Hippus raid leader was not convinced, nor was he happy to see the dwarves traveling without their famous gold. "If your gods cared for you they would not have given you feet which don't reach stirrups. Chain him up, boys!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"You have been warned!" shouted Arturus, throwing up his arms dramatically. He tossed the leather pouch into the smoldering embers of their cook fire as he did so. It was invisible in the darkness. Then the black powder inside was heated by the coals, and for a moment there was no more darkness. Thunder followed the lightning, conjured not by gods on high or ancient magic, but dwarven ingenuity. The Hippus horses were startled. Some began running, and even the best trained required their rider's full attention to restrain. Arturus allies immediately took advantage of this, finally readying their muskets. More thunder rolled as the musket balls struck horses and raiders. Dwarves quickly worked to free each other from the Hippus entrapments, and soon the Hippus ambush turned into a rout.[PARAGRAPH:1]Amidst cheering, the captain the guard came up to Arturus. "Do we turn back, my liege?" he asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus shook his head. "No, we cannot. This is too important. But break camp, we'll get no more sleep tonight."[PARAGRAPH:2]The rest of the journey was calm enough, though Arturus grew nervous for reasons of his own as they reached their destination. They reached the open city gates, but Arturus stopped his group. He turned, whispering, "I have no right to enter." Merchants and other travelers streamed past them into the dwarven city. He turned to the captain of the honor guard, and old friend. "Would you please let him know I am here?" He nodded solemnly and entered the city, heading for the castle.[PARAGRAPH:1]Soon Arturus was looking into a familiar face he hadn't seen in many years. "Hello, Arturus," Kandros Fir said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kandros..." Arturus didn't know where to begin. He cleared his throat gruffly. "You've done well for your people," he said, gesturing towards the city.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Why have you come?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ah, 'tis hard to say it, but I wronged you so. I was young and foolish, and resented the burden of authority. I've no right to ask your forgiveness, but you should have this." He revealed the stone pillar in the cart.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros rushed to it, mouth agape as he ran his fingers over the ancient runic script. "The ancestral Fir clan history!" He knew almost every word by heart, but it filled a void in him to see the history of his people again. The last words would have been carved in his own hand, the disappearance of Luach the Wanderer. Except...[PARAGRAPH:1]"I hope you do not object. I added the last fifty years myself. The founding of Hallowell, the battle of Destrier Hill, the goblin war, the births of Gridmok and young Kandros... you've done well for your people." Kandros rose slowly, and, at long last, embraced his old friend. The feud was over, and the Khazad would be one again, in truth as in name.</English>
		<French>"Cavaliers !" Les cris des guetteurs arrivèrent bien trop tard pour sauver son camp, car le son suivant entendu par Arturus Thorne était le fracas étourdissant des sabots autour de lui. Il sauta sur ses pieds, sa grande hache à la main, mais la plupart de ses gens avaient besoin de bien plus de temps pour préparer leurs armes.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les cavaliers jetèrent des filets sur les guetteurs nains tandis qu'ils pénétraient dans le camp. L'un d'entre eux parvint à se libérer à l'aide de sa hache, mais ses camarades restaient occupés à essayer d'éviter de se faire piétiner tandis que d'autres chevaux se déversaient dans le camp.[PARAGRAPH:1]La garde d'honneur du Roi, réputée pour ses réflexes vifs comme l'éclair, avait réussi à préparer ses hallebardes et formait les rangs autour d'Arturus au centre du camp. Ils étaient peu, mais leurs armes stoppèrent la charge de cavalerie. "Compagnie du Tonnerre !" cria Arturus, "Armez vous !" Si on leur donnait quelques minutes de plus pour préparer leurs armes, la force principale naine pourrait sûrement renverser le cours de l'embuscade.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un son bourdonnant indiqua le changement de tactique des assaillants. Les cavaliers encerclèrent les lignes naines, lançant une nuée de bolas sur les gardes et leurs piques. Une telle tactique n'aurait été qu'un simple désagrément si les Nains n'avait pas été si peu nombreux par rapport aux assaillants. En peu de temps, la garde fut abattue et le reste de la compagnie était tenu en respect du bout des lances.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus maudit sa malchance. Un raccourci au travers de ces collines aurait diminué leur temps de voyage de moitié, mais signifiait qu'ils passeraient quelques jours près des terres des Hippus. Il avait espéré le compenser en voyageant léger et en bougeant rapidement, mais il voyait maintenant clairement son erreur. Personne ne surpasse la vitesse des Hippus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le chef des cavaliers trotta vers Arturus, faisant avancer et reculer son cheval, sa lance pointée de manière menaçante. C'était un homme de grande taille aux cheveur d'un noir de jais. Son visage était caché par un masque, mais il l'enleva pour révéler une bouche transformée en un rictus permanent par une vieille cicatrice. "Ce dingue de Clown Roi nous a payé pour avoir des esclaves nains, mais votre trésor est nôtre. Montre-nous ce qu'il y a dans ces chariots, vieux nain."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus mit au point un plan désespéré. "Je te préviens, humain, je suis le haut-prêtre des anciens dieux nains. Si tu ne libères pas mes gens, tu ne verras pas l'aube." Il ôta la bâche d'un chariot, révélant une grande colonne de pierre, couverte de gravures. Il plia précautionneusement la bâche, la posant au sol. Il trébucha dans le noir alors qu'il se relevait, butant contre un de ses jeunes acolytes et escamotant une petite bourse de sa ceinture.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le chef de raid des Hippus n'était cependant pas convaincu, ni n'était heureux de voir des nains voyager sans leur fameux or. "Si vos dieux avaient tenu à vous, ils ne vous auraient pas donné des pieds qui n'atteignent pas les étriers. Enchaînez-le, les gars !"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Je vous aurai prévenus !" tonna Arturus, levant ses bras dans un geste dramatique. Ce faisant, il lança la petite bourse de cuir dans les braises mourantes de leur feu de cuisine. C'était passé inaperçu dans les ténèbres. Puis la poudre noire à l'intérieur fut chauffée par le charbon, et pendant un instant il n'y eut plus de ténèbres. Le tonnerre suivit l'éclair, invoqué non pas par des dieux puissants ou une magie ancienne, mais par l'ingéniosité naine. Les chevaux des Hippus furent paniqués. Certains partirent au galop, et même les mieux entraînés nécessitèrent la complète attention de leurs cavaliers pour les calmer. Les alliés d'Arturus saisirent immédiatement l'occasion, finissant d'armer leurs mousquets. De nouveaux roulements de tonnerre retentirent tandis que les balles de mousquets frappaient les chevaux et les cavaliers. Les nains libérèrent rapidement leurs compatriotes des entraves des Hippus, et rapidement l'embuscade des Hippus tourna à la déroute.[PARAGRAPH:1]Au milieu des ovations, le capitaine des gardes vint trouver Arturus. "Faisons-nous demi-tour, mon thane ?" demanda-t-il.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus secoua la tête. "Non, nous ne pouvons pas. Ceci est trop important. Mais levez le camp, nous ne dormirons plus cette nuit."[PARAGRAPH:2]Le reste du voyage fut relativement calme, même si Arturus devenait nerveux pour des raisons qui lui étaient propres à mesure qu'ils approchaient de leur destination. Ils atteignirent les portes ouvertes de la ville, mais Arturus arrêta son groupe. Il se tourna, chuchotant, "Je n'ai pas le droit d'entrer." Les marchands et autres voyageurs passaient devant eux et entraient dans la ville naine. Il se tourna vers le capitaine de la garde d'honneur, un vieil ami. "Pourrais-tu lui faire savoir que je suis ici ?" Ce dernier acquiesca d'un hochement de tête solennel et pénétra dans la ville, se dirigeant vers le château.[PARAGRAPH:1]Peu après, Arturus regardait un visage qu'il n'avait pas vu depuis de nombreuses années. "Bonjour, Arturus," dit Kandros Fir.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kandros..." Arturus ne savait pas par où commencer. Il se racla la gorge. "Tu t'es bien occupé de ton peuple," dit-il, en désignant la ville.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Pourquoi es-tu venu ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ah, c'dur à dire, mais je t'ai fait du mal. J'étais jeune et idiot, et le fardeau de l'autorité m'insupportait. Je n'ai pas le droit de te demander ton pardon, mais tu devrais avoir ceci." Il révéla le pilier de pierre dans le chariot.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros se précipita pour l'examiner, bouche bée tandis que ces doigts parcouraient les anciens écrits runiques. "L'histoire du clan ancestral Fir !" Il en connaissait pratiquement chaque mot par c&#156;ur, mais voir à nouveau l'histoire de son peuple comblait un vide dans son c&#156;ur. Les derniers mots auraient dû être ceux qu'il avait lui-même gravé, la disparition de Luach le Voyageur. Et pourtant...[PARAGRAPH:1]"J'espère que ça ne te gêne pas. J'ai ajouté de moi-même les cinquante dernières années. La fondation de Hallowell, la bataille de la Colline Destrier, la guerre gobeline, les naissances de Gridmok et du jeune Kandros... Tu t'es bien occupé de ton peuple." Kandros se leva lentement, et après un long moment, serra son vieil ami dans ses bras. La scission était du passé, et les Khazadors ne feraient plus qu'un dans les faits comme sur le papier.</French>
		<German>[TAB]"Reiter!" Die Schreie der Wachleute kamen viel zu spät um das Lager noch retten zu können, so war das nächste Geräusch, das Arturus Thorne hörte, der Donner der Hufschläge um ihn herum. Er war sofort auf den Beinen, mit seiner großen Axt in den Händen, aber die meisten seiner Begleiter brauchten deutlich mehr Zeit um ihre Waffen bereit zu machen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Pferdemenschen warfen Netze über die Zwergischen Kundschafter als sie in ihr Lager ritten. Einer war in der Lage sich mit seiner Handaxt zu befreien, aber seine Kameraden waren damit beschäftigt nicht plattgetrampelt zu werden, als immer mehr Pferde in das Lager stürmten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Königliche Ehrengarde, berühmt für ihre blitzartigen Reflexe, hatte ihre Hellebarden bereit und bildete eine Formation um Arturus in der Mitte des Lagers. Es waren nicht viele von ihnen, aber ihre Waffen stoppten den Kavallerieangriff. "Donner-Kompanie!" schrie Arturus, "Bewaffnet Euch!" Mit nur ein paar Minuten mehr Zeit um ihre Waffen zu laden, wäre die Hauptmacht der Zwerge sicherlich in der Lage das Blatt in diesem Hinterhalt zu wenden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ein surrender Klang gab den Reitern neue Befehle. Die Reiter umzingelten die zwergischen Linien und warfen einen ganzen Schwarm Bolas auf die Ehrengarde und ihre Stangenwaffen. Solch eine Taktik wäre nur ein simples Ärgernis gewesen, wären die Zwerge nicht hoffnungslos zahlenmäßig unterlegen. Nur einen Moment später war die Garde gefallen und die Kompanie wurde mit Speerspitzen in Schach gehalten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus verfluchte sein Pech. Eine Abkürzung durch diese Hügel hatte ihre Marschzeit halbiert, ließ sie aber auch mehrere Tage in Reichweite der Hippus bleiben. Er hatte gehofft sie durch schnelles Marschieren mit leichtem Gepäck umgehen zu können, sah aber nun seinen Irrtum ein. Keiner entkommt den Hippus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Anführer der Angreifer ritt zu Arturus, ließ sein Pferd vor und zurück tänzeln und hielt ihm seine Speerspitze furchteinflößend vor das Gesicht. Er war ein großer Mann mit pechschwarzem Haar. Sein Gesicht wurde von einer Maske verdeckt, die er nun abnahm um einen Mund zu entblößen, der von einer alten Narbe in ein permanentes Zähnefletschen gezwungen wurde. "Der verrückte Clownkönig hat uns für einige Zwergensklaven bezahlt, aber euer Schatz ist unsere beute. Zeig uns was in dem Wagen ist, alter Zwerg.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus brütete einen verzweifelten Plan aus. "Ich warne euch, Mensch, ich bin der Hoheprister der alten Zwergengötter. Wenn ihr meine Leute nicht sofort freilasst, werdet ihr den nächsten Morgen nicht erleben." Er zog die Plane vom Wagen und enthüllte so eine große Steinsäule, die mit Schnitzereien bedeckt war. Vorsichtig faltete er die Plane zusammen und legte sie auf den Boden. Er stolperte in der Dunkelheit als er sich wieder erhob, stieß mit einem seiner jungen Gefolgsleute zusammen und löste einen kleinen Beutel von seinem Gürtel.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Anführer der Hippus war weder überzeugt, noch war er erfreut, die Zwerge ohne ihr berühmtes Gold reisen zu sehen. "Wenn eure Götter für euch hätten sorgen wollen, so hätten sie euch Füße gegeben, die Steigbügel erreichen können. Fesselt ihn, Jungs!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ihr wurdet gewarnt!" schrie Arturus, seine Arme in daramtischer Weise in die Luft werfend. Dabei warf er den Lederbeutel in die schwelende Glut ihres Lagerfeuers. Der Beutel war während der Dunkelheit nahezu unsichtbar. Das schwarze Pulver in ihm wurde durch die Kohlen erhitzt und einen Moment lang gab es keine Dunkelheit mehr. Donner folgte dem Blitz, nicht erzeugt durch Götter oder alte Magie, sondern durch zwergische Genialität. Die Pferde der Hippus wurden aufgeschreckt. Einige wollten flüchten und selbst die am besten trainierten erforderten die volle Aufmerksamkeit ihrer Reiter, um sie im Zaum zu halten. Arturus Gefährten nutzten das sofort aus und machten ihre Musketen schussbereit. Mehr Donner rollte durch das Tal, als die Musketenkugeln Pferde und Reiter trafen. Die Zwerge befreiten ihre Kameraden zügig aus den Fesseln der Hippus und schon bald hatte sich der Überfall der Hippus in eine Niederlage verwandelt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Inmitten des Jubels kam der Hauptmann der Garde zu Arturus. "Kehren wir um, mein Herr?" fragte er.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus schüttelte den Kopf. "Nein, wir können nicht umkehren. Das ist zu wichtig. Aber wir werden das Lager abbrechen, wir werden ohnehin keinen Schlaf mehr bekommen, heute Nacht."[PARAGRAPH:2]Der Rest der Reise war sehr ruhig, allerdings wurde Arturus aus anderen Gründen nervös, als sie ihr Ziel erreichten. Sie näherten sich offenen Stadttore, aber Arturus stoppte seine Gruppe. Er wandte sich ihnen zu und flüsterte "Ich habe kein Recht, die Stadt zu betreten." Händler und andere Reisen strömten an ihnen vorbei in die Zwergenstadt. Zum Hauptmann der Garde, einem alten Freund, sprach er: "Würdest du ihn bitte wissen lassen, das ich hier bin?" Der Hauptmann nickte feierlich, betrat die Stadt und ging in Richtung der Burg.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kurze Zeit später blickte Arturus in ein verwandtes Gesicht, das er seit sehr vielen Jahren nicht mehr gesehen hatte. "Hallo Arturus", sagte Kandros Fir.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kandros..." Arturus wusste nicht, wo er beginnen sollte. Er räusperte sich. "Du hast deinen Leuten viel gutes getan" sagte er und deutete dabei auf die Stadt.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Warum bist du gekommen?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ah, 's ist nicht leicht das zu sagen, aber ich habe dir so Unrecht getan. Ich war jung und dumm und habe mich über die Bürde der Autorität geärgert. Ich habe kein Recht dich um Vergebung zu bitten, aber du solltest dies hier bekommen." Mit diesen Worten enthüllte er die Steinsäule auf dem Wagen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros eilte zu ihr hin, den Mund weit offen während er seine Finger über die altertümliche Runenschrift gleiten lässt. "Die Geschichte des Clans der Fir!" Er kannte jedes Wort in seinem herzen, aber es füllte eine bisher in ihm gewesene Leere, die Geschichte seines Clans erneut zu sehen. Die letzren Worte würden in seiner Handschrift geritzt sein, das Verschwinden von Luarch, dem Wanderer. Außer ...[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich hoffe du erhebst keine Einwände. Ich hab die letzten fünfzig Jahre selber hinzugefügt. Die Gründung von Hallowell, die Schlacht am Destrier Hill, den Goblinkrieg, die Geburt von Gridmok und dem jungen Kandros... du hast deinen Leuten wirklich viel Gutes gebracht." Kandros erhob sich langsam und, ganz zum Schluss, umarmte seinen alten Freund. Die Fehde war vorüber und die Khazad würden wieder eins sein, auch im Herzen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]"Cavalieri!" L'urlo dei nani di guardia arrivò troppo tardi per salvare il campo, in quanto il rumore seguente che Arturus Thorne sentì fu il rumore di zoccoli tutto intorno a lui. Lui era in piedi in un'istante, con la sua grande ascia in mano, ma la maggior parte della sua compagnia aveva bisogno di più tempo per afferrare le loro armi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dei cavalieri lanciarono delle reti sui nani di guardia mentre gli cavalcavano affianco entrando nel campo. Una delle guardie riuscì a liberarsi con la sua ascia, mentre le altre erano cercavano di non farsi travolgere dalla quantità sempre maggiore di cavalli che entrava nel campo.[PARAGRAPH:1]La guardia d'onore del Re, rinomata per i suoi riflessi fulminei, era riuscita ad impugnare le loro alabarde e stava formando un cerchio intorno ad Arturus al centro del campo. Non erano in molti, ma le loro armi riuscirono a fermare la carica dei cavalieri. "Brigata del Tuono!" Arturus urlò, "Armatevi!" Se forniti di qualche minuto per caricare le loro armi il contingente nanico principale poteva ribaltare sicuramente le sorti dell'imboscata.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un ronzio annunciò le nuove tattiche dei cavalieri. Giravano intorno alle linee naniche, lanciando delle bolas alle guardie e alle loro alabarde. Una simile tatticha sarebbe stata poco più di un semplice fastidio se non fosse stato che i nani erano in pesante inferiorita numerica. In poco tempo la guardia fu neutralizzata e il resto della brigata si ritrovò circondata da lance.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus maledì la sua sfortuna. Una scorciatoia attraverso le colline aveva dimezzato il tempo del loro viaggio, ma ciò comportava passare del tempo vicino alle terre degli Hippus. Aveva sperato di compensare ciò viaggiando leggero e rapidamente, ma riconobbe il suo errore ora. Nessuno è più veloce degli Hippus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il condottiero dei cavalieri si avvicinò ad Arturus, facendo avanti e indietro col cavallo e la lancia puntata minacciosamente. Era un'uomo alto, con capelli neri. Il suo volto era nascosto dietro a una maschera, ma lui se la tolse mostrando una bocca bloccata permanentemente in una smorfia da una vecchia cicatrice. "Il folle Re Pagliaccio ci ha pagato per fornirgli degli schiavi nanici, ma il tuo tesoro sarà il nostro bottino. Mostraci cosa c'è nel carro, vecchio nano."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus sviluppò un piano disperato. "Ti avviso, umano, io sono il sommo sacerdote degli antichi dei nanici. Se non liberi la mia gente, non arriverai a vedere l'alba." Cosi dicendo tirò via il telo dal carro, rivelando un'alta colonna di pietra, ricoperta di incisioni. Poi ripiegò con cura il telo e lo poggiò a terra. Inciampò nell'oscurità mentre si rialzava, andando a sbattere contro un giovane nano e prendendo furtivamente un sacchetto della sua cintura.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il condottiero Hippus non era soddisfatto, ne felice nel vedere che i nani viaggiavano senza il loro famoso oro. "Se i vostri dei si curavano di voi non vi avrebbero mai dato gambe cosi corte da non raggiungere le staffe. Incatenateli ragazzi!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ti avevo avvisato!" gridò Arturus, sollevando le braccia in modo drammatico. Nel mentre lanciò il sacchetto di cuoio nei tozzoni ardenti del fuoco da campo. Era impossibile vederlo al buio. In poco tempo la polvere nera all'interno del sacchetto fu accesa dai tizzoni, e per un secondo non ci fu più buio. Il tuono fu seguito da un lampo, creati non da qualche dio o antica magia, ma bensì dall'ingegno nanico. I cavalli degli Hippus si spaventarono. Alcuni iniziarono a correre, e persino i meglio addestratti richiesero la completa attenzione del loro cavaliere per rimanere tranquilli. Gli alleati di Arturus approfittarono immediatamente della situazione, preparando infine i loro moschetti. Ci furono altri tuoni mentre le palle dei moschetti colpivano cavalli e cavalieri. I nani si aiutarono a vicenda per liberarsi dagli impedimenti degli Hippus, e in poco tempo l'agguato Hippus si trasformò in una rotta.[PARAGRAPH:1]Durante le seguenti esultazioni il capitano della guardia andò da Arturus. "Torniamo indietro, mio Signore?" chiese.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus scosse la testa. "No, non possiamo. Questo è troppo importante. Ma smontate il campo, non dormiremo più stanotte."[PARAGRAPH:2]Il resto del viaggio fu abbastanza calmo, comunque Arturus divenne sempre più nervoso, per motivi personali, man mano che si avvicinavano alla meta. Raggiunsero le porte aperte della città e Arturus fermò il suo gruppo. Si voltò, sussurrando, "Non ho il diritto di entrare." Mercanti e altri viaggiatori gli passavano a fianco entrando nella città nanica. Si voltò verso il capitano della guardia d'onore, un vecchio amico. "Potresti fargli sapere per favore che io sono qui?" Il capitano annuì solennemente e entrò in città, dirigendosi verso il castello.[PARAGRAPH:1]Poco dopo Arturus stava guardando una faccia familiare che non aveva visto in molti anni. "Ciao, Arturus," Kandros Fir disse.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kandros..." Arturus non sapeva da dove iniziare. Si schiarì la gola in modo burbero. "Hai fatto un buon lavoro con la tua gente," disse, gesticolando verso la città.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Perché sei venuto?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ah, è difficile dirlo, ma ti avevo fatto un torto. Ero giovane e incoscente, e risentivo del peso dell'autorità. Non ho alcun diritto di chiedere il tuo perdono, ma dovresti avere questo." E rivelò la colonna di pietra dentro al carro.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros si precipitò verso di essa, con la bocca spalancata mentre passava le dita sopra le vecchie incisioni runiche. "La storia ancestrale del clan Fir!" Kandros conosceva quasi tutte le parole a memoria, ma il vedere la storia della sua gente di nuovo riempì un vuoto che era in lui. Le ultime parole sarebbero state incise dalla sua mano, la scomparsa di Luach il Vagabondo. Tranne che...[PARAGRAPH:1]"Spero non ti dispiaccia. Ho aggiunto io gli ultimi cinquanta anni. La fondazione di Hallowell, la battaglia della Collina Destrier, la guerra coi goblin, la nascita di Gridmok e il giovane Kandros... hai fatto un buon lavoro con la tua gente." Kandros si alzò lentamente, e, finalmente, abbracciò il suo vecchio amico. La faida era finita, e i Khazad sarebberò stati uniti di nuovo, nei fatti come nel nome.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]"Riders!" The cries of the watchmen came far too late to save his camp, for the next sound Arturus Thorne heard was the thunder of hoofbeats around him. He was to his feet in an instant, with his great axe in hand, but most of his company needed far more time to ready their weapons.[PARAGRAPH:1]The horsemen dropped nets on the dwarven watchmen as they rode past into their camp. One managed to free himself with his handaxe, but his comrades were kept busy trying to avoid being trampled as more horses poured into the camp.[PARAGRAPH:1]The King's honor guard, famed for their lightning reflexes, had managed to ready their halberds and were forming ranks around the Arturus in the center of the camp. There were not many of them, but their weapons stopped the cavalry charge. "Thunder Company!" Arturus yelled, "Arm yourselves!" Given a few more minutes to load their weapons the main dwarven force could surely turn the tide of the ambush.[PARAGRAPH:1]A whirring sound heralded the raiders' new tactics. The riders circled the dwarven lines, loosing a swarm of bolas towards the guard and their polearms. Such a tactic would have been a mere annoyance were the Dwarves not badly outnumbered. In moments time the guard was felled and the rest of the company was held at lance point.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus cursed his ill luck. A shortcut through these hills had cut their travel time in half, but meant they spent days near Hippus lands. He had hoped to compensate by traveling light and moving fast, but he saw his mistake clearly now. No one outruns the Hippus.[PARAGRAPH:1]The leader of the raiders rode up to Arturus, pacing his horse back and forth, lance pointed menacingly. He was a tall man, with pitch black hair. His face was obscured by a mask, but he pulled it away to reveal a mouth fixed permanently into a snarl by an old scar. "The crazy Clown King paid us for some dwarven slaves, but your treasure is our spoils. Show us what's in the cart, old dwarf."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus hatched a desperate plan. "I warn you, human, I am the high priest for the ancient dwarven gods. If you do not free my people, you will not see morning." He pulled the tarp away from cart, revealing a tall stone column, covered with carvings. Carefully he folded the tarp, setting it down on the ground. He stumbled in the dark as he arose, bumping into one of his young charges and palming a small pouch from his belt.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Hippus raid leader was not convinced, nor was he happy to see the dwarves traveling without their famous gold. "If your gods cared for you they would not have given you feet which don't reach stirrups. Chain him up, boys!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"You have been warned!" shouted Arturus, throwing up his arms dramatically. He tossed the leather pouch into the smoldering embers of their cook fire as he did so. It was invisible in the darkness. Then the black powder inside was heated by the coals, and for a moment there was no more darkness. Thunder followed the lightning, conjured not by gods on high or ancient magic, but dwarven ingenuity. The Hippus horses were startled. Some began running, and even the best trained required their rider's full attention to restrain. Arturus allies immediately took advantage of this, finally readying their muskets. More thunder rolled as the musket balls struck horses and raiders. Dwarves quickly worked to free each other from the Hippus entrapments, and soon the Hippus ambush turned into a rout.[PARAGRAPH:1]Amidst cheering, the captain the guard came up to Arturus. "Do we turn back, my liege?" he asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus shook his head. "No, we cannot. This is too important. But break camp, we'll get no more sleep tonight."[PARAGRAPH:2]The rest of the journey was calm enough, though Arturus grew nervous for reasons of his own as they reached their destination. They reached the open city gates, but Arturus stopped his group. He turned, whispering, "I have no right to enter." Merchants and other travelers streamed past them into the dwarven city. He turned to the captain of the honor guard, and old friend. "Would you please let him know I am here?" He nodded solemnly and entered the city, heading for the castle.[PARAGRAPH:1]Soon Arturus was looking into a familiar face he hadn't seen in many years. "Hello, Arturus," Kandros Fir said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kandros..." Arturus didn't know where to begin. He cleared his throat gruffly. "You've done well for your people," he said, gesturing towards the city.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Why have you come?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ah, 'tis hard to say it, but I wronged you so. I was young and foolish, and resented the burden of authority. I've no right to ask your forgiveness, but you should have this." He revealed the stone pillar in the cart.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros rushed to it, mouth agape as he ran his fingers over the ancient runic script. "The ancestral Fir clan history!" He knew almost every word by heart, but it filled a void in him to see the history of his people again. The last words would have been carved in his own hand, the disappearance of Luach the Wanderer. Except...[PARAGRAPH:1]"I hope you do not object. I added the last fifty years myself. The founding of Hallowell, the battle of Destrier Hill, the goblin war, the births of Gridmok and young Kandros... you've done well for your people." Kandros rose slowly, and, at long last, embraced his old friend. The feud was over, and the Khazad would be one again, in truth as in name.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ATHEL</Tag>
		<English>Athel Revus</English>
		<French>Athel Revus</French>
		<German>Athel Revus</German>
		<Italian>Athel Revus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Athel Revus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ATHEL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The dwarf looked down on a ghost town. Ten days ago there had been a thriving village at the mouth of the valley, built along the banks of a rocky stream. It had boasted a tavern and a trading-post for the furriers and shepherds who made their living in the high peaks of the area. Indeed, the dwarf had sat in that tavern drinking beer he'd paid for with money made by trading tools to the villagers. Now the buildings were empty, some with doors or windows broken but most intact. The trading post still smoldered where the fires had reduced it to an ash-heap. Here and there a discarded bucket or jug attested to efforts to stop the fire, and a strange smell hung in the air, but there was no other sign of the inhabitants. "So," the dwarf called over his shoulder, "I see things went about as expected." Behind him another dwarf, barely visible in the twilight, nodded agreement. "The booze you sold them put most of the men out," he stated flatly, "and when we fired the post the rest came running. We rounded them up with no trouble." The first dwarf chuckled and rubbed his hands together. "Good. If the lads hurry them along we'll have them on the block in Hexam before the week is out. I appreciate your taking care of this for me. I had a few other ventures that needed my personal attention in the last few days."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I hope one of them was getting rid of those papers. The Stewards don't like knowing someone's got their names in a file, and neither do I."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course you don't. Then again," the merchant snarled, "I don't like being told I'll be 'donating' triple this month if I want my spices to make it back to the Underhome. Do you have any idea what the horselords charge me for those damned roots? You're the ones who lit the fuse on this charge, not me. I admit, though, that I'm sorry I had to get you involved. Blame your cousin for letting on while we were out drinking. That's something you might want to look into when you get back to Halowell."[PARAGRAPH:1]The assassin spat, then melted away into the shadows, leaving Athel Revus to contemplate just what he was going to do with his new herd of sheep... and how long it would be before the cousin, who'd been undercutting him on provisions sales, would be out of the way.</English>
		<French>Le nain posa les yeux sur une ville fantôme. Dix ans plus tôt c'était un village florissant à l'embouchure de la vallée, construit le long des rives rocheuses. Il se targuait de posséder une taverne et un poste de commerce pour les fourreurs et les bergers qui faisaient leur beurre dans les hauts cols de la région. Évidemment, le nain s'était assis dans la taverne pour boire de la bière qu'il avait payé à l'aide de l'argent gagné en échangeant des outils aux villageois. Aujourd'hui les bâtiments étaient vides, certains avec les vitres ou les portes cassées, mais la plupart intacts. Le poste de commerce se consumait encore là où les flammes l'avaient transformé en un tas de cendres. Par ci par là un seau ou un cruche au sol attestaient des efforts pour stopper le feu, et une étrange odeur flottait dans l'air, mais il n'y avait aucun autre signe des habitants. "Ainsi," le nain parlait par-dessus son épaule, "les choses ont évolué comme je m'y attendais." Derrière lui, un autre nain, à peine visible dans le crépuscule, acquiesca d'un signe de tête. "La gnôle que tu leur as vendu en a mis la plupart hors d'état de nuire," constata-t-il simplement, "et quand nous avons mis le feu au poste le reste est venu en courant. Nous les avons encerclés sans mal."[PARAGRAPH:1]Le premier nain rit sous cape et se frotta les mains. "Bien. Si les gosses se dépêchent suffisamment, nous les aurons bloqués à Hexam avant la fin de la semaine. J'apprécie que tu te charges de cette affaire pour moi. J'ai eu quelques affaires qui requéraient mon attention personnelle ces derniers jours."[PARAGRAPH:1]"J'espère que l'un d'entre eux se chargera de ces papiers. Les Stewards n'apprécient pas de savoir que quelqu'un a leurs noms dans un dossier, et moi non plus."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bien sûr que tu n'aimes pas ça. Et à nouveau," le marchand gronda, "je n'aime pas me faire dire que je 'donnerai' trois fois plus ce mois-ci si je veux que mes épices rentrent à la Maisonterre. As-tu la moindre idée de quoi les seigneurs du cheval m'accusent pour ces satanées racines ? Vous êtes ceux qui ont mis le feu aux poudres, pas moi. J'admet, cependant, que je suis désolé d'avoir eu à t'impliquer. Blâme ton cousin pour avoir laissé faire tandis que nous étions sortis boire. C'est quelque chose que tu devrais régler quand tu reviendras à Halowell."[PARAGRAPH:1]L'assassin cracha, puis se fondit dans les ombres, laissant Athel Revus à ses réflexions à propos de ce qu'il ferait de son nouveau troupeau de moutons... et combien de temps ça lui prendrait pour que le cousin, qui cassait les prix sur la vente des provisions, soit hors du circuit.</French>
		<German>[TAB]The dwarf looked down on a ghost town. Ten days ago there had been a thriving village at the mouth of the valley, built along the banks of a rocky stream. It had boasted a tavern and a trading-post for the furriers and shepherds who made their living in the high peaks of the area. Indeed, the dwarf had sat in that tavern drinking beer he'd paid for with money made by trading tools to the villagers. Now the buildings were empty, some with doors or windows broken but most intact. The trading post still smoldered where the fires had reduced it to an ash-heap. Here and there a discarded bucket or jug attested to efforts to stop the fire, and a strange smell hung in the air, but there was no other sign of the inhabitants. "So," the dwarf called over his shoulder, "I see things went about as expected." Behind him another dwarf, barely visible in the twilight, nodded agreement. "The booze you sold them put most of the men out," he stated flatly, "and when we fired the post the rest came running. We rounded them up with no trouble." The first dwarf chuckled and rubbed his hands together. "Good. If the lads hurry them along we'll have them on the block in Hexam before the week is out. I appreciate your taking care of this for me. I had a few other ventures that needed my personal attention in the last few days."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I hope one of them was getting rid of those papers. The Stewards don't like knowing someone's got their names in a file, and neither do I."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course you don't. Then again," the merchant snarled, "I don't like being told I'll be 'donating' triple this month if I want my spices to make it back to the Underhome. Do you have any idea what the horselords charge me for those damned roots? You're the ones who lit the fuse on this charge, not me. I admit, though, that I'm sorry I had to get you involved. Blame your cousin for letting on while we were out drinking. That's something you might want to look into when you get back to Halowell."[PARAGRAPH:1]The assassin spat, then melted away into the shadows, leaving Athel Revus to contemplate just what he was going to do with his new herd of sheep... and how long it would be before the cousin, who'd been undercutting him on provisions sales, would be out of the way.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il nano guardò in basso vedendo una città fantasma. Dieci giorni fa era un fiorente villaggio all'entrata della valle, costruito lungo le rive di un ruscello roccioso. Aveva una taverna e un'emporio per i cacciatori di pelli e i pastori che vivevano alle quote più alte. Persino il nano era stato alla taverna bevendo birra comprata con i soldi che aveva fatto vendendo attrezzi agli abitanti del villaggio. Ora gli edifici era vuoti, alcuni con le porte e finestre rotte, ma la maggior parte ancora intatte. L'emporio era stato ridotto a un cumulo di cenere e stava ancora fumando. Qui e la vi era un secchio o una brocca abbandonati, a dimostrazione del tentativo di spegnere il fuoco, e uno strano odore era ancora presente nell'aria, ma non vi era segno degli abitanti. "Dunque," il nano disse da sopra la spalla, "vedo che le cose sono andate come previsto". Dietro di lui vi era un altro nano, appena visibile nella penombra, che annuì. "Il liquore che gli hai venduto ha messo fuori gioco la maggior parte degli uomini," disse senza emozione, "e quando abbiamo appiccato l'incendio all'emporio gli altri sono accorsi correndo. Li abbiamo catturati senza problemi." Il primo nano ridacchiò e si sfregò le mani. "Bene. Se i ragazzi li fanno muovere in fretta li avremmo insieme al gruppo ad Hexam prima della fine della settimana. Apprezzo che te ne sia occuapto tu per me. Avevo altri affari che richiedevano la mia personale attenzione negli ultimi giorni."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Spero che uno di quelli fosse il liberarsi di quei documenti. Agli Amministratori non piace sapere che qualcuno ha scritto i loro nomi in un documento, e neppure a me piace."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ovvio che non vi piaccia. D'altronde," disse il mercante, "a me non piace che mi venga detto di dover 'donare' il triplo questo mese se voglio che le mie spezie torninò al Sottosuolo. Hai idea di quante tasse i signori dei cavalli mettono su quelle dannate radici? Voi avete causato queste tasse, non io. Ammetto, però, che mi dispiace di avervi messo in mezzo. Date la colpa a vostro cugino che se le lasciato sfuggire mentre bevevamo. Magari è una cosa di cui ti vorrai occupare una volta tornati ad Halowell."[PARAGRAPH:1]L'assassino sputò, per poi svanire nelle ombre, lasciando Athel Revus a contemplare che cosa avrebbe fatto con il nuovo gregge di pecore... e quanto tempo sarebbe passato prima che il cugino, che vendeva provviste a un prezzo inferiore al suo, sarebbe stato fuori dai giochi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The dwarf looked down on a ghost town. Ten days ago there had been a thriving village at the mouth of the valley, built along the banks of a rocky stream. It had boasted a tavern and a trading-post for the furriers and shepherds who made their living in the high peaks of the area. Indeed, the dwarf had sat in that tavern drinking beer he'd paid for with money made by trading tools to the villagers. Now the buildings were empty, some with doors or windows broken but most intact. The trading post still smoldered where the fires had reduced it to an ash-heap. Here and there a discarded bucket or jug attested to efforts to stop the fire, and a strange smell hung in the air, but there was no other sign of the inhabitants. "So," the dwarf called over his shoulder, "I see things went about as expected." Behind him another dwarf, barely visible in the twilight, nodded agreement. "The booze you sold them put most of the men out," he stated flatly, "and when we fired the post the rest came running. We rounded them up with no trouble." The first dwarf chuckled and rubbed his hands together. "Good. If the lads hurry them along we'll have them on the block in Hexam before the week is out. I appreciate your taking care of this for me. I had a few other ventures that needed my personal attention in the last few days."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I hope one of them was getting rid of those papers. The Stewards don't like knowing someone's got their names in a file, and neither do I."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course you don't. Then again," the merchant snarled, "I don't like being told I'll be 'donating' triple this month if I want my spices to make it back to the Underhome. Do you have any idea what the horselords charge me for those damned roots? You're the ones who lit the fuse on this charge, not me. I admit, though, that I'm sorry I had to get you involved. Blame your cousin for letting on while we were out drinking. That's something you might want to look into when you get back to Halowell."[PARAGRAPH:1]The assassin spat, then melted away into the shadows, leaving Athel Revus to contemplate just what he was going to do with his new herd of sheep... and how long it would be before the cousin, who'd been undercutting him on provisions sales, would be out of the way.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_KANDROS</Tag>
		<English>Kandros Fir</English>
		<French>Kandros Fir</French>
		<German>Kandros Fir</German>
		<Italian>Kandros Fir</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kandros Fir</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_KANDROS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Arturus found his friend by candlelight. Torches were forbidden in this hallowed chamber, deep in the Underhome. The soot and smoke they gave off obscured the runes carved into the rows of pillars, covering the names and deeds of the honored Dwarven ancestors. The ancient dwarves who kept these sites, carving new stories and teaching others to read them, were called Runewardens officially but 'Hand Seers' more commonly. Squinting in the candlelight so much invariably robbed them of their sight, so they learned every word and letter by hand. Kandros Fir was at the end of his Clan's section of the Rune Hall, chisel in hand.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I knew I'd find you here," Arturus said, kneeling next to him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I was his closest kin. I must add his name and deeds to our story."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course, old friend. But that isn't all you are planning, is it?" Kandros bowed his head.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am loyal to our king, by my bones, I am loyal."[PARAGRAPH:1]"But?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I can no sooner abandon family than fall on my own axe! Suppose your cousin Grunnos was missing. What would you do?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus snorted. "Speak not of that wastrel, but be glad he has many older brothers to be king before him should good Kanlore pass."[PARAGRAPH:1]"But?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"But... were his fate that of Luach, I should dig to Mammon's hell if it would find him. But not if my king forbid it! I know the bonds of kinship, but what of kith? Do you abandon your duty and your friends for a mad search? The winter will take you too, and what will that accomplish?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros rose, placing the hammer and chisel back on the altar as he turned to leave. "My duty has others to attend it, and my friends as well, dear Arturus. But Luach Fir is alone. If our friendship has meaning to you, you will not hinder me."[PARAGRAPH:2]It had not been easy getting to the surface. No one had been allowed to leave since Kandros' cousin Luach had gone to study the surface. Winter still raged, as it had for more than six generations, but young Luach was undaunted, and had petitioned Kanlore for leave to explore the harsh surface regardless of the danger. Supplies were slim in the Underhome. Their stores of black powder had been exhausted so long ago that the last Dwarves who would even recognize it had passed away, and expansion of the Underhome was tedious work with pick and hammer. Spices had run out early in Kandros youth, and the pork and tubers his children fed on left eating a chore. So Luach had at last been allowed to take another appraisal of the state of the bleak surface, but Kanlore's hesitancy had been proven right when Luach did not return for months. No one was permitted to leave now, meaning Kandros had to sneak past guards in the dark, and would be ill regarded if he returned at all.[PARAGRAPH:1]The exit to the Dwarven home was sealed with a massive stone door, and Kandros exhausted himself prying it open, even using his pick as a lever. He bravely stepped from the familiar darkness of his home into the unknown darkness of the Age of Ice. He emerged from the hillside, setting foot on grass. Not snow, and the night air was crisp but lacked the biting chill he had been warned of all his life. He stretched out his arms, marveling at the open space all around, and broke into a run down the hillside. Running was foolhardy in the Underhome. Low ceilings, sharp turns, and sudden drops presented challenges that demanded a careful step, but here there was freedom.[PARAGRAPH:1]And danger. Kandros found himself surrounded by large, grey dogs. He realized he had nearly charged into the den of these animals, and they cared little for his reason for being there. His hand axe was out barely before the first leapt for his throat. It was his blade that found the wolves throat first. And the skull of the next wolf to charge him. He became a whirl of axe and torch until the last beast lay dead or dying.[PARAGRAPH:1]So many animals... how could there be prey enough for a pack of this size in the wasteland he had been lead to believe the surface was? Then he noticed something half buried in the wolves' den. He walked over slowly, pulling the body from the debris, his breath held tight. Unmistakably the body of a dwarf, though it was a gruesome sight to see after the wolves had fed on its flesh. The pattern of the clothing marked it as a clansman of his, and Kandros knew he had found his cousin. He rent his beard and wept over the body. After a time he gathered the gathered up the body, intending to bury it within sight of the Underhome. Then he noticed ... the left shoulder blade was shorn in two. Not broken, but split with a clean cut. He examined it carefully. Luach had been hit from behind by a battle axe, almost certainly by someone of his height.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Murder..." he whispered to the night.[PARAGRAPH:1]He was answered, not by the night, but by a cloaked dwarf holding a Mithril axe directly behind him. "He, like you, wouldn't leave well enough alone, Fir." The dwarf swung his axe for the kill, but then dropped it clumsily and gurgled blood.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kandros!" Arturus shouted from the entrance of the wolf den, his axe embedded in the neck of the cloaked dwarf. The two friends embraced.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I found Luach, and his killer I think," Kandros informed his friend.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus Thorne went pale. "And I found my cousin as well." The dwarf he had killed was the prince Grunnos.[PARAGRAPH:2]The last time Kandros had been in the King's Hall, he had petitioned for permission to search out his cousin. Now, it was with accusation that the King's own son had killed his kin. Were it not for the well respected Arturus beside him, he would have been called a murderer, and worse, a name-killer for making accusations against Grunnos. Kanlore stood from his throne and faced the two Dwarves, his beard reaching nearly his full height. His eldest son and his honor guard flanked him; otherwise the chamber was empty. "You defied the laws of your people, Kandros Fir. The surface world is a harsh land ruled by a dread god and his legion of giants. It was treason to leave."[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros did not interrupt his king, but rebuked him when he had finished. "The ice is long gone, my liege, and Winter has passed. Your laws made my people's home a prison, and it was based on lies!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tis true, uncle," spoke Arturus. "Your scouts have surely misled you for years!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Not years, foolish Arturus. The ravages of Winter were real enough 10 months ago."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You knew?" gasped Kandros.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, but your cousin had to die to keep this secret. Even with the Winter King gone, the surface world is a vicious realm. Elves and humans wield magic that can destroy any warrior. Greed makes warfare or subjugation unending. Here my people are safe, and here they shall remain."[PARAGRAPH:1]"We are not your children, to be locked away for our own protection. Let the Khazad go forth and prove our worth, not cower in stone chambers like men already dead! You have stolen our spirit, and I name you coward, Kanlore, be it treason or no!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Enough! Guards, kill them!" The honor guard readied their axes, but looked around, uncertain.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are you insane, father? These men did no wrong. You did, and you shamed yourself and your kin." Prince Toril sliced off his braided beard and threw it in the king's face. "You shall have no allegiance when word of this perfidy reaches beyond this hall. Nor shall any of your line." The guards heeded his words, and lowered their weapons.[PARAGRAPH:1]"So you too turn. My son, hear this-when the last dwarf is hunted down, felled by lance or wand, be it your name that they curse with their last breath!" Kanlore staggered from the royal hall, towards the surface that he so feared and into exile.[PARAGRAPH:1]The prince turned to Arturus. "Cousin, you are my closest living kin not of my father. It is you the people shall follow."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus turned to his old friend. "Kandros, could you not have left this alone as I so asked? Because of you I have become kin-slayer and usurper."[PARAGRAPH:1]"What? This foul scene was Kanlore's doing!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"What I say now I say with heavy heart but the weight of the crown. You sought the surface world, and there you must go, banished from the Underhome. Take provisions, take your clan, take all who would seek their fortune above. This is not justice, but there will not be order in the Underhome while a traitor walks its halls, and you did break the royal decree when you left." Arturus sighed. "As did I, when I followed you. Toril, if you will not be king, then be my viceroy, and I shall take the crown to the surface as punishment for my own disobedience, with whoever will follow me."[PARAGRAPH:1]And so the King of the Dwarves left the Underhome for the first time in over 300 years, and at the same time the Fir clan and their allies parted with their allies to forge their own Khazad nation. The two men who had been closest of fiends grew to be the fiercest of rivals for much of the last Age.</English>
		<French>Arturus trouva son ami à la lueur de la bougie. Les torches étaient interdites dans cette chambre sainte, loin dans les entrailles de Maisonterre. La suie et la fumée qu'elles produisent obscurcissaient les runes gravées dans les rangées de piliers, recouvrant les noms et les faits des ancêtres nains honorés. Les anciens nains qui gardaient ces sites, gravant de nouvelles histoires et apprenant aux autres à les lire étaient appelés officiellement les Gardiens des Runes, mais en général surnommés les 'Mains des Prophéties'. Louchant à la lumière des bougies qui leur dérobait si souvent la vue, ils avaient appris à lire chaque mot et lettre avec les mains. Kandros Fir etait à la fin de la section de son Clan dans la Salle des Runes, un ciseau à la main.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Je savais que je te trouverais là," dit Arturus tout en s'agenouillant à ses côtés.[PARAGRAPH:1]"J'étais son parent le plus proche. Je dois ajouter son nom et ses actes à notre histoire."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bien sûr, mon vieil ami. Mais ce n'est pas la seule chose que tu comptes faire, n'est ce pas ?" Kandros baissa la tête.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Je suis fidèle à mon roi, par mes os, je suis loyal."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mais ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Je ne peux pas plus abandonner ma famille que choir sous ma propre hache ! Imagine si ton couson Grunnos était porté disparu. Que ferais-tu ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus grogna. "Ne parle pas de ce prodigue, mais estime toi heureux qu'il ait de nombreux frères ainés prétendants au trone avant lui si notre bon Kanlore devait mourir."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mais ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mais si son destin devait être le même que Luach, je creuserais jusqu'à l'enfer de Mammon pour le retrouver. Mais pas si mon roi me l'interdit ! Je connais les liens de parenté, mais qu'en est-il des amis ? Abandonnes-tu ton devoir et tes amis pour une folle quête ? L'hiver te prendra aussi, et qu'auras-tu alors prouvé ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros se leva, remettant le marteau et le ciseau sur l'autel tandis qu'il partait. "Mon devoir a d'autres pour s'en occuper, de même que mes amis, cher Arturus. Mais Luach Fir est seul. Si notre amitié a un sens pour toi, tu ne me gêneras pas."[PARAGRAPH:2]Ça n'avait pas été simple de parvenir à la surface. Personne n'avait été autorisé à partir depuis que Luach, le cousin de Kandros, était parti pour étudier la surface. L'hiver faisait encore rage, comme il le faisait depuis plus de six générations, mais le jeune Luach n'avait pas froid aux yeux et avait harcelé Kanlore pour pouvoir partir et explorer la rude surface qu'importe le danger. Le ravitaillement était chose rare à Maisonterre. Leurs stocks de poudre noire avait été épuisés depuis si longtemps que les derniers nains qui auraient pu ne serait-ce que l'identifier étaient morts, et l'expansion de Maisonterre était fastidieuse à l'aide de pioches et de marteaux. Les épices s'étaient épuisées dans la jeunesse de Kandros, et le porc et les tubercules restants pour nourrir ses enfants faisaient des repas une corvée. Ainsi Luach avait été autorisé à faire une nouvelle éaluation de l'état de la froide surface, mais les craintes de Kanlore s'étaient avérées lorsque Luach n'était pas revenu pendant des mois. Aujourd'hui, plus personne n'était autorisé à partir, impliquant que Kandros devrait se faufiler au travers des gardes dans le noir, et serait méprisé s'il revenait jamais.[PARAGRAPH:1]La sortie de la maison Naine était scellée par un porte massive en pierre, et Kandros s'épuisa en tentant de l'ouvrir, utilisant même sa pioche comme levier. Il passa bravement des ténèbres familières de sa maison aux ténèbres inconnues de l'Âge de Glace. Il émergea sur la pente de la colline, posant le pied sur l'herbe. Pas de neige, et l'air nocturne était froid mais ne possédait par ce froid mordant dont il avait été mis en garde toute sa vie. Il étira ses bras, s'émerveillant de l'espace libre tout autour, et se lança dans une course vers le bas de la colline. Courir était téméraire à Maisonterre. Plafonds bas, virages serrés, et gouffres soudains représentaient des défis qui requiéraient un pas prudent, mais ici se trouvait la liberté.[PARAGRAPH:1]Et le danger. Kandros se retrouva encerclé par de grands chiens gris. Il se rendit compte qu'il s'était précipité dans la tanière de ces animaux, et qu'ils se fichaient des raisons de sa présence. Sa hache sortit à peine avant que le premier lui saute à la gorge. Ce fut sa lame qui rencontra la première la gorge du loup. Et le crâne du second à le charger. Il devint une tornade de hache et continua jusqu'à ce que la dernière bête gît morte ou mourante.[PARAGRAPH:1]Tant d'animaux... Comment pouvait-il y avoir assez de proies pour une meute de cette taille dans les terres désolées que lui avaient été présentées la surface ? Puis il remarqua quelque chose à moitié enterré dans la tanière des loups. Il le surplomba puis dégagea doucement le corps des débris, retenant son souffle. Sans soute possible le corps d'un nain, bien que ce fût une vision hideuse après ce que les loups avaient fait à sa chair. Les vêtements l'identifiaient comme un membre de son clan, et Kandros sut qu'il avait retrouvé son cousin. Il caressa sa barbe et pleura sur le corps. Au bout d'un moment, il rassembla les parties du corps, comptant l'enterrer en vue de Maisonterre. Puis il remarqua... l'épaule gauche était coupée en deux. Pas brisée, mais coupée nette. Il l'eximina avec attention. Luach avait été touché dans le dos par une hache de bataille, certainement par une personne de sa taille.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Meurtre..." chuchota-t-il dans la nuit.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il eut une réponse, non pas par la nuit, mais par un nain encapuchonné tenant une hache en Mithril juste derrière lui. "Comme toi, seul, il ne vivait pas assez bien, Fir." Le nain abattit sa hache pour tuer, mais la lâcha maladroitement et se mit à gragouiller du sang.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kandros !" cria Arturus depuis l'entrée de la tanière des nains, sa hache enfoncée dans la nuque du nain encapuchonné. Les deux amis s'étreignirent.[PARAGRAPH:1]"J'ai trouvé Luach, ainsi que son meurtrier je pense," dit Kandros à son ami.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus Thorne devint pâle. "Et j'ai également trouvé mon cousin." Le nain qu'il avait tué et le prince Grunnos.[PARAGRAPH:2]La dernière fois que Kandros avait été dans le Hall Royal, il demandait la permission d'aller chercher son cousin. Aujourd'hui, c'était avec l'accusation que le propre fils du Roi avait tué sa famille. S'il n'y avait pas eu le respecté Arturus pour le soutenir, il aurait été appelé meurtrier, et pire, un tueur-de-nom pour ses accusations envers Grunnos. Kanlore se leva de son trône et fit face aux deux nains, sa barbe touchant presque le sol. Son fils aîné et ses thanes le flanquaient ; sinon la chambre était vide. "Tu as défié les lois de ton peuple, Kandros Fir. Le monde de la surface est une terre inhospitalière dirigée par un dieu redoutable et ses légions de géants. C'était une trahison que de partir.'[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros n'interrompit pas son roi, mais le contredit quand il eut fini. "La glace a disparu depuis longtemps, mon seigneur, et l'Hiver s'est terminé. Vos lois ont fait de la maison de mon peuple une prison, et basé sur des mensonges !"[PARAGRAPH:1]"C'vrai, mon oncle," acquiesca Arturus. "Vos éclaireurs vous ont sûrement trompés pendant des années !"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Pas des années, mon pauvre Arturus. Les ravages de l'Hiver étaient encore bien présents il y a 10 mois."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Vous saviez ?" s'étrangla Kandros.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oui, mais ton cousin devait mourir pour garder ça secret. Même avec le Roi de l'Hiver disparu, le monde de la surface est un royaume vicieux. Elfes et humains sont porteurs de magie qui peuvent détruire n'importe quel guerrier. L'avidité rend la guerre et les soumissions sans fin. Ici mon peuple est en sécurité, et ici ils doivent rester."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Nous ne sommes pas vos enfants, devant être enfermés pour notre propre protection. Laissez les khazadors aller de l'avant et prouver notre valeur, et non pas se terrer dans des chambres de pierre comme des hommes déjà morts ! Vous nous avez volé notre âme, et je vous accuse de couardise, Kanlore, que ce soit de la trahison ou non !"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Assez ! Guardes, tuez-les !" Les thanes préparèrent leurs haches, mais regardèrent autour d'eux, incertains.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Etes-vous devenu fou, mon père ? Ces hommes n'ont rien fait de mal. Vous en avez fait, et vous vous êtes couvert de honte, vous et voter famille." Le prince Toril se sectionna sa barbe tressée et la jeta au visage du toi. "Vous n'aurez plus aucune allégeance quand ces mots si perfides sortiront de ces murs. Ni personne de votre lignée." Les thanes acquiescèrent et baissèrent leurs armes.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Et maintenant c'est toi qui me tourne le dos. Mon fils, écoute moi : quand le dernier nain sera abattu, transpercé par une lance ou une flèche, que ce soit ton nom qu'ils maudiront dans leur dernier souffle !" Kanlore tituba depuis le Hall Royal vers la surface tant redoutée et vers son exil.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le prince se tourna vers Arturus. "Cousin, tu es ma famille vivante la plus proche qui ne soi pas de mon père. C'est quoi que le peuple doit suivre."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus se tourna vers son vieil ami. "Kandros, tu n'aurais pas pu laisser tomber comme je te l'avais demandé ? À cause de toi je suis devenu un régicide et un usurpateur."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Quoi ? Cet épisode méprisable était l'&#156;uvre de Kanlore !"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ce que je dis maintenant, je le dis le c&#156;ur lourd mais avec le poids de la couronne. Tu courais après le monde de la surface, alors tu iras, banni de Maisonterre. Prends des provisions, emmène ton clan, emmène tous ceux qui souhaitent trouver fortune là-haut. Ce n'est pas la justice, mais il ne pourra pas y avoir d'ordre à Maisonterre tant qu'un traitre parcourra ses couloirs, et tu as brisé le traité royal quand tu es parti." Arturus soupira. "Tout comme moi, quand je t'ai suivi. Toril, si tu ne veux pas être roi, alors soit mon viceroi, et j'emmènerai la couronne à la surface comme cha^timent pour ma propre désobéissance, avec quiconque voudra me suivre."[PARAGRAPH:1]Ainsi le Roi des Nains quitta Maisonterre pour la première fois depuis 300 ans, tandis que le clan Fir et leurs alliés s'en allaient forger leur propre nation Khazadore. Les deux hommes qui avaient été les plus proches amis devirent les pires rivaux du dernier Âge.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Arturus fand seinen Freund im Kerzenlicht. Fackeln waren verboten in dieser heiligen Kammer, tief in der Unterwelt. Der Ruß und Rauch, den sie abgaben, bedeckte die in die Reihen von Säulen eingemeißelten Runen, die von den Namen und Taten der ehrwürdigen Vorfahren der Zwerge handelten. Die alten Zwerge, die diese Stätte hüteten, dort neue Geschichten eingravierten und andere lehrten, sie zu lesen, wurden offiziell 'Runenwächter' genannt. Geläufiger war jedoch 'Handseher'. Das stete Spähen durch den Kerzenschein raubte ihnen ihr Augenlicht, also erlernten sie jedes Wort und jeden Buchstaben nur mit Hilfe ihrer Finger zu lesen. Kandros Fir war am Ende des Abschnitts seines Clans in der Runenhalle, den Meißel noch in der Hand.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich wusste, ich würde Euch hier finden", sagte Arturus, während er sich neben ihn kniete.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich bin sein nächster Verwandter. Ich muss seinen Namen und seine Taten unserer Geschichte hinzufügen."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Natürlich, alter Freund. Aber das ist nicht dein ganzer Plan, oder irre ich mich?" Kandros neigte seinen Kopf.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich bin dem König treu, bei meinen Gebeinen, ich bin loyal."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Aber?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich falle eher in meine eigene Axt, als meine Familie aufzugeben! Wenn Euer Vetter Grunnos vermisst werden würde. Was würdet Ihr tun?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus schnaubte. "Sprecht nicht von diesem Verschwender, sondern seid glücklich, dass er viele ältere Brüder hat, die vor ihm König werden, sollte der gute Kanlore dahinscheiden.."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Aber?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Aber ... wäre sein Schicksal das von Luach, sollte ich mich bis in Mammons Hölle graben, damit es ihm zuteil wird. Aber nicht, wenn mein König es verbietet! Ich kenne die Fesseln der Blutsverwandtschaft, aber was ist mit Euren Kindern? Gebt Ihr Eure Pflichten und Freunde für eine verrückte Suche auf? Der Winter wird auch Euch holen, und wofür?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros erhob sich, legte Hammer und Meißel zurück auf den Altar, um sich Richtung Ausgang zu wenden. "Meinen Pflichten können sich andere widmen, und meinen Freunden ebenso, lieber Arturus. Aber  Luach Fir ist allein. Wenn Euch unsere Freundschaft etwas bedeutet, werdet Ihr mich nicht hindern."[PARAGRAPH:2]Es war nicht einfach zur Oberfläche zu gelangen. Niemandem war es erlaubt, seit Kandros' Vetter Luach aufbrach um die Oberfläche zu studieren. Der Winter wütete immer noch, wie er es seit sechs Generationen getan hatte, aber der junge Luach war unverdrossen und hatte Kanlore ersucht, gehen zu dürfen um die unwirsche Oberfläche zu erforschen ohne Rücksicht auf die Gefahren. Die Vorräte waren mager in der Unterwelt. Ihre Schwarzpulver-Lager waren schon so lange erschöpft, dass die letzten Zwerge, die sie überhaupt erkennen könnten dahingeschieden sind, und der Ausbau der Unterwelt war mühsam mit Pickel und Hammer. Gewürze gingen schon früh in Kandros' Jugend aus, und das Schweinefleisch und die Wurzelknollen, mit denen seine Kinder ernährt wurden, machten aus der Ernährung eine lästige Pflicht. Also wurde Luach letztendlich gewährt, eine weitere Einschätzung des Zustands der Oberfläche vorzunehmen, doch stellte sich Kanlores Unsicherheit als berechtigt heraus, da Luach seit Monaten nicht zurückgekehrt war. Niemandem war es nun erlaubt zu gehen, was bedeutete, dass Kandros sich im Dunkeln an Wachen vorbeischleichen musste und in Verruf geriet, sollte er zurückkehren. [PARAGRAPH:1]Der Ausgang der Zwergenheimat war durch eine massive Steintür versiegelt und Kandros verausgabte sich vollkommen dabei, sie mit seiner Spitzhacke als Hebel aufzustemmen. Tapfer schritt er aus der vertrauten Dunkelheit seiner Heimat in die unbekannte Dunkelheit der Eiszeit. Er kam an einem Abhang zum Vorschein, die Füße im Gras. Kein Schnee. Die Nachtluft war frostig, aber vermisste die beißende Kälte, vor der er sein gesamtes Leben lang gewarnt wurde. Er streckte die Arme aus, staunte über den freien Raum, der ihn umgab, und sprintete den Abhang hinunter. Rennen war töricht in der Unterwelt. Niedrige Decken, scharfe Kurven und  plötzliche Senken waren Herausforderungen, die einen vorsichtigen Gang verlangten. Aber hier war Freiheit.[PARAGRAPH:1]Und Gefahr. Kandros fand sich umzingelt von großen, grauen Wölfen wieder. Er erkannte, dass er fast direkt in den Bau dieser Tiere gestürmt wäre und sie kümmert sich wenig um seine Motive. Kaum bevor ihm der erste an die Kehle sprang hatte er seine Handaxt hervor geholt. Doch seine Klinge fand die Kehle des Wolfes zuerst. Und den Schädel des nächsten Wolfes, der ihn angriff. Er wurde zu einem Wirbel aus Axt und Fackel bis die letzte Bestie tot oder sterbend am Boden lag...[PARAGRAPH:1]So viele Tiere... wie konnte es genug Beute für ein Rudel dieser Größe in der Einöde geben, die die Oberfläche angeblich sein sollte? Dann entdeckte er etwas, halb vergraben im der Wolfsbau. Er schlich langsam hin, zog den Körper aus dem Geröll und hielt den Atem an. Unverkennbar die Leiche eines Zwergs, auch wenn es ein grausamer Anblick war, nachdem sich die Wölfe an dem Fleisch satt gefressen hatten. Das Muster der Kleidung verriet den Toten als ein Mitglied seines Clans und Kandros war klar, dass er seinen Vetter gefunden hatte. Er zerriss sich den Bart und weinte über dem leblosen Körper. Nach einiger Zeit sammelte er die Leiche in der Absicht auf, sie in Sichtweite zum Eingang zur Zwergenwelt zu begraben. Dann bemerkte er es ... das linke Schulterblatt war entzwei getrennt. Nicht gebrochen, sondern getrennt mit einem sauberen Schnitt. Er untersuchte es vorsichtig. Luach wurde von hinten von einer Kriegsaxt getroffen, nahezu sicher von jemandem seiner Größe.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mord ..." flüsterte er in die Nacht.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er bekam keine Antwort von der Nacht, aber von einem verhüllten Zwerg mit einer Mithrilaxt direkt hinter ihm. "Er würde es, genau wie ihr, einfach nicht gut sein lassen, Fir!" Der Zwerg schwang seine Axt zum Töten, doch ließ sie plump fallen und gurgelte Blut...[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kandros!" rief Arturus vom Eingang der Wolfshöhle, die Axt noch im Nacken des verhüllten Zwerges steckend. Die zwei Freunde umarmten sich.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich habe Luach gefunden, und seinen Mörder ebenfalls denke ich," informierte Kandros seinen Freund.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus Thorne wurde blass. "Und ich habe meinen Vetter auch gefunden." Der Zwerg, den er tötete, war Prinz Grunnos.[PARAGRAPH:2]Das letzte Mal als Kandros im Königssaal war bat er um Erlaubnis nach seinem Vetter zu suchen. Diesmal mit der Anschuldigung, dass des Königs eigener Sohn seinen Verwandten ermordet hatte. Wäre nicht der hoch angesehene Arturus an seiner Seite, wäre er als Mörder beschuldigt worden und, noch schlimmer, als Verleumder aufgrund der Anklage gegen Grunnos. Kanlore stand vor seinem Thron den zwei Zwergen gegenüber, den Bart fast bis zum Boden. Sein ältester Sohn und seine Ehrenwache flankierten ihn; ansonsten war der Raum leer. "Du hast dich den Gesetzen deines Volkes widersetzt, Kandros Fir. Die Welt an der Oberfläche ist eine brutales Land regiert von einem Gott des Schreckens und seine Legion von Riesen. Zu gehen war Hochverrat!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros unterbrach seinen König nicht, sondern wies ihn zurecht nachdem er fertig war. "Das Eis ist lange fort, mein Lehnsheer, und der Winter ist vorbei. Eure Gesetze machten die Heimat meines Volkes zu einem Gefängnis, und alles beruht auf einer Lüge!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Es ist wahr, Onkel", sprach Arturus. "Eure Kundschafter haben euch jahrelang getäuscht!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Nicht Jahre, dummer Arturus. Das verheerende Wüten des Winters war vor zehn Monaten noch real."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ihr wusstet davon?" stieß Kandros hervor.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ja, und dein Vetter musste sterben um dieses Geheimnis zu bewahren. Selbst wenn der Winterkönig abgetreten ist, ist die Oberfläche ein boshaftes Reich. Elfen und Menschen üben Magie aus, die jeden Krieger zerstören kann. Raffgier macht Krieg und Unterwerfung endlos. Hier ist mein Volk sicher, und hier sollen sie bleiben."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Wir sind nicht Eure Kinder, die weggesperrt werden müssen zu ihrer eigenen Sicherheit. Lasst die Khazad vorwärts und beweist unseren Wert, und hockt nicht in Steinkammern wie die Toten! Ihr habt unsere Seele gestohlen, und ich nenne Euch einen Feigling, Kanlore, sei es Verrat oder nicht!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Genug! Wachen, tötet sie!" Die Ehrenwache machte ihre Äxte bereit aber sah sich unsicher um.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Seid Ihr wahnsinnig, Vater? Diese Männer haben nichts Falsches getan. Ihr schon und Ihr beschämt euch selbst und eure Sippe." Prinz Toril schnitt seinen geflochtenen Bart ab und warf ihn dem König ins Gesicht. "Ihr sollt keine Treue erwarten, wenn das Wort dieser Niedertracht diese Halle verlässt. Ihr und niemand Eurer Linie." Die Wachen beherzigten seine Worte und senkten ihre Waffen.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ihr also auch... mein Sohn, höre mir zu, wenn die letzten Zwerge gejagt wurden, von einem Speer oder Zauberstab getötet, dann sei es dein Name, den sie mit ihrem letzten Atemzug verfluchen!" Kanlore schwankte aus der königlichen Halle in Richtung Oberfläche, die er so fürchtete, ins Exil.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Prinz wand sich Arturus zu. "Vetter, Ihr seid mein nächster Verwandter, abgesehen von meinem Vater. Ihr seid es, dem das Volk folgen sollte."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus drehte sich zu seinem alten Freund. "Kandros, hättet ihr das ganze nicht unbehelligt lassen können, wie ich Euch gebeten habe? Wegen euch bin ich ein Blutsmörder und Usurpator geworden."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was? Dieser schändliche Vorfall war Kanlores Tat!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was ich nun sage, sage ich schweren Herzens, doch unter der Last der Krone. Ihr suchtet nach der Oberfläche und dort müsst ihr hingehen, verbannt aus der Unterwelt. Nehmt Vorräte, nehmt Euren Clan, nehmt alle, die ihre Zukunft dort oben sehen. Dies ist nicht gerecht, aber es wird keine Ordnung in der Unterwelt geben solange ein Verräter in diesen Hallen wandelt, und Ihr braucht das königliche Dekret um zu gehen." Arturus seufzte. "Genau wie ich, als ich Euch folgte. Toril, wenn Ihr nicht auf den Thron wollt, dann seid mein Vizekönig und ich trage die Krone zur Oberfläche als Strafe für meinen eigenen Ungehorsam, wer auch immer mir folgt."[PARAGRAPH:1]Und so verließ der König der Zwerge die Unterwelt das erste Mal nach 300 Jahren und zugleich ging auch der Fir-Clan und seine Verbündeten um ihre eigene Khazad-Nation zu schmieden. Die beiden Männer, die beste Freunde waren, wurden zu den erbittertsten Rivalen für den Großteil des letzten Zeitalters.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Arturus trovò il suo amico con la luce della candela. Le torcie erano proibite in queste sacre stanze, nelle profondità del Sottosuolo. La fuliggine e il fumo che generavano avrebbero oscurato le rune incise sulle colonne li presenti, coprendo i nomi e le gesta degli onorati antenati dei Nani. Gli antichi nani che si prendevano cura di questi luoghi, che incidevano nuove storie e inesgnavano agli altri a leggerle, erano chiamati Custodi delle Rune ufficialmente ma venivano chiamati più comunemente 'Veggenti delle Mani'. Il lavorare sempre alla tenue luce delle candele li aveva invariabilmente danneggiato la vista, per questo avevano imparato ogni parola e lettera col tatto. Kandros Fir era alla fine della sezione del suo Clan nella Sala delle Rune con lo scalpello in mano.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sapevo che ti avrei trovato qui," Arturus disse inginocchiandosi vicino a lui.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ero il suo parente più stretto. Devo aggiungere il suo nome e le sue gesta alla nostra storia."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ovviamente, vecchio amico. Ma non è l'unica cosa che stai pianificando, nevvero?" Kandros chinò la testa.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sono fedele al nostro re, fin nelle ossa, sono fedele."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ma?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non posso abbandonare la mia famiglia nello stesso modo in cui non posso cadere sulla mia ascia! Immagina se tuo cugino Grunnos fosse disperso. Che cosa faresti?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus sbuffò. "Non parlarmi di quel buono a nulla, ma sii contento che ha molti fratelli più grandi che diventeranno re prima di lui nel caso il buon Kanlore ci lasciasse."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ma?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ma... se avesse avuto lo stesso destino di Luach, scaverei sino all'inferno di Mammon se farlo mi permetterebbe di ritrovarlo. Ma non se il mio re me lo proibisce! Comprendo i legami di famiglia, ma che dire di kith? Abbandoni il tuo dovere e i tuoi amici per una folle ricerca? L'inverno prenderebbe pure te, e cosa avrai ottenuto?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros si alzò, ripose il martello e lo scalpello sull'altare e si voltò per andarsene. "Il mio dovere ha altri che se ne possono occupare, e i miei amici ugualmente, caro Arturus. Ma Luach Fir è da solo. Se la nostra amicizia ha un qualche valore per te, non mi ostacolerai."[PARAGRAPH:2]Non era stato facile raggiungere la superfice. A nessuno era permesso uscire da quando il cugino di Kandros, Luach, era andato a studiare la superfice. L'inverno continuava a imperversare nello stesso modo che aveva fatto per altre sei generazioni, ma il giovane Luach era imperterrito, e aveva chesto a Kanlore di poter uscire per esplorare l'aspra superficie non curante del pericolo. Le provviste erano scarse nel Sottosuolo. Le loro scorte di polvere nera si erano esaurite cosi tanto tempo fa che gli ultimi nani che avrebbero potuto riconoscerla erano morti, e l'espansione del Sottosuolo era ora un lavoro tedioso di piccone e martello. Le spezie erano finite durante l'infanzia di Kandros, e il maiale e le patate che i suoi figli mangiavano non rendeva il mangiare esattamente invitante. Quindi alla fine Luach ottenne il permesso per andare a fare una stima della desolata superficie, ma l'esitazione di Kanlore nel dare il permesso si dimostrò sensata quando Luach non tornò per mesi. Nessuno poteva uscire ora, il che significava che Kandros avrebbe dovuto superare di nascosto le guardie al buio, e che sarebbe stato malvisto se avesse mai fatto ritorno.[PARAGRAPH:1]L'uscita era bloccata da una massiccia porta di pietra, e Kandros si sfinì nell'aprirla, perfino usando il suo piccone come leva. Passò coraggiosamente dall'oscurità familiare della sua casa a quella sconosciuta dell'Era del Ghiaccio. Uscì sul lato di una collina, calpensando dell'erba. Niente neve, e l'aria della notte era frizzante, ma gli mancava il freddo pungente da cui era stato messo in guardia per tutta la vita. Estese le braccia, meravigliandosi di tutto lo spazio aperto intorno a lui e si mise a correre giù dalla collina. Correre era imprudente nel Sottosuolo. Soffitti bassi, curve strette, e baratri improvvisi richiedevano un passo attento, ma qui c'era la libertà.[PARAGRAPH:1]E il pericolo. Kandros scoprì di essere circondato da dei grossi cani grigi. Capì che era quasi entrato di corsa nella tana di questi animali, e poco importava loro quali erano le ragioni della sua presenza. La sua ascia era appena uscita dal fodero quando il primo provò a saltargli addosso. Fu la sua lama a colpire per prima. Per poi colpire il teschio del secondo lupo che gli si era avvicinato. Divenne un turbine di ascia e torcia fino a quando l'ultima delle bestie non era morta o morente.[PARAGRAPH:1]Cosi tanti animali... come potevano esserci prede sufficenti per un branco di tale grandezza nelle terre desolate che era stato portato a credere fosse la superficie? Poi notò qualcosa mezzo sepolta nella tana dei lupi. Gli si avvicinò lentamente, estraendola dai detriti col fiato sospeso. Inconfondibilmente il corpo di un nano, benché non fosse una bella vista dopo che i lupi si erano cibati della carne. Lo stile dei vestiti lo identificava come un membro del suo clan, e Kandros capì che aveva trovato suo cugino. Si strappò la barba e pianse sul corpo. Dopo un pò raccolse i resti del corpo, con l'intenzione di seppellirlo in vista del Sottosuolo. Poi notò una cosa... la scapola sinistra era tagliata in due. Non rotta, ma con un taglio netto. La esaminò accuratamente. Luach era stato colpito da dietro con un'ascia da battaglia, quasi sicuramente da uno della sua altezza.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Un omicidio..." sussurrò alla notte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ottenne risposta, non dalla notte, ma da un nano ammantato che impugnava un'ascia in Mithril dietro di lui. "Lui, come te, non è andato lontano da solo, Fir". Il nano iniziò a vibrare il colpo per poi cadere a terra goffamente e sputare sangue.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kandros!" Arturus urlò dall'entrata della tana dei lupi con la sua ascia incastrata nel collo del nano ammantato. I due amici si abbracciarono.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ho trovato Luach, e il suo assassino credo" Kandros disse all'amico.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus Thorne impallidì. "E io ho trovato il mio di cugino". Il nano che aveva ucciso era il principe Grunnos.[PARAGRAPH:2]L'ultima volta che Kandros era stato nella Sala del Re era per chiedere il permesso di andare a cercare il cugino. Adesso vi era per accusare il figlio del Re di aver ucciso dei familiari. Se non fosse stato per il tanto rispettato Arturus al suo fianco sarebbe stato etichettato come un omicida e, ancora peggio, un uccisore di nomi per aver formulato delle accuse contro Grunnos. Kanlore si alzò dal trono e andò davanti ai due nani, la sua barba era lunga quasi quanto lui. Il figlio più grande e la sua guardia d'onore gli stavano a fianco; oltre loro non vi era nessuno. "Hai disubbidito alle leggi del tuo popolo, Kandros Fir. Il mondo della superficie è una terra crudele governata da un temibile dio e dalla sua legione di giganti. Andarsene è stato un atto di tradimento".[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros non interruppe il suo re, ma lo criticò una volta che aveva finito. "Il ghiaccio è sparito da tempo, mio signore, e l'Inverno è passato. Le vostre leggi hanno reso la casa del mio popolo una prigione, ed erano tutte basate su bugie!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"È vero zio" disse Arturus. "I tuoi ricoglitori ti hanno sicuramente ingannato per anni!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non anni, stolto Arturus. La desolazione dell'Inverno era abbastanza reale 10 mesi fa".[PARAGRAPH:1]"Lo sapevi?" disse Kandros.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Si, ma tuo cugino doveva morire per mantenere il segreto. Anche senza il Re dell'Inverno il mondo in superficie è un luogo pericoloso. Elfi ed umani utilizzano magie che possono distruggere qualsiasi guerriero. L'avidità rende la guerra o l'oppressione senza fine. Qui il mio popolo è al sicuro, e qui rimarrà".[PARAGRAPH:1]"Noi non siamo i tuoi figli, che puoi rinchiuderci da qualche parte per la nostra salvaguardia. Lascia che i Khazad progrediscano e dimostrino il loro valore, non nascondendoli in stanze di pietra come fosserò già morti! Ci hai privato del nostro spirito e ti chaimo codardo, Kanlore, si tratti di tradimento o no!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Basta! Guardie, uccideteli!" Le guardie d'onore impugnarono le loro asce, ma si guardavano intorno, incerte.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Siete impazzito, padre? Non hanno fatto nulla di sbagliato. Tu lo hai fatto, e hai disonorato te e la tua stirpe." Il principe Toril si tagliò la barba intrecciata e la lanciò in faccia al re. "Nessuno ti sarà fedele quando le voci della tua perfidia usciranno da questa stanza. Come pure la tua stirpe". Le guardie ascoltarono le sue parole ed abbassarono le armi.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Quindi anche tu schieri contro di me. Figlio mio ascolta bene, quando l'ultimo nano verrà abbattuto, da una lancia o una bacchetta, sarà il tuo nome ad essere maledetto col loro ultimo respiro!" Kanlore barcollò fuori dalla sala regale e verso la superficie che tanto temeva in esilio.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il pincipe si rivolse ad Arturus. "Cugino, tu sei il mio familiare più prossimo che non discende da mio padre. Sei tu colui che il nostro popolo seguirà."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus si voltò verso il suo vecchio amico. "Kandros, non potevi lasciare le cose come stavano come ti avevo chiesto? A causa tua sono diventato un uccisore di parenti e un'usurpatore."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Cosa? Questa situazione è opera di Kanlore!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Quello che sto per dire lo dico col cuore pesante e il peso della corona. Hai cercato il mondo di superficie, e li devi andare, bandito dal Sottosuolo. Prendi provviste, prendi il tuo clan, prendi tutti quelli che vogliono cercar fortuna li sopra. Questa non è giustizia, ma non vi sarà ordine nel Sottosuolo fin quando un traditore cammina nelle sue sale, e tu hai infranto il decreto reale quando sei uscito." Arturus sospirò. "Come ho fatto io quando ti ho seguito. Toril, se non sarai il mio re, allora sii il mio viceré, e io porterò la mia corona in superficie come punnizione per la mia disubbidienza, con chiunque mi vorrà seguire."[PARAGRAPH:1]E cosi il Re dei Nani lasciò il Sottosuolo per la prima volta in più 300 anni, allo stesso tempo il clan Fir e i loro alleati partirono per creare la loro nazione Khazad. E cosi i due nani, amici stretti sino ad ora, divennerò accaniti rivali per la maggior parte dell'ultima Era.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Arturus found his friend by candlelight. Torches were forbidden in this hallowed chamber, deep in the Underhome. The soot and smoke they gave off obscured the runes carved into the rows of pillars, covering the names and deeds of the honored Dwarven ancestors. The ancient dwarves who kept these sites, carving new stories and teaching others to read them, were called Runewardens officially but 'Hand Seers' more commonly. Squinting in the candlelight so much invariably robbed them of their sight, so they learned every word and letter by hand. Kandros Fir was at the end of his Clan's section of the Rune Hall, chisel in hand.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I knew I'd find you here," Arturus said, kneeling next to him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I was his closest kin. I must add his name and deeds to our story."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course, old friend. But that isn't all you are planning, is it?" Kandros bowed his head.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am loyal to our king, by my bones, I am loyal."[PARAGRAPH:1]"But?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I can no sooner abandon family than fall on my own axe! Suppose your cousin Grunnos was missing. What would you do?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus snorted. "Speak not of that wastrel, but be glad he has many older brothers to be king before him should good Kanlore pass."[PARAGRAPH:1]"But?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"But... were his fate that of Luach, I should dig to Mammon's hell if it would find him. But not if my king forbid it! I know the bonds of kinship, but what of kith? Do you abandon your duty and your friends for a mad search? The winter will take you too, and what will that accomplish?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros rose, placing the hammer and chisel back on the altar as he turned to leave. "My duty has others to attend it, and my friends as well, dear Arturus. But Luach Fir is alone. If our friendship has meaning to you, you will not hinder me."[PARAGRAPH:2]It had not been easy getting to the surface. No one had been allowed to leave since Kandros' cousin Luach had gone to study the surface. Winter still raged, as it had for more than six generations, but young Luach was undaunted, and had petitioned Kanlore for leave to explore the harsh surface regardless of the danger. Supplies were slim in the Underhome. Their stores of black powder had been exhausted so long ago that the last Dwarves who would even recognize it had passed away, and expansion of the Underhome was tedious work with pick and hammer. Spices had run out early in Kandros youth, and the pork and tubers his children fed on left eating a chore. So Luach had at last been allowed to take another appraisal of the state of the bleak surface, but Kanlore's hesitancy had been proven right when Luach did not return for months. No one was permitted to leave now, meaning Kandros had to sneak past guards in the dark, and would be ill regarded if he returned at all.[PARAGRAPH:1]The exit to the Dwarven home was sealed with a massive stone door, and Kandros exhausted himself prying it open, even using his pick as a lever. He bravely stepped from the familiar darkness of his home into the unknown darkness of the Age of Ice. He emerged from the hillside, setting foot on grass. Not snow, and the night air was crisp but lacked the biting chill he had been warned of all his life. He stretched out his arms, marveling at the open space all around, and broke into a run down the hillside. Running was foolhardy in the Underhome. Low ceilings, sharp turns, and sudden drops presented challenges that demanded a careful step, but here there was freedom.[PARAGRAPH:1]And danger. Kandros found himself surrounded by large, grey dogs. He realized he had nearly charged into the den of these animals, and they cared little for his reason for being there. His hand axe was out barely before the first leapt for his throat. It was his blade that found the wolves throat first. And the skull of the next wolf to charge him. He became a whirl of axe and torch until the last beast lay dead or dying.[PARAGRAPH:1]So many animals... how could there be prey enough for a pack of this size in the wasteland he had been lead to believe the surface was? Then he noticed something half buried in the wolves' den. He walked over slowly, pulling the body from the debris, his breath held tight. Unmistakably the body of a dwarf, though it was a gruesome sight to see after the wolves had fed on its flesh. The pattern of the clothing marked it as a clansman of his, and Kandros knew he had found his cousin. He rent his beard and wept over the body. After a time he gathered the gathered up the body, intending to bury it within sight of the Underhome. Then he noticed ... the left shoulder blade was shorn in two. Not broken, but split with a clean cut. He examined it carefully. Luach had been hit from behind by a battle axe, almost certainly by someone of his height.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Murder..." he whispered to the night.[PARAGRAPH:1]He was answered, not by the night, but by a cloaked dwarf holding a Mithril axe directly behind him. "He, like you, wouldn't leave well enough alone, Fir." The dwarf swung his axe for the kill, but then dropped it clumsily and gurgled blood.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kandros!" Arturus shouted from the entrance of the wolf den, his axe embedded in the neck of the cloaked dwarf. The two friends embraced.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I found Luach, and his killer I think," Kandros informed his friend.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus Thorne went pale. "And I found my cousin as well." The dwarf he had killed was the prince Grunnos.[PARAGRAPH:2]The last time Kandros had been in the King's Hall, he had petitioned for permission to search out his cousin. Now, it was with accusation that the King's own son had killed his kin. Were it not for the well respected Arturus beside him, he would have been called a murderer, and worse, a name-killer for making accusations against Grunnos. Kanlore stood from his throne and faced the two Dwarves, his beard reaching nearly his full height. His eldest son and his honor guard flanked him; otherwise the chamber was empty. "You defied the laws of your people, Kandros Fir. The surface world is a harsh land ruled by a dread god and his legion of giants. It was treason to leave."[PARAGRAPH:1]Kandros did not interrupt his king, but rebuked him when he had finished. "The ice is long gone, my liege, and Winter has passed. Your laws made my people's home a prison, and it was based on lies!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tis true, uncle," spoke Arturus. "Your scouts have surely misled you for years!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Not years, foolish Arturus. The ravages of Winter were real enough 10 months ago."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You knew?" gasped Kandros.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, but your cousin had to die to keep this secret. Even with the Winter King gone, the surface world is a vicious realm. Elves and humans wield magic that can destroy any warrior. Greed makes warfare or subjugation unending. Here my people are safe, and here they shall remain."[PARAGRAPH:1]"We are not your children, to be locked away for our own protection. Let the Khazad go forth and prove our worth, not cower in stone chambers like men already dead! You have stolen our spirit, and I name you coward, Kanlore, be it treason or no!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Enough! Guards, kill them!" The honor guard readied their axes, but looked around, uncertain.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are you insane, father? These men did no wrong. You did, and you shamed yourself and your kin." Prince Toril sliced off his braided beard and threw it in the king's face. "You shall have no allegiance when word of this perfidy reaches beyond this hall. Nor shall any of your line." The guards heeded his words, and lowered their weapons.[PARAGRAPH:1]"So you too turn. My son, hear this-when the last dwarf is hunted down, felled by lance or wand, be it your name that they curse with their last breath!" Kanlore staggered from the royal hall, towards the surface that he so feared and into exile.[PARAGRAPH:1]The prince turned to Arturus. "Cousin, you are my closest living kin not of my father. It is you the people shall follow."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arturus turned to his old friend. "Kandros, could you not have left this alone as I so asked? Because of you I have become kin-slayer and usurper."[PARAGRAPH:1]"What? This foul scene was Kanlore's doing!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"What I say now I say with heavy heart but the weight of the crown. You sought the surface world, and there you must go, banished from the Underhome. Take provisions, take your clan, take all who would seek their fortune above. This is not justice, but there will not be order in the Underhome while a traitor walks its halls, and you did break the royal decree when you left." Arturus sighed. "As did I, when I followed you. Toril, if you will not be king, then be my viceroy, and I shall take the crown to the surface as punishment for my own disobedience, with whoever will follow me."[PARAGRAPH:1]And so the King of the Dwarves left the Underhome for the first time in over 300 years, and at the same time the Fir clan and their allies parted with their allies to forge their own Khazad nation. The two men who had been closest of fiends grew to be the fiercest of rivals for much of the last Age.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_REORX</Tag>
		<English>Reorx Veinhunter</English>
		<French>Reorx Chassefilon</French>
		<German>Reorx Aderjäger</German>
		<Italian>Reorx Veinhunter</Italian>
		<Spanish>Reorx Veinhunter</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_REORX_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Auditor Akrus paced steadily down the long, narrow tunnel. It's length seemed pointlessly excessive, and an apparent waste of funding.[PARAGRAPH:1]Looking at it, Akrus couldn't help but sigh and shake his head. He turned to glance at his guide, Thrumbl. A filthy miner who was busy picking things out of his beard. Suppressing a shudder of disgust (thanking Kilmorph that city dwarves were cleaner), Akrus asked the miner where the Foreman was.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, ri't this way, Aud'tor, yur Honour." Thrumbl muttered in a careless dialect.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sighing once more, Akrus followed Thrumbl down the tunnel, visibly dismayed at the lack of work he saw. Only the occasional labourer chatting, lazing around, gambling, and drinking. Nary a pick or worker in sight. After what seemed like an hour of marching, he and Thrumbl emerged from the tunnel into in a large, well lit cavern. It dawned on him where all the workers had been. On scaffolding all around the edge, they were hammering away at the rock walls.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Thar's him, Farman Reorx Veinhunter." Exclaimed Thrumbl, pointing towards the back of the chamber.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hmph, 'Farman'? Veinhunter? Given what I've seen, he might as well be Reorx Moneywaster", thought Akrus as he strode towards a fairly tall dwarf.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mr. Veinhunter? I'm Auditor Akrus, it is.good to meet you." He said in a dry voice, noticeably lacking sincerity.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Greetings. Call me Reorx, Auditor. To what do I owe this honour?" The Foreman said in clear, well pronounced Kaz'ak.[PARAGRAPH:1]"No honour in this visit, I'm afraid. Lord Kandros is getting impatient with this dig. You've tunneled miles into the earth, bypassing useful veins of copper I'm told, and for all the funding and men that have been allocated, you've produced nothing in the way of results. I've been ordered to shut down the excavation here, and issue the command to cease work."[PARAGRAPH:1]Reorx only smiled knowingly, raising his arm towards the scaffolding on his far left.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Follow me, Auditor. I've somethin' to show ye that'll make Kandros change his tune right fast"[PARAGRAPH:1]Akrus, frowning, following over to the wall, and climbing haphazardly up the sides of the scaffolding. Workers stepped aside to let them pass as Reorx led the auditor over to a part where the wall had been especially cut in.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Demonstrate to the Auditor what we've got here, lads"[PARAGRAPH:1]Two nearby workers lifted a large pick from the floor, and swung together at the rock wall in front of them. The pick penetrated only a few inches before stopping abruptly. When they wrenched it out again, the head was badly bent.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Auditor's breath caught in his throat as the workers pulled back the thin veneer of rock and dirt, revealing a glimmering silver mass behind, untouched by the impact of the pick.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Foreman Veinhunter", he said in a small voice, full of barely suppressed excitement." is this what I think it is."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Aye, indeed it is. Finest blessings of the goddess in this holy earth"[PARAGRAPH:1]"So this is why the tunnel was so long. But please tell me, how did you know this was here."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kilmorph told me." Reorx said with a smile[PARAGRAPH:1]And so, Auditor Akrus carried the news back to Kazak, riding a heavily laden cart full of evidence to show to his superiors. Reorx Veinhunter had rewards and titles heaped upon him in abundance, all the empire's available resources at his command, as an army of dwarven workers filled and expanded his new mine. For he had found the largest known vein of Mithril in all of Erebus, and secured the prosperity of Khazak for generations to come.</English>
		<French>L'auditeur Akrus marchait avec précaution droit dans le long tunnel étroit. Sa longueur semblait inutilement excessive, et une apparente dilapidation des fonds.[PARAGRAPH:1]En le regardant, Akrus ne put s'empêcher de soupirer et secouer la tête. Il se tourna pour dévisager son guide, Thrumbl. Un infect mineur occupé à sortir des choses de sa barbe. Retenant un hoquet de dégoût (et remerciant Kilmorph que les villes naines soient plus propres), Akrus demanda au mineur où se trouvait le contremaître.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, l'bas, 'diteur, vot'onneur," murmura Thrumbl dans un dialecte négligé.[PARAGRAPH:1]Soupirant une fois de plus, Akrus suivait Thrumbl dans le tunnel, abasourdi par le manque de travail qu'il pouvait observer. Seuls quelques travailleurs épisodiques, discutant, traînant, pariant, et buvant. Pas une pioche ou un travailleur à l'horizon. Après ce qui avait semblé être une heure de marche, lui et Thrumbl émergèrent du tunnel dans une grande caverne bien éclairée. Il comprit alors où se trouvaient tous les travailleurs. Sur des échafauds tout le long du bord, ils concassaient les murs de roche.[PARAGRAPH:1]"C'lui, Reorx Chassefilon," s'exclama Thrumbl, désignant le fond de la chambre.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hmpf, Chassefilon ? De ce que je vois, il pourrait bien être Reorx Gâcheargent," pensa Akrus en marchant à grand pas vers un assez grand nain.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mr Chassefilon ? Je suis l'auditeur Akrus, ravi de vous rencontrer," dit-il d'une voix sèche manquant clairement de sincérité.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bienvenue. Appelez moi Reorx, Auditeur. Que me vaut cet honneur ?" répondit le contremaître dans un Kaz'ak clair et bien articulé.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ce n'est pas un honneur, j'en ai bien peur. Le seigneur Kandros s'impatiente avec cette mine. Vous avez creusé des kilomètres sous terre, dépassant les veines utiles de cuivre dont on m'a parlé, et malgré tous les fonds et les hommes alloués, vous n'avez rien produit de ce qui était attendu. J'ai reçu l'ordre de fermer cette excavation, et de faire cesser le travail."[PARAGRAPH:1]Reorx se contenta de sourire d'un air entendu, levant son bras derrière lui vers la gauche.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Suivez-moi, Auditeur. J'ai quequ'chose à v'montrer qui f'ra bien vite l'seigneur Kandros changer d'vis."[PARAGRAPH:1]Akrus, grimaçant de désapprobation, suivit par-dessus le mur, grimpant n'importe comment les tas de gravats. Les travailleurs s'écartèrent pour le laisser passer, tandis que Reorx conduisait l'auditeur vers un pan de mur particulièrement découpé.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Montrez à l'Auditeur ce que nous avons là, les gars."[PARAGRAPH:1]Deux ouvriers proches soulevèrent une grosse pioche, et mirent un grand coup de concert dans le mur en face d'eux. La pioche ne pénétra que de quelques centimètres avant de s'arrêter brusquement. Quand ils l'eurent extraite, sa pointe était fortement tordue.[PARAGRAPH:1]L'auditeur eut le souffle coupé tandis que les ouvriers retiraient la fine couche de pierre et poussière, révélant une masse miroitante d'argent derrière, intacte après l'impact de la pioche.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Contremaître Chasseveine," dit-il d'une petite voix, contenant mal son excitation, "est-ce bien ce que je crois ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yep, bien sûr que c'en est. Le meilleur cadeau de la déesse sur cette terre sacrée."[PARAGRAPH:1]"C'est donc pour ça que le tunnel était si long. Mais dites-moi, comment avez-vous su que c'était là ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kilmorph me l'a dit," répondit Reorx avec un sourire.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ainsi, l'auditeur Akrus rapportait la nouvelle à Kazak, juché sur une charette lourdement chargée de preuves à présenter à ses supérieurs. Reorx Chassefilon reçut des récompenses et des titres en abondance, et toutes les ressources disponibles de l'empire à sa disposition, tandis qu'une armée d'ouvriers nains emplissaient et étendaient sa nouvelle mine. Parce qu'il avait trouvé la plus grande veine de Mithril connue de tout Erebus, et assuré la prospérité de Khazak pour les générations à venir.</French>
		<German>Auditor Akrus paced steadily down the long, narrow tunnel. It's length seemed pointlessly excessive, and an apparent waste of funding.[PARAGRAPH:1]Looking at it, Akrus couldn't help but sigh and shake his head. He turned to glance at his guide, Thrumbl. A filthy miner who was busy picking things out of his beard. Suppressing a shudder of disgust (thanking Kilmorph that city dwarves were cleaner), Akrus asked the miner where the Foreman was.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, ri't this way, Aud'tor, yur Honour." Thrumbl muttered in a careless dialect.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sighing once more, Akrus followed Thrumbl down the tunnel, visibly dismayed at the lack of work he saw. Only the occasional labourer chatting, lazing around, gambling, and drinking. Nary a pick or worker in sight. After what seemed like an hour of marching, he and Thrumbl emerged from the tunnel into in a large, well lit cavern. It dawned on him where all the workers had been. On scaffolding all around the edge, they were hammering away at the rock walls.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Thar's him, Farman Reorx Veinhunter." Exclaimed Thrumbl, pointing towards the back of the chamber.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hmph, 'Farman'? Veinhunter? Given what I've seen, he might as well be Reorx Moneywaster", thought Akrus as he strode towards a fairly tall dwarf.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mr. Veinhunter? I'm Auditor Akrus, it is.good to meet you." He said in a dry voice, noticeably lacking sincerity.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Greetings. Call me Reorx, Auditor. To what do I owe this honour?" The Foreman said in clear, well pronounced Kaz'ak.[PARAGRAPH:1]"No honour in this visit, I'm afraid. Lord Kandros is getting impatient with this dig. You've tunneled miles into the earth, bypassing useful veins of copper I'm told, and for all the funding and men that have been allocated, you've produced nothing in the way of results. I've been ordered to shut down the excavation here, and issue the command to cease work."[PARAGRAPH:1]Reorx only smiled knowingly, raising his arm towards the scaffolding on his far left.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Follow me, Auditor. I've somethin' to show ye that'll make Kandros change his tune right fast"[PARAGRAPH:1]Akrus, frowning, following over to the wall, and climbing haphazardly up the sides of the scaffolding. Workers stepped aside to let them pass as Reorx led the auditor over to a part where the wall had been especially cut in.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Demonstrate to the Auditor what we've got here, lads"[PARAGRAPH:1]Two nearby workers lifted a large pick from the floor, and swung together at the rock wall in front of them. The pick penetrated only a few inches before stopping abruptly. When they wrenched it out again, the head was badly bent.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Auditor's breath caught in his throat as the workers pulled back the thin veneer of rock and dirt, revealing a glimmering silver mass behind, untouched by the impact of the pick.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Foreman Veinhunter", he said in a small voice, full of barely suppressed excitement." is this what I think it is."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Aye, indeed it is. Finest blessings of the goddess in this holy earth"[PARAGRAPH:1]"So this is why the tunnel was so long. But please tell me, how did you know this was here."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kilmorph told me." Reorx said with a smile[PARAGRAPH:1]And so, Auditor Akrus carried the news back to Kazak, riding a heavily laden cart full of evidence to show to his superiors. Reorx Veinhunter had rewards and titles heaped upon him in abundance, all the empire's available resources at his command, as an army of dwarven workers filled and expanded his new mine. For he had found the largest known vein of Mithril in all of Erebus, and secured the prosperity of Khazak for generations to come.</German>
		<Italian>Il contabile Akrus camminava con passo sicuro nel tunnel lungo e stretto. La cui lunghezza sembrava inutilmente eccessiva, e un apparente spreco di finanziamenti.[PARAGRAPH:1]Osservandolo, Akrus non potè non sospirare e scutere la testa. Si volto a guardare la sua guida, Thrumbl. Un sudicio minatore che era impegnato a togliersi roba dalla barba. Sopprimendo un brivido di disgusto (ringraziando Kilmorph che i nani di città erano più puliti), Akrus chiese al minatore dove fosse il Caposquadra.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, prorpio da questa parte, Contabile, vostro onore." Thrumbl borbottò in dialetto.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sospirando ancora una volta Akrus seguì Thrumbl lungo il tunnel, rimanendo visibilmente sgomento a causa della mancanza di lavoro che vedeva. Solo qualche manovale occasionale che chiaccherava, oziava, giocava o beveva. Non aveva visto neanche un piccone o un minatore. Dopo ciò che sembrava essere un'ora di marcia, lui e Thrumbl uscirono da tunnel in un grande e ben illuminata caverna. In quel momento si rese conto do dove fossero tutti i minatori. Sulle impalcature tutte intorno al bordo stavano picconando le pareti di roccia.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Eccolo li, Caposquadra Reorx Veinhunter." Esclamo Thrumbl, indicando verso il fondo della caverna.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hmph, 'Caposquadra'? Veinhunter? Dato ciò che ho visto, potrebbe benissimo essere Reorx Spendaccione", pensò Akrus mentre si dirigeva verso un nano abbastanza alto.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mr. Veinhunter? Sono il Contabile Akrus, è bello incontrarvi." Disse con voce secca, mancando decisamente di sincerità.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Saluti. Chiamatemi Reorx, Contabile. A cosa devo questo onore?" Il Caposquadra disse in un chiaro e ben pronunciato Kaz'ak.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Nessun onore in questa visita temo. Lord Kandros sta diventando impaziente con questo scavo. Avete scavato kilomentri nella roccia, ignorando delle utili vene di rame per quello che mi è stato detto, e nonostante tutti i finanziamenti e gli uomoni che vi sono stati assegnati non avete portato risultati. Mi è stato ordinato di chiudere gli scavi qui, e di ordinare la cessazione dei lavori."[PARAGRAPH:1]Reorx semplicemente sorrise, alzando il braccio verso le impalcature alla sua sinistra.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Seguitemi, Contabile. Ho qualcosa da mostrarvi che farà cambiare parere rapidamente a Kandros"[PARAGRAPH:1]Akrus, corrucciato, lo seguì fino al muro, per poi salire a caso sulle impalcature. I minatori si fecero da parte per farli passare mentre Reorx guidava il contabile verso una parte in cui il muro era stato particolarmente scavato.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mostrate al contabile cosa abbiamo qui ragazzi"[PARAGRAPH:1]Due minatori presero da terra un piccone ciascuno e colpirono insieme il muro di roccia davanti a loro. Il piccone penetrò solo di pochi centimetri prima di bloccarsi improvvisamente. Quando lo estrassero la punta era piegata.[PARAGRAPH:1]Al Contabile gli si bloccò il respiro in gola quando i minatori rimossero il sottile strato di roccia e terra, rivelando una lucente massa argentata, senza graffi nonostante l'impatto del piccone.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Caposquadra Veinhunter", disse con una voce bassa, piena di una eccitazione a malapena trattenuta." è ciò che penso che io sia."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Signorsi, lo è. La benedizione più grande della dea in questa sacra terra"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Quindi questo è il motivo della lunghezza del tunnel. Ma vi prego ditemi, come facevate a sapere dove fosse."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kilmorph me lo ha detto." Reorx disse con un sorriso[PARAGRAPH:1]E cosi, il Contabile Akrus portò la notizia sino a Kazak, guidando un carro pieno di prove da mostrare a suoi superiori. Reorx Veinhunter ricevette ricompense e titoli in abbondanza, e tutte le risorse dell'impero furono messe sotto il suo comando, mentre un esercito di minatori nanici riempiva e ampliava la sua nuova miniera. In quanto lui aveva trovato il filone di Mithril, di cui si aveva conoscenza, più grande di tutto Erebus, e cosi facendo aveva assicurato la prosperità di Khazak per generazioni a venire.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Auditor Akrus paced steadily down the long, narrow tunnel. It's length seemed pointlessly excessive, and an apparent waste of funding.[PARAGRAPH:1]Looking at it, Akrus couldn't help but sigh and shake his head. He turned to glance at his guide, Thrumbl. A filthy miner who was busy picking things out of his beard. Suppressing a shudder of disgust (thanking Kilmorph that city dwarves were cleaner), Akrus asked the miner where the Foreman was.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, ri't this way, Aud'tor, yur Honour." Thrumbl muttered in a careless dialect.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sighing once more, Akrus followed Thrumbl down the tunnel, visibly dismayed at the lack of work he saw. Only the occasional labourer chatting, lazing around, gambling, and drinking. Nary a pick or worker in sight. After what seemed like an hour of marching, he and Thrumbl emerged from the tunnel into in a large, well lit cavern. It dawned on him where all the workers had been. On scaffolding all around the edge, they were hammering away at the rock walls.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Thar's him, Farman Reorx Veinhunter." Exclaimed Thrumbl, pointing towards the back of the chamber.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hmph, 'Farman'? Veinhunter? Given what I've seen, he might as well be Reorx Moneywaster", thought Akrus as he strode towards a fairly tall dwarf.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mr. Veinhunter? I'm Auditor Akrus, it is.good to meet you." He said in a dry voice, noticeably lacking sincerity.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Greetings. Call me Reorx, Auditor. To what do I owe this honour?" The Foreman said in clear, well pronounced Kaz'ak.[PARAGRAPH:1]"No honour in this visit, I'm afraid. Lord Kandros is getting impatient with this dig. You've tunneled miles into the earth, bypassing useful veins of copper I'm told, and for all the funding and men that have been allocated, you've produced nothing in the way of results. I've been ordered to shut down the excavation here, and issue the command to cease work."[PARAGRAPH:1]Reorx only smiled knowingly, raising his arm towards the scaffolding on his far left.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Follow me, Auditor. I've somethin' to show ye that'll make Kandros change his tune right fast"[PARAGRAPH:1]Akrus, frowning, following over to the wall, and climbing haphazardly up the sides of the scaffolding. Workers stepped aside to let them pass as Reorx led the auditor over to a part where the wall had been especially cut in.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Demonstrate to the Auditor what we've got here, lads"[PARAGRAPH:1]Two nearby workers lifted a large pick from the floor, and swung together at the rock wall in front of them. The pick penetrated only a few inches before stopping abruptly. When they wrenched it out again, the head was badly bent.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Auditor's breath caught in his throat as the workers pulled back the thin veneer of rock and dirt, revealing a glimmering silver mass behind, untouched by the impact of the pick.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Foreman Veinhunter", he said in a small voice, full of barely suppressed excitement." is this what I think it is."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Aye, indeed it is. Finest blessings of the goddess in this holy earth"[PARAGRAPH:1]"So this is why the tunnel was so long. But please tell me, how did you know this was here."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kilmorph told me." Reorx said with a smile[PARAGRAPH:1]And so, Auditor Akrus carried the news back to Kazak, riding a heavily laden cart full of evidence to show to his superiors. Reorx Veinhunter had rewards and titles heaped upon him in abundance, all the empire's available resources at his command, as an army of dwarven workers filled and expanded his new mine. For he had found the largest known vein of Mithril in all of Erebus, and secured the prosperity of Khazak for generations to come.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MOTHER_LODE</Tag>
		<English>Mother Lode</English>
		<French>Filon Mère</French>
		<German>Goldrausch</German>
		<Italian>Filone Principale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mother Lode</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MOTHER_LODE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Grants 25 [ICON_GOLD] per Mine improvement and has a 10% chance of raising each Khazad owned flat plot into a hill[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants [ICON_GOLD] per Dwarven Mine improvement. Value depends of the upgrade level of the Improvement.</English>
		<French>Chaque case plate des Khazadors a 10% de chances de se transformer en colline.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fournit 25 [ICON_GOLD] par [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MINE]Mine[\LINK], 50 [ICON_GOLD] par [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_DWARVEN_MINE]Mine Naine[\LINK], 75 [ICON_GOLD] par [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_DWARVEN_SETTLEMENT]Campement Nain[\LINK], 100 [ICON_GOLD] par [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_DWARVEN_HALL]Château Nain[\LINK] et 200 [ICON_GOLD] par [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_DWARVEN_FORTRESS]Forteresse Naine[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Jede Mine liefert 25 [ICON_GOLD] und jedes Geländefeld innerhalb der Kulturgrenzen der Khazad hat eine 10% Chance zu einem Hügel zu werden[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants [ICON_GOLD] per Dwarven Mine improvement. Value depends of the upgrade level of the Improvement.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce 25 [ICON_GOLD] per ogni miglioramento Miniera, e ha una probabilità del 10% di trasformare ogni casella di terreno piatto sotto controllo dei Khazad in una collina[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce [ICON_GOLD] per ogni miglioramento Miniera Nanica. La quantita ricevuta dipende dal livello del miglioramento.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Grants 25 [ICON_GOLD] per Mine improvement and has a 10% chance of raising each Khazad owned flat plot into a hill[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants [ICON_GOLD] per Dwarven Mine improvement. Value depends of the upgrade level of the Improvement.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_GLOBALSPELL_MOTHER_LODE</Tag>
		<English>Grants the caster 25 [ICON_GOLD] for each [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MINE]Mine[\LINK] they control and has a 10% chance per tile to raise any flatland into a hill</English>
		<French>Fournit au lanceur 25 [ICON_GOLD] pour chaque [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MINE]Mine[\LINK] sous son contrôle et a 10% par case de chances de transformer chaque case plate en colline.</French>
		<German>Jede Mine unter Kontrolle des Zaubernden liefert 25 [ICON_GOLD]. Au&#223;erdem besteht f&#252;r jedes Flachland eine 10%ige Chance, zu H&#252;gelland zu werden.</German>
		<Italian>Fornisce a chi la lancia 25 [ICON_GOLD] per ogni [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MINE]Miniera[\LINK] che controlla, e ha una probabilità del 10% per trasformare ogni terreno piatto in una collina</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grants the caster 25 [ICON_GOLD] for each [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MINE]Mine[\LINK] they control and has a 10% chance per tile to raise any flatland into a hill</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWARVEN_SMITHY</Tag>
		<English>Dwarven Smithy</English>
		<French>Forge Naine</French>
		<German>Zwergenschmiede</German>
		<Italian>Fucina Nanica</Italian>
		<Spanish>Herrería Enana</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT</Tag>
		<English>Dwarven Vault</English>
		<French>Chambre Forte Naine</French>
		<German>Zwergengewölbe</German>
		<Italian>Camera Blindata Nanica</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cámara Acorazada Enana</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_ABUNDANT</Tag>
		<English>Dwarven Vault (Abundant)</English>
		<French>Chambre Forte Naine (Abondante)</French>
		<German>Zwergengewölbe (Reichlich gefüllt)</German>
		<Italian>Camera Blindata Nanica (Quasi piena)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cámara Acorazada Enana (Abundante)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_EMPTY</Tag>
		<English>Dwarven Vault (Empty)</English>
		<French>Chambre Forte Naine (Vide)</French>
		<German>Zwergengewölbe (Leer)</German>
		<Italian>Camera Blindata Nanica (Vuota)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cámara Acorazada Enana (Vacía)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_FULL</Tag>
		<English>Dwarven Vault (Full)</English>
		<French>Chambre Forte Naine (Pleine)</French>
		<German>Zwergengewölbe (Voll)</German>
		<Italian>Camera Blindata Nanica (Piena)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cámara Acorazada Enana (Llena)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_LOW</Tag>
		<English>Dwarven Vault (Low)</English>
		<French>Chambre Forte Naine (Basse)</French>
		<German>Zwergengewölbe (kaum gefüllt)</German>
		<Italian>Camera Blindata Nanica (Quasi vuota)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cámara Acorazada Enana (Poco llena)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_OVERFLOWING</Tag>
		<English>Dwarven Vault (Overflowing)</English>
		<French>Chambre Forte Naine (Débordante)</French>
		<German>Zwergengewölbe (Überfüllt)</German>
		<Italian>Dwarven Vault (Strapieno)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cámara Acorazada Enana (Desbordada)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_STOCKED</Tag>
		<English>Dwarven Vault (Stocked)</English>
		<French>Chambre Forte Naine (Approvisionnée)</French>
		<German>Zwergengewölbe (Gut gefüllt)</German>
		<Italian>Camera Blindata Nanica (Rifornita)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cámara Acorazada Enana (Amontonada)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Khazad judge their leaders by the amount of gold they are able to amass. The Dwarven Vault represents this amount.</English>
		<French>Les Khazadors jugent leurs dirigeants à l'aune des quantités d'or qu'ils sont capables d'amasser. La chambre forte est le principal témoin de leurs résultats.</French>
		<German>[TAB]The Khazad judge their leaders by the amount of gold they are able to amass. The Dwarven Vault represents this amount.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]I Khazad giudicano i loro leader in base alla quantita di oro che riescono ad accumulare. La Camera Blindata Nanica da un indicazione di ciò.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Khazad judge their leaders by the amount of gold they are able to amass. The Dwarven Vault represents this amount.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>It will be upgraded automatically depending on the amount of Gold per City (GpC).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]000-049 GpC: [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_EMPTY]Dwarven Vault (Empty)[\LINK] +2 [ICON_UNHAPPY][NEWLINE]050-099 GpC: [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_LOW]Dwarven Vault (Low)[\LINK] +1 [ICON_UNHAPPY][NEWLINE]100-149 GpC: [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT]Dwarven Vault[\LINK][NEWLINE]150-199 GpC: [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_STOCKED]Dwarven Vault (Stocked)[\LINK] +1 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]200-299 GpC: [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_ABUNDANT]Dwarven Vault (Abundant)[\LINK] +10% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +2 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]300-499 GpC: [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_FULL]Dwarven Vault (Full)[\LINK] +25% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +2 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]500 or more GpC: [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_OVERFLOWING]Dwarven Vault (Overflowing)[\LINK] +40% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +3 [ICON_HAPPY][PARAGRAPH:2]So if a Khazad player has 2000 gold and 10 cities he would have 200 Gold per City (GpC) which would earn him a free Dwarven Vault (Abundant) in each of his cities.</English>
		<French>La Chambre Forte sera automatiquement améliorée en fonction de la quantité d'Or par Ville ([ICON_GOLD]/V).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]000 à 049 [ICON_GOLD]/V : [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_EMPTY]Chambre Forte (Vide)[\LINK] +2 [ICON_UNHAPPY], -1 vitesse d'entraînement, +5 criminalité[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]050 à 099 [ICON_GOLD]/V : [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_LOW]Chambre Forte (Basse)[\LINK] +1 [ICON_UNHAPPY], -0,5 vitesse d'entraînement, +2 criminalité[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]100 à 149 [ICON_GOLD]/V : [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT]Chambre Forte[\LINK][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]150 à 199 [ICON_GOLD]/V : [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_STOCKED]Chambre Forte (Approvisionnée)[\LINK] +1 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]200 à 299 [ICON_GOLD]/V: [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_ABUNDANT]Chambre Forte (Abondante)[\LINK] +10% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +2 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]300 à 499 [ICON_GOLD]/V : [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_FULL]Chambre Forte (Pleine)[\LINK] +25% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +2 [ICON_HAPPY], +0,25 vitesse d'entraînement, -5 criminalité[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]500 [ICON_GOLD]/V et + : [LINK=BUILDING_DWARVEN_VAULT_OVERFLOWING]Chambre Forte (Débordante)[\LINK] +40% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +3 [ICON_HAPPY], +0,5 vitesse d'entraînement, -10 criminalité, +25%[ICON_GREATPEOPLE][PARAGRAPH:2]Exemple : un joueur khazador possédant 2000 or et 10 villes dispose de 200 [ICON_GOLD]/V. Ses 10 villes auront donc chacune une chambre forte au niveau abondant.</French>
		<German>It will be upgraded automatically depending on the amount of Gold per City (GpC).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]000-049 GpC: Dwarven Vault (Empty) +2 [ICON_UNHAPPY][NEWLINE]050-099 GpC: Dwarven Vault (Low) +1 [ICON_UNHAPPY][NEWLINE]100-149 GpC: Dwarven Vault[NEWLINE]150-199 GpC: Dwarven Vault (Stocked) +1 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]200-299 GpC: Dwarven Vault (Abundant) +10% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +2 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]300-499 GpC: Dwarven Vault (Full) +25% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +2 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]500 or more GpC: Dwarven Vault (Overflowing) +40% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +3 [ICON_HAPPY][PARAGRAPH:2]So if a Khazad player has 2000 gold and 10 cities he would have 200 Gold per City (GpC) which would earn him a free Dwarven Vault (Abundant) in each of his cities.</German>
		<Italian>Verrà migliorata, o degradata, automaticamente a seconda della quantita di Oro per Città (OpC).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]000-049 OpC: Camera Blindata Nanica (Vuota) +2 [ICON_UNHAPPY][NEWLINE]050-099 OpC: Camera Blindata Nanica (Quasi vuota) +1 [ICON_UNHAPPY][NEWLINE]100-149 OpC: Camera Blindata Nanica[NEWLINE]150-199 OpC: Camera Blindata Nanica (Rifornita) +1 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]200-299 OpC: Camera Blindata Nanica (Quasi piena) +10% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +2 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]300-499 OpC: Camera Blindata Nanica (Piena) +25% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +2 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]500 o più OpC: Camera Blindata Nanica (Strapiena) +40% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +3 [ICON_HAPPY][PARAGRAPH:2]Quindi se un giocatore Khazad ha 2000 di oro e 10 città lui avrebbe 200 Oro per Città (OpC) che gli darebbe una Camera Blindata Nanica (Quasi piena) in ogni sua città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>It will be upgraded automatically depending on the amount of Gold per City (GpC).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]000-049 GpC: Dwarven Vault (Empty) +2 [ICON_UNHAPPY][NEWLINE]050-099 GpC: Dwarven Vault (Low) +1 [ICON_UNHAPPY][NEWLINE]100-149 GpC: Dwarven Vault[NEWLINE]150-199 GpC: Dwarven Vault (Stocked) +1 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]200-299 GpC: Dwarven Vault (Abundant) +10% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +2 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]300-499 GpC: Dwarven Vault (Full) +25% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +2 [ICON_HAPPY][NEWLINE]500 or more GpC: Dwarven Vault (Overflowing) +40% [ICON_PRODUCTION], +3 [ICON_HAPPY][PARAGRAPH:2]So if a Khazad player has 2000 gold and 10 cities he would have 200 Gold per City (GpC) which would earn him a free Dwarven Vault (Abundant) in each of his cities.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_KHAZAD</Tag>
		<English>Khazad Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Khazador</French>
		<German>Palast der Khazad</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo dei Khazad</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Khazad</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MARKET_SLAVE</Tag>
		<English>Slave Market</English>
		<French>Marché aux Esclaves</French>
		<German>Sklavenmarkt</German>
		<Italian>Mercato degli Schiavi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slave Market</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AUDITOR</Tag>
		<English>Auditor</English>
		<French>Auditeur</French>
		<German>Auditor</German>
		<Italian>Contabile</Italian>
		<Spanish>Auditor</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AUDITOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Every battle leaves behind spoils and soldiers, especially conscripts and mercenaries, are notorious for pilfering the choicest bits before the loot is hauled to the victor's treasury. The Khazad have a very special relationship with wealth and so they have taken measures to prevent its misappropriation after a successful combat: Auditors.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Each auditor is technically a government official and receives a monthly stipend. Because they are well paid, professional soldiers whose peace-time task is keeping the books of Khazad balanced, the auditors are renowned for their post-fighting fastidiousness. With their weather-proof ledgers, individually labeled swag-bags and ax/abacus/slide-rule multi-tool, the auditors ensure that even the smallest skirmish is profitable. Be careful warring with the dwarves for they will strip your warriors of their equipment, weapons, boots, coins and, if necessary, lives.[NEWLINE][BOLD]Rule of Acquisition #34[\BOLD], War is good for business."</English>
		<French>"Chaque bataille laisse derrière elle des restes, et les soldats, particulièrement les conscrits et les mercenaires, sont connus pour dérober les morceaux de choix avant que le butin soit ajouté au trésor du vainqueur. Les Khazadors ont une relation très spéciale avec la richesse et ont ainsi pris des mesures pour éviter ces mauvaises appropriations après un combat victorieux : les Auditeurs.[NEWLINE]Chaque auditeur est techniquement un membre du gouvernement et reçoivent une paye mensuele. Parce qu'ils sont des soldats bien payés dont la tâche en temps de paix est de tenir les livres de comptes khazadors à jour, les auditeurs sont connus pour leur méticulosité d'après-combat. Avec leurs registres imperméables, leurs sacs de butin nommés individuellement leur outil multi-usage hache/abaque/règle, les auditeurs s'assurent que même la plus petite des escarmouches est profitable. Soyez prudent lorsque vous guerroyez avec les nains, sinon ils délesteront vos guerriers de leurs équipements, armes, bottes, pièces et si nécessairesn vies.[NEWLINE][BOLD]Règle de commerce #34[\BOLD], la guerre est bonne pour les affaires." </French>
		<German>"Auf jede Schlacht folgen plündernde Soldaten, besonders Rekruten und Söldner sind bekannt dafür, dass sie sich die besten Stücke herauspicken, bevor die erbeuteten Schätze in der Schatzkammer des siegreichen Herrführers verschwinden. Die Khazad haben eine besondere Einstellung zu Reichtum, und so haben sie Maßnahmen ergriffen, um die ungeordnete Umverteilung nach einem erfolgreichen Kampf zu verhindern: Auditoren.[NEWLINE]Jeder Auditor ist technisch gesehen ein offizieller Vertreter der Regierung und erhält eine monatliche Entschädigung. Da sie gut bezahlt und professionelle Soldaten sind, deren Aufgabe zu Friedenszeiten darin besteht, die Bücher der Khazad zu überprüfen, sind die Auditoren für ihreGründlichkeit und ihren Drang nach Ordnung auch in der Zeit nach den Kämpfen bekannt. Mit ihren wetterfesten Kisten, ihren einzeln gekennzeichneten Sammelbeuteln und ihren Abakus/Rechenschieber-Multifunktionswerkzeugen stellen die Auditoren sicher, dass auch jeder noch so kleine Raubzug profitabel ist. Man sollte allerdings bei Zwergen aufpassen, da sie die eigenen Krieger um ihre Ausrüstung, Waffen, Stiefel, Münzen und, wenn es sein muss, auch um ihre Leben bringen werden.[NEWLINE][BOLD]Regel der Aneignung #34[\BOLD], Krieg ist gut fürs Geschäft."</German>
		<Italian>"Ogni battaglia lascia dietro di se del bottino, e i soldati, specialmente coscritti e mercenari, sono famosi per prendere per se le cose migliori prima di inviare il resto alla tesoreria del vincitore. I Khazad, avendo un rapporto speciale con la ricchezza, hanno adottato misure per prevenire una sua appropriazione indebita dopo la vittoria in combattimento: i Contabili.[NEWLINE]Ogni Contabile è tecnicamente un ufficiale governativo e riceve uno stipendio mensile. Essendo soldati professionisti ben pagati, il cui compito in tempo di pace è di tenere in ordine i libri contabili dei Khazad, i Contabili sono rinomati per la loro meticolosità post-combattimento. Con i loro registri, trattati per resistere alle intemperie, dei sacchi per il bottino etichettati individualmente e la loro piccozza/abaco/righello multiuso i Contabili si assicurano che anche la più piccola delle schermaglie sia redditizia. Fai attenzione quando combatti i nani perché loro spoglieranno i tuoi guerrieri del loro equipaggiamento, delle loro armi, dei loro stivali, delle loro monete e, se necessario, delle loro vite.[NEWLINE][BOLD]Regola di Acquisizione #34[\BOLD], La guerra fa bene agli affari." </Italian>
		<Spanish>"Every battle leaves behind spoils and soldiers, especially conscripts and mercenaries, are notorious for pilfering the choicest bits before the loot is hauled to the victor's treasury. The Khazad have a very special relationship with wealth and so they have taken measures to prevent its misappropriation after a successful combat: Auditors.[NEWLINE]Each auditor is technically a government official and receives a monthly stipend. Because they are well paid, professional soldiers whose peace-time task is keeping the books of Khazad balanced, the auditors are renowned for their post-fighting fastidiousness. With their weather-proof ledgers, individually labeled swag-bags and ax/abacus/slide-rule multi-tool, the auditors ensure that even the smallest skirmish is profitable. Be careful warring with the dwarves for they will strip your warriors of their equipment, weapons, boots, coins and, if necessary, lives.[NEWLINE][BOLD]Rule of Acquisition #34[\BOLD], War is good for business." </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DWARVEN_CANNON</Tag>
		<English>Dwarven Cannon</English>
		<French>Bombarde Naine</French>
		<German>Zwergen-Kartaune</German>
		<Italian>Cannone Nanico</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dwarven Cannon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DWARVEN_CANNON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Not to be beaten in the technological arms race concerning their favorite rock-clearing method, the Dwarves have designed their own cannons. Though essentially fulfilling the same purpose as the other races' guns, dwarven cannons are built with dwarven aesthetics in mind: smaller and more compact, yet expertly-crafted and calibrated. These qualities give dwarven cannons an edge over other races' guns; a battery of dwarven cannons can deliver their deadly payloads with great accuracy, wasting less powder and time in bringing down fortifications.</English>
		<French>Pour ne pas être battus dans la course technologique aux armes à propos de leur méthode favorite de nettoyage de rochers, les nains ont conçu leurs propres canons. Bien qu'ils remplissent le même rôle que les 'fusils' des autres races, les canons nains sont construits selon les normes naines : plus petits et compacts, et pourtant construit sans-défaut et parfaitement calibrés. Ces qualités confèrent aux canons nains un avantage sur les 'fusils' es autres races; une batterie de canons nains peut délivrer ses charges utiles mortelles avec une grande précision, gâchant moins de poudre et de temps en destruction de fortifications.</French>
		<German>Not to be beaten in the technological arms race concerning their favorite rock-clearing method, the Dwarves have designed their own cannons. Though essentially fulfilling the same purpose as the other races' guns, dwarven cannons are built with dwarven aesthetics in mind: smaller and more compact, yet expertly-crafted and calibrated. These qualities give dwarven cannons an edge over other races' guns; a battery of dwarven cannons can deliver their deadly payloads with great accuracy, wasting less powder and time in bringing down fortifications.</German>
		<Italian>I Nani progettarono i loro cannoni non volendo rimanere indietro nella corsa alle armi tecnologiche per quanto riguardava il metodo da loro preferito di rimozione con pietre. Sebbene ricoprano lo stesso ruolo dei cannoni delle altre razze, i cannoni nanici sono costruiti in stile nanico: più piccoli e compatti degli altri ma comunque sapientemente costruiti e calibrati. Queste qualità danno ai cannoni nanici un vantaggio rispetto a quelli delle altre razze; una batteria di cannoni nanici può sparare con maggiore precisione e consumando meno polvere e tempo nel distruggere le fortificazioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Not to be beaten in the technological arms race concerning their favorite rock-clearing method, the Dwarves have designed their own cannons. Though essentially fulfilling the same purpose as the other races' guns, dwarven cannons are built with dwarven aesthetics in mind: smaller and more compact, yet expertly-crafted and calibrated. These qualities give dwarven cannons an edge over other races' guns; a battery of dwarven cannons can deliver their deadly payloads with great accuracy, wasting less powder and time in bringing down fortifications.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DWARVEN_CANNON_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Khazad have the most powerful cannons in the game. They are the fastest way to destroy your enemies cities defenses.</English>
		<French>Les Khazadors possèdent les canons les plus puissants du jeu. Ils sont la méthode la plus rapide pour détruire les défenses des villes ennemies.</French>
		<German>The Khazad have the most powerful cannons in the game. They are the fastest way to destroy your enemies cities defenses.</German>
		<Italian>I Khazad hanno i cannoni più forti del gioco. Sono il modo più veloce per abbattere le difese delle città nemiche.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Khazad have the most powerful cannons in the game. They are the fastest way to destroy your enemies cities defenses.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DWARVEN_COMMANDER</Tag>
		<English>Clanhold Chieftain</English>
		<French>Protecteur en chef de clan</French>
		<German>Häuptling des Clansiedlung</German>
		<Italian>Comandante della fortezza del Clan</Italian>
		<Spanish>Clanhold Chieftain</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DWARVEN_DEFENDER</Tag>
		<English>Dwarven Defender</English>
		<French>Défenseur Nain</French>
		<German>Zwergenverteidiger</German>
		<Italian>Difensore Nanico</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dwarven Defender</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DWARVEN_DEFENDER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The first generation of Dwarves never age, they are exactly as they were when they were carved, but each generation of dwarves gets a slightly shorter lifespan.  As they get farther and farther from the breath of Kilmorph, they become more mortal, in spirit and life.  The Dwarven Defenders are drawn from the ranks of the earliest dwarves. Not the very first, for they were few then, but the subsequent generations as they grew and multiplied. Each one has had centuries of training and development in the underhome deeep beneath the earth. Practise daily wearing armour that would crush a mortal man beneath it's weight. Oblivious to the frozen world above, they trained for battle deep within the earth. Though they are not immortal and must die eventually, the Defenders are nevertheless ancient even in dwarven years, and none have yet to die by anything other than a violent means. Now they step forth from their home within the earth, as the Khazad begin the slow but unstoppable Dwarven War March. The Defenders are at the head of the ranks, fearlessly leading the charge into the enemy.</English>
		<French>La première génération de Nains ne vieillit pas, ils restent exactement tels qu'ils furent taillés, mais chaque nouvelle génération de Nains possède une espérance de vie un peu plus courte. Au fur et à mesure qu'ils s'éloignent du souffle de Kilmorph, ils deviennent mortels, physiquement et mentalement. Les Défenseurs Nains sont issus des rangs des premiers Nains. Pas la toute première, qui ne représentait que très peu de Nains, mais des suivantes, tandis qu'ils croissaient et multipliaient. Chacun d'eux s'entraîna pendant des siècles dans le dome souterrain, profondément enterré sous la surface. Ignorant le monde gelé au-dessus d'eux, ils s'entrainèrent au combat loin dans les entrailles d'Erebus. Bien qu'ils ne soient pas immortels et aient toujours un risque de mourir, les Défenseurs sont âgés, même en termes d'années naniques, et aucun n'est décédé autrement que violemment. Aujourd'hui ils marchent depuis leurs maisons souterraines, tandis que les Khazad commencent la lente mais implacable Marche de Guerre Naine. Les Défenseurs sont à la tête de ces rangs, menant sans peur la charge sur les ennemis.</French>
		<German>Die erste Generation der Zwerge altert niemals, sie ist noch genau so, wie sie gemeißelt wurde, aber jede folgende Generation hat eine etwas kürzere Lebensspanne. Je weiter sie sich vom Atem des Kilmorph entfernen, umso sterblicher werden sie, sowohl im Geist wie auch im Körper. Die Zwergenverteidiger rekrutieren sich aus den Reihen der ältesten Zwerge. Nicht aus den allerältesten, aber aus den ersten Nachkommengenerationen. Jeder von ihnen hat Jahrhunderte an Ausbildung und Entwicklung in seinem unterirdischen Heim tief unter der Oberfläche hinter sich. Von der gefrorenen Oberwelt vergessen, haben sie tief in der Erde für die Schlacht trainiert. Obwohl sie nicht unsterblich sind und irgendwann sterben werden, gelten auch die Zwergenverteidiger in Zwergenjahren als uralt, niemand aus ihren Reihen ist allerdings bisher an Altersschwäche gestorben. Nun, da die Khazad ihren langsamen, und doch unaufaltsamen, Kriegsmarsch beginnen, treten sie aus ihren Heimen unter der Erde, und begeben sich in die ersten Reihen, um den Kampf absolut furchtlos zum Feind zu tragen.</German>
		<Italian>La prima generazione di Nani non invecchiano, rimangono esattamente uguali a come quando erano stati scolpiti, ma ogni generazione successiva ha una durata della vita leggermente minore. Man mano che si allontanano dal respiro di Kilmorph diventano sempre più mortali, nella vita e nello spirito. I Difensori Nanici sono composti dai nani delle prime generazioni. Non la prima generazione perché erano pochi allora, ma da quelle successive quando crescevano e si moltiplicavano. Ognuno di loro ha con se secoli di addestramento e di sviluppo passati nel Sottosuolo. Ignari del mondo ghiacciato di sopra, si sono addestrati per combattere in profondità della terra. Anche se non sono immortali e moriranno eventualmente, i Difensori sono comunque antichi anche in anni nanici, e nessuno è ancora morto se non in modo violento. Ora stanno uscendo dalla loro casa sotto terra, mentre i Khazad iniziano la lenta, ma inarrestabile, Marcia da Guerra Nanica. I Difensori sono in prima linea, guidando senza paura gli assalti contro i nemici.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The first generation of Dwarves never age, they are exactly as they were when they were carved, but each generation of dwarves gets a slightly shorter lifespan.  As they get farther and farther from the breath of Kilmorph, they become more mortal, in spirit and life.  The Dwarven Defenders are drawn from the ranks of the earliest dwarves. Not the very first, for they were few then, but the subsequent generations as they grew and multiplied. Each one has had centuries of training and development in the underhome deeep beneath the earth. Oblivious to the frozen world above, they trained for battle deep within the earth. Though they are not immortal and must die eventually, the Defenders are nevertheless ancient even in dwarven years, and none have yet to die by anything other than a violent means. Now they step forth from their home within the earth, as the Khazad begin the slow but unstoppable Dwarven War March. The Defenders are at the head of the ranks, fearlessly leading the charge into the enemy.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_IRONCLAD</Tag>
		<English>Ironclad</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Cuirass&#233; &#224; vapeur</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Panzerschiff</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Corazzata:Corazzate</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Buque blindado:Buques blindados</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_IRONCLAD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>You mean to tell me that a ship without sails came at you, against the wind, to attack you in the middle of the night, and was solely responsible for the destruction of the four ships under your command? I'll teach you to lie to me.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Captain Blackheart, moments before ordering the execution of Captain Johnathan Whiler[\ITALICS][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ironclads are truly a dwarven invention. Rather then using wood and wind, they use metal, coal, and fire. Stronger than normal ships, they are capable of carrying many more cannons. Whoever came up with the rhyme "Dwarves abhor the seas" clearly was not informed about the ironclad.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Anonymous[\ITALICS]</English>
		<French>You mean to tell me that a ship without sails came at you, against the wind, to attack you in the middle of the night, and was solely responsible for the destruction of the four ships under your command? I'll teach you to lie to me.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Captain Blackheart, moments before ordering the execution of Captain Johnathan Whiler[\ITALICS][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ironclads are truly a dwarven invention. Rather then using wood and wind, they use metal, coal, and fire. Stronger than normal ships, they are capable of carrying many more cannons. Whoever came up with the rhyme "Dwarves abhor the seas" clearly was not informed about the ironclad.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Anonymous[\ITALICS]</French>
		<German>You mean to tell me that a ship without sails came at you, against the wind, to attack you in the middle of the night, and was solely responsible for the destruction of the four ships under your command? I'll teach you to lie to me.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Captain Blackheart, moments before ordering the execution of Captain Johnathan Whiler[\ITALICS][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ironclads are truly a dwarven invention. Rather then using wood and wind, they use metal, coal, and fire. Stronger than normal ships, they are capable of carrying many more cannons. Whoever came up with the rhyme "Dwarves abhor the seas" clearly was not informed about the ironclad.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Anonymous[\ITALICS]</German>
		<Italian>Vorresti dirmi che una nave, senza vele, vi ha raggiunto, contro vento, attaccandovi di notte, ed è l'unica responsabile per la distruzione di quattro navi sotto il tuo comando? Ti faccio vedere cosa succede a chi mi mente.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Capitan Blackheart, qualche secondo prima di ordinare l'esecuzione del Capitano Johnathan Whiler[\ITALICS][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Le Corazzate sono un'invenzione nanica. Invece di usare il legno e il vento loro usano il metallo, il carbone e il fuoco. Più forti delle navi normali possono trasportare molti più cannoni. Chiunque abbia creato la rima "I nani aborriscono i mari" non era stato sicuramente informato delle Corazzate.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Anonimo[\ITALICS]</Italian>
		<Spanish>You mean to tell me that a ship without sails came at you, against the wind, to attack you in the middle of the night, and was solely responsible for the destruction of the four ships under your command? I'll teach you to lie to me.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Captain Blackheart, moments before ordering the execution of Captain Johnathan Whiler[\ITALICS][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ironclads are truly a dwarven invention. Rather then using wood and wind, they use metal, coal, and fire. Stronger than normal ships, they are capable of carrying many more cannons. Whoever came up with the rhyme "Dwarves abhor the seas" clearly was not informed about the ironclad.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Anonymous[\ITALICS]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MAROS</Tag>
		<English>Maros</English>
		<French>Maros</French>
		<German>Maros</German>
		<Italian>Maros</Italian>
		<Spanish>Maros</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MAROS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Fear has no place in a dwarf's heart, and many dwarves consider Maros, who was to be their greatest champion, their greatest disappointment. His father was the Umberguard, the Keeper of Keys, Micah, the King of Stone. He was never beaten in battle, and his honor remained untarnished until the day he died.[PARAGRAPH:1]But he did die. The Underdark is a cruel place and only the most cruel can hope to survive there. For centuries the hold of the dwarves had been surrounded by wild cities of deep goblins. Together they could have overrun the dwarves, but they were never coordinated enough to launch any serious attack. Then one day they came flooding through the gates. The dwarves stood to defend their hold; they slaughtered hundreds of goblins, many of which didn't even defend themselves. They weren't attacking, they were running.[PARAGRAPH:1]The following day, a demon approached the dwarven city gates. Flush and crooked, the demon picked at the goblin corpses still lying outside the city. When it finally hailed the city, it offered a deal: instead of a war between the demons and dwarves, they should settle it with honor. A battle between their champions, if the demons win, the dwarves abandon their city; if the dwarves win, then the demons will leave them be.[PARAGRAPH:1]Micah accepted and a thrull was brought forward to fight on the demons' behalf. The thrull looked to have once been a Svartalfar, now possessed by something darker. Unwilling to leave the city vulnerable, a small sidegate was opened and the thrull entered, bringing with it only a ill-fitting chain shirt and thin sword. The fight was brief and fierce, but by the end King Micah was again victorious. The Thrull had managed only a few minor cuts before falling under Micah's powerful hammer.[PARAGRAPH:1]That night Micah died, for the thrull blade had been poisoned. Maros's uncle was crowned King, and he made another deal with the demons. He claimed Micah was a hero, that the demons had been underhanded, but they must now honor their pact: they had lost the deal and they must leave the dwarves be because of it. And that seemed to be what they did.[PARAGRAPH:1]But Maros didn't believe it. He warned his people about the demons' treachery, told them that the demons must be fought not compromised with, that his Uncle wasn't a dwarven hero, he was a pawn of the demons. Then he left the underdark and enlisted in the Order.[PARAGRAPH:1]He was supposed to be king one day; it is said that the Umberguard is to be the champion of Kilmorph when all else has fallen. It is a birthright passed from father to son. Maros is the last of the line, and he will have no children. If there truly is such as a thing as the Umberguard, it dies with him.</English>
		<French>La peur n'a pas sa place dans le c&#156;ur d'un nain, et beaucoup considèrent Maros, qui fut leur plus grand champion, comme leur plus grande déception. Son père était le Gardien des Ombres, le Protecteur des Clés, Micah, le roi de Pierre. Il n'a jamais été vaincu au combat, et son honneur est resté intact jusqu'au jour de sa mort.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mais il est mort. Les Sousténèbres sont un lei cruel où seuls les plus cruels peuvent espérer survivre. Pendant des siècles le territoire des nains avait été encerclé par des cités sauvages de gobelins des profondeurs. Ensemble, ils auraient pu vaincre les nains, mais non jamais été assez coordonnés pour lancer une attaque sérieuse. Puis un jour ils arrivèrent en masse aux portes. Les nains se dressèrent pour défendre leur forteresse ; Ils massacrèrent des centaines de gobelins, dont la plupart ne se sont même pas défendus. Ils n'attaquaient pas, ils fuyaient.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le jour suivant, un démon s'approcha des portes de la ville naine. Couvert de rougeurs et souffreteux, le démon piqua dans le tas de corps de gobelins gisant toujours à l'extérieur de la ville. Quand il parvint finalement à la ville, il proposa un marché : plutôt qu'une guerre entre les démons et les nains, ils devraient régler le problème honorablement par un combat entre leurs champions. Si les démons gagnaient les nains abandonneraient leur ville ; si les nains gagnaient, les démons les laisseraient tranquilles.[PARAGRAPH:1]Micah accepta et un thrull fut amené pour combattre de côté des démons. Le thrull semblait avoir été un jour un Svartálfur, possédé aujourd'hui par quelque chose de pus sombre. Peu désireux de laisser la ville vulnérable, une petite porte dérobée fut ouverte pour faire entrer le thrull, n'apportant qu'une cotte de mailles mal ajustée et une lame fine. Le combat fur bref et intense, mais à l'issue le Roi Micah était encore une fois victorieux. Le Thrull n'était parvenu qu'à infliger de petites entailles avant de tomber face au puissant marteau de Micah.[PARAGRAPH:1]Micah mourut cette nuit là, la lame du thrull étaient empoisonnée. L'oncle de Maros fut couronnée roi, et il fit un autre pacte avec les démons. Il prétendit que Micah était un héros, que les démons avaient été sournois, mais qu'ils devraient maintenant honorer leur pacte : ils avaient perdu et pour cela devaient laisser les nains. Et il sembla que ce fut ce qu'ils firent.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mais Maros n'y croyait pas. Il prévint son peuple du subterfuge des démons, leur dit que les démons devaient être combattus au lieu de faire des pactes avec eux, que son oncle n'était pas un héros nain, que c'était un pion à la solde des démons. Puis il quitta les Sousténèbres et s'engagea dans l'Ordre.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il devait devenir roi un jour ; que le Gardien des Ombres serait le champion de Kilmorph quand tout le reste serait tombé. C'est un droit de naissance passé de père à fils. Maros est le dernier de sa lignée et il n'aura pas d'enfants. S'il existe vraiment quelque chose comme le Gardien des Ombres, ça mourra avec lui</French>
		<German>Angst hat keinen Platz im Herzen eines Zwerges und viele Zwerge halten Maros, der ihr größter Champion sein sollte, für ihre größte Enttäuschung. Sein Vater war die Umbrawache, der Hüter des Schlüssels, Micah, der König des Steins. Er war unbesiegt in der Schlacht und seine Ehre blieb bis zum dem Tag, an dem er starb, unbefleckt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Aber er starb. Unter der Erde ist es grausam und nur die grausamsten können darauf hoffen, dort zu überleben. Für Jahrhunderte war die Heimat der Zwerge von den wilden Städten der Höhlengoblins umgeben. Zusammen hätten sie die Zwerge überrennen können, aber sie waren niemals koordiniert genug, um einen richtigen Angriff zu beginnen. Dann, eines Tages, kamen sie durch die Tore geströmt. Die Zwerge stellten sich ihnen entgegen, um ihre Heimat zu verteidigen; sie schlachteten hunderte von Goblins ab, viele von ihnen verteidigten sich noch nicht einmal. Sie griffen nicht an, sie flohen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Am darauf folgenden Tag erschien ein Dämon vor den Toren der Zwergenstadt. Blutverschmiert und gebeugt stocherte er in den Leichen der Goblins herum, die noch immer vor den Toren der Stadt lagen. Als er schließlich die Stadt anrief, bot er ihr einen Handel an: Anstatt eines Krieges zwischen den Dämonen und den Zwergen sollten sie es mit Ehre regeln. Ein Kampf zwischen ihren Champions. Sollten die Dämonen gewinnen, verlassen die Zwerge ihre Stadt; sollten die Zwerge gewinnen, dann werden die Dämonen sie in Ruhe lassen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Micah akzeptierte und ein willenloser Sklave wurde aufgestellt, um für die Seite der Dämonen zu kämpfen. Der Sklave sah aus, als wäre er einst ein Svartalfar gewesen, nun aber besessen von etwas dunklerem. Unwillig die Stadt angreifbar zu machen, wurde ein kleines Seitentor geöffnet und der Sklave trat, nur mit einem schlecht sitzenden Kettenhemd und einem dünnen Schwert ausgerüstet, ein. Der Kampf war kurz und heftig, aber am Ende war König Micah wieder einmal siegreich. Der Sklave konnte König Micah nur ein paar kleine Schnitte zufügen, bevor er von seinem mächtigen Hammer gefällt wurde.[PARAGRAPH:1]Noch in dieser Nacht starb Micah, da das Schwert des Sklaven vergiftet war. Maros Onkel wurde als König gekrönt und er machte einen weiteren Handel mit den Dämonen. Er erklärte Micah zu einem Helden, der zwar von den Dämonen hereingelegt worden war, aber sie müssten jetzt den Pakt ehren: Sie haben den Handel verloren und müssten nun die Zwerge deswegen in Ruhe lassen. Und es schien so, als würden sie sich daran halten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Aber Maros glaubte nicht daran. Er warnte sein Volk vor dem Verrat der Dämonen, erklärte ihnen, dass die Dämonen bekämpft werden müssten und keine Kompromisse mit ihnen geschlossen werden dürften, dass sein Onkel kein Zwergenheld sei, sondern ein Werkzeug der Dämonen. Dann verließ er die Welt unter der Erde und trat der Religion der Weisung bei.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er hätte eines Tages König werden sollen; es wird gesagt, dass die Umbrawache der Champion von Kilmorph sei, wenn alles andere untergegangen ist. Es ist ein Geburtsrecht, das vom Vater an den Sohn übergeht. Maros ist der letzte dieser Linie und er wird keine Kinder haben. Sollte es wirklich so etwas wie die Umbrawache geben, dann stirbt sie mit ihm.</German>
		<Italian>Non c'è posto nel cuore di un nano per la paura, e molti nani considerano Maros, che era uno dei loro più grandi campioni, la loro più grande delusione. Suo padre era il Guardiano delle Ombre, il Custode delle Chiavi, Micah, il Re di Pietra. Non era mai stato sconfitto in battaglia, e il suo onore rimase senza macchia sino al giorno in cui morì.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il sottosuolo è un posto crudele e solo i più crudeli vi sopravvivono. Per secoli la fortezza dei nani fu circondata da città selvaggie di goblin delle profondità. Uniti avrebbero potuto sconfiggere i nani, ma non erano mai abbastanza coordinati da lanciare alcun attacco serio. Poi un giorno arrivarono in massa dai cancelli. I nani si ersero a difesa della loro città; uccisero centinai di goblin, molti dei quali neppure si difendevano. Loro non stavano attacando, loro stavano scappando.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il giorno seguente un demone si avvicinò ai cancelli nanici. Di color rosso e ricurvo, il demone infierì sui corpi dei goblin che erano fuori dalla città. Quando infine si rivolse alla città offrì un patto: invece di iniziare una guerra tra demoni e nani si sarebbe risolto con onore la questione. Uno scontro tra i loro campioni, se i demoni avessero vinto i nani avrebbero abbandonato la loro città; se i nani avessero vinto allora i demoni li avrebbero lasciati in pace.[PARAGRAPH:1]Micah accettò e un thrull fu fatto avanzare per combattere per conto dei demoni. Il thrull sembrava esser stato uno Svartalfar, ma ora era posseduto da quacosa di più oscuro. Non volendo lasciare la città vulnerabile, un piccolo cancello laterale fù aperto e il thrull vi entrò, portando con se solo un giacco di maglia che gli stava male e una spada sottile. Lo scontro fù breve e feroce, ma alla fine il Re Micah fù il vincitore ancora una volta. Il Thrull riuscì soltanto a causare qualche taglio minore prima di soccombere al potente martello di Micah.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quella stessa notte Micah morì, in quanto la lama del thrull era stata avvelenata. Lo zio di Maros fù incoronato Re, e fece un'altro patto con i demoni. Lui affermò che Micah era un eroe, che i demoni erano stati subdoli, ma che dovevano ora onorare la loro parte del patto: avevano perso e dovevano lasciare in pace i nani di conseguenza. E quello fu ciò che sembrava stessero facendo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ma Maros non ci credeva. Aveva avvisato il suo popolo della slealtà dei demoni, gli aveva detto che i demoni erano da combattere non da farci accordi, che suo zio non era un eroe nanico, ma bensì una pedina dei demoni. Poi abbandonò il sottosuolo e si arruolò nell'Ordine.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sarebbe dovuto diventare re un giorno; si dice che essere il Guardiano delle Ombre significa essere il campione di Kilmorph quando tutto il resto è caduto. È un diritto di nascita passato da padre a figlio. Maros è l'ultimo della sua stirpe, e lui non avrà figli. Se vi è veramente qualcosa come il Guardiano delle Ombre, esso morirà con lui.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Fear has no place in a dwarf's heart, and many dwarves consider Maros, who was to be their greatest champion, their greatest disappointment. His father was the Umberguard, the Keeper of Keys, Micah, the King of Stone. He was never beaten in battle, and his honor remained untarnished until the day he died.[PARAGRAPH:1]But he did die. The Underdark is a cruel place and only the most cruel can hope to survive there. For centuries the hold of the dwarves had been surrounded by wild cities of deep goblins. Together they could have overrun the dwarves, but they were never coordinated enough to launch any serious attack. Then one day they came flooding through the gates. The dwarves stood to defend their hold; they slaughtered hundreds of goblins, many of which didn't even defend themselves. They weren't attacking, they were running.[PARAGRAPH:1]The following day, a demon approached the dwarven city gates. Flush and crooked, the demon picked at the goblin corpses still lying outside the city. When it finally hailed the city, it offered a deal: instead of a war between the demons and dwarves, they should settle it with honor. A battle between their champions, if the demons win, the dwarves abandon their city; if the dwarves win, then the demons will leave them be.[PARAGRAPH:1]Micah accepted and a thrull was brought forward to fight on the demons' behalf. The thrull looked to have once been a Svartalfar, now possessed by something darker. Unwilling to leave the city vulnerable, a small sidegate was opened and the thrull entered, bringing with it only a ill-fitting chain shirt and thin sword. The fight was brief and fierce, but by the end King Micah was again victorious. The Thrull had managed only a few minor cuts before falling under Micah's powerful hammer.[PARAGRAPH:1]That night Micah died, for the thrull blade had been poisoned. Maros's uncle was crowned King, and he made another deal with the demons. He claimed Micah was a hero, that the demons had been underhanded, but they must now honor their pact: they had lost the deal and they must leave the dwarves be because of it. And that seemed to be what they did.[PARAGRAPH:1]But Maros didn't believe it. He warned his people about the demons' treachery, told them that the demons must be fought not compromised with, that his Uncle wasn't a dwarven hero, he was a pawn of the demons. Then he left the underdark and enlisted in the Order.[PARAGRAPH:1]He was supposed to be king one day; it is said that the Umberguard is to be the champion of Kilmorph when all else has fallen. It is a birthright passed from father to son. Maros is the last of the line, and he will have no children. If there truly is such as a thing as the Umberguard, it dies with him.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MYCONID</Tag>
		<English>Myconid</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Myconide:Myconides</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Myconoid</German>
		<Italian>Myconide</Italian>
		<Spanish>Myconid</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MYCONID_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>There are strange creatures deep beneath the earth. It was on the borders of vast underground lakes that the Khazad met one of the most unusual, the Myconid. The Myconid tend to their glowing fungi forests and live quiet lives far from the sun. But late in the Age of Rebirth, if the Khazad need their strength (and their intoxicating spore clouds) the Myconid will come and fight beside those that befriended them in the underhome.</English>
		<French>There are strange creatures deep beneath the earth. It was on the borders of vast underground lakes that the Khazad met one of the most unusual, the Myconid. The Myconid tend to their glowing fungi forests and live quiet lives far from the sun. But late in the Age of Rebirth, if the Khazad need their strength (and their intoxicating spore clouds) the Myconid will come and fight beside those that befriended them in the underhome.</French>
		<German>Seltsame Kreaturen verbergen sich tief im Innern der Erde. Es war am Rande der gewaltigen unterirdischen Seen, wo die Khazad, auf eines der ungewöhnlichsten Wesen zustiessen, den Mykonid. Der Mykonid tendiert, still für sich verborgen, in den glühenden, pilzigen Wäldern zu leben, fernab jeglichem Sonnenlichte. Später jedoch, in der Zeit des Wiedergeburtes, als die Khazad ihre Stärke benötigten (ebenso ihre berauschenden Wolken der Sporen), erschien der Mykonid und kämpft seitdem gern beiseitens derer, die ihn einst in der Unterwelt akzeptierten.</German>
		<Italian>Vi sono strane creature nelle profondità della terra. Ed è sui bordi degli ampi laghi sotterranei che i Khazad incontrarono una delle più inusuali, i Myconidi. I Myconidi si prendono cura delle loro foreste di funghi luminescenti, e vivono semplici vite lontano dalla luce del sole. Ma nella parte finale dell'Era della Rinascita, se i Khazad avessero bisogno della loro forza (e delle loro nubi di spore tossiche) i Myconidi risponderebbero alla chiamata e combatterebbero al fianco di coloro che hanno stretto amicizia con loro nel Sottosuolo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>There are strange creatures deep beneath the earth. It was on the borders of vast underground lakes that the Khazad met one of the most unusual, the Myconid. The Myconid tend to their glowing fungi forests and live quiet lives far from the sun. But late in the Age of Rebirth, if the Khazad need their strength (and their intoxicating spore clouds) the Myconid will come and fight beside those that befriended them in the underhome.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MYCONID_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Myconids replace Beastmasters for the Khazad. They don't receive subdue beast or subdue animal promotions, but they can immobilize foes with their Spores spell.</English>
		<French>Myconids replace Beastmasters for the Khazad. They don't receive subdue beast or subdue animal promotions, but they can immobilize foes with their Spores spell.</French>
		<German>Die Myconoiden ersetzen bei den Khazad die Bestienmeister. Sie erhalten zwar nicht die Bestienzähmung- und Tierzähmungsbeförderungen, aber sie können mit ihrem Sporen-Zauberspruch ihre Gegner lähmen.</German>
		<Italian>Il Myconide rimpiazza il Signore delle Bestie per i Khazad. Non possiedono le promozioni Sottometti Animale o Sottometti Bestia, ma possono immobilizare i nemici con la loro magia Spore.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Myconids replace Beastmasters for the Khazad. They don't receive subdue beast or subdue animal promotions, but they can immobilize foes with their Spores spell.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TREBUCHET</Tag>
		<English>Trebuchet</English>
		<French>Trébuchet</French>
		<German>Tribok</German>
		<Italian>Trabucco</Italian>
		<Spanish>Trebuchet</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MISC_DWARVEN_VAULT_1EMPTY</Tag>
		<English>empty &lt;[SPACE]</English>
		<French>Vide &lt;[SPACE]</French>
		<German>Leer &lt;[SPACE]</German>
		<Italian>empty &lt;[SPACE]</Italian>
		<Spanish>empty &lt;[SPACE]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MISC_DWARVEN_VAULT_2LOW</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE]&lt; low &lt;[SPACE]</English>
		<French>[SPACE]&lt; Basse &lt;[SPACE]</French>
		<German>[SPACE]&lt; kaum gefüllt &lt;[SPACE]</German>
		<Italian>[SPACE]&lt; low &lt;[SPACE]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[SPACE]&lt; low &lt;[SPACE]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MISC_DWARVEN_VAULT_3AVERAGE</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE]&lt; average &lt;[SPACE]</English>
		<French>[SPACE]&lt; Acceptable &lt;[SPACE]</French>
		<German>[SPACE]&lt; average &lt;[SPACE]</German>
		<Italian>[SPACE]&lt; average &lt;[SPACE]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[SPACE]&lt; average &lt;[SPACE]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MISC_DWARVEN_VAULT_4STOCKED</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE]&lt; stocked &lt;[SPACE]</English>
		<French>[SPACE]&lt; Approvisionnée &lt;[SPACE]</French>
		<German>[SPACE]&lt; Gut gefüllt &lt;[SPACE]</German>
		<Italian>[SPACE]&lt; stocked &lt;[SPACE]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[SPACE]&lt; stocked &lt;[SPACE]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MISC_DWARVEN_VAULT_5ABUNDANT</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE]&lt; abundant &lt;[SPACE]</English>
		<French>[SPACE]&lt; Abondante &lt;[SPACE]</French>
		<German>[SPACE]&lt; Reichlich gefüllt &lt;[SPACE]</German>
		<Italian>[SPACE]&lt; abundant &lt;[SPACE]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[SPACE]&lt; abundant &lt;[SPACE]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MISC_DWARVEN_VAULT_6FULL</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE]&lt; full &lt;[SPACE]</English>
		<French>[SPACE]&lt; Pleine &lt;[SPACE]</French>
		<German>[SPACE]&lt; Voll &lt;[SPACE]</German>
		<Italian>[SPACE]&lt; full &lt;[SPACE]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[SPACE]&lt; full &lt;[SPACE]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MISC_DWARVEN_VAULT_7OVERFLOWING</Tag>
		<English>[SPACE]&lt; overflowing</English>
		<French>[SPACE]&lt; Débordante</French>
		<German>[SPACE]&lt; Überfüllt</German>
		<Italian>[SPACE]&lt; overflowing</Italian>
		<Spanish>[SPACE]&lt; overflowing</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
