<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ILLIANS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Illian</English>
		<French>illian:illiane:illians:illianes</French>
		<German>Illianisch</German>
		<Italian>Illian</Italian>
		<Spanish>Illian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ILLIANS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Illians</English>
		<French>Illia</French>
		<German>Reich der Illian</German>
		<Italian>Illian</Italian>
		<Spanish>Illians</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ILLIANS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Illians</English>
		<French>Illians</French>
		<German>Illian</German>
		<Italian>Illian</Italian>
		<Spanish>Illians</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ILLIANS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The lost men of Letum Frigus. They banded together behind Auric Ulvin for a chance to recover their lost dominance. It is said that when the Illians awake, the world sleeps; and when the world sleeps, the Illians awake.</English>
		<French>[TAB] Les hommes perdus de Letum Frigus. Ils se sont rassemblés derrière Auric Ulvin pour avoir une chance de recouvrer leur domination perdue. Il est dit que lorsque le monde est eveillé, les Illians dorment ; et lorsque le monde s'endort, les Illians s'éveillent.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Verlorenen von Letum Frigus. Für die Aussicht, ihre verloren gegangene Vorherrschaft über Erebus wiederzuerlangen, haben sie sich unter der Führung von Auric Ulvin zusammengerottet. Es heißt, dass, wenn die Illianer erwachen, die Welt schläft; und wenn die Welt schläft, erwachen die Illianer.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Gli uomini perduti del Letum Frigus. Si riunirono sotto Auric Ulvin per avere la possibilità di recuperare la loro supremazia perduta. Si dice che quando gli Illian si svegliano il mondo dorme; e che quando il mondo si sveglia gli Illian dormono.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Los hombres perdidos de Letum Frigus. Se fueron juntos detrás de Auric Ulvin para tener la oportunidad de recobrar su perdida dominación.  Se dice que cuando los Illians despertaron, el mundo durmió; y que cuando el mundo duerme, los Illians despiertan.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ILLIANS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[TODO Draft]Terraforming. Illians create polar climate. (It's the 2nd level of cold. The associated terrain is tundra). If they convert to White Hand religion, they will create the 3rd level of cold: Fimbulwinter, with glacier terrain.</English>
		<French>Illia</French>
		<German>Reich der Illian</German>
		<Italian>Illians</Italian>
		<Spanish>Illians</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_AURIC</Tag>
		<English>Auric Ulvin</English>
		<French>Auric Ulvin</French>
		<German>Auric Ulvin</German>
		<Italian>Auric Ulvin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Auric Ulvin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_AURIC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Auric is the leader of the White Hand. He won't accept any other state religion[PARAGRAPH:2][TAB]Following visions and dreams, Auric stumbled across the frozen wastes, his companions left forgotten or dead behind him. He couldn't tell if he was going toward or away from the ivory dragon that haunted him, whose roar echoed in his head, whose wings stretched as far as the horizon. The dragon would kill him, he would be better off to lay down in the snow and die, but he kept going.[PARAGRAPH:1]Would the cold even kill him? He wore prisoner's rags and had been marching for days through a blizzard without any apparent harmful effect. Well, except for the madness. But whether the madness was caused by the cold, shielded him from the cold, or just made him think it shielded him from the cold didn't matter to him. He continued to walk.[PARAGRAPH:1]He would later call the area Letum Frigus, a collapsed mountain surrounded for miles by concentric rings of ice, like frozen waves heading away from a central point. The mountain was once filled with massive caverns, most now destroyed, but deep within the rubble some remained.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric wandered through what was left of the caverns for days, slowly going deeper into the mountain, turned back over and over by blocked passages as he was pressed on by spirits that didn't see the labyrinth as it was, only as it had been. He knew he was being watched, men from past ages, living ghosts that remained at this sacred place even though their god was gone. The people he would later call Illians. Auric even saw the bodies of others that had walked here before him, killed by the Illians. But they would not attack him. When Auric found the heart of the mountain, he stood outside and looked through the broken archway that lead into it. Not even the Illians dared enter the chamber. When Auric reached out to detect anything divine or arcane in the chamber there was nothing. Echoes of past deeds, visions of a great sword with 21 glyphs on its blade, but nothing real. No danger, nothing worth making this trek, nothing worth even stepping over the threshold to enter the room. But he entered anyway.[PARAGRAPH:1]Three days later, Auric Ulvin came out of the chamber, he was no longer the disheveled boy of Auspire, the teenage prisoner of the Shadowed Vale, the son of a widowed farmer's wife. What he was is now is not clear to anyone, and Auric never spoke of what occurred in the chamber, but he commanded the obedience of the Illians when he came out.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Once you had been the greatest of scholars and priests, tributes were paid to you by all nations. You think those days are past, you dream of the return of your lord and I tell you, he will not come. I am your lord now, forget what you have lost, and think only on what can be gained; follow me and I will return your glory. This world will be yours again."[PARAGRAPH:1]They heard Auric's call, and they followed him.</English>
		<French>Auric est le guide de la Main Blanche. Il n'autorisera aucune autre religion d'État.[PARAGRAPH:2][TAB]Suivant des visions et des rêves, Auric tomba par hasard sur les étendues de glace désolées, il avait déjà oublié ses compagnons, du moins ceux qui n'étaient pas morts en le suivant. Il n'aurait pas su dire s'il courait après ou s'il fuyait le dragon d'ivoire qui le pourchassait, dont le grognement résonnait dans sa tête, dont les ailes étaient aussi larges que l'horizon. Le dragon le tuerait, il serait préférable de s'effondrer dans la neige et de mourir, mais il continua d'avancer.[PARAGRAPH:1]Si même le froid pouvait le tuer, il portait des loques de prisonnier et marchait depuis des jours dans le blizzard sans conqéquence apparente. Enfin si ce n'est la folie.  Mais si la folie était provoquée par le froid, se prémunir du froid ou même avoir l'impression d'en être prémuni n'avait aucune importance pour lui. Il continuait à marcher.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il baptiserait plus tard cette endroit Letum Frigus, une montagne dévastée entourée sur des kilomètres par des cercles concentriques de glace, comme des vagues de glace fuyant un même point central.  La montagne avait un jour été creusée de nombreuses cavernes, la plupart aujourd'hui détruites, mais certaines demeuraient enfoncées profondément sous les décombres.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric se demandait ce qu'il restait de ces cavernes depuis tout ce temps, tout en s'enfonçant doucement de plus en plus au c&#156;ur de la montagne, faisant régulièrement demi-tour devant des passages bloqués, pressé par des esprits qui ne voyaient pas le labyrinthe tel quel, mais tel qu'il avait été jadis.  Il se sentait observé par des hommes des anciens âges, des fantômes demeurant dans ce lieu sacré même si leur dieu n'était plus.  Il baptiserait plus tard ces gens les Illiens.  Auric vit même les corps d'autres personnes passées ici avant lui, tuées par les Illiens. Mais ils ne l'attaqueraient pas lui.  Quand Auric trouva le c&#156;ur de la montagne, il resta à l'extérieur et jeta un coup d'oeil à travers l'arche brisée qui y menait.  Même les Illiens ne daignaient pas entrer dans la chambre.  Quand Auric partit à la recherche de quoi que ce soit de divin ou de magique dans la chambre, il n'y avait rien. Les échos de rites passés, la vision d'une épée avec 21 glyphes sur sa lame, mais rien de réel.  Aucun danger, rien qui rende l'endroit pénible, rien non plus qui donne envie de franchir le seuil et d'entrer. Mais il entra quand même.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric Ulvin resortit de la chambre trois jours plus tard, il n'était plus le gamin débraillé d'Auspire, l'adolescent prisonnier de la Vallée des Ombres, le fils de la veuve d'un fermier. Ce qu'il était devenu n'est certain pour personne, et Auric ne raconta jamais ce qui s'était passé dans la chambre mais il avait l'obéissance des Illiens lorsqu'il resortit.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Vous avez jadis été les plus grands des professeurs et des prêtres, toutes les nations vous payaient un tribut.  Vous pensez ces jours révolus, vous rêvez du retour de votre seigneur, mais je vous le dis, il ne viendra pas.  Je suis votre seigneur maintenant, oubliez ce que vous avez perdu et ne pensez plus qu'à ce qui peut etre gagné, suivez-moi et vous retrouverez votre gloire.  Ce monde sera de nouveau le vôtre."[PARAGRAPH:1]Ils ont entendu l'appel d'Auric, et ils l'ont suivi.</French>
		<German>Auric is the leader of the White Hand. He won't accept any other state religion[PARAGRAPH:2][TAB]Von Visionen und Träumen geplagt, stürzte Auric über die eisige Wüste, seine Gefährten hatte er vergessen oder tot zurückgelassen. Er wusste nicht, ob er floh, oder geradewegs auf den elfenbeinernen Drachen zulief, der ihn verfolgte, dessen Brüllen in seinem Kopf widerhallte, und dessen Flügel sich so weit wie der Horizont erstreckten. Der Drache würde ihn töten, es wäre besser für ihn, sich in den Schnee fallen zu lassen und zu sterben, aber er konnte nicht einhalten.[PARAGRAPH:1] Könnte die Kälte ihn überhaupt töten? Er war in eiserne Ketten gelegt worden, und war tagelang durch Schneestürme marschiert, ohne auch nur eine Beeinträchtigung zu erleiden. Gut, abgesehen vom Wahnsinn. Aber ob der Wahnsinn von der Kälte verursacht wurde, ihn vor der Kälte schützte, oder ihn nur glauben machte, er wäre vor der Kälte geschützt, war ihm einerlei. Er setzte seinen Marsch fort.[PARAGRAPH:1]Später würde er diese Gegend Letum Frigus nennen, ein zusammengestürzter Berg, der meilenweit von konzentrischen Eisringen umgeben war, gleich gefrorener Wellen, die sich von einem Mittelpunkt wegbewegten. Der Berg war einst voll von massiven Höhlen gewesen, doch die meisten waren schon zerstört. Einzig tief im Bruchgestein hatten ein paar überdauert.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric durchwanderte die Überreste der Höhlen für Tage, langsam drang er tiefer in den Berg vor, und wurde immer wieder zur Umkehr gezwungen, von eingestürzten und blockierten Gängen, während er weitergetrieben wurde von Gespinsten, die das Labyrinth nicht sahen wie es war, sondern wie es einst ausgesehen hatte. Er wusste, dass er beobachtet wurde, von Menschen aus vergangenen Zeiten, lebenden Geistern die an diesem heiligen Ort verblieben waren, obwohl ihr Gott vergangen war. Diese Geister würde er später Illianer nennen. Auric sah sogar Leichen von anderen die vor ihm hier gewandert waren, bevor sie von den Illianern getötet wurden. Aber ihn griffen sie nicht an. Als Auric das Herz des Berges gefunden hatte, blieb er außerhalb stehen und sah durch den zerbrochenen Bogengang, der hinein führte. Selbst die Illianer wagten es nicht, die Kammer zu betreten. Auric fand nichts, als er erfühlte ob etwas Göttliches oder weltliches in der Kammer zu finden wäre. Echos vergangener Taten, Bilder eines großen Schwertes mit 21 Glyphen auf der Klinge, aber nichts Wirkliches. Keine Gefahr, nichts was diese Reise wert gewesen wäre, nichts was es auch nur wert wäre, die Schwelle zu überschreiten und den Raum zu betreten. Doch er betrat ihn trotzdem.[PARAGRAPH:1]Drei Tage später kam Auric Ulvin aus der Kammer, doch er war nicht länger der zerzauste Junge aus Auspire, der jugendliche Gefangen des Beschatteten Tales, der Sohn einer Bauerswitwe. Was er jetzt war vermag niemand zu ergründen, und Auric sprach nie davon, was in dieser Kammer vorgefallen war, aber er befahl den Illianern Gehorsam, als er hinauskam.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Einst wart ihr die größten der Gelehrten und Priester, und ganze Nationen zollten euch Tribut. Ihr glaubt, dass diese Tage vergangen sind, und träumt von der Rückkehr eures Herren, doch ich sage euch, er wird nicht mehr zurückkehren. Denn nun bin ich euer Herr, vergesst, was ihr verloren habt, und denkt nur noch an das, was ihr erringen könnt; folgt nun mir, und ich werde euch euren Ruhm zurückgeben. Diese Welt, wird wieder die eure sein."[PARAGRAPH:1]Und sie hörten Aurics Ruf, und sie folgten ihm.</German>
		<Italian>Auric è il leader della Mano Bianca. Non accetterà nessun'altra religione di stato[PARAGRAPH:2][TAB]Seguendo visioni e sogni, Auric arrivò nelle distese gelate, i suoi compagni dimenticati o morti dietro di lui. Non sapeva dire se stava andando verso o se si stava allontanando dal drago d'avorio che lo perseguitava, il cui ruggito rieccheggiava nella sua testa, le cui ali si estendevano sino all'orizzonte. Il drago l'avrebbe ucciso, forse avrebbe fatto meglio a distendersi nella neve e morire, invece continuò a muoversi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sarebbe stato il freddo ad ucciderlo? Indossava degli stracci da prigioniero ed aveva camminato per giorni in mezzo a una tempesta di neve senza alcuna ripercussione negativa apparente. Insomma, a parte la pazzia. Ma se anche la pazzia fosse stata causata dal freddo, lo proteggesse dal freddo o semplicemente gli faceva pensare che lo proteggeva non era una cosa che gli importava. Lui continuava a camminare.[PARAGRAPH:1]In seguito avrebbe chiamato quel luogo Letum Frigus, una montagna crollata circondata per miglia da cerchi concentrici di ghiaccio, come fossere onde congelate che si allontanavano da un punto centrale. La montagna un tempo era piena di enormi caverne, la maggior parte ora distrutte, ma in profondita sotto le macerie alcune erano ancora presenti.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric girovagò per giorni in quel che restava delle caverne, inoltrandosi lentamente sempre più in profondità nella montagna, ritornando sui suoi passi ogni volta che la strada era bloccata mentre veniva spronato da spiriti che non vedevano il labirinto per come era adesso ma solo per come era un tempo. Lui sapeva di essere osservato da uomini delle ere passate, fantasmi viventi di coloro che erano rimasti in questo luogo sacro anche dopo la scomparsa del loro dio. Il popolo che in seguito avrebbe chiamato Illian. Auric vide pure i corpi di coloro che erano giunti qui prima di lui, uccisi dagli Illian. Ma non avrebbero attaccato lui. Quando Auric trovò il cuore della montagna rimase fuori e guardò attraverso l'arco spezzato che faceva da entrata. Neppure gli Illian osavano entrare nella camera. Quando Auric cercò d'individuare la presenza di eventuali cose divine o arcane nella camera non trovò nulla. Echi di imprese passate, visioni riguardanti una grande spada con 21 glifi sulla sua lama, ma nulla di reale. Nessun pericolo, niente per cui valeva fare il viaggio o oltrepassare la soglia e entrare nella camera. Ma lui vi entrò comunque.[PARAGRAPH:1]Tre giorni dopo, Auric Ulvin uscì dalla camera, non era più il trasandato ragazzo di Auspire, il prigioniero adolescente della Valle Adombrata, il figlio di una vedova contadina. Cosa lui fosse ora non lo sapeva nessuno, e Auric non parlò mai di cosa accadde nella camera, ma quando ne uscì gli Illian gli obbedirono.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Un tempo voi eravate i più grandi eruditi e sacerdoti e tutte le nazioni vi pagavano tributi. Pensate che quei giorni siano passati, sognate il ritorno del vostro signore e io vi dico che non tornerà. Io sono il vostro signore ora, dimenticate ciò che avete perduto e pensate solo a quello che può essere ottenuto; seguitemi e io vi renderò la vostra gloria. Questo mondo sarà vostro di nuovo."[PARAGRAPH:1]Loro sentirono il richiamo di Auric, e lo seguirono.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Auric is the leader of the White Hand. He won't accept any other state religion[PARAGRAPH:2][TAB]Siguiendo las visiones y los sueños, Auric daba traspiés a través de los páramos congelados, sus compañeros dejados atrás olvidados o muertos.  No podría decir si estaba acercándose o alejándose del ivory dragon that haunted him, whose roar echoed in his head, whose wings stretched as far as the horizon.  The dragon would kill him, he would be better off to lay down in the snow and die, but he kept going.[PARAGRAPH:1]Would the cold even kill him? He wore prisoner's rags and had been marching for days through a blizzard without any apparent harmful effect.  Well, except for the madness.  But whether the madness was caused by the cold, shielded him from the cold, or just made him think it shielded him from the cold didn't matter to him.  He continued to walk.[PARAGRAPH:1]He would later call the area Letum Frigus, a collapsed mountain surrounded for miles by concentric rings of ice, like frozen waves heading away from a central point.  The mountain was once filled with massive caverns, most now destroyed, but deep within the rubble some remained.[PARAGRAPH:1]Auric wandered through what was left of the caverns for days, slowly going deeper into the mountain, turned back over and over by blocked passages as he was pressed on by spirits that didn't see the labyrinth as it was, only as it had been.  He knew he was being watched, men from past ages, living ghosts that remained at this sacred place even though their god was gone.  The people he would later call Illians.  Auric even saw the bodies of others that had walked here before him, killed by the Illians.  But they would not attack him.  When Auric found the heart of the mountain, he stood outside and looked through the broken archway that lead into it.  Not even the Illians dared enter the chamber.  When Auric reached out to detect anything divine or arcane in the chamber there was nothing.  Echoes of past deeds, visions of a great sword with 21 glyphs on its blade, but nothing real.  No danger, nothing worth making this trek, nothing worth even stepping over the threshold to enter the room.  But he entered anyway.[PARAGRAPH:1]Three days later, Auric Ulvin came out of the chamber, he was no longer the disheveled boy of Auspire, the teenage prisoner of the Shadowed Vale, the son of a widowed farmer's wife.  What he was is now is not clear to anyone, and Auric never spoke of what occurred in the chamber, but he commanded the obedience of the Illians when he came out.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Once you had been the greatest of scholars and priests, tributes were paid to you by all nations.  You think those days are past, you dream of the return of your lord and I tell you, he will not come.  I am your lord now, forget what you have lost, and think only on what can be gained; follow me and I will return your glory.  This world will be yours again."[PARARAPH:1]They heard Auric's call, and they followed him.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_RAITLOR</Tag>
		<English>Raitlor</English>
		<French>Raitlor</French>
		<German>Raitlor</German>
		<Italian>Raitlor</Italian>
		<Spanish>Raitlor</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_RAITLOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>After Auric's defeat, the Illians empire fell. Most of its conquered parts were taken back by their rightful owner (sometimes triggering wars, but that's another story). The core of the Illians empire was being mopped up by various armies, like the Bannor, the Hippus and the Lanun. Although Auric was dead, many Illians were still loyal to him and fought to the death to defend the core, to remain independent.

Raitlor and her six sisters organized the militia of their town, ready to kill of the invaders in Auric's name. After the death of one of her sisters, Raitlor changed her mind. She tried to convince the others (and all other members of the militia) that they shouldn't fight, but rather accept their fate and surrender, because it would increase the odds of the survival of the Illians. She didn't find any support and was locked up while the militia launched an attack to take Garduk back.

Of course, the attack failed. All of Raitlor's sisters but one were killed. Leuk came back with very few survivors. They were all afraid of the supposedly incoming retaliation. Leuk went to talk with Raitlor and broke into tears, accabled with guilt over the death of her sisters, and becoming more aware that they should have supported Raitlor. Leuk was desperate that Auric had abandoned them. Raitlor calmed her down and showed her the snow falling outside, she told "Can't you see? He hasn't abandoned us, he's always been here, watching upon us. He did ascend, Leuk. What is the death of one's body for a god? Do you really believe that would stop Auric?".

Raitlor's beliefs gave hope to the town. They surrendered and became vassals of the Bannor. Raitlor was appointed as the mayor of the town; the other cities either fell to the wars or rallied themselves with Raitlor, surrendering their independence for a second chance.

(The Illians eventually broke off from vassalage because the Bannor didn't want to bother with them anymore, having to spend too much for them)

During the vassalage period, Raitlor's government focused on a new cult around Auric and opening new trade routes to put the Illian State back on tracks. Her government was very informal, ad hoc, but people accepted it and even saw her as the spokeperson of Auric, kind of. One thing leading to another, the government shaped itself around priests; Raitlor being the de facto first High Priestess of the White Hand. Because of their focus on trade, the White Hand became known outside the Illian State and spread there.

(Note that it's actually the outsiders who were naming it the White Hand, name which became used afterwards by the Illians themselves)

When the vassalage period ended, the efforts of Raitlor to keep the cohesion of her people strong became apparent: many immigrants came to the Illian State (whether newly converted to the White Hand or Illians who hide themselves after the defeat of Auric), no city tried to declare its independence and no one was questioning Raitlor's rule. But she did call for a big gathering, known as the "Winter Assembly", to officially decide on the one leader of the Illians, the shape of the government and many other things.

The main tendency was in favor of a White Hand-oriented government, an enforcement of their culture, a rejection of either councils but with the same focus on trade that was so beneficial. Raitlor was designed as the "Aurikvyarn", the "priest(ess) of Auric", both the head of the Illian State and the highest ranking priest of the White Hand; a kind of Pope if you prefer.

The Winter Assembly put the newly independent Illian State under the lights. Many states expressed their fear towards the growing popularity of the White Hand and towards the growing power of the Illian State. However, such fears were quickly dispersed by the apparition of the D'Tesh...


		</English>
		<French>After Auric's defeat, the Illians empire fell. Most of its conquered parts were taken back by their rightful owner (sometimes triggering wars, but that's another story). The core of the Illians empire was being mopped up by various armies, like the Bannor, the Hippus and the Lanun. Although Auric was dead, many Illians were still loyal to him and fought to the death to defend the core, to remain independent.

Raitlor and her six sisters organized the militia of their town, ready to kill of the invaders in Auric's name. After the death of one of her sisters, Raitlor changed her mind. She tried to convince the others (and all other members of the militia) that they shouldn't fight, but rather accept their fate and surrender, because it would increase the odds of the survival of the Illians. She didn't find any support and was locked up while the militia launched an attack to take Garduk back.

Of course, the attack failed. All of Raitlor's sisters but one were killed. Leuk came back with very few survivors. They were all afraid of the supposedly incoming retaliation. Leuk went to talk with Raitlor and broke into tears, accabled with guilt over the death of her sisters, and becoming more aware that they should have supported Raitlor. Leuk was desperate that Auric had abandoned them. Raitlor calmed her down and showed her the snow falling outside, she told "Can't you see? He hasn't abandoned us, he's always been here, watching upon us. He did ascend, Leuk. What is the death of one's body for a god? Do you really believe that would stop Auric?".

Raitlor's beliefs gave hope to the town. They surrendered and became vassals of the Bannor. Raitlor was appointed as the mayor of the town; the other cities either fell to the wars or rallied themselves with Raitlor, surrendering their independence for a second chance.

(The Illians eventually broke off from vassalage because the Bannor didn't want to bother with them anymore, having to spend too much for them)

During the vassalage period, Raitlor's government focused on a new cult around Auric and opening new trade routes to put the Illian State back on tracks. Her government was very informal, ad hoc, but people accepted it and even saw her as the spokeperson of Auric, kind of. One thing leading to another, the government shaped itself around priests; Raitlor being the de facto first High Priestess of the White Hand. Because of their focus on trade, the White Hand became known outside the Illian State and spread there.

(Note that it's actually the outsiders who were naming it the White Hand, name which became used afterwards by the Illians themselves)

When the vassalage period ended, the efforts of Raitlor to keep the cohesion of her people strong became apparent: many immigrants came to the Illian State (whether newly converted to the White Hand or Illians who hide themselves after the defeat of Auric), no city tried to declare its independence and no one was questioning Raitlor's rule. But she did call for a big gathering, known as the "Winter Assembly", to officially decide on the one leader of the Illians, the shape of the government and many other things.

The main tendency was in favor of a White Hand-oriented government, an enforcement of their culture, a rejection of either councils but with the same focus on trade that was so beneficial. Raitlor was designed as the "Aurikvyarn", the "priest(ess) of Auric", both the head of the Illian State and the highest ranking priest of the White Hand; a kind of Pope if you prefer.

The Winter Assembly put the newly independent Illian State under the lights. Many states expressed their fear towards the growing popularity of the White Hand and towards the growing power of the Illian State. However, such fears were quickly dispersed by the apparition of the D'Tesh...


		</French>
		<German>After Auric's defeat, the Illians empire fell. Most of its conquered parts were taken back by their rightful owner (sometimes triggering wars, but that's another story). The core of the Illians empire was being mopped up by various armies, like the Bannor, the Hippus and the Lanun. Although Auric was dead, many Illians were still loyal to him and fought to the death to defend the core, to remain independent.

Raitlor and her six sisters organized the militia of their town, ready to kill of the invaders in Auric's name. After the death of one of her sisters, Raitlor changed her mind. She tried to convince the others (and all other members of the militia) that they shouldn't fight, but rather accept their fate and surrender, because it would increase the odds of the survival of the Illians. She didn't find any support and was locked up while the militia launched an attack to take Garduk back.

Of course, the attack failed. All of Raitlor's sisters but one were killed. Leuk came back with very few survivors. They were all afraid of the supposedly incoming retaliation. Leuk went to talk with Raitlor and broke into tears, accabled with guilt over the death of her sisters, and becoming more aware that they should have supported Raitlor. Leuk was desperate that Auric had abandoned them. Raitlor calmed her down and showed her the snow falling outside, she told "Can't you see? He hasn't abandoned us, he's always been here, watching upon us. He did ascend, Leuk. What is the death of one's body for a god? Do you really believe that would stop Auric?".

Raitlor's beliefs gave hope to the town. They surrendered and became vassals of the Bannor. Raitlor was appointed as the mayor of the town; the other cities either fell to the wars or rallied themselves with Raitlor, surrendering their independence for a second chance.

(The Illians eventually broke off from vassalage because the Bannor didn't want to bother with them anymore, having to spend too much for them)

During the vassalage period, Raitlor's government focused on a new cult around Auric and opening new trade routes to put the Illian State back on tracks. Her government was very informal, ad hoc, but people accepted it and even saw her as the spokeperson of Auric, kind of. One thing leading to another, the government shaped itself around priests; Raitlor being the de facto first High Priestess of the White Hand. Because of their focus on trade, the White Hand became known outside the Illian State and spread there.

(Note that it's actually the outsiders who were naming it the White Hand, name which became used afterwards by the Illians themselves)

When the vassalage period ended, the efforts of Raitlor to keep the cohesion of her people strong became apparent: many immigrants came to the Illian State (whether newly converted to the White Hand or Illians who hide themselves after the defeat of Auric), no city tried to declare its independence and no one was questioning Raitlor's rule. But she did call for a big gathering, known as the "Winter Assembly", to officially decide on the one leader of the Illians, the shape of the government and many other things.

The main tendency was in favor of a White Hand-oriented government, an enforcement of their culture, a rejection of either councils but with the same focus on trade that was so beneficial. Raitlor was designed as the "Aurikvyarn", the "priest(ess) of Auric", both the head of the Illian State and the highest ranking priest of the White Hand; a kind of Pope if you prefer.

The Winter Assembly put the newly independent Illian State under the lights. Many states expressed their fear towards the growing popularity of the White Hand and towards the growing power of the Illian State. However, such fears were quickly dispersed by the apparition of the D'Tesh...


		</German>
		<Italian>After Auric's defeat, the Illians empire fell. Most of its conquered parts were taken back by their rightful owner (sometimes triggering wars, but that's another story). The core of the Illians empire was being mopped up by various armies, like the Bannor, the Hippus and the Lanun. Although Auric was dead, many Illians were still loyal to him and fought to the death to defend the core, to remain independent.

Raitlor and her six sisters organized the militia of their town, ready to kill of the invaders in Auric's name. After the death of one of her sisters, Raitlor changed her mind. She tried to convince the others (and all other members of the militia) that they shouldn't fight, but rather accept their fate and surrender, because it would increase the odds of the survival of the Illians. She didn't find any support and was locked up while the militia launched an attack to take Garduk back.

Of course, the attack failed. All of Raitlor's sisters but one were killed. Leuk came back with very few survivors. They were all afraid of the supposedly incoming retaliation. Leuk went to talk with Raitlor and broke into tears, accabled with guilt over the death of her sisters, and becoming more aware that they should have supported Raitlor. Leuk was desperate that Auric had abandoned them. Raitlor calmed her down and showed her the snow falling outside, she told "Can't you see? He hasn't abandoned us, he's always been here, watching upon us. He did ascend, Leuk. What is the death of one's body for a god? Do you really believe that would stop Auric?".

Raitlor's beliefs gave hope to the town. They surrendered and became vassals of the Bannor. Raitlor was appointed as the mayor of the town; the other cities either fell to the wars or rallied themselves with Raitlor, surrendering their independence for a second chance.

(The Illians eventually broke off from vassalage because the Bannor didn't want to bother with them anymore, having to spend too much for them)

During the vassalage period, Raitlor's government focused on a new cult around Auric and opening new trade routes to put the Illian State back on tracks. Her government was very informal, ad hoc, but people accepted it and even saw her as the spokeperson of Auric, kind of. One thing leading to another, the government shaped itself around priests; Raitlor being the de facto first High Priestess of the White Hand. Because of their focus on trade, the White Hand became known outside the Illian State and spread there.

(Note that it's actually the outsiders who were naming it the White Hand, name which became used afterwards by the Illians themselves)

When the vassalage period ended, the efforts of Raitlor to keep the cohesion of her people strong became apparent: many immigrants came to the Illian State (whether newly converted to the White Hand or Illians who hide themselves after the defeat of Auric), no city tried to declare its independence and no one was questioning Raitlor's rule. But she did call for a big gathering, known as the "Winter Assembly", to officially decide on the one leader of the Illians, the shape of the government and many other things.

The main tendency was in favor of a White Hand-oriented government, an enforcement of their culture, a rejection of either councils but with the same focus on trade that was so beneficial. Raitlor was designed as the "Aurikvyarn", the "priest(ess) of Auric", both the head of the Illian State and the highest ranking priest of the White Hand; a kind of Pope if you prefer.

The Winter Assembly put the newly independent Illian State under the lights. Many states expressed their fear towards the growing popularity of the White Hand and towards the growing power of the Illian State. However, such fears were quickly dispersed by the apparition of the D'Tesh...


		</Italian>
		<Spanish>After Auric's defeat, the Illians empire fell. Most of its conquered parts were taken back by their rightful owner (sometimes triggering wars, but that's another story). The core of the Illians empire was being mopped up by various armies, like the Bannor, the Hippus and the Lanun. Although Auric was dead, many Illians were still loyal to him and fought to the death to defend the core, to remain independent.

Raitlor and her six sisters organized the militia of their town, ready to kill of the invaders in Auric's name. After the death of one of her sisters, Raitlor changed her mind. She tried to convince the others (and all other members of the militia) that they shouldn't fight, but rather accept their fate and surrender, because it would increase the odds of the survival of the Illians. She didn't find any support and was locked up while the militia launched an attack to take Garduk back.

Of course, the attack failed. All of Raitlor's sisters but one were killed. Leuk came back with very few survivors. They were all afraid of the supposedly incoming retaliation. Leuk went to talk with Raitlor and broke into tears, accabled with guilt over the death of her sisters, and becoming more aware that they should have supported Raitlor. Leuk was desperate that Auric had abandoned them. Raitlor calmed her down and showed her the snow falling outside, she told "Can't you see? He hasn't abandoned us, he's always been here, watching upon us. He did ascend, Leuk. What is the death of one's body for a god? Do you really believe that would stop Auric?".

Raitlor's beliefs gave hope to the town. They surrendered and became vassals of the Bannor. Raitlor was appointed as the mayor of the town; the other cities either fell to the wars or rallied themselves with Raitlor, surrendering their independence for a second chance.

(The Illians eventually broke off from vassalage because the Bannor didn't want to bother with them anymore, having to spend too much for them)

During the vassalage period, Raitlor's government focused on a new cult around Auric and opening new trade routes to put the Illian State back on tracks. Her government was very informal, ad hoc, but people accepted it and even saw her as the spokeperson of Auric, kind of. One thing leading to another, the government shaped itself around priests; Raitlor being the de facto first High Priestess of the White Hand. Because of their focus on trade, the White Hand became known outside the Illian State and spread there.

(Note that it's actually the outsiders who were naming it the White Hand, name which became used afterwards by the Illians themselves)

When the vassalage period ended, the efforts of Raitlor to keep the cohesion of her people strong became apparent: many immigrants came to the Illian State (whether newly converted to the White Hand or Illians who hide themselves after the defeat of Auric), no city tried to declare its independence and no one was questioning Raitlor's rule. But she did call for a big gathering, known as the "Winter Assembly", to officially decide on the one leader of the Illians, the shape of the government and many other things.

The main tendency was in favor of a White Hand-oriented government, an enforcement of their culture, a rejection of either councils but with the same focus on trade that was so beneficial. Raitlor was designed as the "Aurikvyarn", the "priest(ess) of Auric", both the head of the Illian State and the highest ranking priest of the White Hand; a kind of Pope if you prefer.

The Winter Assembly put the newly independent Illian State under the lights. Many states expressed their fear towards the growing popularity of the White Hand and towards the growing power of the Illian State. However, such fears were quickly dispersed by the apparition of the D'Tesh...


		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_STASIS</Tag>
		<English>Stasis</English>
		<French>Stase</French>
		<German>Stase</German>
		<Italian>Stasi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Stasis</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_STASIS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Temporarily disables other players research and production</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Temporarily disables other players research and production</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Schaltet für eine gewisse Zeit die Forschung und Produktion eines anders Spielers aus</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Disabilita temporaneamente la ricerca e la produzione degli altri giocatori</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Temporarily disables other players research and production</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_ILLIANS</Tag>
		<English>Illian Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Illien</French>
		<German>Palast der Illian</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo degli Illian</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Illian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AURIC_ASCENDED</Tag>
		<English>Auric Ascended</English>
		<French>Auric Exalté</French>
		<German>Aufgestiegener Auric</German>
		<Italian>Auric Asceso</Italian>
		<Spanish>Auric Ascended</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AURIC_WINTER</Tag>
		<English>Commander Auric</English>
		<French>Commandant Auric</French>
		<German>Commander Auric</German>
		<Italian>Comandante Auric</Italian>
		<Spanish>Commander Auric</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_AURIC_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>Auric Ulvin has voiced his claim over the Precept of Ice.</English>
		<French>Auric Ulvin a revendiqué sa mainmise sur le Précepte de la Glace.</French>
		<German>Auric Ulvin hat seinen Anspruch auf das Gesetz des Eises erhoben.</German>
		<Italian>Auric Ulvin ha espresso la sua rivendicazione del Precetto del Ghiaccio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Auric Ulvin has voiced his claim over the Precept of Ice.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_UPGRADE_AURIC</Tag>
		<English>Upgrade to Commander</English>
		<French>Améliorer en Commandant</French>
		<German>Aufwerten zu Commander</German>
		<Italian>Migliora in Comandante</Italian>
		<Spanish>Upgrade to Commander</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_POP_AURIC</Tag>
		<English>Auric has begun his campaign to claim the Precept of Stasis.</English>
		<French>Auric a commencé sa campagne pour conquérir le Précepte de la Stase.</French>
		<German>Auric hat mit damit begonnen, das Gesetz der Stasis für sich zu beanspruchen.</German>
		<Italian>Auric ha iniziato la sua campagna per rivendicare il Precetto della Stasi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Auric has begun his campaign to claim the Precept of Stasis.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ICE_DRUID</Tag>
		<English>Mulyalfar Elf</English>
		<French>Elfe Mulyalfar</French>
		<German>Mulyalfar Elf</German>
		<Italian>Elfo Mulyalfar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mulyalfar Elf</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ICE_DRUID_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Discontented, power-hungry elves who joined the Svartalfar found that they had gotten nothing for their betrayal with the coming of the Age of Ice, and some chose to betray again. At their lead was one Sakanna, one of Queen Faeryl Viconia's allies. They formed the basis of the Mulyalfar, promising Mulcarn their allegiance in return for survival.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then too are those who stuck with the Summer Court, but with little conviction, seeking only to end up on what they believed was the 'winning' or 'good' side. They joined the Mulyalfar simply because Mulcarn was in power, but there were far fewer of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Regardless of their background, Mulcarn turned away none of the traitorous elves. Instead, he taught to their high priestesses the knowledge of ice, and how to spread it across all of Erebus. The Mulyalfar civilization collapsed with the end of the Age of Ice, and their druids and mages will offer their service to any who seek to bring back the Age of Ice, such as the Illians and the Frozen. Their knowledge of ice magic makes them very useful as ice druids.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 8, Volume I of The Elves of Mulcarn, by Sidar Historian Jevhan</English>
		<French>[TAB]Discontented, power-hungry elves who joined the Svartalfar found that they had gotten nothing for their betrayal with the coming of the Age of Ice, and some chose to betray again. At their lead was one Sakanna, one of Queen Faeryl Viconia's allies. They formed the basis of the Mulyalfar, promising Mulcarn their allegiance in return for survival.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then too are those who stuck with the Summer Court, but with little conviction, seeking only to end up on what they believed was the 'winning' or 'good' side. They joined the Mulyalfar simply because Mulcarn was in power, but there were far fewer of them.[TAB]Regardless of their background, Mulcarn turned away none of the traitorous elves. Instead, he taught to their high priestesses the knowledge of ice, and how to spread it across all of Erebus. The Mulyalfar civilization collapsed with the end of the Age of Ice, and their druids and mages will offer their service to any who seek to bring back the Age of Ice, such as the Illians and the Frozen. Their knowledge of ice magic makes them very useful as ice druids.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 8, Volume I of The Elves of Mulcarn, by Sidar Historian Jevhan</French>
		<German>[TAB]Discontented, power-hungry elves who joined the Svartalfar found that they had gotten nothing for their betrayal with the coming of the Age of Ice, and some chose to betray again. At their lead was one Sakanna, one of Queen Faeryl Viconia's allies. They formed the basis of the Mulyalfar, promising Mulcarn their allegiance in return for survival.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then too are those who stuck with the Summer Court, but with little conviction, seeking only to end up on what they believed was the 'winning' or 'good' side. They joined the Mulyalfar simply because Mulcarn was in power, but there were far fewer of them.[TAB]Regardless of their background, Mulcarn turned away none of the traitorous elves. Instead, he taught to their high priestesses the knowledge of ice, and how to spread it across all of Erebus. The Mulyalfar civilization collapsed with the end of the Age of Ice, and their druids and mages will offer their service to any who seek to bring back the Age of Ice, such as the Illians and the Frozen. Their knowledge of ice magic makes them very useful as ice druids.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 8, Volume I of The Elves of Mulcarn, by Sidar Historian Jevhan</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Gli elfi assetati di potere e insoddisfatti che si erano uniti agli Svartalfar scoprirono, con l'arrivo dell'Era del Ghiaccio, che non avrebbero guadagnato nulla dal loro tradimento, e cosi alcuni decisero di tradire di nuovo. Alla loro guida vi era Sakanna, una degli alleati della Regina Faeryl Viconia. Loro furono i primi Mulyalfar, promettendo la loro lealtà a Mulcarn in cambio della loro sopravvivenza.[PARAGRAPH:1]In seguito gli si unirono anche alcuni elfi che erano rimasti con la Corte D'Estate, ma con poca convinzione, in quanto cercavano di stare dalla parte che credevano 'vincente' o 'buona'. Questi ultimi si unirono ai Mulyalfar semplicemente perché Mulcarn era al potere, ma ve ne erano molto pochi di loro.[PARAGRAPH:1]Indipendentemente dalle loro origini Mulcarn non respinse nessuno di questi elfi traditori. Bensì insegnò alle loro somme sacerdotesse i segreti del ghiaccio, e di come fare per spargerlo su tutto Erebus. La civiltà Mulyalfar collassò con la fine dell'Era del Ghiaccio, e i loro druidi e maghi ora offrono i loro servigi a chiunque abbia l'intenzione di ripristinare l'Era del Ghiaccio, come gli Illian e i Ghiacciati. La loro conoscenza della magia del ghiaccio li rende molto utili come druidi del ghiaccio.[PARAGRAPH:2]Dal Capitolo 8, Volume I di Gli Elfi di Mulcarn, dello Storico Sidar Jevhan</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Discontented, power-hungry elves who joined the Svartalfar found that they had gotten nothing for their betrayal with the coming of the Age of Ice, and some chose to betray again. At their lead was one Sakanna, one of Queen Faeryl Viconia's allies. They formed the basis of the Mulyalfar, promising Mulcarn their allegiance in return for survival.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then too are those who stuck with the Summer Court, but with little conviction, seeking only to end up on what they believed was the 'winning' or 'good' side. They joined the Mulyalfar simply because Mulcarn was in power, but there were far fewer of them.[TAB]Regardless of their background, Mulcarn turned away none of the traitorous elves. Instead, he taught to their high priestesses the knowledge of ice, and how to spread it across all of Erebus. The Mulyalfar civilization collapsed with the end of the Age of Ice, and their druids and mages will offer their service to any who seek to bring back the Age of Ice, such as the Illians and the Frozen. Their knowledge of ice magic makes them very useful as ice druids.[PARAGRAPH:2]From Chapter 8, Volume I of The Elves of Mulcarn, by Sidar Historian Jevhan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ICE_DRUID_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Mulyalfar Elf is a replacement for the Druid. It is only available to the Illians and Frozen civilizations, and does not require the Neutral alignment. It can use the Freeze Forest ability, either raising a forest on a snow plot or turning a plot a forest stands on into a snow plot.</English>
		<French>The Mulyalfar Elf is a replacement for the Druid. It is only available to the Illians and Frozen civilizations, and does not require the Neutral alignment. It can use the Freeze Forest ability, either raising a forest on a snow plot or turning a plot a forest stands on into a snow plot.</French>
		<German>The Mulyalfar Elf is a replacement for the Druid. It is only available to the Illians and Frozen civilizations, and does not require the Neutral alignment. It can use the Freeze Forest ability, either raising a forest on a snow plot or turning a plot a forest stands on into a snow plot.</German>
		<Italian>L'Elfo Mulyalfar rimpiazza il Druido. È disponibile solo alle civiltà Illian e Ghiacciati, e non richede l'allineamento Neutrale. Può usare l'abilità Gela Foresta, che fa crescere una foresta su una casella di neve o trasforma una casella in cui c'è una foresta in una casella di neve.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Mulyalfar Elf is a replacement for the Druid. It is only available to the Illians and Frozen civilizations, and does not require the Neutral alignment. It can use the Freeze Forest ability, either raising a forest on a snow plot or turning a plot a forest stands on into a snow plot.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WILBOMAN</Tag>
		<English>Wilboman</English>
		<French>Wilboman</French>
		<German>Wilboman</German>
		<Italian>Wilboman</Italian>
		<Spanish>Wilboman</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WILBOMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The frost giant steamed gently. He always steamed, except when he was in the deepest frozen regions, the lands where the temperature never rose above freezing, even in summer. The only reason he didn't die whenever he joined an expedition away from Letum Frigus was the contingent of mages that followed him everywhere, casting Ice spells to cool him down. As it was, the heat still made the creature's brain boil, killing what little intelligent thought he may have possessed and making him angry, irrational and a lot more dangerous. He was also less reactive and a bit more sluggish than he would have been in his homeland, but that didn't matter much when he had the impetus and crushing force of a glacier. He was a blunt instrument, and like a glacier he may have moved slowly, but he left nothing alive in his wake.[PARAGRAPH:1]Granted, occasionally the creature would go berserk and kill some of his allies, but there was always a price to be paid for power. Auric knew that better than anyone alive. At least, as far as he knew; a shudder that wasn't his ran down his spine and for a second he had a vision of a weather-worn man with hard, cold eyes, wielding a magnificent sword...[PARAGRAPH:1]It was an effort and a major investment to have so many mages devoted to the single job of keeping the Frost Giant's cool (which also left them in a dangerous position most of the time), but as far as Auric was concerned, it was worth it. He had yet to see anyone stand up to his monster and win.[PARAGRAPH:1]Of course, the monster's volatile nature had to be contained as much as possible, otherwise he'd have an... unfortunate... effect on the morale of the other Illian soldiers. Monsters that are as likely to kill you as the enemy are often detrimental to team spirit. Such containment was the purpose of this exercise.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was, Auric reflected, rather like training a dog. This creature was larger, meaner and more dangerous than any dog Auric had ever had in his youth, but the basic principles remained the same: you could not reason with or convince this Frost Giant, any more than you could a boar hound. The only thing that would work, was conditioning-in effect, the creature had to be taught that the White Hand was dangerous, and that attacking the White Hand was bad behavior and meant pain. To that end, the mental link between Wilboman and Auric's "guest" was very handy.[PARAGRAPH:1]At the moment, the creature was lumbering around an arena filled with terrified prisoners dressed in various liveries. From the walls of the arena, archers launched arrows at him, wounding him, driving him into new paroxysms of pure, blind rage. The arrows were no danger to the Frost giant, any more than pin pricks to a human. His viscous blood ran so sluggishly that even the deepest sword stroke could not cause him to bleed out. His entire body was covered in scars, ice-like patches where the slings and arrows of countless foes had left their mark. And so, the only purpose served by the hail of arrows was to drive him to even greater heights of uncaring fury. All part of the exercise, of course.[PARAGRAPH:1]Whenever he dismembered prisoners wearing the Crown of the Bannor or that accursed Sunrise of the Amurites, Auric gave him a mental pat on the back. Every time he turned his attentions to a group wearing the White Hand, Auric caused a searing pain to strike the monster's mind. And so, slowly, he would learn-if that is what it could be called. As the last of the "enemies" were dispatched, and the survivors hauled off to go back to the chain gangs, Wilboman was led by one of his handlers, one of the few humans he had learned to obey and trust, back to the ice cold room in which he was stored when he was not needed.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wilboman, the man from Wilbo, dug out of a glacier, a remnant of the glorious Age of Ice, carrying that same name. It was not terribly inventive, true, but it was the name the soldiers had given the creature, and by now it had stuck. Who knew what the Frost Giant had been called in the simple, brutalistic language of his race? Who cared? He was the last of the Frost Giants, what his kin had called him mattered for nothing in this new age.[PARAGRAPH:1]As he watched his weapon of mass destruction be led meekly away, a thought stole through Auric's mind: He will not be the last of his race much longer.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The frost giant steamed gently. He always steamed, except when he was in the deepest frozen regions, the lands where the temperature never rose above freezing, even in summer. The only reason he didn't die whenever he joined an expedition away from Letum Frigus was the contingent of mages that followed him everywhere, casting Ice spells to cool him down. As it was, the heat still made the creature's brain boil, killing what little intelligent thought he may have possessed and making him angry, irrational and a lot more dangerous. He was also less reactive and a bit more sluggish than he would have been in his homeland, but that didn't matter much when he had the impetus and crushing force of a glacier. He was a blunt instrument, and like a glacier he may have moved slowly, but he left nothing alive in his wake.[PARAGRAPH:1]Granted, occasionally the creature would go berserk and kill some of his allies, but there was always a price to be paid for power. Auric knew that better than anyone alive. At least, as far as he knew; a shudder that wasn't his ran down his spine and for a second he had a vision of a weather-worn man with hard, cold eyes, wielding a magnificent sword...[PARAGRAPH:1]It was an effort and a major investment to have so many mages devoted to the single job of keeping the Frost Giant's cool (which also left them in a dangerous position most of the time), but as far as Auric was concerned, it was worth it. He had yet to see anyone stand up to his monster and win.[PARAGRAPH:1]Of course, the monster's volatile nature had to be contained as much as possible, otherwise he'd have an... unfortunate... effect on the morale of the other Illian soldiers. Monsters that are as likely to kill you as the enemy are often detrimental to team spirit. Such containment was the purpose of this exercise.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was, Auric reflected, rather like training a dog. This creature was larger, meaner and more dangerous than any dog Auric had ever had in his youth, but the basic principles remained the same: you could not reason with or convince this Frost Giant, any more than you could a boar hound. The only thing that would work, was conditioning-in effect, the creature had to be taught that the White Hand was dangerous, and that attacking the White Hand was bad behavior and meant pain. To that end, the mental link between Wilboman and Auric's "guest" was very handy.[PARAGRAPH:1]At the moment, the creature was lumbering around an arena filled with terrified prisoners dressed in various liveries. From the walls of the arena, archers launched arrows at him, wounding him, driving him into new paroxysms of pure, blind rage. The arrows were no danger to the Frost giant, any more than pin pricks to a human. His viscous blood ran so sluggishly that even the deepest sword stroke could not cause him to bleed out. His entire body was covered in scars, ice-like patches where the slings and arrows of countless foes had left their mark. And so, the only purpose served by the hail of arrows was to drive him to even greater heights of uncaring fury. All part of the exercise, of course.[PARAGRAPH:1]Whenever he dismembered prisoners wearing the Crown of the Bannor or that accursed Sunrise of the Amurites, Auric gave him a mental pat on the back. Every time he turned his attentions to a group wearing the White Hand, Auric caused a searing pain to strike the monster's mind. And so, slowly, he would learn-if that is what it could be called. As the last of the "enemies" were dispatched, and the survivors hauled off to go back to the chain gangs, Wilboman was led by one of his handlers, one of the few humans he had learned to obey and trust, back to the ice cold room in which he was stored when he was not needed.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wilboman, the man from Wilbo, dug out of a glacier, a remnant of the glorious Age of Ice, carrying that same name. It was not terribly inventive, true, but it was the name the soldiers had given the creature, and by now it had stuck. Who knew what the Frost Giant had been called in the simple, brutalistic language of his race? Who cared? He was the last of the Frost Giants, what his kin had called him mattered for nothing in this new age.[PARAGRAPH:1]As he watched his weapon of mass destruction be led meekly away, a thought stole through Auric's mind: He will not be the last of his race much longer.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Der Frostriese dampfte gemächlich. Er dampfte immer, außer wenn er sich in den Tiefen gefrorener Länder befand, den Gebieten in welchen die Temperaturen niemals den Gefrierpunkt überschritten, auch nicht im Sommer. Der einzige Grund warum er nicht jedesmal starb wenn er eine Expedition außerhalb von Letum Frigus begleitete war die Gruppe von Magiern die ihm überallhin folgten und Eiszauber auf ihn wirkten um ihn kühl zu halten. Dennoch brachte die Hitze das Gehirn der Kreatur zum kochen und töten war ein Gedanke der nicht viel Intelligenz erforderte und von dem er besessen war und was ihn wütend, irrational und um einiges gefährlicher machte. Außerdem reagierte er langsam und wurde träger als in seiner Heimat, aber das störte nicht sonderlich, da er den Schwung und die zermalmende Macht eines Gletschers hatte. Er war ein stumpfes Werkzeug und wie ein Gletscher mochte er sich langsam bewegen, doch ebenso ließ er nichts lebendes auf seinem Weg zurück.[PARAGRAPH:1]Zwar lief er zugegebenermaßen hin und wieder Amok und tötete einige seiner Verbündeten, aber die Macht verlangte stets einen hohen Preis. Auric wusste das besser als jeder andere Lebende. Zumindest, soweit er wusste. Ein Schauder lief ihm kalt den Rücken herunter, für eine Sekunde hatte er die Vision von einem vom Wetter gegerbten Mann mit harten, kalten Augen der ein prächtiges Schwert schwang.[PARAGRAPH:1]Es war eine Anstrengung und eine große Investition so viele Zauberer einzig der Aufgabe zuzuweisen, den Frostriesen kühl zu halten (was auch für sie meist eine gefährliche Position war), doch soweit es Auric betraf war es das wert. Er musste nur sehen wie sie sich mit seinem Monster erhoben und siegten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Natürlich musste der flüchtige Zustand des Monsters weitesgehend erhalten bleiben, sonst hätte dies einen schlechten Einfluss auf die Moral der anderen Soldaten der Illians. Monster, die ebenso gerne eigene wie feindliche Soldaten töten, sind meist schädlich für den Teamgeist. Dem entgegenzuwirken war der Sinn dieser Übung.[PARAGRAPH:1]Es war, so dachte Auric, eher wie die Dressur eines Hundes. Die Kreatur war größer, bösartiger und gefährlicher als jeder Hund den Auric in seiner Jugend besaß, doch die grundsätzlichen Prinzipien blieben die selben: Du kannst mit dem Frostriesen nicht diskutieren, kannst ihn nicht mit Argumenten überzeugen, das Wildschwein nicht zu jagen. Das einzige was funktionieren würde war Konditionierung  mit anderen Worten also musste das Wesen lernen dass die Weiße Hand gefährlich war und dass ein Angriff auf sie ein schlechtes Verhalten war und Schmerz bedeutete. Am Ende war die geistige Verbindung zwischen Wilboman und Aurics "Gast" sehr nützlich.[PARAGRAPH:1]Im Moment trampelte die Kreatur durch eine Arena die mit vom Terror erfüllten Gefangenen in verschiedensten Kleidern gefüllt war. Von den Wänden der Arena aus feuerten Bogenschützen auf den Frostriesen um ihn zu verwunden, was beim Riesen zu extatischer, blinder Wut führte. Die Pfeile waren keine Bedrohung für den Frostriesen, vergleichbar mit Nadelstichen bei Menschen. Sein zähflüssiges Blut lief so träge, dass selbst der tiefste Schwertstreich ihn nicht zum ausbluten bringen konnte. Sein gesamter Körper war mit Narben bedeckt, eisartige Flecken an denen die Geschosse und Pfeile von zahllosen Feinden ihre Spuren hinterlassen hatten. Und so war der einzige Sinn der Pfeile der, dass sie ihn in noch größere Höhen apathischer Raserei führten. All das war natürlich ein Teil der Übung.[PARAGRAPH:1]Jedesmal wenn er einen Gefangenen mit der Krone der Bannor oder dem Sonnenaufgang der Amurite zerstückelte, gab ihm Auric einen geistigen Klaps auf den Rücken. Jedesmal wenn er seine Aufmerksamkeit auf eine Gruppe von Mitgliedern der weißen Hand lenkte, verursachte Auric stechende Schmerzen in der Seele der Kreatur. Auf diese Weise konnte er langsam lernen, wenn man das so nennen will. Nachdem der letzte der "Feinde" zerstückelt wurde und die Überlebenden an ihren Ketten in die Verliese zurückgezehrt wurden, wurde Wilboman von einem seiner "Betreuer", einige wenige Menschen zu denen er Vertrauen gefasst hatte und denen er gehorchte, zurück in den eiskalten Raum geführt in dem er gelagert wurde, wenn er nicht gebraucht wurde.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wilboman, der Mann aus Wilbo, ausgehauen aus einem Gletscher, ein Überbleibsel des glorreichen Zeitalters des Eises, der den selben Namen trägt. Wer wusste schon, wie der Frostriese in der einfachen, brutalen Sprache seiner Rasse genannt wurde? Und wen interessierte es? Er war der letzte der Frostriesen und wie seine Art ihn nannte hatte keinerlei Bedeutung in diesem neuen Zeitalter.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als er seiner Massenvernichtungswaffe dabei zusah wie sie sanftmütig fortgeführt wurde, stahl sich ein Gedanke in Aurics Kopf: Wilboman würde nicht mehr lange der letzte seiner Rasse sein.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il gigante del gelo vaporò leggermente. Lo faceva sempre, tranne quando era nelle terre profondamente ghiacciate, nelle quali la temperatura non saliva mai al di spora dello zero, persino in estate. L'unico motivo per cui non moriva ogni volta che partecipava ad una spedizione lontana dal Letum Frigus era che un contingente di maghi lo seguiva ovunque andasse, lanciando magie del Ghiaccio per raffreddarlo. Il calore però gli faceva comunque bollire il cervello, eliminando anche il più semplice pensiero intelligente che aveva e rendendolo irascibile, irrazionale e tremendamente più pericoloso. Diveniva anche meno reattivo e più lento di quanto non fosse nella sua terra natia, non che avesse molta importanza quando aveva l'impeto e la forza di un ghiacciaio. Era uno strumento grezzo, e sebbene si muovesse lentamente come un ghiacciaio non lasciava nulla in vita sulla sua scia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Certo, occasionalmente la creatura va in berserk e uccide alcuni dei suoi alleati, ma c'è sempre un prezzo da pagare per il potere. Auric lo sapeva meglio di chiunque altro fosse in vita. Almeno per quanto lui ne sapeva; un brivido che non era suo gli corse lungo la schiena e per un secondo vide un uomo logorato dalle imtemperie dagli occhi duri e freddi, che impugnava una splendida spada...[PARAGRAPH:1]Era sia un costo che una grande investimento avere cosi tanti maghi dedicati al solo compito di mantenere bassa la temperatura del Gigante del Gelo (il che comportava anche farli stare in posti pericolosi la maggior parte delle volte), ma per Auric ne valeva la pena. Nessuno era finora riuscito ad affrontare il suo mostro e vincere.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ovviamente la natura volubile del mostro doveva essere contenuta il più possibile, altrimenti avrebbe avuto... spiacevoli... effetti sul morale degli altri soldati Illian. I mostri che hanno la stessa probabilità di uccidere te o i nemici tendono ad essere dannosi per lo spirito di squadra. E questo era il motivo di questo esercizio.[PARAGRAPH:1]Era come, Auric rifletté, quando si addestra un cane. Questa creatura era più grande, più cattiva e più pericolosa di qualsiasi cane Auric avesse mai avuto nella sua gioventù, ma i principi erano gli stessi: non si poteva ragionare con questo Gigante del Gelo più di quanto non si potesse fare con un cinghiale. L'unica cosa che poteva funzionare era un condizionamento istintivo, la creatura doveva imparare che la Mano Bianca era pericolosa, e che attaccarla era un comportamento cattivo che comportava dolore. A tal fine il collegamento esistente tra Wilboman e Auric era molto utile.[PARAGRAPH:1]Al momento la creatura stava girando per un'arena piena di prigionieri terrorizzati, vestiti con diverse livree. Dagli spalti dell'arena degli arcieri gli tiravano delle frecce, ferendolo e spingendolo in una acuta cieca rabbia. Le frecce non erano un pericolo per il Gigante del Gelo. Il suo sague viscoso era cosi lento che neppure un profondo taglio di spada lo avrebbe fatto morire dissanguato. Il suo corpo era completamente ricoperto di cicatrici, i segni lasciati da frecce di innumerevoli avversari. Pertanto l'unico scopo che aveva quella pioggia di frecce era quello di farlo infuriare sempre di più. Ovviamente era tutto parte dell'esercizio.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ogni volta che smembrava i prigionieri che indossavano la Corona dei Bannor o la maledetta Alba degli Amurite Auric gli dava una pacca sulla schiena mentale. Quando invece si dirigeva verso un gruppo che indossava la Mano Bianca Auric gli causava un dolore lancinante. E cosi, lentamente, imparava, se cosi si potrebbe dire. Quando l'ultimo dei "nemici" fu eliminato, e i sopravvissuti portati via, Wilboman fu guidato da uno dei suoi addestratori, uno dei pochi umani a cui obbediva e di cui si fidava, alla stanza congelata in cui veniva tenuto quando non c'era bisogno di lui.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wilboman, l'uomo da Wilbo, estratto da un ghiacciaio, un residuo della gloriosa Era del Ghiaccio, che portava il suo stesso nome. Non era molto creativo, vero, ma era il nome che i soldati avevano dato alla creatura e gli era rimasto attaccato ormai. Chi sa quale era il nome del Gigante del Gelo nella lingua semplice e brutale della sua razza? A chi importava? Lui era l'ultimo dei Giganti del Gelo, come veniva chiamato dai suoi simili non aveva importanza in questa nuova era.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mentre guardava quest'arma di distruzione di massa venir guidata via docilmente, un pensiero passò per la mente di Auric: Non rimarrà l'ultimo della sua specie ancora per molto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The frost giant steamed gently. He always steamed, except when he was in the deepest frozen regions, the lands where the temperature never rose above freezing, even in summer. The only reason he didn't die whenever he joined an expedition away from Letum Frigus was the contingent of mages that followed him everywhere, casting Ice spells to cool him down. As it was, the heat still made the creature's brain boil, killing what little intelligent thought he may have possessed and making him angry, irrational and a lot more dangerous. He was also less reactive and a bit more sluggish than he would have been in his homeland, but that didn't matter much when he had the impetus and crushing force of a glacier. He was a blunt instrument, and like a glacier he may have moved slowly, but he left nothing alive in his wake.[PARAGRAPH:1]Granted, occasionally the creature would go berserk and kill some of his allies, but there was always a price to be paid for power. Auric knew that better than anyone alive. At least, as far as he knew; a shudder that wasn't his ran down his spine and for a second he had a vision of a weather-worn man with hard, cold eyes, wielding a magnificent sword...[PARAGRAPH:1]It was an effort and a major investment to have so many mages devoted to the single job of keeping the Frost Giant's cool (which also left them in a dangerous position most of the time), but as far as Auric was concerned, it was worth it. He had yet to see anyone stand up to his monster and win.[PARAGRAPH:1]Of course, the monster's volatile nature had to be contained as much as possible, otherwise he'd have an... unfortunate... effect on the morale of the other Illian soldiers. Monsters that are as likely to kill you as the enemy are often detrimental to team spirit. Such containment was the purpose of this exercise.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was, Auric reflected, rather like training a dog. This creature was larger, meaner and more dangerous than any dog Auric had ever had in his youth, but the basic principles remained the same: you could not reason with or convince this Frost Giant, any more than you could a boar hound. The only thing that would work, was conditioning-in effect, the creature had to be taught that the White Hand was dangerous, and that attacking the White Hand was bad behavior and meant pain. To that end, the mental link between Wilboman and Auric's "guest" was very handy.[PARAGRAPH:1]At the moment, the creature was lumbering around an arena filled with terrified prisoners dressed in various liveries. From the walls of the arena, archers launched arrows at him, wounding him, driving him into new paroxysms of pure, blind rage. The arrows were no danger to the Frost giant, any more than pin pricks to a human. His viscous blood ran so sluggishly that even the deepest sword stroke could not cause him to bleed out. His entire body was covered in scars, ice-like patches where the slings and arrows of countless foes had left their mark. And so, the only purpose served by the hail of arrows was to drive him to even greater heights of uncaring fury. All part of the exercise, of course.[PARAGRAPH:1]Whenever he dismembered prisoners wearing the Crown of the Bannor or that accursed Sunrise of the Amurites, Auric gave him a mental pat on the back. Every time he turned his attentions to a group wearing the White Hand, Auric caused a searing pain to strike the monster's mind. And so, slowly, he would learn-if that is what it could be called. As the last of the "enemies" were dispatched, and the survivors hauled off to go back to the chain gangs, Wilboman was led by one of his handlers, one of the few humans he had learned to obey and trust, back to the ice cold room in which he was stored when he was not needed.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wilboman, the man from Wilbo, dug out of a glacier, a remnant of the glorious Age of Ice, carrying that same name. It was not terribly inventive, true, but it was the name the soldiers had given the creature, and by now it had stuck. Who knew what the Frost Giant had been called in the simple, brutalistic language of his race? Who cared? He was the last of the Frost Giants, what his kin had called him mattered for nothing in this new age.[PARAGRAPH:1]As he watched his weapon of mass destruction be led meekly away, a thought stole through Auric's mind: He will not be the last of his race much longer.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
