<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LUCHUIRP_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Luchuirp</English>
		<French>luchuri:luchurie:luchuris:luchuries</French>
		<German>Luchuirpisch</German>
		<Italian>Luchuirp</Italian>
		<Spanish>Luchuirp</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LUCHUIRP_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Luchuirp</English>
		<French>Luchuirp</French>
		<German>Reich der Luchuirpen</German>
		<Italian>Luchuirp</Italian>
		<Spanish>Luchuirp</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LUCHUIRP_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Luchuirp</English>
		<French>Luchuris</French>
		<German>Luchuirp</German>
		<Italian>Luchuirp</Italian>
		<Spanish>Luchuirp</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LUCHUIRP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Dwarves do not always live in caves. The Empire of Kradh-Ke-zun, the Open-Skiers, suffered terrible losses during the Age of Ice precisely because they, as opposed to their cousins the Khazad, had adapted to a life on the surface and forgotten the secrets of making their lives in the subterranean world. Fantastic craftsmen, cunning artificers, and proficient enchanters, the Kradh-Ke-zun were creators of some of the greatest artifacts of the Age of Magic, not least of which were the golems: golems for war, golems for transport, golems for farming, for mining and for industry. Life, for the Open-Skiers with their endless supply of infallibly obedient servants, was good, and the people thrived.[PARAGRAPH:1]The new reality of the Age of Ice was harsh on the Open-Skiers. When the glaciers rolled forth, strangling life, isolating populations, and crushing cities beneath tons of grinding blue ice, the Luchuirp watched helplessly as the cunning devices they had entrusted so much of their survival to succumbed to the long winter.[PARAGRAPH:1]Three-foot-tall city dwellers are not adapted to the rigorous, marginal, nomadic existence of Ice Age hunters, and few survived for long. Of the once mighty empire of great cities, thriving farmlands and millions of contented citizens, only one particularly hardy clan survived: the Luchuirp. Though weakened by the dominance of Mulcarn, Kilmorph still managed to hold a warding hand over this little tribe of surface-dwelling dwarves. She came to the leader, the now-legendary Graoin the Delver, and taught him the things his people had forgotten: how to dig, how to build homes under the mountain. Combining this with what little of their incredible artistry and golem mastery they could still make use of, they fashioned themselves a society of sorts in the caves beneath the Ice, and they waited, knowing that one day, the clan of Luchuirp, heirs of the Open-Skiers, would once again walk under the sun.[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri Bawl is a true heir to Graoin the Delver, not only in blood, but in spirit. He is a survivalist by nature, organized and effective, but he has never forgotten his roots and his ancestry. His highest goal is to reclaim a spot on the surface, but that does not mean he intends to make the mistake of his forefathers and neglect the lower reaches of the world. His approach is a symbiosis of the refined craftsmanship of the old Empire and the hardy jury-rigging the Luchuirp taught themselves during the Age of Ice.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Les Nains ne vivent pas toujours dans des grottes. L'empire des Kradh-Ke-zun (ceux qui vivent à Ciel Ouvert), ont subies des pertes terribles durant l'Age de Glace, parce que, contrairement à leurs cousins les khazadors, ils se sont adaptés à la vie en surface et ont oublié les secrets de la vie dans le monde souterrain. Des artisans fantastiques, des artificiers habiles et des enchanteurs compétents, les Kradh-Ke-zun créèrent quelques uns des meilleurs artefacts de l'Age de la Magie, parmi lesquels étaient les Golems : des Golems pour la guerre,  des Golems pour le transport, des Golems pour l'agriculture, l'extraction et l'industrie. La vie, pour ceux qui vivaient à Ciel Ouvert avec leur apport incessant de serviteurs obéissants et infaillibles, était bonne, et la population prospérait. [PARAGRAPH:1]La nouvelle réalité de l'Age de Glace fut très dure pour les Kradh-Ke-zun. Lorsque  les glaciations survinrent, étranglant la vie, isolant les populations, et écrasant les cités sous des tonnes de glace bleue, les luchuris regardèrent les systèmes ingénieux sur lesquels ils avaient basés leur survie succomber au long hiver sans pouvoir rien y faire. [PARAGRAPH:1] Les demeures d'un mètre de haut ne sont pas adaptées à l'existence rigoureuse, marginale et nomade des chasseurs de l'Age de Glace, et peu survécurent longtemps. Parmi l'immense empire de grandes villes, de fermes prospères et de millions de citoyens contents, seul un clan  particulièrement résistant survécut : les luchuris. Bien qu'affaiblie par la domination de Mulcarn, Kilmorph réussit quand même à étendre une main protectrice sur cette petite tribu de nains vivant en surface. Elle vint à leur dirigeant, le maintenant légendaire Graoin le Fouilleur, et lui enseigna les choses que son peuple avait oubliées : comment creuser, comment construire des demeures sous les montagnes. Combinant cela avec le peu de l'artisanat incroyable et de la Maitrise des Golems dont ils pouvaient encore se servir, ils se créèrent une société de cavernes sous la glace, et ils attendirent, sachant qu'un jour, le clan des luchuris, héritiers des Kradh-Ke-zun, marcheraient de nouveau sous le soleil. [PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri Bawl est un véritable héritier de Graoin le Fouilleur, non seulement par le sang, mais en matière d'esprit. C'est un survivant par nature, organisé et efficace, mais il n'a jamais oublié ses racines et ses ancêtres. Son plus grand but est de réclamer une part de la surface, mais cela ne signifie pas qu'il a l'intention de faire l'erreur de ses ancêtres et de négliger les parties plus profondes du monde. Son approche est une symbiose entre l'artisanat retrouvé de l'ancien Empire et la difficile leçon qu'apprirent les Luichurp durant l'Age de Glace.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Zwerge leben nicht immer in Höhlen. Das Reich von Kradh-Ke-zun, den Zwergen der Oberwelt, musste schlimme Verluste während des Zeitalters des Eises hinnehmen, weil sie sich im Gegensatz zu ihren Verwandten, den Khazad, an das Leben an der Oberfläche angepasst und die Geheimnisse des Lebens unter der Erde vergessen hatten. Als fantastische Handwerker, geschickte Erfinder und geübte Beschwörer waren die Kradh-Ke-zun die Schöpfer einiger der großartigsten Werke des Zeitalters der Magie, hier seien nicht zuletzt die Golems erwähnt: Golems für den Krieg, Golems für den Transport, Golems für die Feldarbeit, für den Bergbau und die Produktion. Mit dem endlosen Nachschub von unfehlbaren ergebenen Dienern war das Leben für die Zwerge der Oberwelt leicht und das Volk gedieh prächtig.[PARAGRAPH:1]Aber die neue Realität im Zeitalter des Eises traf die Zwerge der Oberwelt hart. Als die Gletscher vordrangen, das Leben abwürgten, Gemeinschaften trennten und die Städte unter vielen Tonnen knirschendem blauen Eis zermalmten, mussten die Luichurp hilflos mitansehen, wie die ausgeklügelten Apparate, denen sie ihr Überleben anvertraut hatten, dem langen Winter zum Opfer fielen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Meter große Stadtbewohner sind nicht für das harte, entbehrungsreiche und nomadische Leben eines Jägers im Zeitalter des Eises geschaffen und nur wenige überlebten dies lang. Von dem einst mächtigen Imperium mit großen Städten, florierender Landwirtschaft und Millionen von zufriedenen Bürgern überlebte nur ein besonders zäher Klan: die Luchuirp. Obwohl sie von der Herrschaft Mulcarns geschwächt war, schaffte es Kilmorph dennoch, ihre schützende Hand über diesen kleinen Stamm der an der Oberfläche lebenden Zwerge zu halten. Sie erschien deren Anführer, dem inzwischen legendären Graoin dem Gräber und brachte ihm jene Dinge bei, die sein Volk vergessen hatte: wie man in die Tiefe gräbt, wie man Behausungen in den Berg hinein treibt. Zusammen mit dem verbliebenen Rest ihrer unglaublichen Handwerkskunst und der Golembeherrschung, von dem sie noch Gebrauch machen konnten, erschufen sie sich in den Höhlen unter dem Eis eine Art von Gesellschaft und warteten. Denn sie wussten, dass der Klan der Luichurp, Erben der Zwerge der Oberwelt, eines Tages wieder unter der Sonne leben würden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri Bawl ist ein würdiger Nachfolger von Graoin dem Gräber, nicht nur dem Blute nach, sondern auch im Geiste. Er ist ein geborener Überlebenskünstler, organisiert und effektiv, ohne seine Wurzeln oder seine Abstammung zu vergessen. Sein höchstes Ziel ist es, den Platz an der Oberfläche zurückzugewinnen, aber das bedeutet nicht, dass er vorhat, den gleichen Fehler wie seine Vorväter zu machen und die unterirdischen Bereiche der Welt zu vernachlässigen. In seinem Vorgehen verbindet sich die feine Handwerkskunst des alten Imperiums mit der zähen Aufbauarbeit, die die Luichurp im Zeitalter des Eises geleistet haben, zu einer Einheit.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]I nani non sempre vivono sottoterra. L'Impero dei Kradh-Ke-zun, coloro che vivono a cielo aperto, subì ingenti perdite durante l'Era del Ghiaccio per via del fatto che loro, contrariamente ai loro cugini Khazad, si erano adattati a una vita sulla superfice e avevano dimenticato i segreti per vivere sottoterra. Artigiani fenomenali, astuti artefici, e incantatori provetti, i Kradh-Ke-zun furono i creatori di alcuni dei più grandi artefatti dell'Era della Magia, non ultimi di questi furono i golem: golem per la guerra, golem per i trasporti, golem per l'agricoltura, per l'industria mineraria e quella manufatturiera. La vita, per i Kradh-Ke-zun con il loro numero infinito di servitori obbedienti, era buona, e la gente prosperò.[PARAGRAPH:1]La nuova realtà dell'Era del Ghiaccio fu dura per i Kradh-Ke-zun. Quando i ghiacciai si espansero, eliminando vite, isolando popolazioni, e schiacciando città sotto tonnellate di ghiaccio, i Luchuirp guardarono impotenti i loro congegni, ai quali si affidavano per la loro sopravvivenza, soccombere al lungo inverno.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dei cittadini alti circa un metro non sono adatti al rigido, marginale e nomadico stile di vita dei cacciatori dell'Era del Ghiaccio, e in pochi soppravvisero a lungo. Dell'impero un tempo potente dalle grandi città, coltivazioni prosperose e milioni di cittadini felici, solo un clan particolarmente resistente sopravvisse: i Luchuirp. Anche se indebolita dal dominio di Mulcarn, Kilmorph riuscì a mantenere una mano protettrice su questa piccola tribù di nani della superfice. Andò dal leader, l'ora leggendario Graoin lo Scavatore, e gli insegnò le cose che il suo popolo aveva dimenticato: come scavare, come costruire case sotto la montagna. Combinando questo con quel poco della loro abilità e padronanza dei golem che erano riusciti a mantenere, crearono una sorta di società nelle caverne sotto il ghiaccio, e li attesero, sapendo che un giorno il clan dei Luchuirp, eredi dei Kradh-Ke-zun, avrebbero di nuovo camminato sotto al sole.[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri Bawl è un vero erede di Graoin lo Scavatore, non solo nel sangue, ma anche nello spirito. È un survivalista naturale, organizzato ed efficente, ma non ha mai dimenticato le sue radici e i suoi antenati. Il suo obiettivo più grande è di reclamare un posto sulla superfice, ma questo non significa che intende commettere lo stesso errore di coloro che sono venuti prima e ignorare le profondità del mondo. Il suo approccio è una simbiosi del fine artigianato del vecchio impero e la robusta improvvisazione che i Luchuirp hanno appreso durante l'Era del Ghiaccio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Los enanos no siempre viven en cuevas. El Imperio de Kradh-Ke-zun, los Esquiadores-Abiertos, sufrieron terribles pérdidas durante la Edad de Hielo precisamente porque ellos, al contrario que sus primos Kazhad, se han adaptado a la vida en la superficie y olvidaron los secretos de cómo vivir en el mundo subterráneo. Fantásticos artesanos, ingeniosos artificieros, y eficientes encantadores, los Kradh-Ke-zun fueron los creadores de algunos de los más grandes artefactos de la Edad de la Magia, y entre estos estaban los Golems: Golems de guerra, Golems de transporte, Golems de granja, de minería y de industria. La vida, para los Esquiadores-Abiertos con su suministro ilimitado de infatigables y obedientes sirvientes, era buena, y su pueblo floreció.[PARAGRAPH:1]La nueva realidad de la Edad de Hielo era severa para los Esquiadores-Abiertos. Cuando los glaciares avanzaron, sofocando la vida a su paso, asolando poblaciones, y aplastando ciudades bajo toneladas de aplastante hielo azul, los Luchuirp observaron desolados como los ingeniosos dispositivos en los que ellos confiaron tanto para sobrevivir sucumbían al largo invierno.[PARAGRAPH:1]Los habitantes de las ciudades de tres pies de altura no estaban adaptadas a la rigurosa, marginal y nómada existencia de los cazadores de la Edad de Hielo, y pocos duraron demasiado. Del una vez poderoso Imperio de grandes ciudades, florecientes tierras de labranza y millones de ciudadanos satisfechos, sólo un clan en particular a duras penas sobrevivió: los Luchuirp. Aunque debilitados por el dominio de Mulcarn, Kilmorph se las arregló para mantener una mano vigilante sobre esta pequeña tribu de enanos habitantes de la superficie. Ella se presentó ante el líder, el ahora legendario Graoin el Ahondador, y le enseñó las cosas que su pueblo había olvidado: cómo escavar, cómo construir casas bajo la montaña. Combinando esto con lo poco de su increíble artesanía y maestría de Golems que podían aplicar aún, se crearon algún tipo de sociedad en las cuevas bajo el hielo, y esperaron, sabiendo que algún día el Clan Luchuirp, hijos de los Esquiadores-Abiertos, caminarían de nuevo bajo el sol.[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri Bawl es un verdadero heredero de Graoin el Ahondador, no sólo por sangre, sino por espírito. Es un superviviente por naturaleza, organizado y eficiente, pero nunca ha olvidado sus raíces y a sus ancestros. Su principal objetivo es reclamar un lugar en la superficie, pero eso no significa que intente cometer el error de sus parientes y negar las profundidades de la tierra. Su intento es una simbiosis de la refinada artesanía del viejo Imperio y la dura lección aprendida por los Luchuirp en la Edad de Hielo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LUCHUIRP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategy: Golems gain no experience, but a combination of the different golem-boosting buildings and Barnaxus will make them pretty mean anyway. Combine this with the fact that they're slightly more powerful than the units they replace, and you'll get a tough army, equally useful for defense and offense. Should you lose Barnaxus, you still have a chance of rebuilding him if you can kill the unit that destroyed him.</English>
		<French>[H1]Spécificités[\H1][H2]Golems[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Le héros [LINK=UNIT_BARNAXUS]Barnaxus[\LINK] est le seul golem à progresser normalement. Les autres golems ne gagnent jamais de niveaux.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Il existe 5 façons de renforcer vos golems :[PARAGRAPH:1][ICON_BULLET]Si Barnaxus possède la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_COMBAT1]Combat[\LINK] (rang I à V), vos autres golems obtiendront automatiquement la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_EMPOWER1]Habileté[\LINK] au même rang (I à V)[PARAGRAPH:1][ICON_BULLET]Un golem construit dans une ville disposant de la [LINK=BUILDING_PALLENS_ENGINE]Manufacture Pallens[\LINK] (Divination + mana de Soleil) entrera en jeu avec la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Vision parfaite[\LINK] (détection des ennemis invisibles).[PARAGRAPH:1][ICON_BULLET]Un golem construit dans une ville disposant de la [LINK=BUILDING_ADULARIA_CHAMBER]Chambre d'Adularia[\LINK] (Nécromancie + mana d'Ombre) entrera en jeu avec la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Dissimulé[\LINK] (invisible jusqu'à ce qu'il attaque ou lance un sort)[PARAGRAPH:1][ICON_BULLET]Un golem construit dans une ville disposant de l'[LINK=BUILDING_BLASTING_WORKSHOP]Atelier d'Explosifs[\LINK] (Sorcellerie + mana de Feu) entrera en jeu avec la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_FIRE2]Feu II[\LINK] (lancement de [LINK=UNIT_FIREBALL]boules de feu[\LINK], y compris pour vos golems ouvriers !)[PARAGRAPH:1][ICON_BULLET]Si vous choisissez le dirigeant Gimil, le trait Maître-Artisan donnera de la [LINK=PROMOTION_MOBILITY3]Mobilité[\LINK] au niveau 1, un choix d'équipement (dégâts+immunité) au niveau 2, et une [LINK=AFFINITY_ENCHANTMENT_GIMIL]affinité au mana d'Enchantement[\LINK] au niveau 3.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Vos golems se réparent lentement. Pour les aider, vos adeptes peuvent utiliser le sort de [LINK=SPELL_REPAIR]réparation[\LINK] (le mana d'enchantement est fourni par votre palais)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Si Barnaxus est détruit, vous aurez une chance de le [LINK=SPELL_REBUILD_BARNAXUS]reconstruire[\LINK] en tuant l'unité qui l'a détruit et en récupérant ses [LINK=EQUIPMENT_PIECES_OF_BARNAXUS]restes[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]TODO : rédiger la suite.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Unité mondiale [LINK=]Golem de Mithril[\LINK][H2]Autres informations[\H2]sort mondial : [LINK=]marteau doré[\LINK]. Équipement, 1 exemplaire par ville. Plusieurs usages : Petit bonus de combat ou vitesse de travail d'un ouvrier ou artisan gratuit en ville.[NEWLINE]Accès aux mines naines : uniquement avec la religion des Runes et les [LINK=]soldats de Kilmorph[\LINK][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=]Druides nains[\LINK] Terre plutôt que Nature : évocation d'[LINK=]élémentaires de Terre[\LINK][NEWLINE][H1]Dirigeants[\H1]Beery, Garim, Letigo (déjà parlé de Gimil)</French>
		<German>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategie: Golems Erlangen keine Erfahrung, aber eine Kombination aus den verschiedenen Golem-Verbessernden Gebäuden und Barnaxus, wird sie sowieso ziemlich hinterhältig machen. Kombinieren Sie dies mit der Tatsache, dass sie etwas stärker sind, als die Einheiten, die sie ersetzen, und Sie werden eine fähige Armee erhalten, die gleich brauchbar für Verteidigung und Angriff sein wird. Sollten Sie Barnaxus verlieren, haben sie immer noch eine Chance, ihn wieder zu zusammenzubauen, wenn Sie die Einheit töten können, die ihn zerstört hat.</German>
		<Italian>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategia: I golem non ottengono esperienza, ma una serie di edifici, che gli forniscono capacità particolari, e Barnaxus li possono rendere comunque parecchio forti. Combina tutto questo con il fatto che loro sono leggermente più forti delle unità che vanno a sostituire e otterrai un'esercito robusto, equamente utile nella difesa cosi come nell'offesa. Se dovessi perdere Barnaxus, hai sempre la possibilità di ricostruirlo se riesci a portare i suoi resti in una città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Estrategia: Los golems no ganan experiencia, pero una combinación de las diferentes construcciones potenciadoras de golems y Barnaxus los convertirá en una buena inversión. Combinar esto con el hecho de que son destacablemente más poderosos que las unidades normales que sustituyen, proporcionará un duro ejército, igualmente útil para defensa y ataque. Si se pierde a Barnaxus, aún habrá una posibilidad de reconstruirlo si se destruye a la unidad que lo destruyó a él.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_BEERI</Tag>
		<English>Beeri Bawl</English>
		<French>Beeri Bawl</French>
		<German>Beeri Bawl</German>
		<Italian>Beeri Bawl</Italian>
		<Spanish>Beeri Bawl</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_BEERI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]"Come now, people, come behold, the midget as he digs for gold!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The shout made Beeri stir from his uncomfortable sleep on the cage floor. He grudgingly started to get to his feet. The first few days of his imprisonment he had attempted to resist when the show was announced; stubbornly maintaining his lying position, but he had quickly found out that it only made things worse.[PARAGRAPH:1]He blinked against the brilliant light of the many torches lining the throne room of Perpentach, that thrice-damned carnival clown who'd taken him captive just a few weeks ago. A raiding party of merrymen had assaulted the outlying border town he had been visiting, confounding everyone with their strange dance-like fighting, and subsequently hauling Beeri off like a sack of potatoes, singing and laughing as they went.[PARAGRAPH:1]Laughter had become his worst adversary these past few days. He sometimes wished that Perpentach had just ordered him killed, or even hauled him down to some dark dungeon for torture. The harlequin seemed determined to break his spirit, and had skillfully assessed the most effective way of doing this. Or perhaps he was merely bored, Beeri could not really understand Perpentach. But his reasons were not important, as Beeri was completely certain of the one thing that mattered-he wanted to kill the man, to wipe that grotesque smile off his face once and for all.[PARAGRAPH:1]The show was about to begin. "Kilmorph, give me strength" he muttered under his breath, as Perpentach went on with his announcement:[PARAGRAPH:1]"A brilliant light in darkness shines, a piece of gold in muddy mines!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Perpentach had risen from his throne and addressed the many noblemen assembled before him, all garbed in clothes of the most bizarre shapes and colors, and most wearing masques to hide their faces. Beeri suspected that their real faces underneath might not wear quite as happy expressions as the masques-like him, they were just playing along to avoid their ruler's wrath.[PARAGRAPH:1] At the far end of Beeri's cage there was a circular hole in the floor, filled up with mud. Perpentach's preferred way of torturing him involved his diving head-first into the hole to recover a small gold-piece that had been placed there, usually near the bottom.[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri quickly walked towards the puddle, he wanted to get this over with as fast as possible. He kneeled down and plunged his arms and head into the mud, trying to shut the laughter and applause of the gathered noblemen out of his mind. Luckily he quickly got a hold of the familiar round shape of the coin. As his hand closed around it he suddenly hesitated. Something was moving in the mud, slithering shapes. A hiss penetrated his left ear, and with a roar he threw himself backwards-still clutching the coin-seconds before the viper would have let its fangs sink into his neck. The snake hissed and slithered back into the hole.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Danger in the mines it seems, a terror from the darkest dreams"[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri's heart was pounding. Perpentach had been creative with him before, but usually not in such a potentially fatal fashion. Perhaps it meant that he was getting bored of his new toy, and sought to dispose of him. He shrugged as he realized that the thought seemed welcome. The only thing that kept him from throwing himself back into the hole with the snake was the thought of the laughing bastard just outside the bars, and of all the creative things he could do to him given the chance.[PARAGRAPH:1]The show was not over yet, however:[PARAGRAPH:1]"The midget keeps his gold you see, if this foul beast will let him be..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri whirled around as a section of wall in his cave slid away, opening a passageway he hadn't known existed. His eyes widened as he beheld the enormous hill giant that stood there, grunting furiously, and holding a club thrice the height and twice the width of Beeri's own body. He was most certainly meant to die now.[PARAGRAPH:1]Still, something deep within Beeri was not prepared to merely give in and die. He did not think of his friends and family back in the mountains, nor of his people who would most certainly be lost without him as he drew strength. All he could think of was that Perpentach meant for him to die, would draw pleasure from his death-and so it should not happen.[PARAGRAPH:1]He ignored the lumbering giant and instead dug a strong hand into the hole, grasping the writhing body of the viper. He then proceeded to fling the snake towards the giant with all his might. It landed by his left leg, and sensing a threat it immediately dug its teeth into the giant's feet. It roared with pain and fury and cracked the viper's skull with its club, but within moments it started to go into convulsions, and soon it fell flat on its back, greenish foam dripping from its mouth. Perpentach had obviously chosen a viper with a very potent venom. Ironic that it should be his savior.[PARAGRAPH:1]The crowd in the throne room applauded again, but Beeri was merely waiting for Perpentach to initiate the next death-trap. What followed surprised him, however:[PARAGRAPH:1]"The midget won the greatest prize, he proved to be both brave and wise.[PARAGRAPH:1]The game is won, the midgets foes, shall all applaud him as he goes"[PARAGRAPH:1]Perpentach gracefully walked to the door of his cage, unlocked it and opened it wide, a mysterious smile on his lips. Beeri couldn't believe his eyes. Was this another trap? He heard some of the noblemen muttering angrily, he thought he heard the phrases "…wasting a valuable hostage" and "One of his usual fancies..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Slowly Beeri started to walk. For a moment he considered assaulting Perpentach as he went out the door, grabbing his throat in an attempt to strangle him before his guards could rush to his aid. As the adrenaline rush of the battle faded, however, he started to think more clearly and realized that it would be suicide. If Perpentach was really serious about letting him go he could return in force later, and the thought of a mighty clockwork golem mashing the harlequin underfoot was enough to speed him on his way.[PARAGRAPH:1]He started to run across the floor of the throne room, looking backwards on occasion, but no one made any attempt at stopping him, and Perpentach just stood by the open prison door and smiled.[PARAGRAPH:1]Well out of Perpentach's palace, Beeri shook his head at the insanity of the place, and started to make his way home.</English>
		<French>[TAB]"Venez, public, venez voir le nabot qui cherche de l'or !"[PARAGRAPH:1]Le cri tira Beeri de son sommeil inconfortable sur le sol de la cage. Il se dressa à contrec&#156;ur sur ses jambes. Durant ses premiers jours de captivité il avait entrepris de résister; à l'annonce de son numéro il restait obstinément allongé, mais avait rapidement réalisé que cela ne faisait qu'empirer les choses.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il cligna des yeux, ébloui par l'éclat des nombreuses torches alignées dans la salle du trône de Perpentach, ce damné clown de carnaval qui l'avait capturé il y a tout juste quelques semaines. Un groupe de troubadours avait pris d'assaut la ville de la bordure extérieure où il se trouvait, pratiquant leur étrange chorégraphie de combat pour capturer leurs proies, dont Beeri qu'ils avaient traîné comme un vulgaire sac de pommes de terre, en chantant et riant à foison.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le rire était devenu son pire ennemi ces derniers jours. Il lui arrivait parfois de souhaiter que Perpentach ordonne de le tuer, ou même de l'expédier dans le plus sombre de ses cachots pour être torturé. L'arlequin semblait bien décidé à le briser moralement, et avait judicieusement determiné le moyen le plus efficace d'y parvenir. Ou peut-être s'ennuyait-il tout simplement, Beeri ne parvenait pas vraiment à comprendre Perpentach. Mais ses raisons n'avaient aucune importance, puisqu'une seule chose comptait pour Beeri - il voulait tuer l'homme, et effacer une fois pour toutes ce sourire grotesque de son visage.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le spectacle allait débuter. "Kilmorph, donne moi la force" murmura-t-il dans un souffle, tandis que Perpentach l'annonçait :[PARAGRAPH:1]"Un éclat brillant rayonne dans l'ombre, une pièce d'or dans des mines sombres !"[PARAGRAPH:1]Perpentach s'était levé de son trône et s'adressait aux nombreux nobles rassemblés devant lui, tous vêtus de tenues aux formes et couleurs bizarres, la plupart portant un masque pour cacher leur visage. Beeri soupçonnait que leurs vrais visages n'affichaient peut-être pas des expressions aussi joyeuses que leurs masques – comme lui ils jouaient la comédie pour éviter le courroux de leur dirigeant.[PARAGRAPH:1]A l'extrémité de la cage de Beeri se trouvait un trou circulaire, rempli de boue. La torture favorite de Perpentach était de le plonger la tête la première dans le trou pour récupérer une petite piece d'or préalablement placée là, généralement près du fond.[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri se dirigea promptement vers la flaque, il voulait en finir au plus vite. Il s'agenouilla, plongea la tête et les bras dans la boue, espérant ne plus entendre les rires et les applaudissements de l'assemblée de nobles. Par chance il localisa rapidement la forme arrondie familière de la pièce. Tandis qu'il l'enfermait dans sa main il eut une hésitation. Quelque chose bougeait dans la boue... une forme fuyante. Un sifflement stridant lui perca les tympans. Il se recula en grognant, la pièce toujours serrée dans sa main, quelques secondes avant que la vipère n'ait eu le temps de planter ses crochets dans sa nuque. Le serpent siffla et se faufila dans le trou.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Le danger guette dans le noir, du fond de votre pire cauchemar"[PARAGRAPH:1]Le c&#156;ur de Beeri battait fort. Perpentach avait été très créatif avec lui jusque là, mais jamais d'une manière aussi potentiellement mortelle. Cela signifiait peut-être qu'il commençait à se lasser de son nouveau jouet, et cherchait à s'en débarasser. Il haussa les épaules en réalisant que cette pensée le réjouissait. La seule chose qui l'empêchait de se jeter de lui-même dans le trou du serpent était la perspective d'entendre le bâtard rire de l'autre côté des barreaux, et l'idée de ce qu'il pourrait lui faire subir si on lui laissait une chance.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le spectacte n'était cependant pas terminé :[PARAGRAPH:1]"Le nabot garde son or précieusement, si toutefois la bête lui en laisse le temps..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri se retourna lorsqu'une partie du mur de la cave bougea, ouvrant un passage dont il ignorait l'existence. Il écarquilla les yeux en voyant l'énorme géant des collines qui se tenait là, grognant furieusement, et tenant un gourdin trois fois haut et deux fois large comme le corps de Beeri. Il était certainement destiné à mourir maintenant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Pourtant, quelque chose de profondément ancré en Beeri n'était pas prêt à céder et à se laisser tuer. Il ne pensait ni à ses amis ni à sa famille laissés dans les montagnes, pas plus qu'à son peuple qui serait sans doute perdu sans sa grande force. Tout ce à quoi il pensait était que Perpentach, qui avait décidé qu'il périrait, prendrait plaisir à le voir mourir - et cela ne devait pas arriver.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il ignora l'attaque du géant, plongea la main dans le trou, et empoigna le corps de la vipère. Il jeta de toutes ses forces le serpent, qui attérit près de la jambe gauche du géant et, se sentant en danger, planta immédiatement ses dents dans son pied. Le géant, hurlant de douleur et de rage, écrasa de son gourdin le crâne de la vipère, mais quelques instants plus tard il commença à se tordre en convulsions, et tomba rapidement sur le dos, une mousse verdâtre coulant de sa bouche. Perpentach avait apparemment choisi une vipère au venin puissant. Quelle ironie que cela l'ait sauvé.[PARAGRAPH:1]La foule dans la salle du trône applaudissait une fois de plus, mais Beeri s'attendait à ce que Perpentach déclenche un nouveau piège mortel. La suite le surprit pourtant :[PARAGRAPH:1]"Le nabot a remporté la plus haute récompense, il a montré à la fois courage et intelligence.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le nain maléfique a gagné, applaudissons sa liberté."[PARAGRAPH:1]Perpentach se dirigea gracieusement vers le porte de sa cage, la dévérouilla et l'ouvrit en grand, un mystérieux sourire sur les lèvres. Beeri n'en croyait pas ses yeux. Etait-ce un nouveau piège ? Il entendit certains nobles gronder de colère, et perçut des phrases comme "...gaspille un hôtage de valeur" et "Encore une de ses fantaisies..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri se mit à marcher doucement. L'espace d'un instant il pensa attaquer Perpentach tandis qu'il franchissait la porte, attraper sa gorge et l'étrangler avant que ses gardes n'aient le temps de venir à son secours. Quand la poussée d'adrénaline retomba, cependant, il réfléchit plus calmement et réalisa que ce serait du suicide. Si Perpentach était vraiment en train de le libérer, il pourrait revenir en force plus tard, et la pensée d'un puissant golem enfonçant l'arlequin six pieds sous terre suffit à lui faire presser le pas.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il se mit à courir à travers la salle du trône, tout en se retournant de temps en temps, mais personne ne tenta de l'arrêter, et Perpentach restait immobile devant la porte de la cage et souriait.[PARAGRAPH:1]Une fois sorti du palais de Perpentach, Beeri secoua la tête, et prit le chemin du retour.</French>
		<German>[TAB]"Seht nun, ihr Herrn und Damen hold, wie dieser Winzling gräbt nach Gold!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Ausruf weckte Beeri aus seinem ungemütlichen Schlaf auf dem Käfigboden. Schlechtgelaunt stand er auf. In den ersten Tagen seiner Gefangenschaft hatte er versucht, Widerstand zu leisten, wenn die Vorstellung angekündigt wurde, indem er stur liegen blieb, doch er hatte schnell herausgefunden, dass das alles nur noch schlimmer machte.[PARAGRAPH:1] Er blinzelte unter dem hellen Licht der vielen Fackeln in Perpentachs Thronhalle, der Halle dieses dreimal verdammten Zirkusclowns, der ihn vor ein paar Wochen gefangen hatte. Eine räuberische Bande von Narrenkriegern hatte die abgelegene Grenzstadt überfallen, die er besucht hatte. Sie hatten jeden mit ihrer seltsamen tanzähnlichen Art zu kämpfen verwirrt, und anschließend Beeri mit sich genommen wie einen Sack Kartoffeln, singend und lachend. [PARAGRAPH:1]Sein schlimmster Feind in den letzten Tagen war das Gelächter geworden. Manchmal wünschte er sich, Perpentach hätte lediglich befohlen, ihn zu töten, oder sogar in die tiefsten Kerker zur Folter verurteilt. Doch der Harlekin wollte anscheinend seinen Geist brechen, und hatte geschickt die beste Art dazu gewählt. Vielleicht war er auch nur gelangweilt, es fiel Beeri schwer, Perpentach zu verstehen. Aber Perpentachs Gründe waren nicht wesentlich, denn Beeri war sich der einzigen wichtigen Sache sicher: er wollte diesen Mann töten, sein groteskes Lächeln zum erlöschen bringen, ein für alle Mal.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Vorstellung würde nun beginnen. "Kilmorph, gib mir Kraft!" murmelte er in seinen Bart, als Perpentach mit seiner Ankündigung fortfuhr:[PARAGRAPH:1]"Es scheint ein Licht im Dunklen hold, in Minen liegt ein Stück von Gold!"[PARAGRAPH:1] Perpentach hatte sich von seinem Thron erhoben und sprach nun die vielen Adligen vor ihm an. Diese waren alle in Kleider von bizarrsten Formen und Farben gehüllt, und die meisten trugen Masken um ihre Gesichter zu verbergen. Beeri vermutete, dass die Gesichter darunter wohl keinen so fröhlichen Ausdruck zur Schau stellten, wie die Masken; sie spielten, wie er, nur mit um den Zorn ihres Herrschers nicht zu entzünden.[PARAGRAPH:1]An dem anderen Ende von Beeris Käfig war ein rundes Loch im Boden, gefüllt mit Schlamm. Perpentachs bevorzugte Weise, ihn zu foltern, beinhaltete, dass Beeri kopfüber in das Loch tauchte, und ein kleines Stück Gold hinausholte, das dort verborgen war, normalerweise in der Nähe des Bodens.[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri ging schnell auf das Loch zu, er wollte dies so schnell wie möglich hinter sich bringen. Er kniete nieder, und tauchte seine Arme und seinen Kopf in den Schlamm, und versuchte das Lachen und den Applaus der versammelten Edelleute zu ignorieren. Glücklicherweise bekam er schnell die vertraute runde Form der Münze zu fassen. Als sich seine Hand darum schloss, zögerte er. Etwas bewegte sich in dem Schlamm...in schlängelnden Figuren. Ein Zischeln drang in sein linkes Ohr, und mit einem Schrei warf er sich nach hinten - die Münze noch in seiner Hand - nur Sekunden bevor die Viper ihre Zähne in seinen Nacken hatte versenken können. Die Schlange zischte und schlängelte sich zurück in das Loch.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Doch innen ist, erwartet kaum, ein Schrecken wie aus schlimmstem Traum"[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeris Herz schlug wie wild. Perpentach war schon zuvor sehr fantasievoll gewesen, aber normalerweise nicht auf eine so gefährliche und tödliche Art. Vielleicht hieß dies, dass er seines neuen Spielzeugs überdrüssig geworden war, und ihn nun entsorgen wollte. Beeri zuckte, als er merkte, dass ihn dieser Gedanke erleichterte. Das einzige, was ihn davon abhielt, sich wieder in das Loch mit der Schlange zu werfen, war der Gedanke an den lachenden Bastard hinter den Gitterstäben, und an alle interessanten Dinge, die er mit ihm tun könnte, wenn er nur die Gelegenheit dazu hätte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Doch die Vorstellung war anscheinend noch nicht vorbei: [PARAGRAPH:1]"Der Winzling wird das Gold behalten, lässt ihn die schrecklich Bestie walten..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri wirbelte herum, als ein Teil der Mauer seiner Höhle beiseite glitt, und einen Gang offenbarte, den er erst jetzt zum ersten Mal sah. Seine Augen weiteten sich, als sie den gewaltigen Hügelriesen erfassten, der in dem Gang stand, wütend grunzte, und eine Keule in der Hand hielt, die wohl dreimal so groß und zweimal so dick war wie Beeris Körper. Es war anscheinend sicher vorgesehen, dass er jetzt sterben sollte.[PARAGRAPH:1] Trotzdem, immer noch gab es etwas tief in Beeri, das nicht bereit war, aufzugeben, und ihn sterben zu lassen. Er dachte nicht an seine Freunde und seine Familie daheim in den Bergen, oder an sein Volk, das höchst sicher verloren war, ohne ihn als treibende Kraft. Alles an das er denken konnte, war, dass Perpentach, der wohl vorgesehen hatte, dass er sterben sollte, sich an seinem Tod erfreuen würde - und darum würde das nicht geschehen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er kümmerte sich nicht weiter um den lauernden Riesen, sondern griff mit starker Hand in das Loch, und bekam den sich windenden Körper der Viper zu fassen, diesen schleuderte er nun mit aller Kraft auf den Giganten. Die Viper landete neben dessen linken Bein, und versenkte, da sie die Gefahr spürte, ihre Zähne in den Fuß des Riesen. Dieser brüllte aus Schmerz und Wut, und zerschmetterte den Schädel der Schlange mit seiner Keule, doch innerhalb von Augenblicken brach er in Zuckungen aus, und kurz darauf fiel er flach auf seinen Rücken, und grünlicher Schaum tropfte aus seinem Mund. Perpentach musste eine Viper mit besonders starkem Gift ausgesucht haben, ironisch, dass diese nun Beeri gerettet hatte. [PARAGRAPH:1]Die Menge im Thronsaal applaudierte ein weiteres Mal, doch Beeri wartete nur auf Perpentachs nächste Falle. Doch was nun folgte, hatte er nicht erwartet:[PARAGRAPH:1]"Der Winzling, er war kühn und weise, gewinnt den höchsten Preis der Preise.[PARAGRAPH:1] Das Spiel ist aus, er kann nun geh'n, und Feinde applaudieren seh'n.[PARAGRAPH:1]Perpentach schritt elegant zu der Tür von Beeris Käfig, sperrte sie auf, und öffnete sie weit, mit einem geheimnisvollen Lächeln auf den Lippen. Beeri traute seinen Augen nicht. War das eine weitere Falle? Er hatte einige der Edelmänner ungehalten flüstern hören, und glaubte die Phrasen "...verschwendet eine nützliche Geisel" und "Eine seiner üblichen Launen..." zu verstehen.[PARAGRAPH:1] Langsam begann Beeri zu gehen. Einen Moment lang, überlegte er sich, ob er Perpentach angreifen sollte, seinen Hals ergreifen und ihn erwürgen sollte, bevor dessen Wachen ihm helfen könnten, doch als der Adrenalinstoß aus dem Kampf nachließ, dachte er klarer, und erkannte, dass so ein Versuch Selbstmord wäre. Wenn es Perpentach wirklich ernst war, ihn gehen zu lassen, könnte er später mit mehr Macht wiederkehren, und der Gedanke an einen mächtigen mechanischen Golem, der den Unterschenkel des Harlekins zerquetschte, war genug, um seinen Weg zu beschleunigen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er begann, aus dem Thronsaal zu laufen, und schaute nur selten zurück, doch niemand versuchte, ihn aufzuhalten, und Perpentach stand einfach nur an der offenen Käfigtür und lächelte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Erst als er schon ein gutes Stück von Perpentachs Palast entfernt war, schüttelte Beeri seinen Kopf in Gedanken an den Wahnsinn dieses Ortes, und begab sich auf den Weg nach Hause.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]"Venite gente, venite ad osservare il nano che cerca l'oro!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Quel grido svegliò Beeri dal suo riposo ben poco confortevole sul pavimento della gabbia. A malincuore iniziò a rimettersi in piedi. I primi giorni della sua prigionia aveva cercato di resistere quando lo spettacolo veniva annunciato; rimanendo ostinatamente in posizione sdraiata, ma aveva scoperto rapidamente che farlo peggiorava soltanto le cose.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sbatté le palpebre per via della luce brillante delle molte torce presenti nella sala del trono di Perpentach, quel tre volte maledetto pagliaccio da circo che lo aveva catturato qualche settimana prima. Una squadra di razziatori aveva assaltato la cittadina di confine che stava visitando, avevano confuso tutti con il loro strano stile di combattimento simil danza, e successivamente avevano preso Beeri come fosse un sacco di patate, cantando e ridendo mentre se ne andavano.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le risate erano diventate il suo peggior nemico nei giorni passati. A volte desiderava soltanto che Perpentach ordinasse di ucciderlo, o anche solo mandarlo in qualche oscuro sotteraneo per torturarlo. L'arlecchino sembrava determinato a spezzare il suo spirito, e aveva abilmente individuato il modo migliore per farlo. O forse era semplicemente annoiato, Beeri non poteva capire veramente Perpentach. Ma le sue ragioni non erano importanti, in quanto Beeri era sicuro della cosa che importava veramente, voleva uccidere quell'uomo, eliminare quel grottesco sorriso dalla sua faccia una volta per tutte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Lo spettacolo stava per iniziare. "Kilmorph, dammi la forza" mormorò, mentre Perpentach continuava col suo annuncio:[PARAGRAPH:1]"Una luce brillante splende nell'oscurità, una moneta d'oro in miniere fangose!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Perpentach si era alzato dal suo trono e si rivolgeva ai molti nobili davanti a lui, tutti con vestiti dalle foggie e colori più bizzarri, la maggior parte indossava maschere per nascondere il volto. Beeri sospettava che le facce sotto di esse potessero non avere espressioni felici come le maschere, come lui anche loro stavano simulando per evitare l'ira del loro sovrano.[PARAGRAPH:1]All'estremità della gabbia di Beeri vi era un buco nel pavimento, riempito di fango. Il modo preferito di Perpentach di torturarlo consisteva nel farlo immergere di testa nel buco per recuperare una moneta d'oro che veniva messa di solito vicino al fondo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri camminò rapidamente verso il buco, voleva concludere il prima possibile. Si inginocchio e infilò braccia e testa nel fango, cercando di ignorare le risate e gli applausi dei nobili presenti. Fortunatamente trovò rapidamente la forma familiare della moneta d'oro. Mentre la sua mano si chiudeva esitò improvvisamente. Qualcosa si stava muovendo nel fango, qualcosa di strisciante. Un sibilo penetrò il suo orecchio sinistro, e con un ruggito si lanciò all'indietro, aveva ancora la moneta in mano, ancora pochi secondi e la vipera avrebbe affondato i suoi denti nel suo collo. Il serpente sibilò e tornò strisciando dentro il buco.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Pericoli nelle miniere sembrerebbe, un terrore dai sogni più oscuri"[PARAGRAPH:1]Il cuore di Beeri batteva forte. Perpentach era stato creativo con lui prima, ma di solito non in maniera cosi potenzialmente fatale. Forse significava che si stava annoiando del suo nuovo giocattolo, e cercava di liberarsi di lui. Scrollò le spalle realizando che anche quell'evento fosse il benvenuto. L'unica cosa che lo tratteneva dal gettarsi di nuovo nel buco col serpente era il pensiero del bastardo che rideva fuori dalla gabbia, e ti tutte le cose che gli affrebbe potuto fare.[PARAGRAPH:1]Lo spettaccolo non era ancora finito comunque:[PARAGRAPH:1]"Il nano si tiene l'oro vedete, se questa bestia feroce lo lascia fare..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri si voltò mentre una sezione della parete della sua caverna si spostava, aprendo un passaggio che lui non sapeva esistere. I suoi occhi si dilatarono nel vedere un'enorme gigante delle colline al suo interno che grugniva furiosamente, e che impugnava una clava grande tre volte l'altezza e due volte la larghezza di Beeri. Era sicuro di morire adesso.[PARAGRAPH:1]Eppure, qualcosa dentro Beeri non era pronta ad arrendersi e morire cosi. Non pensò ai suoi amici o alla sua famiglia nelle montagne, ne al suo popolo che quasi sicuramente sarebbe stato perso senza di lui, mentre raccoglieva le forze. Tutto ciò a cui riusciva a pensare era che Perpentach voleva che lui morisse, che avrebbe tratto piacere dalla sua morte, e per questo non sarebbe avvenuta.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ignorò l'imponente gigante e invece infilò una mano nel buco, afferrando il corpo della vipera. Poi lanciò il serpente verso il gigante con tutta la sua forza. Atterrò sulla gamba sinistra del gigante e, percependo un pericolo, affondò immediatamente i denti nel piede del gigante. Quest'ultimo ruggi di dolore e rabbia e schiacciò la testa della vipera con la sua clava, ma in poco tempo iniziò ad avere le convulsioni, e poco dopo cascò all'indietro, con schiuma verdastra che usciva dalla sua bocca. Perpentach aveva ovviamente scelto una vipera con un potentissimo veleno. Ironico che fosse anche il suo salvatore.[PARAGRAPH:1]La folla della sala del trono applaudì di nuovo, ma Beeri stava semplicemente aspettando che Perpentach desse inizio alla prossima trappola mortale. Ciò che avvenne però lo sorprese:[PARAGRAPH:1]"Il nano ha vinto il premio più grande, ha dimostrato sia coraggio che saggezza.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ha vinto il gioco, che tutti lo applaudiscano mentre va via"[PARAGRAPH:1]Perpentach camminò con grazia verso la porta della sua gabbia, la sbloccò e l'aprì completamente con un sorriso misterioso sulle labbra. Beeri non poteva credere ai suoi occhi. Era un'altra trappola? Sentiva qualche nobile mormorare arrabbiato, pensava di aver sentito le frasi "sprecare un ostaggio cosi prezioso" e "Una delle sue solite fantasie..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Lentamente Beeri iniziò a camminare. Per un momento considerò l'attaccare Perpentach mentre attraversava la porta, afferrare la sua gola e cercare di strangolarlo prima che le sue guardie potessero aiutarlo. Mentre l'adrenalina della battaglia svaniva però iniziò a pensare più lucidamente, e realizzò che sarebbe stato un suicidio. Se Perpentach era veramente serio sul lasciarlo andare sarebbe potuto tornare in forze più tardi, il pensiero di un potente golem meccanico che schiacciava l'arlecchino sotto il piede fù sufficente a fargli accellerare il passo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Iniziò a correre per la sala del trono, lanciando occhiate dietro di lui occasionalmente, ma nessuno cerco di fermarlo, e Perpentach rimaneva vicino alla porta della gabbia sorridendo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Una volta fuori dal palazzo di Perpentach, Beeri scosse la testa per l'assurdità del posto, e inizio a percorrere la strada per casa.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]"Come now, people, come behold, the midget as he digs for gold!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The shout made Beeri stir from his uncomfortable sleep on the cage floor. He grudgingly started to get to his feet. The first few days of his imprisonment he had attempted to resist when the show was announced; stubbornly maintaining his lying position, but he had quickly found out that it only made things worse.[PARAGRAPH:1]He blinked against the brilliant light of the many torches lining the throne room of Perpentach, that thrice-damned carnival clown who'd taken him captive just a few weeks ago. A raiding party of merrymen had assaulted the outlying border town he had been visiting, confounding everyone with their strange dance-like fighting, and subsequently hauling Beeri off like a sack of potatoes, singing and laughing as they went.[PARAGRAPH:1]Laughter had become his worst adversary these past few days. He sometimes wished that Perpentach had just ordered him killed, or even hauled him down to some dark dungeon for torture. The harlequin seemed determined to break his spirit, and had skillfully assessed the most effective way of doing this. Or perhaps he was merely bored, Beeri could not really understand Perpentach. But his reasons were not important, as Beeri was completely certain of the one thing that mattered-he wanted to kill the man, to wipe that grotesque smile off his face once and for all.[PARAGRAPH:1]The show was about to begin. "Kilmorph, give me strength" he muttered under his breath, as Perpentach went on with his announcement:[PARAGRAPH:1]"A brilliant light in darkness shines, a piece of gold in muddy mines!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Perpentach had risen from his throne and addressed the many noblemen assembled before him, all garbed in clothes of the most bizarre shapes and colors, and most wearing masques to hide their faces. Beeri suspected that their real faces underneath might not wear quite as happy expressions as the masques-like him, they were just playing along to avoid their ruler's wrath.[PARAGRAPH:1] At the far end of Beeri's cage there was a circular hole in the floor, filled up with mud. Perpentach's preferred way of torturing him involved his diving head-first into the hole to recover a small gold-piece that had been placed there, usually near the bottom.[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri quickly walked towards the puddle, he wanted to get this over with as fast as possible. He kneeled down and plunged his arms and head into the mud, trying to shut the laughter and applause of the gathered noblemen out of his mind. Luckily he quickly got a hold of the familiar round shape of the coin. As his hand closed around it he suddenly hesitated. Something was moving in the mud, slithering shapes. A hiss penetrated his left ear, and with a roar he threw himself backwards-still clutching the coin-seconds before the viper would have let its fangs sink into his neck. The snake hissed and slithered back into the hole.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Danger in the mines it seems, a terror from the darkest dreams"[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri's heart was pounding. Perpentach had been creative with him before, but usually not in such a potentially fatal fashion. Perhaps it meant that he was getting bored of his new toy, and sought to dispose of him. He shrugged as he realized that the thought seemed welcome. The only thing that kept him from throwing himself back into the hole with the snake was the thought of the laughing bastard just outside the bars, and of all the creative things he could do to him given the chance.[PARAGRAPH:1]The show was not over yet, however:[PARAGRAPH:1]"The midget keeps his gold you see, if this foul beast will let him be..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Beeri whirled around as a section of wall in his cave slid away, opening a passageway he hadn't known existed. His eyes widened as he beheld the enormous hill giant that stood there, grunting furiously, and holding a club thrice the height and twice the width of Beeri's own body. He was most certainly meant to die now.[PARAGRAPH:1]Still, something deep within Beeri was not prepared to merely give in and die. He did not think of his friends and family back in the mountains, nor of his people who would most certainly be lost without him as he drew strength. All he could think of was that Perpentach meant for him to die, would draw pleasure from his death-and so it should not happen.[PARAGRAPH:1]He ignored the lumbering giant and instead dug a strong hand into the hole, grasping the writhing body of the viper. He then proceeded to fling the snake towards the giant with all his might. It landed by his left leg, and sensing a threat it immediately dug its teeth into the giant's feet. It roared with pain and fury and cracked the viper's skull with its club, but within moments it started to go into convulsions, and soon it fell flat on its back, greenish foam dripping from its mouth. Perpentach had obviously chosen a viper with a very potent venom. Ironic that it should be his savior.[PARAGRAPH:1]The crowd in the throne room applauded again, but Beeri was merely waiting for Perpentach to initiate the next death-trap. What followed surprised him, however:[PARAGRAPH:1]"The midget won the greatest prize, he proved to be both brave and wise.[PARAGRAPH:1]The game is won, the midgets foes, shall all applaud him as he goes"[PARAGRAPH:1]Perpentach gracefully walked to the door of his cage, unlocked it and opened it wide, a mysterious smile on his lips. Beeri couldn't believe his eyes. Was this another trap? He heard some of the noblemen muttering angrily, he thought he heard the phrases "…wasting a valuable hostage" and "One of his usual fancies..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Slowly Beeri started to walk. For a moment he considered assaulting Perpentach as he went out the door, grabbing his throat in an attempt to strangle him before his guards could rush to his aid. As the adrenaline rush of the battle faded, however, he started to think more clearly and realized that it would be suicide. If Perpentach was really serious about letting him go he could return in force later, and the thought of a mighty clockwork golem mashing the harlequin underfoot was enough to speed him on his way.[PARAGRAPH:1]He started to run across the floor of the throne room, looking backwards on occasion, but no one made any attempt at stopping him, and Perpentach just stood by the open prison door and smiled.[PARAGRAPH:1]Well out of Perpentach's palace, Beeri shook his head at the insanity of the place, and started to make his way home.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_GARRIM</Tag>
		<English>Garrim Gyr</English>
		<French>Garrim Gyr</French>
		<German>Garrim Gyr</German>
		<Italian>Garrim Gyr</Italian>
		<Spanish>Garrim Gyr</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_GARRIM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Garrim looked at the crystal that lay on the table before him. It had been brought in by the miners yesterday; at first mistaking it for silver, they had lost two of their number to its power. It had yet to be explained why. According to the disturbing tales of the other miners, the workers had simply died when they touched the substance, without it inflicting any visible wound on them. They'd merely fallen to the ground without a sound, their lifeforce disappearing completely. Finally, the miners realized the source of the threat, and one of them, unusually courageous, attempted to pick up the crystal with a piece of cloth, and so it was that they had brought it to him.[PARAGRAPH:1]He was about invoke a basic spell of scrying when his apprentice, Haeris, walked into his study.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What have I told you about knocking?!" Garrim yelled, with a fury more motivated by his tension than by actual irritation. Haeris seemed quite startled at his master's unusual display of temper.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sorry master, but you'd just sent for me, I thought..." he trailed off.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hmpf...well, now that you've come, you might as well stay. Who knows, you might even learn something from this. But please be quiet!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Haeris walked closer to the table in silence, but he appeared a bit sullen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Garrim ignored him, and returned his attention to the crystal. It was quite beautiful, and he fully understood why the unlucky miners had felt compelled to pick it up. Lights sparkled within its surface, red, purple and blue. Perhaps it would have been wiser to dispose of it, to take it to one of the deep mineshafts that were scheduled for closing soon, but Garrim had always been very curious about magical artifacts, whether they were benevolent or harmful.[PARAGRAPH:1]He raised his left hand, and started to invoke the spell of scrying. Surprisingly, there was no reaction whatsoever from the substance, he might as well have used the spell on a common rock. Puzzled, he looked closely at the crystal. It still sparkled with light...but it seemed the colors had grown darker while the light grew more intense...a truly unusual phenomenon to behold. As he watched, a dark mist suddenly started to emanate from the crystal, making a hissing sound somewhat akin to that of sulfuric acid liquefying metal. The mist started to approach Garrim, and soon it had surrounded him completely. The hissing sound became louder, and he realized it was actually a chorus of whispers: "You....binder of spells.....we need you...you need us...power...power beyond imagination....follow us...follow us...touch the relic...and you shall be free at last..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Garrim felt himself drawn towards the crystal, and he was about to reach out and touch it when he suddenly pulled himself back through a sheer effort of will. His ears away from the whispers and his head clear once more, he suddenly realized what he was dealing with here. "Mammon..." he muttered under his breath. He leapt backwards as the mist approached again, made a complicated hand-gesture and invoked the most powerful defensive spell he could remember. A pillar of brilliant light appeared before him, and the mist moved backwards, the whispers now more furious than compelling. Garrim drew a breath of relief. That had been close.[PARAGRAPH:1]Relief quickly gave way to terror, as Garrim suddenly saw Haeris on the other side of the barrier, and the mist that was rapidly closing in on him. It enveloped Haeris in much the same way as it had enveloped him moments earlier, but Haeris proved less resilient. He leaned forward and touched the crystal while Garrim watched, stunned by the sheer horror of the events taking place behind the wall of light.[PARAGRAPH:1]Haeris let out a scream of anguish, as a shaft of light from the crystal struck him in the chest. It lingered on as a pulsating beam seemed to be sucking the life away from him. Haeris' face became increasingly distorted, his flesh was slowly drained of all color, and his eyes gained a bluish hue. But suddenly the shaft of dark-red light subsided, and the mist dispersed with it. Garrim regained his senses, quickly dispelled the wall of light, and rushed to the side of his apprentice, who stood with a blank stare in his eyes.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are you all right? Haeris, speak to me!"[PARAGRAPH:1]At first he merely stared blankly at the crystal in front of him. Then he eyed Garrim, and his pale face was distorted by a sudden sneer.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am perfectly fine, master... I can see clearly now..."Garrim was shocked to hear the contempt in the voice of his previously amiable apprentice. What came next would prove even more horrifying, however.[PARAGRAPH:2]The battle had been rough. Garrim doubled over and coughed up blood, but managed to stay on his feet. Before him lay the burnt and disfigured corpse of his apprentice and friend, burned-and this was what hurt the most-by Garrim's own spells. Yet he had had no choice. The crystal still laid on the table, its surface now deceptively calm. The idea of throwing it into a deep mineshaft seemed much more compelling now. That thing had never been meant for daylight.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Garrim looked at the crystal that lay on the table before him. It had been brought in by the miners yesterday; at first mistaking it for silver, they had lost two of their number to its power. It had yet to be explained why. According to the disturbing tales of the other miners, the workers had simply died when they touched the substance, without it inflicting any visible wound on them. They'd merely fallen to the ground without a sound, their lifeforce disappearing completely. Finally, the miners realized the source of the threat, and one of them, unusually courageous, attempted to pick up the crystal with a piece of cloth, and so it was that they had brought it to him.[PARAGRAPH:1]He was about invoke a basic spell of scrying when his apprentice, Haeris, walked into his study.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What have I told you about knocking?!" Garrim yelled, with a fury more motivated by his tension than by actual irritation. Haeris seemed quite startled at his master's unusual display of temper.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sorry master, but you'd just sent for me, I thought..." he trailed off.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hmpf...well, now that you've come, you might as well stay. Who knows, you might even learn something from this. But please be quiet!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Haeris walked closer to the table in silence, but he appeared a bit sullen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Garrim ignored him, and returned his attention to the crystal. It was quite beautiful, and he fully understood why the unlucky miners had felt compelled to pick it up. Lights sparkled within its surface, red, purple and blue. Perhaps it would have been wiser to dispose of it, to take it to one of the deep mineshafts that were scheduled for closing soon, but Garrim had always been very curious about magical artifacts, whether they were benevolent or harmful.[PARAGRAPH:1]He raised his left hand, and started to invoke the spell of scrying. Surprisingly, there was no reaction whatsoever from the substance, he might as well have used the spell on a common rock. Puzzled, he looked closely at the crystal. It still sparkled with light...but it seemed the colors had grown darker while the light grew more intense...a truly unusual phenomenon to behold. As he watched, a dark mist suddenly started to emanate from the crystal, making a hissing sound somewhat akin to that of sulfuric acid liquefying metal. The mist started to approach Garrim, and soon it had surrounded him completely. The hissing sound became louder, and he realized it was actually a chorus of whispers: "You....binder of spells.....we need you...you need us...power...power beyond imagination....follow us...follow us...touch the relic...and you shall be free at last..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Garrim felt himself drawn towards the crystal, and he was about to reach out and touch it when he suddenly pulled himself back through a sheer effort of will. His ears away from the whispers and his head clear once more, he suddenly realized what he was dealing with here. "Mammon..." he muttered under his breath. He leapt backwards as the mist approached again, made a complicated hand-gesture and invoked the most powerful defensive spell he could remember. A pillar of brilliant light appeared before him, and the mist moved backwards, the whispers now more furious than compelling. Garrim drew a breath of relief. That had been close.[PARAGRAPH:1]Relief quickly gave way to terror, as Garrim suddenly saw Haeris on the other side of the barrier, and the mist that was rapidly closing in on him. It enveloped Haeris in much the same way as it had enveloped him moments earlier, but Haeris proved less resilient. He leaned forward and touched the crystal while Garrim watched, stunned by the sheer horror of the events taking place behind the wall of light.[PARAGRAPH:1]Haeris let out a scream of anguish, as a shaft of light from the crystal struck him in the chest. It lingered on as a pulsating beam seemed to be sucking the life away from him. Haeris' face became increasingly distorted, his flesh was slowly drained of all color, and his eyes gained a bluish hue. But suddenly the shaft of dark-red light subsided, and the mist dispersed with it. Garrim regained his senses, quickly dispelled the wall of light, and rushed to the side of his apprentice, who stood with a blank stare in his eyes.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are you all right? Haeris, speak to me!"[PARAGRAPH:1]At first he merely stared blankly at the crystal in front of him. Then he eyed Garrim, and his pale face was distorted by a sudden sneer.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am perfectly fine, master... I can see clearly now..."Garrim was shocked to hear the contempt in the voice of his previously amiable apprentice. What came next would prove even more horrifying, however.[PARAGRAPH:2]The battle had been rough. Garrim doubled over and coughed up blood, but managed to stay on his feet. Before him lay the burnt and disfigured corpse of his apprentice and friend, burned-and this was what hurt the most-by Garrim's own spells. Yet he had had no choice. The crystal still laid on the table, its surface now deceptively calm. The idea of throwing it into a deep mineshaft seemed much more compelling now. That thing had never been meant for daylight.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Garrim betrachtete den Kristall, der vor ihm auf dem Tisch lag. Die Bergleute hatten ihn gestern gebracht, sie hielten ihn vorerst für Silber, jedoch verloren sie zwei von ihnen durch seine Kraft. Die Ursache muss unbedingt aufgeklärt werden. Nach den Berichten der verstörten Bergleute hatten zwei von ihnen den Kristall nur berührt, als sie sofort und geräuschlos tot umfielen, ohne sichtbare Wunden. Ihre Lebenskraft wurde einfach aus ihnen herausgesogen. Dadurch erkannten die Bergleute die Gefahr und der mutigste von ihnen wickelte ein Stück Stoff darüber, sodass er gefahrlos ergriffen werden konnte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er war gerade dabei, einen Spruch ... zu beginnen, als sein Lehrling Haeris in sein Zimmer trat.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was habe ich dich gelehrt betreffend Anklopfen?" rief Garrim überrascht aus. Seine Wut kam mehr aus seiner Anspannung als aus der Irritation. Haeris schien sehr erschreckt über die ungewohnte Reaktion seines Meisters.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tut mir leid, Meister, ich dachte, du hast nach mir geschickt." klagte er.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Naja, na gut, wo du schon hier bist, kannst du auch bleiben. Wer weiss, vielleicht lernst du etwas daraus. Aber sei bitte still!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Haeris kam ruhig näher zum Tisch, er schien etwas gedämpft.[PARAGRAPH:1]Garrim beachtete ihn nicht weiter und wandte seine Aufmerksamkeit wieder dem Kristall zu. Dieser war sehr schön, er verstand, warum sich die unglücklichen Bergleute so angezogen fühlten. Lichter flogen über seine Oberfläche, rot, violett und blau. Vielleicht war es weiser, ihn einfach wegzuwerfen, in eine der tiefen Minenschächte, die bald verschlossen werden. Aber Garrim war stets neugierig, besonders auf magische Artefakte, egal ob sie harmlos oder gefährlich waren.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er hob wieder seinen Arm, um den ...Spruch zu beginnen. Überraschenderweise trat keine Reaktion auf dem Kristall ein, er reagierte wie ein gewöhnlicher Felsbrocken. Verblüfft sah er genauer hin: Es stoben noch immer Funken, es schien, die Farben waren dunkler geworden, die Helligkeit war gestiegen - ein tatsächlich ungewöhnliches Phänomen. Als er weiter beobachtete, sah er, wie plötzlich vom Kristall aus ein dunkler Nebel aufstieg, ein zischendes Geräusch war hörbar, als ob Schwefelsäure ein unedles Metall auflöste. Der Nebel kam zu Garrim und bald war er völlig eingehüllt. Das Zischen wurde lauter, plötzlich verstand er den Chor der flüsternden Stimmen: "Du ... Spruchbinder ...wir brauchen dich...du brauchst uns...Macht...Macht über alle Vorstellung... folge uns...folge uns...berühre den Kristall...und du wirst endlich frei sein..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Garrim fühlte sich selbst hingezogen zum Kristall, er war dabei, die Hand auszustrecken, um ihn zu berühren. Plötzlich zog er sich selbst durch reine Willenstärke zurück. Seine Ohren hörten das Flüstern nicht mehr, sein Kopf war wieder klar. Plötzlich verstand er, womit er es zu tun hatte: "Mammon ..."stieß er hervor. Er sprang zurück, als der Nebel wieder kam, er vollführte eine komplizierte Geste, als er seinen mächtigsten Verteidigungszauber anwandte, den er kannte. Eine Säule aus strahlendem Licht erschien vor ihm, der Nebel trat zurück, das Flüstern wurde mehr zornig als unwiderstehlich. Garrim zog scharf den Atem ein, das war sehr knapp gewesen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Ruhe wich dem Schrecken, als er plötzlich Haeris auf der anderen Seite der Barriere sah, wie sich ihm der Nebel rasch näherte. Er umhüllte Haeris wie zuvor ihn, aber dieser erwies sich als weniger widerstandsfähig. Er beugte sich vor und berührte den Kristall, während Garrim zusah, völlig gebannt durch den Schrecken der Ereignisse, die hinter der Lichtwand abliefen.[PARAGRAPH:1] Haeris stieß einen qualvollen Schrei aus, als ihn ein Lichtstrahl vom Kristall in der Brust traf. Dieser pulsierende Strahl schien ihm das Leben auszusaugen. Haeris Gesicht wurde stark entstellt, seine Haut verlor sämtliche Farbe, seine Augen bekamen einen bläulichen Schein. Aber plötzlich verschwand der dunkelrote Lichtstrahl und der Nebel verschwand mit ihm. Garrim war wieder handlungsfähig, brachte rasch die Lichtwand zum Verschwinden und sprang zu seinem Lehrling, der mit blankem Entsetzen in den Augen starr dastand.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bist du in Ordnung? Haeeris, sprich zu mir!"[PARAGRAPH:1] Zuerst starrte er nur auf den Kristall vor ihm. Dann sah er zu Garrim und sein blasses Gesicht wurde durch ein plötzliches höhnisches Grinsen entstellt.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mir geht es sehr gut, Meister! ...Ich sehe nun ganz klar..." Garrim war geschockt, eine derartige Verachtung in der Stimme seines sonst so freundlichen Lehrlings zu hören. Was folgte, war jedoch noch viel erschreckender.[PARAGRAPH:2]Der Kampf war hart gewesen. Garrim wankte und hustete Blut, aber er schaffte es, auf den Füßen zu bleiben. Vor ihm lag der verbrannte und entstellte Leichnam seines Lehrlings und Freunds, verbrannt, was ihn am meisten traf - durch Garrims eigene Zaubersprüche. Aber Er hatte keine andere Wahl gehabt. Der Kristall lag ruhig auf den Tisch, seine Oberfläche war nun völlig ruhig. Der Gedanke, ihn in den tiefsten Schacht zu werfen, war nun viel verlockender geworden. Dieses Artefakt war niemals für Tageslicht gedacht.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Garrim osservò il cristallo che stava sopra il tavolo davanti a lui. Gli era stato portato dai minatori ieri; all'inizio lo avevano scambiato per argento, e due minatori erano morti a causa del suo potere. Bisognava ancora capire perché però. Secondo gli inquietanti racconti degli altri minatori, i due che sono morti hanno toccato il cristallo, senza però che questo gli infliggesse alcuna ferita visibile. SI erano semplicemente accasciati a terra senza un lamento, la loro vitalità svanita completamente. Alla fine i minatori compresero la fonte del pericolo, e uno di loro, insolitamente coraggioso, provò a raccogliere il cristallo con un pezzo di stoffa, ed è cosi che glielo avevano portato.[PARAGRAPH:1]Stava per lanciare una magia di divinazione quando il suo apprendista, Haeris, entrò nel suo studio.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Che cosa ti ho detto riguardo il bussare?!" Garrim urlò, con una furia motivata più dalla tensione che da un'effettiva irritazione. Haeris sembrò abbastanza sorpreso da questo insolito umore del suo maestro.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Scusate maestro, ma mi avete fatto chiamare, ho pensato..." poi si interruppe.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hmpf...be, ora che sei qui, puoi anche rimanere. Chi sa, potresti anche imparare qualcosa da questo. Ma per piacere fai silenzio!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Haeris si avvicinò al tavolo in silenzio, ma sembrava un pò cupo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Garrim lo ignorò, e rivolse di nuovo le sue attenzioni al cristallo. Era abbastanza bello, e comprendeva pienamente perchè i minatori sfortunati avevano cercato di prenderlo. Delle luci scintillavano sulla sua superfice, rosse, viola e blu. Forse sarebbe stato più saggio disfarsene, di portarlo in una delle miniere più profonde che erano da chiudere a breve, ma Garrim era sempre stato curioso riguardo artefatti magici, sia che fossero vantaggiosi o dannosi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alzò la mano sinistra, e iniziò a lanciare una magia di divinazione. Sorprendentemente non vi fù alcuna reazione da parte del cristallo. Perplesso osservò più da vicino il cristallo. Era ancora scintillante di luci...ma sembrava che i colori diventavano sempre più scuri e la luce più intensa...un fenomeno veramente insolito da ammirare. Mentre lo osservava, il cristallo iniziò ad emettere improvvisamente una nebbiolina, facendo anche un sibilo simile a quello fatto dall'acido solforico che scioglie il metallo. La nebbiolina si stava avvicinando a Garrim, e in breve lo circondò completamente. Il sibilo divenne più forte e comprese che era in realtà un coro di sussurri: "Tu....lanciatore di magie.....abbiamo bisogno di te...tu hai bisogno di noi...potere...potere oltre ogni immaginazione....seguici...seguici...tocca la reliquia...e sarai finalmente libero..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Garrim si sentì attratto dal cristallo, e stava quasi per toccarlo quando improvvisamente si ritrasse attraverso uno sforzo di volontà. Con le orecchie lontane dai sussurri e il pensiero di nuovo chiaro comprese improvvisamente con cosa aveva a che fare. "Mammon..." mormorò. Si allontanò di nuovo quando la nebbiolina provò ad avvicinarsi di nuovo, compì dei complicati gesti e lanciò la magia di difesa più forte che riusciva a ricordare. Un pilastro di luce brillante apparve davanti a lui, e la nebbiolina indietreggiò, i sussurri ora erano più furiosi che compiacenti. Garrim tirò un sospiro di sollievo. C'era mancato poco.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il sollievo fu rapidamente sostituito dal terrore quando Garrim vide improvvisamente Haeris dall'altra parte della barriera, con la nebbiolina che si stava rapidamente dirigendo verso di lui. Quest'ultima avvolse Haeris nello stesso modo che aveva fatto con lui poco prima, ma Haeris si dimostrò meno resistente. Lui toccò il cristallo mentre Garrim osservava, stordito dall'orrore di ciò che stava succedendo dietro il muro di luce.[PARAGRAPH:1]Haeris urlò di dolore mentre un fascio di luce proveniente dal cristallo lo colpiva nel petto. Rimase fermo mentre il fascio di luce sembrava prosciugare la sua essenza vitale. Il volto di Haeris si deformò ancor di più, la sua pelle venne lentamente privata di qualsiasi colore, e i suoi occhi divennerò bluastri. Poi improvvisamente il fascio di luce rosso scuro svanì e la nebbiolina si disperse. Garrim tornò in se, disspiò rapidamente il muro di luce, e corse al fianco dell'apprendista, che aveva uno sguardo vuoto negli occhi.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Stai bene? Haeris, parlami!"[PARAGRAPH:1]All'inizio fissò senza espressione il cristallo davanti a lui. Poi si voltò verso Garrim, e sul suo volto pallido comparì improvvisamente un ghigno.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sto benissimo, maestro... Posso vedere chiaramente ora..."Garrim rimase scioccato dal disprezzo che sentiva nella voce del suo apprendista che era sempre stato molto amabile. Ciò che avvenne dopo si dimostrò perfino più orribile però.[PARAGRAPH:2]Lo scontro era stato duro. Garrim si piegò in due e tossì sangue, ma riuscì a rimanere in piedi. Davanti a lui c'era il cadavere bruciato e deformato del suo apprendista e amico, bruciato, e questo era ciò che lo feriva maggiormente, dalle stesse magie di Garrim. Eppure non ha avuto scelta. Il cristallo era ancora sul tavolo, la sua superfice apparentemente tranquilla. L'idea di lanciarlo nella miniera più profonda era molto più attraente ora. Quella cosa non era fatta per vedere la luce del giorno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Garrim looked at the crystal that lay on the table before him. It had been brought in by the miners yesterday; at first mistaking it for silver, they had lost two of their number to its power. It had yet to be explained why. According to the disturbing tales of the other miners, the workers had simply died when they touched the substance, without it inflicting any visible wound on them. They'd merely fallen to the ground without a sound, their lifeforce disappearing completely. Finally, the miners realized the source of the threat, and one of them, unusually courageous, attempted to pick up the crystal with a piece of cloth, and so it was that they had brought it to him.[PARAGRAPH:1]He was about invoke a basic spell of scrying when his apprentice, Haeris, walked into his study.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What have I told you about knocking?!" Garrim yelled, with a fury more motivated by his tension than by actual irritation. Haeris seemed quite startled at his master's unusual display of temper.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sorry master, but you'd just sent for me, I thought..." he trailed off.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hmpf...well, now that you've come, you might as well stay. Who knows, you might even learn something from this. But please be quiet!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Haeris walked closer to the table in silence, but he appeared a bit sullen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Garrim ignored him, and returned his attention to the crystal. It was quite beautiful, and he fully understood why the unlucky miners had felt compelled to pick it up. Lights sparkled within its surface, red, purple and blue. Perhaps it would have been wiser to dispose of it, to take it to one of the deep mineshafts that were scheduled for closing soon, but Garrim had always been very curious about magical artifacts, whether they were benevolent or harmful.[PARAGRAPH:1]He raised his left hand, and started to invoke the spell of scrying. Surprisingly, there was no reaction whatsoever from the substance, he might as well have used the spell on a common rock. Puzzled, he looked closely at the crystal. It still sparkled with light...but it seemed the colors had grown darker while the light grew more intense...a truly unusual phenomenon to behold. As he watched, a dark mist suddenly started to emanate from the crystal, making a hissing sound somewhat akin to that of sulfuric acid liquefying metal. The mist started to approach Garrim, and soon it had surrounded him completely. The hissing sound became louder, and he realized it was actually a chorus of whispers: "You....binder of spells.....we need you...you need us...power...power beyond imagination....follow us...follow us...touch the relic...and you shall be free at last..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Garrim felt himself drawn towards the crystal, and he was about to reach out and touch it when he suddenly pulled himself back through a sheer effort of will. His ears away from the whispers and his head clear once more, he suddenly realized what he was dealing with here. "Mammon..." he muttered under his breath. He leapt backwards as the mist approached again, made a complicated hand-gesture and invoked the most powerful defensive spell he could remember. A pillar of brilliant light appeared before him, and the mist moved backwards, the whispers now more furious than compelling. Garrim drew a breath of relief. That had been close.[PARAGRAPH:1]Relief quickly gave way to terror, as Garrim suddenly saw Haeris on the other side of the barrier, and the mist that was rapidly closing in on him. It enveloped Haeris in much the same way as it had enveloped him moments earlier, but Haeris proved less resilient. He leaned forward and touched the crystal while Garrim watched, stunned by the sheer horror of the events taking place behind the wall of light.[PARAGRAPH:1]Haeris let out a scream of anguish, as a shaft of light from the crystal struck him in the chest. It lingered on as a pulsating beam seemed to be sucking the life away from him. Haeris' face became increasingly distorted, his flesh was slowly drained of all color, and his eyes gained a bluish hue. But suddenly the shaft of dark-red light subsided, and the mist dispersed with it. Garrim regained his senses, quickly dispelled the wall of light, and rushed to the side of his apprentice, who stood with a blank stare in his eyes.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are you all right? Haeris, speak to me!"[PARAGRAPH:1]At first he merely stared blankly at the crystal in front of him. Then he eyed Garrim, and his pale face was distorted by a sudden sneer.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am perfectly fine, master... I can see clearly now..."Garrim was shocked to hear the contempt in the voice of his previously amiable apprentice. What came next would prove even more horrifying, however.[PARAGRAPH:2]The battle had been rough. Garrim doubled over and coughed up blood, but managed to stay on his feet. Before him lay the burnt and disfigured corpse of his apprentice and friend, burned-and this was what hurt the most-by Garrim's own spells. Yet he had had no choice. The crystal still laid on the table, its surface now deceptively calm. The idea of throwing it into a deep mineshaft seemed much more compelling now. That thing had never been meant for daylight.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_GIMIL</Tag>
		<English>Gimil</English>
		<French>Gimil</French>
		<German>Gimil</German>
		<Italian>Gimil</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gimil</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_GIFTS_OF_NANTOSUELTA</Tag>
		<English>Gifts of Nantosuelta</English>
		<French>Présents de Nantosuelta</French>
		<German>Geschenke des Nantosuelta</German>
		<Italian>Doni di Nantosuelta</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gifts of Nantosuelta</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_GIFTS_OF_NANTOSUELTA_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Creates a Golden Hammer in each of your cities</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Crée un Marteau doré dans chacune de vos villes</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erschafft einen Goldenen Hammer in jeder euerer Städte</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Crea un Martello Dorato in ognuna delle tue città</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Creates a Golden Hammer in each of your cities</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ADULARIA_CHAMBER</Tag>
		<English>Adularia Chamber</English>
		<French>Chambre d'Adularia</French>
		<German>Mineralienkammer</German>
		<Italian>Camera Adularia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Adularia Chamber</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ADULARIA_CHAMBER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Grants every golem built in the city the [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Hidden[\LINK] promotion, which makes them invisible until they attack or cast a spell.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Offre à chaque golem construit dans la ville la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Dissimulé[\LINK], ce qui les rend invisible jusqu'à ce qu'ils attaquent ou lancent un sort.</French>
		<German>Durch die Mineralienkammer erhält jeder in der Stadt gebaute Golem die [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Versteckt[\LINK] Beförderung, die sie unsichtbar macht bis sie angreifen oder einen Zauber sprechen.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a ogni golem costruito dalla città la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Nascosto[\LINK], che rende l'unità invisibile sino a quando attacca o lancia una magia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Grants every golem built in the city the [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Hidden[\LINK] promotion, which makes them invisible until they attack or cast a spell.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ADULARIA_CHAMBER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Grants every golem built in the city the [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Hidden[\LINK] promotion, which makes them invisible until they attack or cast a spell.</English>
		<French>Offre à chaque golem construit dans la ville la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Dissimulé[\LINK], ce qui les rend invisible jusqu'à ce qu'ils attaquent ou lancent un sort.</French>
		<German>Durch die Mineralienkammer erhält jeder in der Stadt gebaute Golem die [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Versteckt[\LINK] Beförderung, die sie unsichtbar macht bis sie angreifen oder einen Zauber sprechen.</German>
		<Italian>Fornisce a ogni golem costruito dalla città la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Nascosto[\LINK], che rende l'unità invisibile sino a quando attacca o lancia una magia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grants every golem built in the city the [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Hidden[\LINK] promotion, which makes them invisible until they attack or cast a spell.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BLASTING_WORKSHOP</Tag>
		<English>Blasting Workshop</English>
		<French>Atelier d'Explosifs</French>
		<German>Sprengwerkstatt</German>
		<Italian>Fabbrica di Esplosivi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Taller de Explosivos</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BLASTING_WORKSHOP_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Grants all golems produced in the city the ability to cast [LINK=SPELL_FIREBALL]Fireball[\LINK].</English>
		<French>Donne à tous les Golems construits dans la ville la capacité de lancer des [LINK=SPELL_FIREBALL]Boules de Feu[\LINK].</French>
		<German>Alle in dieser Stadt gebauten Golems erhalten die Fähigkeit Feuerbälle zu schleudern.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a ogni golem costruito dalla città l'abilità di lanciare [LINK=SPELL_FIREBALL]Palle di Fuoco[\LINK].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Proporciona a todos los golems producidos en la ciudad con la habilidad de lanzar [LINK=SPELL_FIREBALL]Bola de Fuego[\LINK].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BLASTING_WORKSHOP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Grants all golems produced in the city the ability to cast [LINK=SPELL_FIREBALL]Fireball[\LINK].</English>
		<French>Donne à tous les Golems construit dans la ville la capacité de lancer des Boules de Feu.</French>
		<German>Alle in dieser Stadt gebauten Golems erhalten die Fähigkeit Feuerbälle zu schleudern.</German>
		<Italian>Fornisce a ogni golem costruito dalla città l'abilità di lanciare [LINK=SPELL_FIREBALL]Palle di Fuoco[\LINK].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Proporciona a todos los golems producidos en la ciudad con la habilidad de lanzar Bola de Fuego.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MACHINISTS_SHOP</Tag>
		<English>Machinists Shop</English>
		<French>Atelier des Machinistes</French>
		<German>Mechanikus</German>
		<Italian>Laboratorio dei Macchinisti</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tienda del Maquinista</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_LUCHUIRP</Tag>
		<English>Luchuirp Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Luchuri</French>
		<German>Palast der Luchuirp</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo dei Luchuirp</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Luchuirp</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALLENS_ENGINE</Tag>
		<English>Pallens Engine</English>
		<French>Manufacture Pallens</French>
		<German>Pallens Maschine</German>
		<Italian>Reattore Pallen</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pallens Engine</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALLENS_ENGINE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Grants every golem built in the city the [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Perfect Sight[\LINK] promotion, which makes them able to see invisible opponents.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Grants every golem built in the city the [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Perfect Sight[\LINK] promotion, which makes them able to see invisible opponents.</French>
		<German>Durch Pallens Maschine erhält jeder in der Stadt gebaute Golem die [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Perfekte Sicht[\LINK] Beförderung, die es ermöglicht unsichtbare Gegner zu sehen.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce ad ogni golem costruito dalla città la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Vista Perfetta[\LINK], che dà all'unità la capacità di vedere le unità invisibili.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Grants every golem built in the city the [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Perfect Sight[\LINK] promotion, which makes them able to see invisible opponents.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALLENS_ENGINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Grants every golem built in the city the [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Perfect Sight[\LINK] promotion, which makes them able to see invisible opponents.</English>
		<French>Grants every golem built in the city the [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Perfect Sight[\LINK] promotion, which makes them able to see invisible opponents.</French>
		<German>Durch Pallens Maschine erhält jeder in der Stadt gebaute Golem die [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Perfekte Sicht[\LINK] Beförderung, die es ermöglicht unsichtbare Gegner zu sehen.</German>
		<Italian>Fornisce ad ogni golem costruito dalla città la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Vista Perfetta[\LINK], che dà all'unità la capacità di vedere le unità invisibili.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grants every golem built in the city the [LINK=PROMOTION_PERFECT_SIGHT]Perfect Sight[\LINK] promotion, which makes them able to see invisible opponents.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SCULPTORS_STUDIO</Tag>
		<English>Sculptor's Studio</English>
		<French>Atelier de Sculpture</French>
		<German>Bildhauerwerkstatt</German>
		<Italian>Studio dello Scultore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Estudio del Escultor</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SCULPTORS_STUDIO_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In most Luchuirp cities, the sculptor's studio can be found next to the graveyard. Charged with crafting both golems and gravestones, the mason's art perfectly embodies both life and death.[PARAGRAPH:1]It is a well-known fact that the craft of a sculptor is often one of the most profitable professions within Luchuirp society. Many years ago, a young sculptor carved an iron golem with the face of Athos Ulthane, the savior of Ironstone Pass. Since that day many prominent citizens became supporters of the arts in the hope that they might be remembered in a similar fashion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Yet what of the lesser golems, those baked from mud and clay and the detritus of the streets. The silent servants that perform the tasks that no one else wants to. Who knows what faces adorn these pitiless creatures? Ask all you want. For all the words written in the heads, none will ever emerge from their lips.[PARAGRAPH:1]But if you pay for sufficient drinks and listen carefully to the whispers of the right rotgut beggar in the wrong part of Ithralia, you might learn that the golem which cleans the sewers at the docks bears an uncanny resemblance to Hamish Two-Strings, the infamous murderer and thief.[PARAGRAPH:1]In death, as in life, social hierarchies remain, carved in metal and stone and clay forever.</English>
		<French>[TAB]In most Luchuirp cities, the sculptor's studio can be found next to the graveyard. Charged with crafting both golems and gravestones, the mason's art perfectly embodies both life and death.[PARAGRAPH:1]It is a well-known fact that the craft of a sculptor is often one of the most profitable professions within Luchuirp society. Many years ago, a young sculptor carved an iron golem with the face of Athos Ulthane, the savior of Ironstone Pass. Since that day many prominent citizens became supporters of the arts in the hope that they might be remembered in a similar fashion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Yet what of the lesser golems, those baked from mud and clay and the detritus of the streets. The silent servants that perform the tasks that no one else wants to. Who knows what faces adorn these pitiless creatures? Ask all you want. For all the words written in the heads, none will ever emerge from their lips.[PARAGRAPH:1]But if you pay for sufficient drinks and listen carefully to the whispers of the right rotgut beggar in the wrong part of Ithralia, you might learn that the golem which cleans the sewers at the docks bears an uncanny resemblance to Hamish Two-Strings, the infamous murderer and thief.[PARAGRAPH:1]In death, as in life, social hierarchies remain, carved in metal and stone and clay forever.</French>
		<German>[TAB]In most Luchuirp cities, the sculptor's studio can be found next to the graveyard. Charged with crafting both golems and gravestones, the mason's art perfectly embodies both life and death.[PARAGRAPH:1]It is a well-known fact that the craft of a sculptor is often one of the most profitable professions within Luchuirp society. Many years ago, a young sculptor carved an iron golem with the face of Athos Ulthane, the savior of Ironstone Pass. Since that day many prominent citizens became supporters of the arts in the hope that they might be remembered in a similar fashion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Yet what of the lesser golems, those baked from mud and clay and the detritus of the streets. The silent servants that perform the tasks that no one else wants to. Who knows what faces adorn these pitiless creatures? Ask all you want. For all the words written in the heads, none will ever emerge from their lips.[PARAGRAPH:1]But if you pay for sufficient drinks and listen carefully to the whispers of the right rotgut beggar in the wrong part of Ithralia, you might learn that the golem which cleans the sewers at the docks bears an uncanny resemblance to Hamish Two-Strings, the infamous murderer and thief.[PARAGRAPH:1]In death, as in life, social hierarchies remain, carved in metal and stone and clay forever.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Nella maggior parte delle città Luchuirp lo Studio dello Scultore si trova vicino al cimitero. Incaricati di creare sia golem che lapidi, l'arte degli scultori rappresenta perfettamente sia la vita che la morte.[PARAGRAPH:1]È cosa risaputa che il mestiere dello scultore è spesso una delle professioni più remunerativa tra i Luchuirp. Molti anni fa un giovane scultore creò un golem di ferro con il volto di Athos Ulthane, il salvatore del Passo di Pietraferrea. Da quel giorno molti cittadini importanti divennero sostenitori delle arti nella speranza di venir ricordati un giorno nella stessa maniera.[PARAGRAPH:1]E per quanto riguarda i golem minori, quelli fatti di fango, argilla e detriti delle strade. I silenziosi servitori che portano a termine i compiti che nessun altro vuole fare. Chi sa quale volto hanno queste creature? Chiediglelo pure. Per quanto le loro teste siano piene di parole non una esce mai dalla loro bocca.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ma se paghi sufficenti bevute e ascolti attentamente i sussurri dei giusti mendicanti ubriaconi dei peggiori posti di Ithralia, postresti scoprire che i golem che puliscono le fogne al porto sono stranamente simili a Hamish Due Corde, il famigerato omicida e ladro.[PARAGRAPH:1]Nella morte, come in vita, le gerarchie sociali rimangono, scolpite nel metallo, nella pietra e nell'argilla per sempre.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]In most Luchuirp cities, the sculptor's studio can be found next to the graveyard. Charged with crafting both golems and gravestones, the mason's art perfectly embodies both life and death.[PARAGRAPH:1]It is a well-known fact that the craft of a sculptor is often one of the most profitable professions within Luchuirp society. Many years ago, a young sculptor carved an iron golem with the face of Athos Ulthane, the savior of Ironstone Pass. Since that day many prominent citizens became supporters of the arts in the hope that they might be remembered in a similar fashion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Yet what of the lesser golems, those baked from mud and clay and the detritus of the streets. The silent servants that perform the tasks that no one else wants to. Who knows what faces adorn these pitiless creatures? Ask all you want. For all the words written in the heads, none will ever emerge from their lips.[PARAGRAPH:1]But if you pay for sufficient drinks and listen carefully to the whispers of the right rotgut beggar in the wrong part of Ithralia, you might learn that the golem which cleans the sewers at the docks bears an uncanny resemblance to Hamish Two-Strings, the infamous murderer and thief.[PARAGRAPH:1]In death, as in life, social hierarchies remain, carved in metal and stone and clay forever.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TINKERERS_WORKSHOP</Tag>
		<English>Tinkerer's Workshop</English>
		<French>Atelier du Bricoleur</French>
		<German>Bastlerwerkstatt</German>
		<Italian>Laboratorio del Tuttofare</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tinkerer's Workshop</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TINKERERS_WORKSHOP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Luchuirp all like to pitch in.  Craftsman who leave their workshops unattended may return to discover much of their work done for them.  The best craftsman have very good locks.  The smart craftsman don't bother - too many of their peers like a challenge.</English>
		<French>The Luchuirp all like to pitch in.  Craftsman who leave their workshops unattended may return to discover much of their work done for them.  The best craftsman have very good locks.  The smart craftsman don't bother - too many of their peers like a challenge.</French>
		<German>Die Luchuirp mögen es alle hineinzuspringen.  Handwerker, die ihre Werkstatt unbeaufsichtigt zurücklassen, mögen bei ihrer Rückkehr viel von ihrer Arbeit erledigt vorfinden. Die besten Handwerker haben sehr gute Schlösser.  Den kluge Handwerker kümmert's nicht - zu viele ihrer Art lieben die Herausforderung.</German>
		<Italian>A tutti i Luchuirp piace partecipare. Gli artigiani che lasciano i loro laboratori incustoditi potrebbero trovare la maggior parte del lavoro già fatto da altri al loro ritorno. Gli artigiani migliori hanno lucchetti moto buoni. Quelli intelligenti non se ne preoccupano, a troppi dei loro simili piacciono le sfide.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Luchuirp all like to pitch in.  Craftsman who leave their workshops unattended may return to discover much of their work done for them.  The best craftsman have very good locks.  The smart craftsman don't bother - too many of their peers like a challenge.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BARNAXUS</Tag>
		<English>Barnaxus</English>
		<French>Barnaxus</French>
		<German>Barnaxus</German>
		<Italian>Barnaxus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Barnaxus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BARNAXUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Barnaxus was beautiful, perfect. The pinnacle of years of work, of finding the right words to power him, of selecting just the right pieces, of lovingly sculpting every little detail of his joints and his features. Barnaxus was more nimble, more exact, more careful and more effective in everything he did than any of the other golems that were built in the empire of Khrad'Ke-zun. For many hundred years, this giant did as he was told, when he was told, and always did it better than anyone else, dwarven or golem. Barnaxus works were the pride of the Empire, and, when the ice sheets smothered the world, the name and reputation of Barnaxus passed into legend.[PARAGRAPH:1]Perhaps it was this legendary status that meant that when, years after the Ice had pulled back and the Luchuirp embarked on their mission of rebuilding the Empire, a tall, weather-worn golem appeared at the gates of the capital, he was instantly recognized as the long-lost Barnaxus. For, surely, only a golem of such perfection and brilliance as Barnaxus could have survived so long without maintenance and protection? [PARAGRAPH:1]It quickly became clear that Barnaxus was unlike any other golem. Barnaxus did not "take orders." He cooperated, he discussed, and he made suggestions. Barnaxus was a thinking golem, a learning golem. No one could guess how he had managed to break the magical ties that bind a golem to the two-dimensional world of "order and execution", and nobody really expected that they would ever find out. When asked, Barnaxus merely said: "A man spoke to me in the wastes and I awoke," he would say no more. [PARAGRAPH:1]True, Barnaxus could do what he wished, but what he wished was to help the Luchuirp. He wished to help them rebuild the Empire, to recall what was forgotten, and to perfect what was remembered. He appeared to harbor a love for the Luchuirp that mirrored that of a doting father, with a hint of a patronizing air to some of his advice. And the Luchuirp, amazingly, instead of rankling at being "taught" by a golem, loved him back. He was their link to the past and an amazing store of knowledge. Golems, after all, never forget. But most important of all, Barnaxus also taught the golems. What Barnaxus learned, the other golems soon copied. [PARAGRAPH:1]And so it was that Barnaxus went from being the "King of the Golems" to being a true leader of golems and of dwarves.</English>
		<French>Barnaxus was beautiful, perfect. The pinnacle of years of work, of finding the right words to power him, of selecting just the right pieces, of lovingly sculpting every little detail of his joints and his features. Barnaxus was more nimble, more exact, more careful and more effective in everything he did than any of the other golems that were built in the empire of Khrad'Ke-zun. For many hundred years, this giant did as he was told, when he was told, and always did it better than anyone else, dwarven or golem. Barnaxus works were the pride of the Empire, and, when the ice sheets smothered the world, the name and reputation of Barnaxus passed into legend.[PARAGRAPH:1]Perhaps it was this legendary status that meant that when, years after the Ice had pulled back and the Luchuirp embarked on their mission of rebuilding the Empire, a tall, weather-worn golem appeared at the gates of the capital, he was instantly recognized as the long-lost Barnaxus. For, surely, only a golem of such perfection and brilliance as Barnaxus could have survived so long without maintenance and protection? [PARAGRAPH:1]It quickly became clear that Barnaxus was unlike any other golem. Barnaxus did not "take orders." He cooperated, he discussed, and he made suggestions. Barnaxus was a thinking golem, a learning golem. No one could guess how he had managed to break the magical ties that bind a golem to the two-dimensional world of "order and execution", and nobody really expected that they would ever find out. When asked, Barnaxus merely said: "A man spoke to me in the wastes and I awoke," he would say no more. [PARAGRAPH:1]True, Barnaxus could do what he wished, but what he wished was to help the Luchuirp. He wished to help them rebuild the Empire, to recall what was forgotten, and to perfect what was remembered. He appeared to harbor a love for the Luchuirp that mirrored that of a doting father, with a hint of a patronizing air to some of his advice. And the Luchuirp, amazingly, instead of rankling at being "taught" by a golem, loved him back. He was their link to the past and an amazing store of knowledge. Golems, after all, never forget. But most important of all, Barnaxus also taught the golems. What Barnaxus learned, the other golems soon copied. [PARAGRAPH:1]And so it was that Barnaxus went from being the "King of the Golems" to being a true leader of golems and of dwarves.</French>
		<German>Barnaxus war schön, er war perfekt. Er war der Höhepunkt von Jahren der Arbeit, dem Finden des richtigen Spruchs um ihn zu beleben, der genauen Auswahl des richtigen Holzes vom richtigen Baum, der liebevollen Formung seiner Körperteile und seiner Fähigkeiten. Barnaxus war geschickter, genauer, vorsichtiger und effektiver in allem was er tat als alle anderen Golems die im Königreich Khrad’Ke-zun geschaffen wurden. Für viele Jahrhunderte tat dieser aus Eisen und Holz geschaffene Riese wie ihm befohlen wurde und er tat es immer besser als alle anderen, egal ob Zwerg oder Golem. Barnaxus war der König der Golems. Seine Werke waren der Stolz des Königreichs und als das Eis die Welt überzog ging das Königreich und der Ruf Barnaxus ein in das Reich der Legenden.[PARAGRAPH:1] Vielleicht war es dieser legendäre Ruf, der Jahre nachdem sich das Eis zurückzog und die Luichuip damit begannen das Reich wieder aufzubauen, ein großer, vom Wetter gegerbter Golem an den Toren der Hauptstadt erschien, dazu führte dass er sofort als der lange verlorene Barnaxus erkannt wurde. Denn konnte nicht nur solch ein brillianter und perfekter Golem wie Barnaxus es sicherlich war, so lange ohne Reparaturen und Schutz überlebt haben? [PARAGRAPH:1] Es wurde schnell klar, dass Barnaxus anders war als jeder andere Golem. Barnaxus befolgte keine Befehle. Er kooperierte, er diskutierte und er machte Vorschläge. Barnaxus war ein denkender und lernfähiger Golem. Niemand konnte sagen wie er es geschafft hat die magischen Banden zu durchbrechen, die einen Golem in der zweidimensionalen Welt von "Befehl und Ausführung" gefangen halten und niemand glaubte daran es jemals zu erfahren. Wenn er gefragt wurde, dann antwortete er lediglich: "Ich hatte viel Zeit um nachzudenken" und obwohl sie wussten dass es unmöglich war, schworen sie, auf seinem Gesicht ein unscheinbares Lächeln gesehen zu haben.[PARAGRAPH:1] Wahrlich, Barnaxus konnte tun was er wollte, doch was er wollte war es den Luichurp zu helfen. Er wollte ihnen beim Wiederaufbau des Königreichs helfen um das wieder ins Gedächtnis zu rufen was vergessen war und um das zu perfektionieren an was man sich erinnerte. Er schien in sich eine Liebe für die Luichurp zu hegen, die dem eines peniblen Vaters entsprach, dessen Rat ein beschützender Hauch anhaftete. Und überraschenderweise erwiderten die Luichurp diese Liebe, statt sich darüber zu ärgern von einem Golem "belehrt" zu werden. Was Barnaxus erlernte übernahmen die anderen Golems bald.[PARAGRAPH:1]Und so kam es dass Barnaxus vom "König der Golems" zu einem wahrhaftigen Anführer von Golems und Zwergen wurde.</German>
		<Italian>Barnaxus era bellissimo, perfetto. L'apice di anni di lavoro, della ricerca delle giuste parole per alimentarlo, della selezione dei giusti pezzi, del scolpire amabilmente ogni piccolo dettaglio delle sue articolazioni e del suo aspetto. Barnaxus era più agile, più preciso, più attento e più efficente in tutto ciò che faceva di ogni altro golem che era stato costruito nell'impero dei Khrad'Ke-zun. Per molti secoli questo gigante fece ciò che gli veniva detto, quando gli veniva detto, e sempre in maniera migliore rispetto a chiunque altro, nano o golem. Le opere di Barnaxus erano l'orgoglio dell'impero, e, quando il ghiaccio coprì il mondo, il nome e la reputazione di Barnaxus divennerò leggenda.[PARAGRAPH:1]Forse fu per via di questo status leggendario che quando anni dopo che il ghiaccio si era ritirato e i Luchuirp avevano intrapreso la loro missione di ricostruire l'impero, un golem alto e rovinato comparve davanti ai cancelli della loro capitale fu instantaneamente riconosciuto come Barnaxus. Perchè quale altro golem di tale perfezione e splendore come Barnaxus avrebbe potuto sopravvivere cosi a lungo senza manuntenzione e protezione? [PARAGRAPH:1]Diventò rapidamente chiaro che Barnaxus era diverso da tutti gli altri golem. Barnaxus non prendeva "ordini". Lui collaborava e discuteva e dava consigli. Barnaxus era un golem pensante, un golem che apprendeva. Nessuno aveva idea di come avesse fatto a rompere i legami magici che legavano un golem al mondo a due dimensioni del "ordine e esecuzione", e nessuno si aspettava che si sarebbe scoperto. Quando glielo si chiedeva Barnaxus diceva semplicemente: "Un'uomo mi ha parlato nelle terre desolate e io mi sono svegliato" senza dire poi altro. [PARAGRAPH:1]Vero, Barnaxus poteva fare quello che desiderava, e quello che desiderava fare era aiutare i Luchuirp. Desiderava aiutarli a ricostruire l'impero, a ricordare quello che era stato dimenticato, e di perfezionare quello che era stato ricordato. Sembrava avere un amore per i Luchuirp simile a quello che ha un padre per il figlio, dando consigli in maniera paternalistica. E i Luchuirp, incredibilmente, invece di offendersi dall'essere "istruiti" da un golem, ricambiarono il suo amore. Lui era il loro collegamento col passato e una incredibile fonte di conoscenza. I golem dopotutto non dimenticano niente. Ma la cosa più importante di tutte era che Barnaxus insegnava anche ai golem. Quello che Barnaxus imparava, gli altri golem copiavano poco dopo. [PARAGRAPH:1]E cosi che Barnaxus passò dal essere il "Re dei Golem" all'essere un vero leader di golem e nani.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Barnaxus was beautiful, perfect. The pinnacle of years of work, of finding the right words to power him, of selecting just the right pieces, of lovingly sculpting every little detail of his joints and his features. Barnaxus was more nimble, more exact, more careful and more effective in everything he did than any of the other golems that were built in the empire of Khrad'Ke-zun. For many hundred years, this giant did as he was told, when he was told, and always did it better than anyone else, dwarven or golem. Barnaxus works were the pride of the Empire, and, when the ice sheets smothered the world, the name and reputation of Barnaxus passed into legend.[PARAGRAPH:1]Perhaps it was this legendary status that meant that when, years after the Ice had pulled back and the Luchuirp embarked on their mission of rebuilding the Empire, a tall, weather-worn golem appeared at the gates of the capital, he was instantly recognized as the long-lost Barnaxus. For, surely, only a golem of such perfection and brilliance as Barnaxus could have survived so long without maintenance and protection? [PARAGRAPH:1]It quickly became clear that Barnaxus was unlike any other golem. Barnaxus did not "take orders." He cooperated, he discussed, and he made suggestions. Barnaxus was a thinking golem, a learning golem. No one could guess how he had managed to break the magical ties that bind a golem to the two-dimensional world of "order and execution", and nobody really expected that they would ever find out. When asked, Barnaxus merely said: "A man spoke to me in the wastes and I awoke," he would say no more. [PARAGRAPH:1]True, Barnaxus could do what he wished, but what he wished was to help the Luchuirp. He wished to help them rebuild the Empire, to recall what was forgotten, and to perfect what was remembered. He appeared to harbor a love for the Luchuirp that mirrored that of a doting father, with a hint of a patronizing air to some of his advice. And the Luchuirp, amazingly, instead of rankling at being "taught" by a golem, loved him back. He was their link to the past and an amazing store of knowledge. Golems, after all, never forget. But most important of all, Barnaxus also taught the golems. What Barnaxus learned, the other golems soon copied. [PARAGRAPH:1]And so it was that Barnaxus went from being the "King of the Golems" to being a true leader of golems and of dwarves.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BARNAXUS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>If Barnaxus has the Combat I-Combat V promotions, all golems in his empire will have a higher strength. Success of the Luchuirp is dependant on the players ability to level up Barnaxus and gain those promotions. If Barnaxus is killed his pieces will be claimed by the unit that destroyed him, a player that can recover those pieces can rebuild him in one of the Luchuirp cities.</English>
		<French>Le premier golem vivant, Barnaxus, est capable de changer et de s'adapter à son environnement. Encore plus amusant, il est capable de partager ses connaissances avec tous les golems de son empire. L'effet en jeu est que si Barnaxus possède la promotion Combat (rang I à V), tous les golems de son empire auront la promotion Habileté au même rang (I à V)</French>)
		<German>Barnaxus kann die Stärke aller anderen Golems seiner Zivilisation erhöhen, wenn er die Beförderungen "Kampf I" bis "Kampf IV" erlangt. Dadurch hängt der Erfolg der Luchuirp direkt davon ab, Barnaxus so viele Erfahrungspunkte wie möglich zu verschaffen, damit er diese Beförderungen erlangen kann. Falls Barnaxus getötet wird, erhält die Einheit, die ihn besiegt hat, seine Einzelteile. Diese können, wenn sie von den Luichuirp wiedererlangt und in eine ihrer Städte gebracht werden, wieder zusammengesetzt werden, um Barnaxus erneut zu erschaffen.</German>
		<Italian>Se Barnaxus possiede le promozioni Combattimento I-Combattimento V, tutti i golem del suo impero avranno una forza maggiore. Il successo dei Luchuirp dipende dall'abilità del giocatore di far salire di livello Barnaxus e ottenere quelle promozioni. Se Barnaxus viene ucciso i suoi pezzi possono essere recuperati dall'unità che lo ha ucciso, e con essi si può ricostruirlo in una delle città Luchuirp.</Italian>
		<Spanish>If Barnaxus has the Combat I-Combat V promotions, all golems in his empire will have a higher strength. Success of the Luchuirp is dependant on the players ability to level up Barnaxus and gain those promotions. If Barnaxus is killed his pieces will be claimed by the unit that destroyed him, a player that can recover those pieces can rebuild him in one of the Luchuirp cities.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_REBUILD_BARNAXUS</Tag>
		<English>Rebuild Barnaxus</English>
		<French>Reconstruire Barnaxus</French>
		<German>Erschaffe Barnaxus neu</German>
		<Italian>Rebuild Barnaxus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rebuild Barnaxus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_REBUILD_BARNAXUS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows a player to rebuild Barnaxus in a Luchuirp city (Barnaxus will be built as a Luchuirp unit)</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Permet au joueur de reconstruire Barnaxus dans une ville luchurie (Barnaxus sera reconstruit comme une unité luchurie)</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt einem Spieler Barnaxus neu zu erschaffen in einer Stadt der Luchuirp. Barnaxus ist dann eine Einheit der Luchuirp</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Allows a player to rebuild Barnaxus in a Luchuirp city (Barnaxus will be built as a Luchuirp unit)</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows a player to rebuild Barnaxus in a Luchuirp city (Barnaxus will be built as a Luchuirp unit)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_PIECES_OF_BARNAXUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]If these pieces are recovered by the Luchuirp and returned to their cities Barnaxus can be remade</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Si ces morceaux sont récupérés par les Luchuris et ramenés dans leurs villes, Barnaxus peut être reconstruit.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Werden diese Teile von den Luichuirp wiedererlangt und in eine ihrer Städte gebracht, kann Barnaxus neu erschaffen werden.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]If these pieces are recovered by the Luchuirp and returned to their cities Barnaxus can be remade</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]If these pieces are recovered by the Luchuirp and returned to their cities Barnaxus can be remade</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BONE_GOLEM</Tag>
		<English>Bone Golem</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Golem d'Os:Golems d'Os</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Knochengolem</German>
		<Italian>Golem D'Osso</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bone Golem</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BONE_GOLEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Age of Rebirth saw the first appearance of the Bone Golem. Each part must be carved entirely from one piece of bone or similar material, and only elephants, descended from the mammoths abundant in the Age of Winter, can provide adequate sized raw materials. Curiosity led the Luchuirp craftsmen to attempt these creations, however they become one of their favorite toys, as the bone absorbed their magic as no metal could, leading them to reanimate when defeated.</English>
		<French>The Age of Rebirth saw the first appearance of the Bone Golem. Each part must be carved entirely from one piece of bone or similar material, and only elephants, descended from the mammoths abundant in the Age of Winter, can provide adequate sized raw materials. Curiosity led the Luchuirp craftsmen to attempt these creations, however they become one of their favorite toys, as the bone absorbed their magic as no metal could, leading them to reanimate when defeated.</French>
		<German>Das Zeitalter der Wiedergeburt sah das erste Auftreten des Knochengolems. Jedes seiner Teile muss gänzlich aus einem Stück aus Bein oder ähnlichem Material geschnitzt werden, und nur die Elefanten, die von den Mammuts, die im Zeitalter des Winters reichlich vorhanden waren, abstammen, liefern solches Material in ausreichender Größe. Neugier brachte die Luchuirp-Handwerker dazu, diese Schöpfungen auszuprobieren, und tatsächlich wurden sie zu einem ihrer beliebtesten Spielzeuge, da die Knochen ihre Magie besser als jedes Metal aufsogen, was diese dazu brachte, sich wieder zu beleben wenn sie besiegt wurden.</German>
		<Italian>Il Golem D'Osso fu creato per la prima volta nell'Era della Rinascita. Ogni sua parte deve essere scolpita da un pezzo di osso o materiale simile, e solo gli elefanti, discendenti dei mammoth presenti in gran numero durante l'Era del Ghiaccio, possono fornire materiale delle giuste dimensioni. È stata la curiosità a spingere gli artigiani Luchuirp a provare a costruire tali golem, nonostante ciò, essi divennerò uno dei tipi da loro preferiti, in quanto l'osso assorbe la loro magia meglio di qualsiasi metallo, permettendogli di rianimare il golem quando viene sconfitto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Age of Rebirth saw the first appearance of the Bone Golem. Each part must be carved entirely from one piece of bone or similar material, and only elephants, descended from the mammoths abundant in the Age of Winter, can provide adequate sized raw materials. Curiosity led the Luchuirp craftsmen to attempt these creations, however they become one of their favorite toys, as the bone absorbed their magic as no metal could, leading them to reanimate when defeated.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BONE_GOLEM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Bone Golems are Immortal replacements that can be built directly. Being golems, their resurrection won't save you a highly promoted unit, but will save you needing to build another.</English>
		<French>Bone Golems are Immortal replacements that can be built directly. Being golems, their resurrection won't save you a highly promoted unit, but will save you needing to build another.</French>
		<German>Knochengolems ersetzen Unsterbliche, können jedoch direkt gebaut werden. Da sie Golems sind, wird ihre Wiedererschaffung zwar keine hochbeförderte Einheit retten, aber immerhin erspart sie es, eine weitere Einheit zu bauen.</German>
		<Italian>I Golem D'Osso rimpiazzano l'unità Immortale, ma al contrario di quest'ultimi possono venire creati direttamente. Essendo golem la loro resurrezione non comporta il salvataggio di un'unità estremamente esperta, ma ti risparmia il doverla ricreare.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bone Golems are Immortal replacements that can be built directly. Being golems, their resurrection won't save you a highly promoted unit, but will save you needing to build another.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CLOCKWORK_GOLEM</Tag>
		<English>Clockwork Golem</English>
		<French>Golem Mécanique</French>
		<German>Mechanischer Golem</German>
		<Italian>Golem Meccanico</Italian>
		<Spanish>Clockwork Golem</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CLOCKWORK_GOLEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>It takes the fine tools of a Machinist shop and a sturdy metal such as iron or mithril to produce the intricate detail required in this masterpiece of Luchuirp construction, but the performance is remarkable. Tiny springs and gears plus careful enchantment spells give it reflexes that can rival even a wild beast, enabling the Clockwork golem to damage any units near its target once it gets going. Repairs are not covered by warranty, however, so it is advisable to bring along a dwarven adept for repairs.</English>
		<French>It takes the fine tools of a Machinist shop and a sturdy metal such as iron or mithril to produce the intricate detail required in this masterpiece of Luchuirp construction, but the performance is remarkable. Tiny springs and gears plus careful enchantment spells give it reflexes that can rival even a wild beast, enabling the Clockwork golem to damage any units near its target once it gets going. Repairs are not covered by warranty, however, so it is advisable to bring along a dwarven adept for repairs.</French>
		<German>Man braucht die feinen Werkzeuge eines Mechanikus und ein robustes Metall wie Eisen oder Mithril, um die komplexen Details zu ermöglichen, die für dieses Meisterwerk der Konstruktion der Luchuirp unerlässlich sind, aber das Ergebnis ist beeindruckend. Winzige Federn und Rädchen, zusammen mit vorsichtigen Verzauberungssprüchen, machen Reflexe möglich, die sogar mit denen eines wilden Tieres verglichen werden können, und die dem Mechanischen Golem einmal in Bewegung gesetzt erlauben, jede Einheit in der Nähe seines Ziels zu beschädigen.</German>
		<Italian>Sono richiesti i precisi strumenti del Laboratorio dei Macchinisti e un metallo resistente, come il ferro o il mithril, per creare gli intricati dettagli richesti da questo capolavoro Luchuirp, e le prestazioni sono notevoli. Delle piccole molle e ingranaggi insieme ad attenti incantamenti gli conferiscono riflessi simili a quelli di una bestia selvaggia, permettendo al Golem Meccanico di danneggiare le unità vicine al suo bersaglio. Le riparazioni non sono garantite però, perciò è consigliabile farlo accompagnare da un'adepto nanico per ripararlo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>It takes the fine tools of a Machinist shop and a sturdy metal such as iron or mithril to produce the intricate detail required in this masterpiece of Luchuirp construction, but the performance is remarkable. Tiny springs and gears plus careful enchantment spells give it reflexes that can rival even a wild beast, enabling the Clockwork golem to damage any units near its target once it gets going. Repairs are not covered by warranty, however, so it is advisable to bring along a dwarven adept for repairs.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CLOCKWORK_GOLEM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Clockwork Golems are functionally identical to Berserkers, causing collateral damage to four other units when attacking stacks. They require the Machinery technology instead of Rage, however, and start with higher strength. Being golems prevents leveling up to take promotions.</English>
		<French>Clockwork Golems are functionally identical to Berserkers, causing collateral damage to four other units when attacking stacks. They require the Machinery technology instead of Rage, however, and start with higher strength. Being golems prevents leveling up to take promotions.</French>
		<German>Mechanische Golems sind von ihrer Funktion her identisch mit Berserkern: beim Angriff auf einen Einheitenstapel verursachen sie Kollateralschaden an vier weiteren Einheiten. Sie erfordern die Technologie Maschinenbau anstatt Raserei, und haben eine höhere Stärke. Als Golems können sie jedoch nicht befördert werden.</German>
		<Italian>I Golem Meccanici sono funzionalmente identici ai Berserker, causano danni collatterali sino ad un massimo di altre 4 unità quando attaccano un gruppo. Richiedono la tecnologia Meccanica al posto di Rabbia, e iniziano con una forza leggermente maggiore. Essendo golem non possono guadagnare livelli e ottenere promozioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Clockwork Golems are functionally identical to Berserkers, causing collateral damage to four other units when attacking stacks. They require the Machinery technology instead of Rage, however, and start with higher strength. Being golems prevents leveling up to take promotions.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GARGOYLE</Tag>
		<English>Gargoyle</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Gargouille:Gargouilles</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Gargoyle</German>
		<Italian>Gargoyle</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gargoyle</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GARGOYLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Most Luchuirp, like other practical dwarves, value form over function. Gargoyles, designed to perch upon city walls when not descending upon intruders, are an exception to this. Showing off the intricate detail the crafters are capable of, Gargoyles are expressive, often with demonic appearances, though some are comical as well. These are carved from stone or marble. A Luchuirp city is safer when protected by Gargoyles, and an intriguing place to wander through.</English>
		<French>Most Luchuirp, like other practical dwarves, value form over function. Gargoyles, designed to perch upon city walls when not descending upon intruders, are an exception to this. Showing off the intricate detail the crafters are capable of, Gargoyles are expressive, often with demonic appearances, though some are comical as well. These are carved from stone or marble. A Luchuirp city is safer when protected by Gargoyles, and an intriguing place to wander through.</French>
		<German>Den meisten Luchuirp ist, der praktischen Veranlagung der Zwerge folgend, die Funktion wichtiger als die Form. Eine Ausnahme hiervon bilden die Gargoyles. Sie wurden erschaffen, um die Stadtmauern zu zieren, wenn sie nicht gerade auf Eindringlinge herabstürzen. Ihre Schöpfer versahen diese Kreaturen aus Stein oder Marmor mit einem detailverliebten und ausdruckstarken Äußeren, das vom Dämonischen bis zum Komischen reicht.</German>
		<Italian>La maggior parte dei Luchuirp, come è solito per i nani, danno maggiore importanza alla funzione che all'aspetto. I Gargoyle, progettati per rimanere sulle mura della città quando non attaccano eventuali intrusi, sono un'eccezione alla regola. Mostrando l'intricato dettaglio di cui sono capaci gli artigiani i Gargoyle sono estremamente espressivi, spesso avendo aspetti demoniaci, anche se però ne sono presenti anche di comici. Sono fatti di pietra o marmo. Le città Luchuirp sono più sicure quando vengono protette dai Gargoyles, e un'intrigante posto da attraversare.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Most Luchuirp, like other practical dwarves, value form over function. Gargoyles, designed to perch upon city walls when not descending upon intruders, are an exception to this. Showing off the intricate detail the crafters are capable of, Gargoyles are expressive, often with demonic appearances, though some are comical as well. These are carved from stone or marble. A Luchuirp city is safer when protected by Gargoyles, and an intriguing place to wander through.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GARGOYLE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Gargoyles are perfect defenders for cities, as they start with the defensive promotion, allowing for an additional 25% fortification bonus. And your foes will never walk past a cathedral or mausoleum again.</English>
		<French>Gargoyles are perfect defenders for cities, as they start with the defensive promotion, allowing for an additional 25% fortification bonus. And your foes will never walk past a cathedral or mausoleum again.</French>
		<German>Eine Stadt der Luchuirp wird durch ihre Anwesenheit faszinierend und wehrhaft zugleich. …und eure Feinde werden nie wieder ruhigen Gewissens eine Kathedrale oder ein Grabmahl passieren.</German>
		<Italian>I Gargoyle sono dei difensori perfetti per le città, in quanto inziano con la promozione Difensivo, che da un'ulteriore 25% al bonus di fortificazione base. E i tuoi avversari non passeranno più vicino a una cattedrale o mausoleo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gargoyles are perfect defenders for cities, as they start with the defensive promotion, allowing for an additional 25% fortification bonus. And your foes will never walk past a cathedral or mausoleum again.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_IRON_GOLEM</Tag>
		<English>Iron Golem</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Golem d'Acier:Golems d'Acier</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Eisengolem</German>
		<Italian>Golem di Ferro</Italian>
		<Spanish>Iron Golem</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_IRON_GOLEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Iron Golems were the first golems made, early in the Age of Magic, and they remained the most common type of golem on Erebus even late into the Age of Magic when pestilence and plague made metal more reliable than flesh. Even in hearty times Iron Golems were superior to most fighting men, fusing Luchuirp fine craftsmanship with a sturdy, dependable metal. </English>
		<French>Iron Golems were the first golems made, early in the Age of Magic, and they remained the most common type of golem on Erebus even late into the Age of Magic when pestilence and plague made metal more reliable than flesh. Even in hearty times Iron Golems were superior to most fighting men, fusing Luchuirp fine craftsmanship with a sturdy, dependable metal. </French>
		<German>Eisengolems waren die ersten Golems, die erschaffen wurden, in den frühen Jahren des Zeitalters der Magie. Sie blieben der gebräuchlichste Golemtyp auf Erebus bis gegen Ende des Zeitalters, als einige ihrer Schöpfer ihre Geheimnisse an andere Rassen weitergaben und die Massenproduktion von Kupfergolems begann. Selbst in diesen Zeiten erwiesen sich Eisengolems als überlegen, eine Kombination aus der großen Kunstfertigkeit der Luchuirp und einem soliden, widerstandsfähigen Metall.</German>
		<Italian>I Golem di Ferro sono stati i primi ad essere stati costruiti, agli inizi dell'Era della Magia, e rimasero il tipo più comune di golem su Erebus sino alla fine di quell'era in cui pestilenze e malattie rendevano il metallo più affidabile della carne. Anche durante tempi migliori i Golem di Ferro erano superiori alla maggior parte dei combattenti, nati dalla fusione dell'abilità artigiana Luchuirp con un metallo resistente e affidabile. </Italian>
		<Spanish>Iron Golems were the first golems made, early in the Age of Magic, and they remained the most common type of golem on Erebus even late into the Age of Magic when pestilence and plague made metal more reliable than flesh. Even in hearty times Iron Golems were superior to most fighting men, fusing Luchuirp fine craftsmanship with a sturdy, dependable metal. </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_IRON_GOLEM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Iron Golems are likely to form the bulk of a Luchuirp army. They have high strength but as golems will not gain promotions from combat. They aren't going to end up as powerful as a highly promoted Champion, but losing any one particular iron golem isn't likely to be a huge setback.</English>
		<French>Iron Golems are likely to form the bulk of a Luchuirp army. They have high strength but as golems will not gain promotions from combat. They aren't going to end up as powerful as a highly promoted Champion, but losing any one particular iron golem isn't likely to be a huge setback.</French>
		<German>Eisengolems bilden das Rückrat der luchuirp’schen Armee. Als Golems erhalten sie allerdings keine Beförderungen durch Kämpfe, weshalb sie auch niemals so stark sein werden wie ein hochrangiger Champion, allerdings ist es auch kein allzu großer Verlust, wenn man einen der Eisengolems verliert.</German>
		<Italian>I golem di Ferro molto probabilmente sarannò la forza maggiore degli eserciti Luchuirp. Hanno un'elevata forza, ma essendo golem non possono ottenere promozioni. Non diventeranno potenti come un Campione esperto, ma di contro la perdita di uno di loro non è un danno enorme.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Iron Golems are likely to form the bulk of a Luchuirp army. They have high strength but as golems will not gain promotions from combat. They aren't going to end up as powerful as a highly promoted Champion, but losing any one particular iron golem isn't likely to be a huge setback.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MUD_GOLEM</Tag>
		<English>Mud Golem</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Golem d'Argile:Golems d'Argile</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Tongolem</German>
		<Italian>Golem di Fango</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mud Golem</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MUD_GOLEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Being small is perfect for living in caverns and surviving a harsh unending winter. Upon leaving their burrows to reclaim their place on the surface, however, the first project the Luchuirp engineers and enchanters began was constructing their mud golem workers. Taller than dwarves, and even elves and men, these constructs are able to labor day and night without complaint, with the strength of several men allowing for grand projects.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The mud golem was one of the first types of golems to be built by the Luchuirp. Mud is a plentiful resource, and is very easy to work with for even a beginner enchanter. Unfortunately, the same qualities which make mud easy to work with, make it bad in battle. As a result, the mud golem has minimal combat capabilities and is used for hard manual labor.</English>
		<French>Being small is perfect for living in caverns and surviving a harsh unending winter. Upon leaving their burrows to reclaim their place on the surface, however, the first project the Luchuirp engineers and enchanters began was constructing their mud golem workers. Taller than dwarves, and even elves and men, these constructs are able to labor day and night without complaint, with the strength of several men allowing for grand projects.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The mud golem was one of the first types of golems to be built by the Luchuirp. Mud is a plentiful resource, and is very easy to work with for even a beginner enchanter. Unfortunately, the same qualities which make mud easy to work with, make it bad in battle. As a result, the mud golem has minimal combat capabilities and is used for hard manual labor.</French>
		<German>Klein zu sein, ist perfekt für ein Leben in Höhlen und um einen harten Winter zu überleben. sie verließen ihre Höhlen um sich ihren Platz an der Oberwelt zurück zu erobern, wie auch immer, das erste Projekt das die Luchuirp-Ingenieure und -Beschwörer begannen war die Konstruktion eines Tongolems. Größer als Zwerge, selbst  als Elfen und Menschen, können diese Konstruktionen  den ganzen Tag und die ganze Nacht arbeiten ohne zu klagen, mit der Stärke von mehreren Männern konnten sie auch für größere Projekte eingesetzt werden.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The mud golem was one of the first types of golems to be built by the Luchuirp. Mud is a plentiful resource, and is very easy to work with for even a beginner enchanter. Unfortunately, the same qualities which make mud easy to work with, make it bad in battle. As a result, the mud golem has minimal combat capabilities and is used for hard manual labor.</German>
		<Italian>L'essere piccoli è perfetto per vivere in caverne e sopravvivere in un inverno senza fine. Ma appena lasciati i loro rifugi per reclamare un posto sulla superfice la prima cosa che fecero gli ingegneri e incantatori Luchuirp fu creare i Golem di Fango. Più alti dei nani degli elfi e degli umani, questi costrutti sono capaci di lavorare giorno e notte senza lamentarsi e con la forza di diversi uomini.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Being small is perfect for living in caverns and surviving a harsh unending winter. Upon leaving their burrows to reclaim their place on the surface, however, the first project the Luchuirp engineers and enchanters began was constructing their mud golem workers. Taller than dwarves, and even elves and men, these constructs are able to labor day and night without complaint, with the strength of several men allowing for grand projects.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The mud golem was one of the first types of golems to be built by the Luchuirp. Mud is a plentiful resource, and is very easy to work with for even a beginner enchanter. Unfortunately, the same qualities which make mud easy to work with, make it bad in battle. As a result, the mud golem has minimal combat capabilities and is used for hard manual labor.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MUD_GOLEM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The mud golems offer two bonuses to make up for their expense-they work faster than other workers, and cities can grow while building them.</English>
		<French>Les Golems d'Argile offre deux bonus en compensation de leur prix : ils travaillent plus vite que les autres ouvriers et les villes peuvent grandir durant leur production.</French>
		<German>Es gibt zwei gute Gründe, sich Tongolems zu leisten: Sie arbeiten schneller als es Lebende Wesen vermögen, und da für ihre Ausbildung keine Nahrung notwendig ist, können die Städte, die sie bauen, Weiter wachsen.</German>
		<Italian>I Golem di Fango hanno due vantaggi per compensare il loro costo: lavorano più rapidamente degli altri lavoratori, e le città possono crescere quando li costruiscono.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The mud golems offer two bonuses to make up for their expense-they work faster than other workers, and cities can grow while building them.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NULLSTONE_GOLEM</Tag>
		<English>Nullstone Golem</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Golem d'Obsidienne:Golems d'Obsidienne</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Obsidiangolem</German>
		<Italian>Golem di Pietra Levigata</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nullstone Golem</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NULLSTONE_GOLEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>It was upon watching an armorer from a friendly neighboring civilization produce armor for their Knights that a Luchuirp enchanter had an epiphany. In the same manor that the forged armor deflected arrows, a properly shaped and sufficiently polished stone body might deflect spells sent its way. The experiment was more successful than the enchanter was prepared for. The Nullstone Golem deflects magical energy completely, often keeping spells intact and sending them in unpredictable directions. The first time a Nullstone Golem advanced on a group of well-prepared enemy mages, a nearby iron golem was rusted instead, three fireballs were returned towards their senders, and four passing cows were charmed.</English>
		<French>It was upon watching an armorer from a friendly neighboring civilization produce armor for their Knights that a Luchuirp enchanter had an epiphany. In the same manor that the forged armor deflected arrows, a properly shaped and sufficiently polished stone body might deflect spells sent its way. The experiment was more successful than the enchanter was prepared for. The Nullstone Golem deflects magical energy completely, often keeping spells intact and sending them in unpredictable directions. The first time a Nullstone Golem advanced on a group of well-prepared enemy mages, a nearby iron golem was rusted instead, three fireballs were returned towards their senders, and four passing cows were charmed.</French>
		<German>Als er dem Schmied einer benachbarten freundlich gesinnten Zivilisation dabei zuschaute, wie er Panzerung für einen Ritter herstellte, hatte ein Beschwörer der Luchuirp eine Offenbarung. Auf die gleiche Art, wie eine geschmiedete Panzerung einen Pfeil abwehrt, müsste auch ein steinerner Körper, in die passende Form gebracht und ausreichend poliert, Zaubersprüche reflektieren können. Das Experiment war viel erfolgreicher, als es sich der Beschwörer jemals erträumt hatte. Der Obsidiangolem reflektiert magische Energie vollständig und sendet sie in unvorhersehbare Richtung wieder aus. Als ein Obsidiangolem zum ersten Mal einer Gruppe wohl gerüsteter feindlicher Magier gegenüber stand, wurde an seiner Stelle ein naher Eisengolem verrostet, drei Feuerbälle wurden an ihre Absender zurückgeschickt und vier vorbeilaufende Kühe wurden bezaubert.</German>
		<Italian>Fù osservando un'armaiolo di una civiltà vicina, che stava creando armature per dei Cavalieri, che un'incantatore Luchuirp ebbe un'illuminazione. Nella stessa maniera in cui un'armatura deflette le frecce un corpo di pietra adeguatamente levigata e angolata avrebbe potuto deflettere le magie lanciategli contro. L'esperimento ebbe più successo di quanto l'incantatore si aspettava. Il Golem di Pietra Levigata defletteva completamente l'energia magica, spesso mantenendo le magie intatte e facendogli prendere direzioni imprevedibili. La prima volta che un Golem di Pietra Levigata attaccò un gruppo di maghi nemici competenti un Golem di Ferro vicino si arrugginì al posto di quello di pietra levigata, tre palle di fuoco vennerò rispedite al mittente e quattro mucche vennerò charmate.</Italian>
		<Spanish>It was upon watching an armorer from a friendly neighboring civilization produce armor for their Knights that a Luchuirp enchanter had an epiphany. In the same manor that the forged armor deflected arrows, a properly shaped and sufficiently polished stone body might deflect spells sent its way. The experiment was more successful than the enchanter was prepared for. The Nullstone Golem deflects magical energy completely, often keeping spells intact and sending them in unpredictable directions. The first time a Nullstone Golem advanced on a group of well-prepared enemy mages, a nearby iron golem was rusted instead, three fireballs were returned towards their senders, and four passing cows were charmed.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NULLSTONE_GOLEM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Starting with Magic Immune gives the Nullstone Golem an obvious use of defending cities against attackers who favor direct damage spells. They will also be better than their strength would predict against any unit that relies on strength of a specific type. Golem promotion gives them additional immunities, forcing foes to take them down head on.</English>
		<French>Starting with Magic Immune gives the Nullstone Golem an obvious use of defending cities against attackers who favor direct damage spells. They will also be better than their strength would predict against any unit that relies on strength of a specific type. Golem promotion gives them additional immunities, forcing foes to take them down head on.</French>
		<German>Seine Immunität gegen Magie macht den Obsidiangolem sehr nützlich bei der Verteidigung von Städten gegen Gegner, die direkte Schadenszauber bevorzugen. Er ist ebenfalls besser, als seine Stärke vermuten lässt, gegen Einheiten, deren Stärke auf einer bestimmten Affinität beruht. Die "Golem"-Beförderung verleiht ihm bestimmte Immunitäten und zwingt Feinde dazu, ihn im Kampf Mann gegen Mann zu besiegen.</German>
		<Italian>Iniziando con la promozione Immune alla Magia il Golem di Pietra Levigata è ovviamente molto utile per difendere una città da aggressori che ne fanno elevato uso per offendere. Sono anche più forti di quanto la loro forza non suggerisca contro qualsiasi unità che si affida a una forza di tipo specifico. La promozione Golem gli fornisce immunità aggiuntive obbligando i nemici ad affrontarlo direttamente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Starting with Magic Immune gives the Nullstone Golem an obvious use of defending cities against attackers who favor direct damage spells. They will also be better than their strength would predict against any unit that relies on strength of a specific type. Golem promotion gives them additional immunities, forcing foes to take them down head on.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WOOD_GOLEM</Tag>
		<English>Wood Golem</English>
		<French>Golem de Bois</French>
		<German>Holzgolem</German>
		<Italian>Golem di Legno</Italian>
		<Spanish>Wood Golem</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WOOD_GOLEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The novice Luchuirp crafters at the start of the age of rebirth tried working the exotic materials that their ancestors used, but found they needed more practice to get useful forms for their enchanting process. The wood golems produced by this practice turned out to make decent fighters, and could be found filling out the ranks amidst their sturdier relatives throughout the age.</English>
		<French>The novice Luchuirp crafters at the start of the age of rebirth tried working the exotic materials that their ancestors used, but found they needed more practice to get useful forms for their enchanting process. The wood golems produced by this practice turned out to make decent fighters, and could be found filling out the ranks amidst their sturdier relatives throughout the age.</French>
		<German>Zu Beginn des Zeitalters der Wiedergeburt versuchten die unerfahrenen Luchuirp-Handwerker die exotischen Materialien ihrer Ahnen zu bearbeiten, aber sie erkannte, daß sie bessere Fertigkeiten brauchten, um nutzbare Formen für den Verzauberungsprozeß zu bekommen. Die aus diesen Versuchen entstandenen Waldgolems gaben passable Kämpfer ab und standen während des Zeitalters Seite an Seite mit ihren kräftigeren Verwandten.</German>
		<Italian>Gli artigiani novizi Luchuirp all'inizio dell'Era della Rinascita provarono a lavorare gli esotici materiali che venivano usati dai loro antenati, ma si resero conto che avevano bisogno di fare più pratica prima di poter ottenere delle forme utili per i loro processi di incantamento. I Golem di Legno creati per fare pratica si dimostrarono combattenti decenti, e vennerò usati per coprire i buchi nei ranghi dei loro cugini più resistenti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The novice Luchuirp crafters at the start of the age of rebirth tried working the exotic materials that their ancestors used, but found they needed more practice to get useful forms for their enchanting process. The wood golems produced by this practice turned out to make decent fighters, and could be found filling out the ranks amidst their sturdier relatives throughout the age.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WOOD_GOLEM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Luchuirp's first golem unit, Wood golems are good as attackers or defenders, being stronger than the units most civs are likely to have access to at the same time. Like all golems, however, they cannot level up to gain promotions. Beware their vulnerability to fire.</English>
		<French>Premier golem des Luchuirps, les Golems de Bois sont de bons attaquants et défenseurs, plus forts que les unités que la plupart des civilisations ont accès au même moment. Comme tous les golems, il ne progressent pas et ne gagnent pas de promotions. Attention à leur vulnérabilité au feu.</French>
		<German>Die erste Golem-Einheit der Luchuirp, der Holzgolem, ist ebenso gut im Angriff wie in der Verteidigung und ist stärker als die Einheiten, die die meisten anderen Zivs zur selben Zeit normalerweise ausbilden können. Allerdings sammeln sie, wie alle Golems, keine Erfahrung. Pass auf ihre Schwäche gegen Feuer auf.</German>
		<Italian>La prima unità golem dei Luchuirp, i Golem di Legno sono dei buoni attaccanti e difensori essendo più forti delle unità che le altre civiltà dovrebbero avere nello stesso momento. Come tutti i golem però non possono ottenere livelli e promozioni. Fai attenzione alla loro vulnerabilità al fuoco.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Luchuirp's first golem unit, Wood golems are good as attackers or defenders, being stronger than the units most civs are likely to have access to at the same time. Like all golems, however, they cannot level up to gain promotions. Beware their vulnerability to fire.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SIEGE_GOLEM</Tag>
		<English>Siege Golem</English>
		<French>Golem de Siège</French>
		<German>Siege Golem</German>
		<Italian>Siege Golem</Italian>
		<Spanish>Siege Golem</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MARBLE_GOLEM</Tag>
		<English>Marble Golem</English>
		<French>Golem de Marbre</French>
		<German>Marble Golem</German>
		<Italian>Marble Golem</Italian>
		<Spanish>Marble Golem</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
