<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - Units -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIN_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Austrin</English>
		<French>Austrin</French>
		<German>Reich der Austrin</German>
		<Italian>Austrin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Austrin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Austrin</English>
		<French>Austrinois</French>
		<German>Austrin</German>
		<Italian>Austrin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Austrin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Austrin</English>
		<French>austrinois:austrinoise:austrinois:austrinoises</French>
		<German>Austrinisch:Austrinischen:Austrinische</German>
		<Italian>Austrin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Austrin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Austrin are explorers. All civilizations are naturally drawn to discover what lies outside their walls - knowing of threats and opportunities is essential to their development - but for the Austrin the need is compelling. They did not exist as an organized people before the Age of Ice - they could be identified only as the loners who defied the advice of the village elders and walked the frozen lands around the village. During the time that the ice receded, they were among the first to take to the wilds. Many were surprised to see others there at all, but when they did meet they found kindred spirits.[PARAGRAPH]Eventually they began to settle, often in the furthest reaches of a windswept moor or heath. Their cities are practical constructions - roughly built yet designed to endure - where young Austrin are prepared to make their way in the world.[PARAGRAPH]The defacto leader of the Austrin is Deirdra - a prolific wanderer and self stated worshipper of Tali, though few among the Austrin have ever seen her perform any form of religious rite to prove her devotion. Those who know better realize that worshipping Tali is generally a personal matter and better suited to a mountaintop than a temple and Deirdra often travels to find such a place when she faces a difficult choice on behalf of her people. To outsiders, she is enigmatic yet charming, often seemiming whimsical - though if a foreign diplomat mistakes this for a weakness of character which can be exploited, they swiftly discover this is not the case.[PARAGRAPH]Whilst the Austrin are generally aware of and appreciate Tali's nature, his worship is not a principle religion amongst them. Their settlements often have temples dedicated to various powers, even to Kilmorph who is traditionally the antithesis of Tali (for a time a group worshipping Kilmorph became quite prominent in Telynohn, though their popularity fluctuated and waned - the Austrin often change their mind).[PARAGRAPH]More important than religion to most Austrin however is the Exploration Guild. This started as a loose group of explorers who combined their efforts to chart the surrounding lands, but has since grown to be a place of training and preparation for the young as well as a respite for those too elderly to travel the world anymore. The first charts have become atlases and the guild claims to know more about the world than even the omniscient seers of the neighbouring Amurites. Despite the wealth of knowledge the guild holds, the Austrin are still drawn to that which lies beyond their maps - the unknown.</English>
		<French>Les Austrins sont des explorateurs. Toutes les civilisations doivent naturellement découvrir ce qui se cache derrière leurs murs (connaître les opportunités et les menaces est essentiel dans leur développement), mais chez les Austrins ce besoin est compulsif. Ils n'existaient pas en tant que peuple organisé avant l'Ère Glaciaire. Ils pouvaient uniquement être indentifiés comme des solitaires qui bravaient les consiels des anciens des villages et se promenaient dans les terres gelées autour. Quand les glaces ont commencé à reculer, il furent parmi les premiers à s'élacer dans les contrées sauvages. Beaucoup furent étonnés de voir qui que ce soit d'autre, mais quand ils se rencontrèrent ils virent qu'ils étaient des âmes sour.[PARAGRAPH]Il finirent par s'installer, souvent dans les confins d'une lande ou d'une bruyère. Leurs villes sont constituées de constructions pratiques, construites grossièrement mais conçues pour durer, et dans des lieux où les jeunes Austrins se préparent à faire leur voyage dans le monde.[PARAGRAPH]Defait, le Dirigeant des Austrins est Deirdra, un vagabond prolifique auto-proclamé adorateur de Tali, même si peu parmi les Austrins l'aient jamais vu pratiquer un quelconque rite religieux prouvant sa dévotion. Ceux qui la connaissent mieux réalisent que le culte de Tali est plus une affaire personnelle et plus en accord avec un sommet montagneux qu'un temple, et Deirdra voyage souvent pour trouver de tels endroits quand elle doit faire façe à un choix difficile dans la gestion de son peuple. Pour les étrangers, elle est énigmatique bien que charmante, semblant souvent étrange. Et si un diplomate étranger confond ça avec une faiblesse de caractère qui pourrait etre exploitée, ils découvrent vite que ce n'est pas le cas.[PARAGRAPH]Tandis que les Austrins sont généralement conscients et apprécient la nature de Tali, son culte n'est pas leur religion principale. Leurs campements possèdent souvent des temples dédiés à des puissances diverses, y compris Kilmorph qui est traditionnellement l'antithèse de Tali (pour un temps un groupe vénérant Kilmorph devint majoritaire à Telynohn, puis leur popularité fluctua et fini par disparaître, les Austrins changeant souvent d'avis).[PARAGRAPH]Pour la plupart des Austrins, ce qui est cependant plus important que la religion est la Guilde des Explorateurs. Tout commença par un petit groupe d'explorateurs qui combinèrent leurs efforts pour cartographier les contrées alentour. Elle a depuis grossi pour devenir un lieu d'entraînement et de préparation pour les jeunes, de même qu'un lieu de repos pour ceux trop âgés pour découvrir le monde. Les premières cartes sont devenues des atlas et la Guilde clame maintenant même connaître plus du monde que les voyants omniscients de leurs voisins Amurites. Malgré la richesse du savoir que détient la Guilde, les Austrins sont toujours attirés pas ce qui se cache derrière leurs cartes : l'inconnu.</French>
		<German>The Austrin are explorers. All civilizations are naturally drawn to discover what lies outside their walls - knowing of threats and opportunities is essential to their development - but for the Austrin the need is compelling. They did not exist as an organized people before the Age of Ice - they could be identified only as the loners who defied the advice of the village elders and walked the frozen lands around the village. During the time that the ice receded, they were among the first to take to the wilds. Many were surprised to see others there at all, but when they did meet they found kindred spirits.[PARAGRAPH]Eventually they began to settle, often in the furthest reaches of a windswept moor or heath. Their cities are practical constructions - roughly built yet designed to endure - where young Austrin are prepared to make their way in the world.[PARAGRAPH]The defacto leader of the Austrin is Deirdra - a prolific wanderer and self stated worshipper of Tali, though few among the Austrin have ever seen her perform any form of religious rite to prove her devotion. Those who know better realize that worshipping Tali is generally a personal matter and better suited to a mountaintop than a temple and Deirdra often travels to find such a place when she faces a difficult choice on behalf of her people. To outsiders, she is enigmatic yet charming, often seemiming whimsical - though if a foreign diplomat mistakes this for a weakness of character which can be exploited, they swiftly discover this is not the case.[PARAGRAPH]Whilst the Austrin are generally aware of and appreciate Tali's nature, his worship is not a principle religion amongst them. Their settlements often have temples dedicated to various powers, even to Kilmorph who is traditionally the antithesis of Tali (for a time a group worshipping Kilmorph became quite prominent in Telynohn, though their popularity fluctuated and waned - the Austrin often change their mind).[PARAGRAPH]More important than religion to most Austrin however is the Exploration Guild. This started as a loose group of explorers who combined their efforts to chart the surrounding lands, but has since grown to be a place of training and preparation for the young as well as a respite for those too elderly to travel the world anymore. The first charts have become atlases and the guild claims to know more about the world than even the omniscient seers of the neighbouring Amurites. Despite the wealth of knowledge the guild holds, the Austrin are still drawn to that which lies beyond their maps - the unknown.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Austrin sono esploratori. Tutte le civiltà sono portate naturalmente a scoprire cosa c'è fuori dalle loro mura, la conoscenza dei pericoli e delle opportunità presenti è essenziale per il loro sviluppo, ma per gli Austrin questo bisogno è irresistibile. Loro non esistevano sotto forma di popolo organizzato prima dell'Era del Ghiaccio, al massimo potevano essere identificati come i solitari che, sfidando i consigli degli anziani del villaggio, giravano per le lande ghiacciate attorno ai loro villaggi. Quando il ghiaccio iniziò a sciogliersi, loro furono i primi a partire per le terre selvagge. Molti erano sorpresi di trovare qualcun'altro in quei posti, ma quando si incontravano trovavano degli spiriti affini.[PARAGRAPH]Alla fine incominciarono a insediarsi, spesso nelle brughiere spazzate dal vento più distanti. Le loro città sono costruite per essere funzionali, magari costruite approssimativamente ma progettate per durare, dove i giovani Austrin si preparano per seguire la loro strada in giro per il mondo.[PARAGRAPH]Il leader de facto degli Austrin è Deirdra, una viaggiatrice prolifica e veneratrice di Tali auto dichiarata, anche se pochi tra gli Austrin la hanno mai vista effettuare qualche rito religioso come prova della sua devozione. Quelli che ne sanno un pò di più sanno che l'adorazione di Tali è generalmente una questione personale e più consona sulla cima di una montagna che in un tempio e Deirdra viaggia spesso per trovare questi posti dove affronta scelte difficili per conto del suo popolo. Per gli estranei, lei è enigmatica ma allo stesso tempo affascinante e spesso sembra stravagante, se un diplomatico straniero scambia questo comportamento per una debolezza di carattere che può essere strumentalizzata scoprirebbe rapidamente che non è questo il caso.[PARAGRAPH]Sebbene tra gli Austrin la natura di Tali sia generalmente conosciuta e apprezzata, il suo culto non è la religione principale. I loro insediamenti spesso hanno templi dedicati a diversi poteri, persino a Kilmorph che è tradizionalmente l'antitesi di Tali (per un periodo di tempo un gruppo di adoratori di Kilmorph diventò piuttosto importante in Telynohn, anche se poi la loro popolarità diminuì, gli Austrin cambiano idea spesso).[PARAGRAPH]Più importante della religione per molti Austrin è invece la Gilda degli Esploratori. Iniziato come un gruppo aperto di esploratori che unirono le forze per mappare le terre circostanti, è cresciuto sino a diventare un posto di addestramento e preparazione per i giovani cosi come un posto di riposo per coloro ormai troppo vecchi per viaggiare per il mondo. Le prime mappe sono diventati atlanti e la gilda afferma di avere una conoscenza del mondo maggiore persino dei veggenti onniscenti dei vicini Amurite. Nonostante la quantita di conoscenza che la gilda possiede, gli Austrin sono ancora attratti da ciò che sta al di là delle loro mappe, l'ignoto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Austrin are explorers. All civilizations are naturally drawn to discover what lies outside their walls - knowing of threats and opportunities is essential to their development - but for the Austrin the need is compelling. They did not exist as an organized people before the Age of Ice - they could be identified only as the loners who defied the advice of the village elders and walked the frozen lands around the village. During the time that the ice receded, they were among the first to take to the wilds. Many were surprised to see others there at all, but when they did meet they found kindred spirits.[PARAGRAPH]Eventually they began to settle, often in the furthest reaches of a windswept moor or heath. Their cities are practical constructions - roughly built yet designed to endure - where young Austrin are prepared to make their way in the world.[PARAGRAPH]The defacto leader of the Austrin is Deirdra - a prolific wanderer and self stated worshipper of Tali, though few among the Austrin have ever seen her perform any form of religious rite to prove her devotion. Those who know better realize that worshipping Tali is generally a personal matter and better suited to a mountaintop than a temple and Deirdra often travels to find such a place when she faces a difficult choice on behalf of her people. To outsiders, she is enigmatic yet charming, often seemiming whimsical - though if a foreign diplomat mistakes this for a weakness of character which can be exploited, they swiftly discover this is not the case.[PARAGRAPH]Whilst the Austrin are generally aware of and appreciate Tali's nature, his worship is not a principle religion amongst them. Their settlements often have temples dedicated to various powers, even to Kilmorph who is traditionally the antithesis of Tali (for a time a group worshipping Kilmorph became quite prominent in Telynohn, though their popularity fluctuated and waned - the Austrin often change their mind).[PARAGRAPH]More important than religion to most Austrin however is the Exploration Guild. This started as a loose group of explorers who combined their efforts to chart the surrounding lands, but has since grown to be a place of training and preparation for the young as well as a respite for those too elderly to travel the world anymore. The first charts have become atlases and the guild claims to know more about the world than even the omniscient seers of the neighbouring Amurites. Despite the wealth of knowledge the guild holds, the Austrin are still drawn to that which lies beyond their maps - the unknown.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AUSTRIN_STRATEGY</Tag>
        <English>The Austrin excel at exploration, and have several unique features to assist in that endeavor. Several of their unique units are scouts with added mobility, who are more likely to get better results from lairs. They also have access to several unique features:[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROJECT_PREPARE_EXPEDITION]Prepare Expedition[\LINK] - A special ritual that allows recon units to found cities. [LINK=SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND]Found Settlement[\LINK] does not consume the recon unit, and may be used if the unit has no movement left. For each time this ability is used, you will need to build the Prepare Expedition ritual again.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_SUMMON_PEGASUS]Summon Pegasus[\LINK] - At Air II, Austrins can summon a permanent [LINK=UNIT_PEGASUS]pegasus[\LINK]. This allows them easy access to [LINK=BUILDING_GRIFFON_WEYR]Flying Mounts Stable[\LINK]. Further, melee, archery, and arcane units may then mount the pegasus to gain the [LINK=PROMOTION_PEGASUS]Pegasus Rider[\LINK] promotion. It's worth noting that created Flying Mounts Stable will allow the same mage to recast Summon Pegasus, but mounting the pegasus will not. So you may want to create a Flying Mounts Stable in each prior to mounting a pegasus.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_ASSEMBLE_SHOREPARTY]Assemble Shoreparty[\LINK] - Austrin naval units may use assemble shoreparty if the naval unit is on a land tile, such as in a city you own or in a city of a player that you have open borders with. This creates a [LINK=UNIT_SHOREPARTY]Shore Party[\LINK] unit, which, as a recon unit, can use [LINK=SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND]Found Settlement[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_TRAVEL_LIGHT]Travel Light[\LINK] - Grants [LINK=PROMOTION_LIGHT]Light[\LINK] promotion to a melee unit. This allows them to move more quickly, at the cost of lowered strength. A melee unit may then [LINK=SPELL_REEQUIP]Re-Equip[\LINK], although this takes up the remainder of the unit's movement.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROMOTION_WINDSTONES_RECON]Windstones[\LINK] - An item for recon units available through the [LINK=BUILDING_MASTER_OUTFITTER]Master Outfitter[\LINK] building. It allows recon units to engage in ranged combat.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROMOTION_DOUBLETIME_TEAM]Doubletime[\LINK] - The Austrins are one of four civilizations who gain access to the Doubletime promotion through the [LINK=BUILDING_MASTER_SIEGE]Master Siege[\LINK] building.</English>
        <French>The Austrin excel at exploration, and have several unique features to assist in that endeavor. Several of their unique units are scouts with added mobility, who are more likely to get better results from lairs. They also have access to several unique features:[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROJECT_PREPARE_EXPEDITION]Prepare Expedition[\LINK] - A special ritual that allows recon units to found cities. [LINK=SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND]Found Settlement[\LINK] does not consume the recon unit, and may be used if the unit has no movement left. For each time this ability is used, you will need to build the Prepare Expedition ritual again.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_SUMMON_PEGASUS]Summon Pegasus[\LINK] - At Air II, Austrins can summon a permanent [LINK=UNIT_PEGASUS]pegasus[\LINK]. This allows them easy access to [LINK=BUILDING_GRIFFON_WEYR]Flying Mounts Stable[\LINK]. Further, melee, archery, and arcane units may then mount the pegasus to gain the [LINK=PROMOTION_PEGASUS]Pegasus Rider[\LINK] promotion. It's worth noting that created Flying Mounts Stable will allow the same mage to recast Summon Pegasus, but mounting the pegasus will not. So you may want to create a Flying Mounts Stable in each prior to mounting a pegasus.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_ASSEMBLE_SHOREPARTY]Assemble Shoreparty[\LINK] - Austrin naval units may use assemble shoreparty if the naval unit is on a land tile, such as in a city you own or in a city of a player that you have open borders with. This creates a [LINK=UNIT_SHOREPARTY]Shore Party[\LINK] unit, which, as a recon unit, can use [LINK=SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND]Found Settlement[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_TRAVEL_LIGHT]Travel Light[\LINK] - Grants [LINK=PROMOTION_LIGHT]Light[\LINK] promotion to a melee unit. This allows them to move more quickly, at the cost of lowered strength. A melee unit may then [LINK=SPELL_REEQUIP]Re-Equip[\LINK], although this takes up the remainder of the unit's movement.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROMOTION_WINDSTONES_RECON]Windstones[\LINK] - An item for recon units available through the [LINK=BUILDING_MASTER_OUTFITTER]Master Outfitter[\LINK] building. It allows recon units to engage in ranged combat.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROMOTION_DOUBLETIME_TEAM]Doubletime[\LINK] - The Austrins are one of four civilizations who gain access to the Doubletime promotion through the [LINK=BUILDING_MASTER_SIEGE]Master Siege[\LINK] building.</French>
        <German>The Austrin excel at exploration, and have several unique features to assist in that endeavor. Several of their unique units are scouts with added mobility, who are more likely to get better results from lairs. They also have access to several unique features:[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROJECT_PREPARE_EXPEDITION]Prepare Expedition[\LINK] - A special ritual that allows recon units to found cities. [LINK=SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND]Found Settlement[\LINK] does not consume the recon unit, and may be used if the unit has no movement left. For each time this ability is used, you will need to build the Prepare Expedition ritual again.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_SUMMON_PEGASUS]Summon Pegasus[\LINK] - At Air II, Austrins can summon a permanent [LINK=UNIT_PEGASUS]pegasus[\LINK]. This allows them easy access to [LINK=BUILDING_GRIFFON_WEYR]Flying Mounts Stable[\LINK]. Further, melee, archery, and arcane units may then mount the pegasus to gain the [LINK=PROMOTION_PEGASUS]Pegasus Rider[\LINK] promotion. It's worth noting that created Flying Mounts Stable will allow the same mage to recast Summon Pegasus, but mounting the pegasus will not. So you may want to create a Flying Mounts Stable in each prior to mounting a pegasus.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_ASSEMBLE_SHOREPARTY]Assemble Shoreparty[\LINK] - Austrin naval units may use assemble shoreparty if the naval unit is on a land tile, such as in a city you own or in a city of a player that you have open borders with. This creates a [LINK=UNIT_SHOREPARTY]Shore Party[\LINK] unit, which, as a recon unit, can use [LINK=SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND]Found Settlement[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_TRAVEL_LIGHT]Travel Light[\LINK] - Grants [LINK=PROMOTION_LIGHT]Light[\LINK] promotion to a melee unit. This allows them to move more quickly, at the cost of lowered strength. A melee unit may then [LINK=SPELL_REEQUIP]Re-Equip[\LINK], although this takes up the remainder of the unit's movement.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROMOTION_WINDSTONES_RECON]Windstones[\LINK] - An item for recon units available through the [LINK=BUILDING_MASTER_OUTFITTER]Master Outfitter[\LINK] building. It allows recon units to engage in ranged combat.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROMOTION_DOUBLETIME_TEAM]Doubletime[\LINK] - The Austrins are one of four civilizations who gain access to the Doubletime promotion through the [LINK=BUILDING_MASTER_SIEGE]Master Siege[\LINK] building.</German>
        <Italian>Gli Austrin eccellono nell'esplorazione, e hanno parecchie caratteristiche uniche che li aiutano in questa impresa. Molte delle loro unità uniche sono ricognitori con più mobilità che hanno maggiori probabilità di avere risultati positivi dalle tane. Hanno anche accesso a diverse caratteristiche uniche:[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROJECT_PREPARE_EXPEDITION]Prepara una Spedizione[\LINK] - Un rituale speciale che permette alle unità da ricognizione di fondare città. [LINK=SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND]Fonda Insediamento[\LINK] non consuma l'unità da ricognizione, e può essere usata anche se l'unità ha finito il movimento. Ogni volta che questa abilità viene utilizzata, dovrai rifare il rituale Preparare una Spedizione per poterla riusare.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_SUMMON_PEGASUS]Evoca Pegaso[\LINK] - Ad Aria II, gli Austrin possono evocare un [LINK=UNIT_PEGASUS]Pegaso[\LINK] permanente. Questo gli permette un facile accesso alla [LINK=BUILDING_GRIFFON_WEYR]Stalla delle Cavalcature Volanti[\LINK]. Ulteriormente le unità da combattimento ravvicinato, di arcieri e arcane possono poi cavalcare il pegaso per ottenere la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_PEGASUS]Cavaliere di Pegaso[\LINK]. Vale la pena notare che creare la Stalla delle Cavalcature Volanti permette allo stesso mago di rilanciare Evoca Pegaso mentre cavalcarlo non lo permette. Quindi potresti decidere di creare prima la Stalla delle Cavalcature Volanti prima di cavalcare il pegaso.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_ASSEMBLE_SHOREPARTY]Crea Gruppo d'Esplorazione[\LINK] - Le unità navali Austrin possono usare crea gruppo d'esplorazione se si trovano su una casella di terra, come quando sono dentro una città che possiedi o in una città di un giocatore con cui hai il diritto di passaggio. Farlo crea un'unita di [LINK=UNIT_SHOREPARTY]Gruppo d'Esplorazione[\LINK], che, essendo un'unita da ricognizione, può usare [LINK=SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND]Fonda Insediamento[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_TRAVEL_LIGHT]Viaggia Leggero[\LINK] - Fornisce ad un'unità da combattimento ravvicinato la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_LIGHT]Leggero[\LINK]. Questo permette loro di muoversi più velocemente, ma con una forza minore. L'unità da combattimento ravvicinato può poi [LINK=SPELL_REEQUIP]Riequipaggiarsi[\LINK], sebbene farlo consuma il restante movimento.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROMOTION_WINDSTONES_RECON]Pietra del Vento[\LINK] - Un'oggetto per le unità da ricognizione disponibile attraverso l'edificio [LINK=BUILDING_MASTER_OUTFITTER]Mastro Fornitore d'attrezzatura[\LINK]. Permette alle unità da ricognizione di effettuare attacchi dalla distanza.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROMOTION_DOUBLETIME_TEAM]Passo Svelto[\LINK] - Gli Austrin sono una della quattro civiltà che possono accedere alla promozione Passo Svelto attraverso l'edificio [LINK=BUILDING_MASTER_SIEGE]Mastro Fabbro d'assedio[\LINK].</Italian>
        <Spanish>The Austrin excel at exploration, and have several unique features to assist in that endeavor. Several of their unique units are scouts with added mobility, who are more likely to get better results from lairs. They also have access to several unique features:[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROJECT_PREPARE_EXPEDITION]Prepare Expedition[\LINK] - A special ritual that allows recon units to found cities. [LINK=SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND]Found Settlement[\LINK] does not consume the recon unit, and may be used if the unit has no movement left. For each time this ability is used, you will need to build the Prepare Expedition ritual again.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_SUMMON_PEGASUS]Summon Pegasus[\LINK] - At Air II, Austrins can summon a permanent [LINK=UNIT_PEGASUS]pegasus[\LINK]. This allows them easy access to [LINK=BUILDING_GRIFFON_WEYR]Flying Mounts Stable[\LINK]. Further, melee, archery, and arcane units may then mount the pegasus to gain the [LINK=PROMOTION_PEGASUS]Pegasus Rider[\LINK] promotion. It's worth noting that created Flying Mounts Stable will allow the same mage to recast Summon Pegasus, but mounting the pegasus will not. So you may want to create a Flying Mounts Stable in each prior to mounting a pegasus.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_ASSEMBLE_SHOREPARTY]Assemble Shoreparty[\LINK] - Austrin naval units may use assemble shoreparty if the naval unit is on a land tile, such as in a city you own or in a city of a player that you have open borders with. This creates a [LINK=UNIT_SHOREPARTY]Shore Party[\LINK] unit, which, as a recon unit, can use [LINK=SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND]Found Settlement[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=SPELL_TRAVEL_LIGHT]Travel Light[\LINK] - Grants [LINK=PROMOTION_LIGHT]Light[\LINK] promotion to a melee unit. This allows them to move more quickly, at the cost of lowered strength. A melee unit may then [LINK=SPELL_REEQUIP]Re-Equip[\LINK], although this takes up the remainder of the unit's movement.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROMOTION_WINDSTONES_RECON]Windstones[\LINK] - An item for recon units available through the [LINK=BUILDING_MASTER_OUTFITTER]Master Outfitter[\LINK] building. It allows recon units to engage in ranged combat.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][LINK=PROMOTION_DOUBLETIME_TEAM]Doubletime[\LINK] - The Austrins are one of four civilizations who gain access to the Doubletime promotion through the [LINK=BUILDING_MASTER_SIEGE]Master Siege[\LINK] building.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_DEIRDRA</Tag>
		<English>Deirdra</English>
		<French>Deirdra</French>
		<German>Deirdra</German>
		<Italian>Deirdra</Italian>
		<Spanish>Deirdra</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_DEIRDRA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"My home? Where I lay my head is home."[NEWLINE]  "But where do you come from?"[NEWLINE]"Long ago I lived in the east, now I travel west"[NEWLINE]  "Where are you going?"[NEWLINE]"Wherever I may."[NEWLINE]  "So you're what, some sort of traveller?"[NEWLINE]"Of a sort. Rove or wanderer. Nomad, vagabond - call me what you will."[NEWLINE]  "But you travel the wastes alone? Unarmed? How do you survive out there?"[NEWLINE]"I adapt to the unknown. Under the wandering stars I've grown - by myself but not alone. I ask of no-one."[NEWLINE]  "You speak oddly, milady, but if you keep to the laws of the city, you are welcomed in Brookden."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The guards stepped aside and permitted Deirdra to enter the city. A majestic sight indeed, the massive bronzed dome of the Dural palace dominating the scene but surrounded by sights of at least equal beauty - statues, murals and the finest architecture. One could spend a lifetime here and not have time to fully appreciate the arts of the Dural. She would not be there long however. There was still a long road ahead.</English>
		<French>"Mon foyer? L'endroit où je dors est mon foyer."[NEWLINE]"Mais d'où venez vous?"[NEWLINE]"Il y a longtemps je vivais à l'Est, et maintenant je voyage à l'Ouest"[NEWLINE]"Où allez-vous?"[NEWLINE]"Partout où je peux."[NEWLINE]"Donc vous êtes quoi, une espèce de voyageuse?"[NEWLINE]"D'une certaine manière. Errante, vagabonde, nomade, appelez moi comme vous le souhaitez."[NEWLINE]"Mais vous traversez les terres perdues seule et non-armée? Comment arrivez-vous à survivre?"[NEWLINE]"Je m'adapte à l'inconnu. J'ai grandi sous les étoiles solitaires. Par moi-même mais pas seule. Je ne demande rien."[NEWLINE]"Vous parlez bizarrement, madame, mais si vous respectez les lois de la cité, vous êtes la bienvenue à Brookden."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Les gardes s'écartèrent et laissèrent Deirdra entrer dans la ville. Une vue magnifique, d'ailleurs, le dôme de bronze massif du palais Dural dominant la scène, but entouré par des vues d'une beauté équivalente de statues, fresques et d'architecture la plus fine. On pourrait passer sa vie ici et ne pas avoir le temps de pleinement apprécier l'art des Durals. Elle ne resterait pourtant pas longtemps. Il restait une longue route à parcourir.</French>
		<German>"My home? Where I lay my head is home."[NEWLINE]  "But where do you come from?"[NEWLINE]"Long ago I lived in the east, now I travel west"[NEWLINE]  "Where are you going?"[NEWLINE]"Wherever I may."[NEWLINE]  "So you're what, some sort of traveller?"[NEWLINE]"Of a sort. Rove or wanderer. Nomad, vagabond - call me what you will."[NEWLINE]  "But you travel the wastes alone? Unarmed? How do you survive out there?"[NEWLINE]"I adapt to the unknown. Under the wandering stars I've grown - by myself but not alone. I ask of no-one."[NEWLINE]  "You speak oddly, milady, but if you keep to the laws of the city, you are welcomed in Brookden."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The guards stepped aside and permitted Deirdra to enter the city. A majestic sight indeed, the massive bronzed dome of the Dural palace dominating the scene but surrounded by sights of at least equal beauty - statues, murals and the finest architecture. One could spend a lifetime here and not have time to fully appreciate the arts of the Dural. She would not be there long however. There was still a long road ahead.</German>
		<Italian>"La mia casa? Dove poggio la mia testa."[NEWLINE]  "Ma da dove arrivi?"[NEWLINE]"Molto tempo fa vivevo ad est, ora viaggio verso ovest"[NEWLINE]  "Dove stai andando?"[NEWLINE]"Dovunque io possa."[NEWLINE]  "Quindi cosa sei, una specie di viaggiatore?"[NEWLINE]"Solo di un tipo. Nomade, vagabondo - chiamami come preferisci."[NEWLINE]  "Ma viaggi da sola? Disarmata? Come fai a sopravvivere la fuori?"[NEWLINE]"Mi adatto all'ignoto. Sotto le stelle erranti sono cresciuta - da sola ma non da sola. Non chiedo niente a nessuno."[NEWLINE]  "Parlate in modo strano, mia signora, ma se rispetterete le leggi della città siete la benvenuta a Brookden."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Le guardie si fecero da parte e permisero a Deirdra di entrare in città. Una veduta veramente magnifica, l'imponente cupola bronzea del palazzo dei Dural dominava la scena ma era circondata da cose di eguale bellezza - statue, affreschi e una bellissima archittetura. Uno poteva passare tutta la vita qui e non avere comunque tempo per apprezzare appieno tutte le arti dei Dural. Lei, comunque, non sarebbe rimasta qui per molto. C'era ancora una lunga strada da percorrere.</Italian>
		<Spanish>"My home? Where I lay my head is home."[NEWLINE]  "But where do you come from?"[NEWLINE]"Long ago I lived in the east, now I travel west"[NEWLINE]  "Where are you going?"[NEWLINE]"Wherever I may."[NEWLINE]  "So you're what, some sort of traveller?"[NEWLINE]"Of a sort. Rove or wanderer. Nomad, vagabond - call me what you will."[NEWLINE]  "But you travel the wastes alone? Unarmed? How do you survive out there?"[NEWLINE]"I adapt to the unknown. Under the wandering stars I've grown - by myself but not alone. I ask of no-one."[NEWLINE]  "You speak oddly, milady, but if you keep to the laws of the city, you are welcomed in Brookden."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The guards stepped aside and permitted Deirdra to enter the city. A majestic sight indeed, the massive bronzed dome of the Dural palace dominating the scene but surrounded by sights of at least equal beauty - statues, murals and the finest architecture. One could spend a lifetime here and not have time to fully appreciate the arts of the Dural. She would not be there long however. There was still a long road ahead.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AUSTRIN_SETTLEMENT</Tag>
		<English>Austrin Settlement</English>
		<French>Campement Austrin</French>
		<German>Austrinische Siedlung</German>
		<Italian>Insediamento Austrin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Austrin Settlement</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AUSTRIN_SETTLEMENT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Austrin do not worry about great distances between their cities - their wanderers travel often and communication is easy.</English>
		<French>Les Austrin ne s'inquiètent pas des grandes distances entre leurs villes. Leurs rôdeurs voyagent souvent et la communication est aisée.</French>
		<German>The Austrin do not worry about great distances between their cities - their wanderers travel often and communication is easy.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Austrin non si preoccupano delle grandi distanze tra le loro città - i loro esploratori viaggiano spesso e mantenere i contatti è facile.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Austrin do not worry about great distances between their cities - their wanderers travel often and communication is easy.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AUSTRIN_SETTLEMENT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Austrin Settlement is present in all Austrin cities, massively reducing the maintenance due to distance that they need to pay.</English>
		<French>Le Campement Austrin est présent dans toutes les villes Austrin, et réduit massivement les coûts d'entretien dûs à l'éloignement du Palais.</French>
		<German>The Austrin Settlement is present in all Austrin cities, massively reducing the maintenance due to distance that they need to pay.</German>
		<Italian>L'Insediamento Austrin è presente in tutte le città Austrin, riducendo enormemente il mantenimento da pagare dovuto alla distanza.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Austrin Settlement is present in all Austrin cities, massively reducing the maintenance due to distance that they need to pay.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EXPLORATION_GUILD</Tag>
		<English>Exploration Guild</English>
		<French>Guilde des Explorateurs</French>
		<German>Erkundungsgilde</German>
		<Italian>Gilda degli Esploratori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Exploration Guild</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EXPLORATION_GUILD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Those of a like mind often band together. With so many amongst the Austrin with a mind to explore, it is unsurprising to find an exploration guild in most of their cities.</English>
		<French>Les esprits similaires se regroupent souvent. Avec tant de gens parmi les Austrin avec une mentalité d'explorateur, il n'est pas étonnant de trouver une Guilde des Explorateurs dans la plupart de leurs villes.</French>
		<German>Those of a like mind often band together. With so many amongst the Austrin with a mind to explore, it is unsurprising to find an exploration guild in most of their cities.</German>
		<Italian>Coloro dal pensiero affine spesso si riuniscono in gruppi. Essendoci cosi tante persone interessate all'esplorazione tra gli Austrin, non può sorprendere trovare una gilda degli esploratori in quasi tutte le loro città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Those of a like mind often band together. With so many amongst the Austrin with a mind to explore, it is unsurprising to find an exploration guild in most of their cities.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_AUSTRIN</Tag>
		<English>Austrin Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Austrin</French>
		<German>Palast der Austrin</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo degli Austrin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Austrin Palace</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_PREPARE_EXPEDITION</Tag>
		<English>Prepare Expedition</English>
		<French>Préparer une Expédition</French>
		<German>Richte Expedition aus</German>
		<Italian>Prepara una Spedizione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Prepare Expedition</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_PREPARE_EXPEDITION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Once an expedition is prepared, you may found a city with any recon unit. You must prepare a separate expedition for every settlement you wish to found in this way.</English>
		<French>Une fois l'expédition préparée, vous pouvez fonder une ville avec n'importe quelle unité de reconnaissance. Il est nécessaire de préparer une expédition pour chaque ville fondée de cette manière.</French>
		<German>Once an expedition is prepared, you may found a city with any recon unit. You must prepare a separate expedition for every settlement you wish to found in this way.</German>
		<Italian>Una volta che una spedizione viene preparata, potrai fondare una città con qualsiasi unità da ricognizione. Dovrai preparare una spedizione diversa per ogi insediamento che vuoi fondare in questa maniera.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Once an expedition is prepared, you may found a city with any recon unit. You must prepare a separate expedition for every settlement you wish to found in this way.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_ASSEMBLE_SHOREPARTY</Tag>
		<English>Assemble Shoreparty</English>
		<French>Réunir les Marsouins</French>
		<German>Küstentrupp versammeln</German>
		<Italian>Crea Gruppo d'Esplorazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Assemble Shoreparty</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND</Tag>
		<English>Found Settlement</English>
		<French>Installer un Campement</French>
		<German>Gründe Siedlung</German>
		<Italian>Fonda Insediamento</Italian>
		<Spanish>Found Settlement</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Requires you to "Prepare an Expedition" in one of your cities[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Allows your recon unit to found a city</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Nécessite de "Préparer une Expédition" dans une de vos villes[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Permet à vos unités de Reconnaissance de fonder une ville.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erfordert "Richte Expedition aus" in einer Eurer Städte[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt es einer Aufklärungseinheit, eine Stdt zu gründen</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Richiede il "Preparare una Spedizione" in una delle tue città[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Permette alle tue unità da ricognizione di fondare una città</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Requires you to "Prepare an Expedition" in one of your cities[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Allows your recon unit to found a city</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_AUSTRIN_REMOTE_FOUND_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Austrin wanderers often find far flung locations with valuable resources. After reporting back, an expedition may be sent to found a permanent settlement.</English>
		<French>Les rôdeurs Austrin trouvent souvent des régions inhabitées riches en ressources. Après avoir rapporté l'information, une expédition peut être envoyée pour installer un campement permanent.</French>
		<German>Austrin wanderers often find far flung locations with valuable resources. After reporting back, an expedition may be sent to found a permanent settlement.</German>
		<Italian>I viaggiatori Austrin spesso trovano posti lontani con risorse preziose. Dopo averne fatto rapporto, una spedizione potrebbe essere inviata per fondare un'insediamento permanente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Austrin wanderers often find far flung locations with valuable resources. After reporting back, an expedition may be sent to found a permanent settlement.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_BLADEWIND</Tag>
		<English>Bladewind</English>
		<French>Lame du Vent</French>
		<German>Wind der Klingen</German>
		<Italian>Lama del Vento</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bladewind</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MOUNT_PEGASUS</Tag>
		<English>Mount Pegasus</English>
		<French>Chevaucher Pégase</French>
		<German>Pegasus satteln</German>
		<Italian>Cavalca Pegaso</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mount Pegasus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_REEQUIP</Tag>
		<English>Re-equip</English>
		<French>Ré-équipeemnt</French>
		<German>Wiederausrüsten</German>
		<Italian>Riequppagiarsi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Re-equip</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_REEQUIP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Whilst the Austrin armies tend to travel with little equipment, they will normally scavenge or create weapons as they near the battlefield.</English>
		<French>Bien que les armées Austrins aient tendance à voyager avec peu d'équipement, ils récupèrent ou créent leurs armes à l'approche du champ de bataille.</French>
		<German>Whilst the Austrin armies tend to travel with little equipment, they will normally scavenge or create weapons as they near the battlefield.</German>
		<Italian>Siccome gli eserciti Austrin tendono a viaggiare con poco equipaggiamento, di solito recuperano delle armi o se le creano mentre si avvicinano al campo di battaglia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Whilst the Austrin armies tend to travel with little equipment, they will normally scavenge or create weapons as they near the battlefield.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_REEQUIP_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Using this ability returns the unit to normal speed and removes the combat penalty from travelling light. It does take a full turn to take effect however and does not restore weapon promotions - these must be regained in a city.</English>
		<French>Utiliser cette compétence permet à l'unité de récupérer sa vitesse normale et annuler la pénalité de combat dûe au voyage léger. Cela prend cependant un tour complet pour faire effet et ne rétablit pas les promotions d'armes qui doivent être obtenues dans une ville.</French>
		<German>Using this ability returns the unit to normal speed and removes the combat penalty from travelling light. It does take a full turn to take effect however and does not restore weapon promotions - these must be regained in a city.</German>
		<Italian>Usare questa abilità ripristina la forza e la velocita normale dell'unità che erano state modificate dal viaggiare leggeri. Ma per avere effetto ci impiega un'intero turno e non ripristina eventuali miglioramenti delle armi - quelli devono essere ri ottenuti in una città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Using this ability returns the unit to normal speed and removes the combat penalty from travelling light. It does take a full turn to take effect however and does not restore weapon promotions - these must be regained in a city.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SUMMON_PEGASUS</Tag>
		<English>Summon Pegasus</English>
		<French>Évocation de Pégase</French>
		<German>Pegasus beschwören</German>
		<Italian>Evoca Pegaso</Italian>
		<Spanish>Summon Pegasus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_TEMPEST</Tag>
		<English>Tempest</English>
		<French>Tempête</French>
		<German>Seesturm</German>
		<Italian>Tempesta</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tempest</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_TEMPEST_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Immobilizes all enemy units in your territory for a random amount of time (1-5 turns)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]May create air elementals in your territory with a random duration (1-5 turns)</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Immobilise toutes lse unités ennemies sur votre territoire pour une durée aléatoire (1-5 tours)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Peut créer des Élémentaires d'Air sur votre territoire pour une durée aléatoire (1-5 tours)</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Verhindert die Bewegung aller feindlicher Einheiten auf Eurem Gebiet für eine ungewisse Zeit (1-5 Runden)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Kann auf Eurem Territorium Luftelementare mit einer ungewissen Verweildauer (1-5 Runden) erschaffen</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Immobilizza tutte le unità nemiche che sono all'interno dei tuoi territori per un periodo di tempo casuale (1-5 turni)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Potrebbe creare elementali dell'aria nei tuoi territori dalla durata casuale (1-5 turni)</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Immobilizes all enemy units in your territory for a random amount of time (1-5 turns)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]May create air elementals in your territory with a random duration (1-5 turns)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_TEMPEST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>When the air itself turns against you, there's nowhere left to run.</English>
		<French>Quand l'air lui-même se retourne contre vous, il n'y a plus d'endroit où vous cacher.</French>
		<German>Wenn die Luft selbst sich gegen Dich wendet, gibt es keinen ort mehr, an den Du fliehen kannst.</German>
		<Italian>Quando l'aria stessa si rivolta contro di te, non c'è nessun posto dove scappare.</Italian>
		<Spanish>When the air itself turns against you, there's nowhere left to run.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_TRAVEL_LIGHT</Tag>
		<English>Travel Light</English>
		<French>Voyager Léger</French>
		<German>Reiselicht</German>
		<Italian>Viaggia Leggero</Italian>
		<Spanish>Travel Light</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_TRAVEL_LIGHT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A warrior carries much to aid him in battle, but much of this can be discarded in favour of speed. Afterall- new equipment can often be found at the destination.</English>
		<French>Un guerrier porte énormément d'équipement pour l'aider au combat, mais la plupart peut être sacrifiée au profit de la vitesse. Après tout, un nouvel équipement peut souvent être trouvé à destination.</French>
		<German>A warrior carries much to aid him in battle, but much of this can be discarded in favour of speed. Afterall- new equipment can often be found at the destination.</German>
		<Italian>Un guerriero trasporta molta roba che lo aiuta in battaglia, ma la maggior parte di tutta quella roba può essere abbandonata per essere più veloci. Dopotutto del nuovo equipaggiamento può essere trovato spesso una volta arrivati a destinazione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A warrior carries much to aid him in battle, but much of this can be discarded in favour of speed. Afterall- new equipment can often be found at the destination.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_EXPLORER</Tag>
		<English>Explorer</English>
		<French>Explorateur</French>
		<German>Kundschafter</German>
		<Italian>Esploratore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Explorer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_EXPLORER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Most civilizations search the areas surrounding their lands to discover new resources and neighbouring civilizations. The Austrin however explore the world purely for the love of discovering the unknown. Often, that unknown can be hostile or even deadly, but the Exploration guild trains its members well and most fare well in the wild.</English>
		<French>La plupart des civilisations explorent les contrées proches pour découvrir de nouvelles ressources et les civilisations proches. Mais les Austrins explorent le monde pour le plaisir pur de découvrir l'inconnu. Souvent, cet incoonu peut être hostile voire mortel, mais la Guilde des Explorateurs entraîne bien ses membres, et la plupart se débrouille bien dans les contrées sauvages.</French>
		<German>Most civilizations search the areas surrounding their lands to discover new resources and neighbouring civilizations. The Austrin however explore the world purely for the love of discovering the unknown. Often, that unknown can be hostile or even deadly, but the Exploration guild trains its members well and most fare well in the wild.</German>
		<Italian>La maggior parte delle civiltà esplora le zone circostanti per scoprire nuove risorse e le civiltà confinanti. Gli Austrin invece esplorano il mondo puramente per amore della scoperta dell'ignoto. Spesso, quell'ignoto può essere ostile o addirittura mortale, ma la Gilda degli Esploratori addestra i suoi membri bene e molti se la cavano bene nelle terre selvagge.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Most civilizations search the areas surrounding their lands to discover new resources and neighbouring civilizations. The Austrin however explore the world purely for the love of discovering the unknown. Often, that unknown can be hostile or even deadly, but the Exploration guild trains its members well and most fare well in the wild.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_EXPLORER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>This Hunter-replacement unit shares many of the hunter's strengths, whilst being available at Cartography and also able to traverse difficult terrain rapidly.</English>
		<French>Ce remplaçant du Chasseur partage beaucoup des atouts de ce dernier, mais est en couple capable de devenir Cartographe et également capable de franchir rapidement les terrains difficiles.</French>
		<German>This Hunter-replacement unit shares many of the hunter's strengths, whilst being available at Cartography and also able to traverse difficult terrain rapidly.</German>
		<Italian>Quest'unità (che rimpiazza il Cacciatore) condivide molti dei punti di forza del cacciatore, pur essendo disponibile dopo aver scoperto la tecnologia Cartografia, inoltre è capace di attraversare i terreni difficoltosi rapidamente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>This Hunter-replacement unit shares many of the hunter's strengths, whilst being available at Cartography and also able to traverse difficult terrain rapidly.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FALCONER</Tag>
		<English>Falconer</English>
		<French>Fauconnier</French>
		<German>Falkner</German>
		<Italian>Falconiere</Italian>
		<Spanish>Falconer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HARMATT</Tag>
		<English>Harmatt</English>
		<French>Harmatt</French>
		<German>Harmatt</German>
		<Italian>Harmatt</Italian>
		<Spanish>Harmatt</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HARMATT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The ocean spread before him, Harmatt breathed in the salt-air. He had travelled the breadth of this land, from Telynohn to the Great Western Sea. Now he could travel no more, as the water stretched out to the north and south, forming a barrier. Yet the horizon still called him. This was not the edge of the world, he could feel it. There was more to find, to see.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As night fell, he crept back to the Amurite port. Ships travelled along the coast at all hours to dock at Glorairine, though they were mostly cargo ships - ugly, cumbersome and ill-suited to a voyage on untamed waves. Then he saw it. A cruiser - simple and elegant lines, designed for speed, belonging to some high-ranking mage who needed to travel between the Amurite cities and beyond rapidly.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Harmatt held no antipathy toward the Amurites - in fact they'd been nothing but accomadating when he'd paid Cervedes a visit. He needed to sail however and the cruiser was the key to that. He quickly slipped on board and darted across the main deck. The craft was designed for a crew of a dozen or more, but he had sailed far larger crafts alone in the past - the winds favoured him. Checking that there were none aboard, he sliced the mooring ropes and prepared to make way.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It would not move. He had spent minutes that felt like a lifetime trying to set sail, but the vessel was stuck fast. The small anchor had been raised, the moorings were cleared and the sails had been dropped enough to man&#156;uvre (though hopefully not enough to attract attention from the docks) - but still it refused to move. Knowing that time was short, Harmatt opened the sails full, hoping that a sail full of wind would pull him free of the unseen obstruction. The ship lurched uncertainly, then began to vibrate, but still it refused to move.[NEWLINE]A light on the dockside alerted him to the approach of guards, he could flee into the water, but despite being a strong swimmer, he doubted he could outpace an archer's arrow. He stood his ground as the guards laid a gang plank and boarded the ship.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At their head stood a mage. "What exactly are you doing here, in the dead of night? Speak quickly, lest I think you a thief"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]  "Surely not a thief", said Harmatt. "I am merely here to render this vessel seaworthy once more - something unseen has snared it and the owner wished me to free it". The Mage looked amused.[NEWLINE]This vessel will become seaworthy only when its owner wishes it to be so. This is the personal transport of Archmage Govannon - without his magic, it will never move."[NEWLINE]  "Oh. Drat. I guess it's not what I needed afterall then. The water it is..." Before the Amurites could respond, he had darted back several feet and flung himself from the deck, over the side of the boat. The guards ran to the rail as something heavy splashed into the water and seconds later the area was showered with arrows. They waited several minutes, but naught but the thief's hat surfaced.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Hanging on grimly to the underside of the anchor, Harmatt lamented the loss of his hat and swordbelt - cast into the water as he made his escape. This was not turning out to be a good night...</English>
		<French>L'océan s'étalant devant lui, Harmatt huma l'air salé. Il avait parcouru l'étendue de cette terre, de Telynohn à la Grande Mer Occidentale. Il ne pouvait plus voyager, la mer s'étendant du nord au sud, formant une barrière. Mais l'horizon continuait de l'appeler. Ce n'était pas le bord du monde, il pouvait le sentir. Il restait à découvir, à explorer.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Il regagna le port Amurite à la nuit tombante. Les navires longeaient la côte à tout heure pour accoster à Glorairine, mais étaient généralement des navires cargo, laids, emcombrants et inadaptés à la navigation sur des mers déchaînées. Puis il le vit. Un croiseur aux lignes simples et élégantes, conçu pour la vitesse et appartenant à un quelconque mage de haut-rang ayant besoin de voyager rapidement entre les villes Amurites et ailleurs.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Hermatt ne ressentait aucune animosité vis-à-vis des Amurites; en fait ils n'étaient qu'accomodants quand il visita Cervedes. Mais il avait besoin de naviguer et le croiseur en était la clé. Il se glissa rapidement à bord et se précipita sur le pont principal. Le navire était conçu pour un équipage d'au moins 10 personnes, mais il avait déjà navigué seul sur des navires plus grands par le passé, les vents lui étant favorables. Vérifiant qu'il n'y avait personne à bord, il trancha les amarres et se prépara à partir.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Il refusa de bouger. Il passa plusieurs minutes longues comme une vie à essayer de lever l'ancre, mais le navire était rivé. La petite ancre etait levée, les amarres étaient détachées et les voiles étaient suffisamment hissées pour man&#156;uvrer (mais avec un peu de chance suffisamment peu pour ne pas attirer l'attention depuis les docks) et pourtant il refusait de bouger. Se sachant pris par le temps, Harmatt hissa complètement les voiles, espérant que les voiles gonflées par les vents suffiraient à l'arracher à l'obstacle invisible. Le navire vacilla, commença à vibrer, mais refusa toujours de bouger.[NEWLINE]Une lumière du côté des docks l'alerta de l'approche des gardes. Il pouvait fuir en plongeant mais même s'il était bon nageur, il doutait de pouvoir distancer une flêche. Il resta sur place tandis que les gardes déployaient une passerelle et montaient à bord.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Il y avait à leur tête un mage. "Que faites-vous ici au beau milieu de la nuit? Parlez rapidement ou nous vous considérerons comme un voleur."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Je ne suis sûrement pas un voleur", dit Harmatt. "Je suis simplement ici pour rendre encore une fois ce navire utilisable, quelque chose d'inconnu l'entravant, et le propriétaire souhaitant me voir le libérer." Le mage parut amusé.[NEWLINE]"Ce navire ne sera utilisable que si son propriétaire le souhaite. Ceci est le transport personnel de l'Archimage Govannon, et sans son pouvoir ce navire ne bougera jamis."[NEWLINE]"Oh, flûte! Je suppose que je n'en avais pas besoin après tout. L'eau..." Avant que les Amurites aient pu réagir, il avait reculé de quelques pas et se jeta par-dessus bord. Les gardes se précipitèrent à la rambarde tandis que quelque chose plongeait lourdement dans l'eau, et la seconde d'après une pluie de flèches couvrait la zone. Ils attendirent plusieurs minutes, mais seul le chapeau du voleur fit surface.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]S'accrochant d'un air mécontent au bas de l'ancre, Harmatt se lamentait sur la perte de se chapeau et son fourreau d'épée, lancés dans l'eau tandis qu'il s'échappait. Ça n'allait pas être une bonne nuit...</French>
		<German>The ocean spread before him, Harmatt breathed in the salt-air. He had travelled the breadth of this land, from Telynohn to the Great Western Sea. Now he could travel no more, as the water stretched out to the north and south, forming a barrier. Yet the horizon still called him. This was not the edge of the world, he could feel it. There was more to find, to see.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As night fell, he crept back to the Amurite port. Ships travelled along the coast at all hours to dock at Glorairine, though they were mostly cargo ships - ugly, cumbersome and ill-suited to a voyage on untamed waves. Then he saw it. A cruiser - simple and elegant lines, designed for speed, belonging to some high-ranking mage who needed to travel between the Amurite cities and beyond rapidly.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Harmatt held no antipathy toward the Amurites - in fact they'd been nothing but accomadating when he'd paid Cervedes a visit. He needed to sail however and the cruiser was the key to that. He quickly slipped on board and darted across the main deck. The craft was designed for a crew of a dozen or more, but he had sailed far larger crafts alone in the past - the winds favoured him. Checking that there were none aboard, he sliced the mooring ropes and prepared to make way.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It would not move. He had spent minutes that felt like a lifetime trying to set sail, but the vessel was stuck fast. The small anchor had been raised, the moorings were cleared and the sails had been dropped enough to manoeuvre (though hopefully not enough to attract attention from the docks) - but still it refused to move. Knowing that time was short, Harmatt opened the sails full, hoping that a sail full of wind would pull him free of the unseen obstruction. The ship lurched uncertainly, then began to vibrate, but still it refused to move.[NEWLINE]A light on the dockside alerted him to the approach of guards, he could flee into the water, but despite being a strong swimmer, he doubted he could outpace an archer's arrow. He stood his ground as the guards laid a gang plank and boarded the ship.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At their head stood a mage. "What exactly are you doing here, in the dead of night? Speak quickly, lest I think you a thief"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]  "Surely not a thief", said Harmatt. "I am merely here to render this vessel seaworthy once more - something unseen has snared it and the owner wished me to free it". The Mage looked amused.[NEWLINE]This vessel will become seaworthy only when its owner wishes it to be so. This is the personal transport of Archmage Govannon - without his magic, it will never move."[NEWLINE]  "Oh. Drat. I guess it's not what I needed afterall then. The water it is..." Before the Amurites could respond, he had darted back several feet and flung himself from the deck, over the side of the boat. The guards ran to the rail as something heavy splashed into the water and seconds later the area was showered with arrows. They waited several minutes, but naught but the thief's hat surfaced.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Hanging on grimly to the underside of the anchor, Harmatt lamented the loss of his hat and swordbelt - cast into the water as he made his escape. This was not turning out to be a good night...</German>
		<Italian>L'oceano si estendeva davanti a lui, Harmatt respirò l'aria salmastra. Aveva viaggiato per queste terre in lungo e in largo, da Telynohn sino al Grande Mare Occidentale. Ora non poteva viaggiare oltre, siccome l'acqua si estendeva sia verso nord che verso sud, formando una barriera. Eppure l'orizzonte continuava a chiamarlo. Questo non era il bordo del mondo, lo percepiva. C'era altro da trovare, da vedere.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Quando calò la notte, si intrufolo nel porto Amurite. Le navi viaggiavano sottocosta a tutte le ore per attraccare a Glorairine, sebbene erano per la maggior parte navi da trasporto - brutte, ingombranti e poco adatte ai viaggi in acque agitate. Poi lo vide. Un incrociatore - dalle linee semplici ed eleganti, progettato per essere veloce, appartenente a qualche mago di alto rango che necessitava di viaggiare tra le città Amurite e oltre in modo rapido.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Harmatt non aveva antipatie verso gli Amurite - in effetti non erano stati altro che accomodanti quando aveva fatto una visita a Cervedes. Aveva comunque bisogno di salpare e l'incorciatore era la chiave di tutto. Salì velocemente a bordo e sfrecciò sul ponte principale. L'imbarcazione è stata progettata per un equipaggio di dodici o più, ma in passato era riuscito a navigare da solo con imabarcazioni molto più grandi - i venti gli erano anche favorevoli. Controllando che nessuno fosse a bordo, tagliò le funi di attracco e si preparò a prendere il largo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Non si spostava. Passò dei minuti, che sembrarono una vita intera, cercando di salpare, ma il vascello era saldamente bloccato. La piccola ancora era stata issata, gli ormeggi erano stati rimossi e le vele erano state spiegate a sufficenza per manovrare (anche se, sperava, non abbastanza da ttirare l'attenzione dalla banchina) - ma ancora si rifiutava di muoversi. Sapendo che il tempo stava finendo, Harmatt spiegò le vele completamente, sperando che le vele gonfie di vento avrebbero liberato il vascello dall'ostacolo invisibile. La nave rollò incerta, poi iniziò a vibrare, ma ancora non si muoveva.[NEWLINE]Una luce sulla banchina lo avvertì dell'arrivo delle guardie, poteva buttarsi in acqua, ma nonostante fosse un bravo nuotatore dubitava di poter essere più rapido di una freccia. Mantenne la sua posizione mentre le guardie poggiavano una passerella e salivano sulla nave.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A guidarli c'era un mago. "Cosa staresti facendo qui esattamente, nel pieno della notte? Parla in fretta, prima che io pensi che tu sia un ladro"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]  "Sicuramente non un ladro", disse Harmatt. "Sono qui solo per rendere nuovamente navigabile questa nave - qualcosa di invisibile lo ha intrappolata e il proprietario mi ha chiesto di liberarla". Il Mago sembrava divertito.[NEWLINE]Questo vascello diventerà di nuovo navigabile quando il suo proprietario desiderera che lo sia. Questo è il trasporto personale dell'Arcimago Govannon - senza la sua magia, non si muoverà mai."[NEWLINE]  "Oh. Drat. Immagino che non sia quello di cui avevo bisogno dopotutto. Allora l'acqua..." Prima che gli Amurite potessero rispondere, era indietreggiato di diversi metri e si buttò oltre il bordo. Le guardie corsero al parapetto mentre qualcosa di pesante entrava in acqua, pochi secondi dopo quell'area fu tempestata di frecce. Attesero qualche minuto, ma niente oltra al cappello del ladro torno a galla.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rimanendo attaccato alla parte inferiore dell'ancora, Harmatt compianse la perdita del suo cappello e della cintura della spada - gettati in acqua mentre fuggiva. Non si stava rivelando una buona notte...</Italian>
		<Spanish>The ocean spread before him, Harmatt breathed in the salt-air. He had travelled the breadth of this land, from Telynohn to the Great Western Sea. Now he could travel no more, as the water stretched out to the north and south, forming a barrier. Yet the horizon still called him. This was not the edge of the world, he could feel it. There was more to find, to see.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As night fell, he crept back to the Amurite port. Ships travelled along the coast at all hours to dock at Glorairine, though they were mostly cargo ships - ugly, cumbersome and ill-suited to a voyage on untamed waves. Then he saw it. A cruiser - simple and elegant lines, designed for speed, belonging to some high-ranking mage who needed to travel between the Amurite cities and beyond rapidly.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Harmatt held no antipathy toward the Amurites - in fact they'd been nothing but accomadating when he'd paid Cervedes a visit. He needed to sail however and the cruiser was the key to that. He quickly slipped on board and darted across the main deck. The craft was designed for a crew of a dozen or more, but he had sailed far larger crafts alone in the past - the winds favoured him. Checking that there were none aboard, he sliced the mooring ropes and prepared to make way.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It would not move. He had spent minutes that felt like a lifetime trying to set sail, but the vessel was stuck fast. The small anchor had been raised, the moorings were cleared and the sails had been dropped enough to manoeuvre (though hopefully not enough to attract attention from the docks) - but still it refused to move. Knowing that time was short, Harmatt opened the sails full, hoping that a sail full of wind would pull him free of the unseen obstruction. The ship lurched uncertainly, then began to vibrate, but still it refused to move.[NEWLINE]A light on the dockside alerted him to the approach of guards, he could flee into the water, but despite being a strong swimmer, he doubted he could outpace an archer's arrow. He stood his ground as the guards laid a gang plank and boarded the ship.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At their head stood a mage. "What exactly are you doing here, in the dead of night? Speak quickly, lest I think you a thief"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]  "Surely not a thief", said Harmatt. "I am merely here to render this vessel seaworthy once more - something unseen has snared it and the owner wished me to free it". The Mage looked amused.[NEWLINE]This vessel will become seaworthy only when its owner wishes it to be so. This is the personal transport of Archmage Govannon - without his magic, it will never move."[NEWLINE]  "Oh. Drat. I guess it's not what I needed afterall then. The water it is..." Before the Amurites could respond, he had darted back several feet and flung himself from the deck, over the side of the boat. The guards ran to the rail as something heavy splashed into the water and seconds later the area was showered with arrows. They waited several minutes, but naught but the thief's hat surfaced.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Hanging on grimly to the underside of the anchor, Harmatt lamented the loss of his hat and swordbelt - cast into the water as he made his escape. This was not turning out to be a good night...</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HARMATT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Harmatt is an early hero though has some mid-game potential thanks to his Air-affinity. He is best used to explore and is able to deal with the worst that the wild can throw at him.</English>
		<French>Harmatt est un héros de début de jeu ayant un bon potentiel en milieu de jeu grâce à son affinité à l'Air. Il est idéal pour explorer et capable de faire face au pire que peut lui envoyer la nature.</French>
		<German>Harmatt is an early hero though has some mid-game potential thanks to his Air-affinity. He is best used to explore and is able to deal with the worst that the wild can throw at him.</German>
		<Italian>Harmatt è un eroe da inizio partita sebbene abbia un certo potenziale anche verso metà partita grazie alla sua affinità con l'Aria. Il suo utilizzo migliore consiste nell'usarlo per esplorare essendo capace di gestire il peggio che le terre selvagge possono mandargli contro.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Harmatt is an early hero though has some mid-game potential thanks to his Air-affinity. He is best used to explore and is able to deal with the worst that the wild can throw at him.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HIGHLANDER</Tag>
		<English>Highlander</English>
		<French>Montagnard</French>
		<German>Hochländer</German>
		<Italian>Montanaro</Italian>
		<Spanish>Highlander</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HIGHLANDER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Trained not in cramped barracks, but out on the hillsides of erebus, Highlanders are the core of an Austrin offensive army. They live their lives camping out in glens and forests, hunting for food, honing their survival skills, fighting wild beasts, and sparring for training. This lifestyle gives them a natural affinity for rough terrain, and a good experience of fending off wild animals.[PARAGRAPH:1][PARAGRAPH:1]They carry a large Claymore on their back, a powerful and flexible greatsword that is carried like a polearm, but swung like a sword. The base of the blade is blunted and wrapped in dark cloth, giving an extra place to grip when holding it at the ready, and both hands are moved down to the hilt when swinging, allowing it to gather massive momentum from its huge arc of motion. Such a weapon favours combat in open spaces, though. And unlike their city-dwelling cousins, they are not well used to fighting on cramped battlements and castle hallways, much preferring combat in the field.</English>
		<French>Entraînés non pas dans des casernes exigües mais à l'extérieur dans les collines d'Erebus, les Montagnards sont le cour de l'armée offensive des Austrins. Ils vivent leurs vies campant dans les vallées encaissées et les forêts, chassant pour se nourrir, aiguisant leurs compétences de survie, combattant les animaux sauvages et s'entraînant au combat. Ce mode de vie leur confère une affinité naturelle pour les terrains difficiles et une bonne expérience pour repousser les animaux sauvages.[PARAGRAPH:2]Ils portent une grande claymore dans le dos, une épée à deux mains puissante et maniable portée comme une masse mais équilibrée comme une épée. La base de la lame est émoussée et emballée dans un drap noir, donnant un endroit supplémentaire pour la tenir sur le qui-vive. Les deux mains mains sont descendues sur la garde quand utilisée, permettant d'accumuler un maximum d'énergie lors de ses mouvements amples. Mais une telle arme n'est utile que dans les endroits dégagés. Et contrairement à leurs cousins citadins, ils sont pas habitués à se battre sur des remparts étroits ou dans des couloirs de chateau, préférant de loin les combats sur le terrain.</French>
		<German>Ausgebildet nicht in verkrampften Kasernen, aber heraus auf den Abhängen von erebus, sind Hochländer der Kern jeder Austrin Offensivarmee. Sie leben ihre Leben kampierend heraus in den Schluchten und in den Wäldern und jagen für Nahrung und ziehen ihre überlebensfähigkeiten, kämpfenden wilden Tiere und sparring für Training ab. Dieser Lebensstil gibt ihnen eine natürliche Affinität für raues Gelände und einer guten Erfahrung des Abwehrens weg von den wilden Tieren.[PARAGRAPH:1][PARAGRAPH:1]Sie tragen ein großes Claymore auf ihrer Rückseite, einem leistungsfähigen und flexiblen greatsword, das wie ein polearm getragen wird, aber geschwungen wie eine Klinge. Die Unterseite des Blattes wird abgestumpft und eingewickelt im dunklen Tuch, einen Extraplatz gebend, um wann das Halten er am bereiten und an beiden Händen zu greifen, nach unten auf den Griff beim Schwingen bewogen werden und es massives Momentum von seinem sehr großen Bogen der Bewegung erfassen lassen. Solch eine Waffe bevorzugt Kampf in den offenen Räumen, zwar. Und anders als ihre Stadtwohnung Vetter, sind sie nicht gewohnt zu auf, verkrampften Zinnen zu kämpfen wohles und ziehen sich Hallen, viel bevorzugenkampf im Feld zurück.</German>
		<Italian>Addestrati non in anguste caserme, ma fuori sui pendii delle colline di erebus, i Montanari sono il centro di un esercito offensivo Austrin. Vivono le loro vite accampandosi nelle valli e nelle foreste, cacciando il loro cibo, affinando le loro abilità di sopravvivenza, combattendo le bestie selvagge e allenandosi nel combattimento. Questo stile di vita dà loro un'affinità naturale per i terreni accidentati e li porta ad essere esperti nel difendersi dagli animali selvatici.[PARAGRAPH:1][PARAGRAPH:1]Trasportano un grande Claymore sulla loro schiena, uno spadone potente e flessibile che può venire impugnata come fosse un'arma ad asta. La parte della lama vicino all'elsa è smussata e, di solito, coperta da un panno o cuoio, permettendo di afferarla per eseguire particolari tecniche. Per come viene maneggiata quando viene sferrato un fendente la lama ottiene una forza cinetica molto elevata. Una arma come questa favorisce il combattimento negli spazi aperti. Diversamente dai loro cugini delle città, non sono adatti al combattimento sui merli e nei corridoi dei castelli, preferendo di gran lunga combattere in battaglie campali.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Entrenado no en cuarteles encogidos, sino hacia fuera en las laderas del erebus, los montañeses son la base de un ejército de la ofensiva de Austrin. Viven sus vidas que acampan hacia fuera en cañadas y bosques, buscando para el alimento, afilando con piedra sus habilidades de la supervivencia, bestias salvajes que luchan, y sparring para el entrenamiento. Esta forma de vida da les una afinidad natural para el terreno áspero, y a buena experiencia del mantenimiento de animales salvajes.[PARAGRAPH:1][PARAGRAPH:1]Llevan un Claymore grande en su parte posterior, un greatsword de gran alcance y flexible que se lleve como un polearm, pero hecho pivotar como una espada. La base de la lámina se embota y envuelto en el paño oscuro, dando un lugar adicional para agarrar cuando llevarlo a cabo en el listo, y ambas manos se baja al puño al hacer pivotar, permitiendo que recolecte ímpetu masivo de su arco enorme del movimiento. Tal arma favorece combate en espacios abiertos, aunque. Y desemejante de sus primos de la ciudad-vivienda, no están bien usados a luchar en los almenajes encogidos y no se escudan los vestíbulos, mucho combate que prefiere en el campo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HIGHLANDER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>With their extra attack strength, bonuses in hills, and against animals, Highlanders are a well rounded unit perfect for exploring the world and battling against the elements. However, they lack in city attack capability compared to similar units, and so large numbers may be needed if you wish to use them for conquest.</English>
		<French>Grâce à leur puissance supérieure, leurs bonus dans les collines et contre les animaux, les Montagnards sont des unités équilibrées parfaites pour explorer le monde et lutter contre les éléments. Cependant, ils sont faibles pour l'attaque de villes, comparé aux unités équivalentes. Si vous souhaitez les utiliser pour la conquêtes, vous pourrez avoir besoin d'un grand nombre d'entre eux.</French>
		<German>Mit ihrer Extraangriffsstärke, Prämien in den Hügeln und gegen Tiere, sind Hochländer eine gut gerundete Maßeinheit, die für die Erforschung der Welt und das Kämpfen gegen die Elemente vollkommen ist. Jedoch ermangeln sie in der Stadtangriffsfähigkeit, die mit ähnlichen Maßeinheiten verglichen wird und also können große Zahlen erforderlich sein, wenn Sie sie für Eroberung benutzen möchten.</German>
		<Italian>Con la loro forza d'attacco extra, i bonus se in collina e contro gli animali, i Montanari sono un'unità versatile perfetta per esplorare il mondo e lottare contro gli elementi. Tuttavia, se paragonate a unità simili non sono altrettanto utili nell'attacare le città e potrebbero essere necessari in grande quantita se li si vuole usare per conquistare.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Con su fuerza adicional del ataque, las primas en colinas, y contra animales, los montañeses son una unidad bien redondeada perfecta para explorar el mundo y luchar contra los elementos. Sin embargo, carecen en la capacidad del ataque de la ciudad comparada a las unidades similares, y así que los grandes números pueden ser necesarios si usted desea utilizarlas para la conquista.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRAVELLER</Tag>
		<English>Traveller</English>
		<French>Voyageur</French>
		<German>Reisender</German>
		<Italian>Viaggiatore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Traveller</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRAVELLER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The palace may reject foreign envoys, the army prevents the encroachment of foreign forces and the temple may reject the advances of foreign missionaries. The tavern however will never reject the coin of foreign drinkers and this is where the traveller tends to be found. Seemingly displaced individuals, they spend time in the cities of their rivals learning as much as is necessary to survive. They are not (all) criminals, but they do have a tendency to find themselves in places they do not belong.</English>
		<French>Le palais peut refouler les émissaires étrangers, l'armée empêche les incursions des corces értangères et le temple peut rejeter les avances de missionnaires étrangers. La taverne ne refusera cependant jamais les pièces des buveurs étrangers, et c'est là que l'on trouve généralement le Voyageur. Semblant ne jamais être à sa place, ils passent leur temps dans les villes de leurs rivaux, apprenant autant que nécessaire pour survivre. Ce ne sont pas (tous) des criminels, mais ils ont tendance à se trouver là où ils ne devraient pas.</French>
		<German>The palace may reject foreign envoys, the army prevents the encroachment of foreign forces and the temple may reject the advances of foreign missionaries. The tavern however will never reject the coin of foreign drinkers and this is where the traveller tends to be found. Seemingly displaced individuals, they spend time in the cities of their rivals learning as much as is necessary to survive. They are not (all) criminals, but they do have a tendency to find themselves in places they do not belong.</German>
		<Italian>Il palazzo può respingere i diplomatici stranieri, l'esercito può impedire l'invasione di forze straniere e il tempio può impedire ai missionari stranieri di fare progressi. La taverna invece non rifiutera mai le monete dei bevitori stranieri ed è qui che si può trovare il viaggiatore. Apparentemente individui senza una patria, passano il tempo nelle città dei loro rivali imparando quanto necessario per sopravvivere. Loro non sono (tutti) criminali, ma hanno la tendenza a trovarsi in posti a cui non appartengono.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The palace may reject foreign envoys, the army prevents the encroachment of foreign forces and the temple may reject the advances of foreign missionaries. The tavern however will never reject the coin of foreign drinkers and this is where the traveller tends to be found. Seemingly displaced individuals, they spend time in the cities of their rivals learning as much as is necessary to survive. They are not (all) criminals, but they do have a tendency to find themselves in places they do not belong.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRAVELLER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Travellers are scout units that are able to travel through rival territory freely and investigate their cities. This information may be of use when planning for diplomacy, expansion or war.</English>
		<French>Les voyageurs sont des unités de reconnaissance capables de traverser librement le territoire adverse et espionner leurs villes. Ces informations peuvent être utiles pour la diplomatie, l'expansion ou la guerre.</French>
		<German>Travellers are scout units that are able to travel through rival territory freely and investigate their cities. This information may be of use when planning for diplomacy, expansion or war.</German>
		<Italian>I viaggiatori sono ricognitori capaci di attraversare il territorio rivale liberamente e ispezionare le loro città. Queste informazioni possono essere utili quando si pianifica per la diplomazia, l'espansione o la guerra.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Travellers are scout units that are able to travel through rival territory freely and investigate their cities. This information may be of use when planning for diplomacy, expansion or war.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PEGASUS</Tag>
		<English>Pegasus</English>
		<French>Pégase</French>
		<German>Pegasus</German>
		<Italian>Pegaso</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pegasus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PEGASUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Pegasus is a mythical creature, generally remembered due to its namesake constellation. They are wild animals who have tasted the freedom of the skies, though they are also highly intelligent and will allow themselves to be ridden if the cause suits them.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] "It's a horse with wings. I don't see what's so dan-"[NEWLINE]Last Words of Valen Meldea, horseman third class of Junil's Lancers.</English>
		<French>Le Pégase est une créature mythologique, généralement connu grâce à la constellation éponyme. Ce sont des animaux sauvages qui ont goûté à la liberté des cieux, bien que très intelligents et capables de se laisser chevaucher si la cause leur convient.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] "It's a horse with wings. I don't see what's so dan-"[NEWLINE]Last Words of Valen Meldea, horseman third class of Junil's Lancers.</French>
		<German>The Pegasus is a mythical creature, generally remembered due to its namesake constellation. They are wild animals who have tasted the freedom of the skies, though they are also highly intelligent and will allow themselves to be ridden if the cause suits them.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] "It's a horse with wings. I don't see what's so dan-"[NEWLINE]Last Words of Valen Meldea, horseman third class of Junil's Lancers.</German>
		<Italian>Il Pegaso è una creatura mitologica, generalmente ricordato a causa della sua costellazione omonima. Sono animali selvaggi che hanno provato la libertà dei cieli, sebbene siano anche molto intelligenti e si farebberò cavalcare se la causa li convince.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] "È un cavallo con le ali. Non vedo cosa ci sia di così per-"[NEWLINE]Ultime parole di Valen Meldea, cavaliere terza classe dei Lanceri di Junil.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Pegasus is a mythical creature, generally remembered due to its namesake constellation. They are wild animals who have tasted the freedom of the skies, though they are also highly intelligent and will allow themselves to be ridden if the cause suits them.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] "It's a horse with wings. I don't see what's so dan-"[NEWLINE]Last Words of Valen Meldea, horseman third class of Junil's Lancers.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PEGASUS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Pegasi are maginally useful as a unit, but far more useful as a mount for an existing high level unit. Using the "Ride Pegasus" ability, any Melee, Archer or Adept unit can ride the Pegasus, allowing it rapid and unrestricted movement.</English>
		<French>Les Pégases sont peu utiles en tant qu'unité, mais bien plus utiles en tant que monture pour une unité de haut niveau. En utilisant la capacité "Chevaucher Pégase", n'importe quelle unité de mélée, à distance ou adepte peut chevaucher le Pégase, lui conférant un mouvement rapide et sans restriction.</French>
		<German>Pegasi are maginally useful as a unit, but far more useful as a mount for an existing high level unit. Using the "Ride Pegasus" ability, any Melee, Archer or Adept unit can ride the Pegasus, allowing it rapid and unrestricted movement.</German>
		<Italian>I Pegasi non sono molto utili come unità di per se, ma molto più utili come cavalcatura per un'unità di alto livello. Usando l'abilità "Cavalca Pegaso", qualsiasi unità da Combattimento Ravvicinato, di Arcieri o Arcana può cavalcare Pegaso, permettendogli un movimento rapido e senza restrizioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pegasi are maginally useful as a unit, but far more useful as a mount for an existing high level unit. Using the "Ride Pegasus" ability, any Melee, Archer or Adept unit can ride the Pegasus, allowing it rapid and unrestricted movement.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RECURVE_ARCHER</Tag>
		<English>Recurve Archer</English>
		<French>Archer à arc courbe</French>
		<German>Recurve Bogenschützen</German>
		<Italian>Arciere con Arco Ricurvo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Recurve Archer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RECURVE_ARCHER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A recurve bow is a form of bow defined by the side-view profile; in contrast to the simple longbow, a recurve bow has tips that curve away from the archer when the bow is unstrung. By one technical definition, the difference between recurve and other bows is that the string touches sections of the limbs of recurve bows when the bow is strung. A recurve bow stores more energy than an equivalent straight-limbed bow, giving a greater amount of cast to the arrow. A recurve will permit a shorter bow than the simple bow for a given arrow energy and this form was preferred by archers in environments where long weapons could be cumbersome, such as in brush and forest terrain, or while on horseback. By contrast, the traditional straight longbow tends to "stack" that is, the required draw force increases more rapidly per unit of draw length as the string is drawn back.</English>
		<French>Un arc courbe est une forme d'arc définie par son profil; contrairement à l'arc long classique, un arc courbe a les extrémités qui s'écartent de l'archer quand il n'est pas tendu. D'un point de vue technique, la différence entre l'arc courbe et les autres est que la corde s'appuie sur des portions complètes de l'arc courbe quand celui-ci est bandé. Un arc courbe stocke plus d'énergie que son équivalent droit, lui conférant une plus grande portée. Un arc courbe permet un arc plus court qu'un arc simple pour la même quantité d'énergie, et cette forme a été privilégiée dans les endroits où des armes longues peuvent être handicapantes, tels que les buissons ou les forêts, ou encore à cheval. Par ailleurs, l'arc droit classique nécessite plus de force pour tendre la corde qu'un arc courbe et sa corde "recourbée".</French>
		<German>A recurve bow is a form of bow defined by the side-view profile; in contrast to the simple longbow, a recurve bow has tips that curve away from the archer when the bow is unstrung. By one technical definition, the difference between recurve and other bows is that the string touches sections of the limbs of recurve bows when the bow is strung. A recurve bow stores more energy than an equivalent straight-limbed bow, giving a greater amount of cast to the arrow. A recurve will permit a shorter bow than the simple bow for a given arrow energy and this form was preferred by archers in environments where long weapons could be cumbersome, such as in brush and forest terrain, or while on horseback. By contrast, the traditional straight longbow tends to "stack" that is, the required draw force increases more rapidly per unit of draw length as the string is drawn back.</German>
		<Italian>L'arco ricurvo è un tipo di arco caratterizzato da un particolare profilo; diversamento dal normale arco lungo, un'arco ricurvo ha le estremita dei flettenti che si allontanano dall'arciere quando l'arco è senza corda. Usando la definizione tecnica, la differenza tra l'arco ricurvo e gli altri tipi di arco è che la corda tocca parte dei flettenti quando la corda è montata. Un'arco ricurvo immagazzina più energia rispetto a un arco dai flettenti dritti, permettendo di imprimere una maggiore forza alla freccia. Un'arco ricurvo può essere più corto di uno classico ma avere la stessa potenza e per questo è preferito dagli arcieri che combattono in ambienti dove le armi lunghe erano difficili da usare, come nei terreni boschivi, o in sella a un cavallo. Inoltre, il tradizionale arco lungo dritto richiede una forza maggiore per essere teso rispetto ad un'arco ricurvo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A recurve bow is a form of bow defined by the side-view profile; in contrast to the simple longbow, a recurve bow has tips that curve away from the archer when the bow is unstrung. By one technical definition, the difference between recurve and other bows is that the string touches sections of the limbs of recurve bows when the bow is strung. A recurve bow stores more energy than an equivalent straight-limbed bow, giving a greater amount of cast to the arrow. A recurve will permit a shorter bow than the simple bow for a given arrow energy and this form was preferred by archers in environments where long weapons could be cumbersome, such as in brush and forest terrain, or while on horseback. By contrast, the traditional straight longbow tends to "stack" that is, the required draw force increases more rapidly per unit of draw length as the string is drawn back.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RECURVE_ARCHER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>This longbow replacement is able to defend both in cities and in the wilds, thanks to the Woodsman Promotion. The shorter Recurve bow also allows them to loose arrows more quickly, giving them greater chance to strike first.</English>
		<French>Cette alternative à l'arche à arc long est capable à la fois de se défendre à la fois dans les villes et les contrées sauvages grâce à sa promotion Forestier. L'arc courbe plus court permet de décocher les flèches plus rapidement, leur donnant une meilleure chance de tirer les premiers.</French>
		<German>This longbow replacement is able to defend both in cities and in the wilds, thanks to the Woodsman Promotion. The shorter Recurve bow also allows them to loose arrows more quickly, giving them greater chance to strike first.</German>
		<Italian>Quest'unità sostitutiva dell'arciere con arco lungo è capace di difendersi adeguatamente sia in città che nelle terre selvagge, grazie alla promozione Taglialegna. L'arco ricurvo, essendo più piccolo, permette un lancio delle frecce più rapido, dandogli una maggiore probabilità di colpire per primi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>This longbow replacement is able to defend both in cities and in the wilds, thanks to the Woodsman Promotion. The shorter Recurve bow also allows them to loose arrows more quickly, giving them greater chance to strike first.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHOREPARTY</Tag>
		<English>Shore Party</English>
		<French>Marsouin</French>
		<German>Küstentrupp</German>
		<Italian>Gruppo d'Esplorazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shore Party</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHOREPARTY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Whilst most sailors stick to sailing, the Austrin can't resist investigating newly discovered lands. All their seamen are experienced in tracking and wilderness survival and so will explore at least a short distance into any island they encouter before putting back out to sea.</English>
		<French>Tandis que la majorité des marins se cantonnent à la navigation, les marins Austrin ne peuvent résister à l'exploration des terres fraîchement découvertes. Tous leurs marins sont entraînés au pistage et à la survie, et exploreront au moins les premiers mètres de chaque île découverte avant de retourner sur leurs navires.</French>
		<German>Whilst most sailors stick to sailing, the Austrin can't resist investigating newly discovered lands. All their seamen are experienced in tracking and wilderness survival and so will explore at least a short distance into any island they encouter before putting back out to sea.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre la maggior parte dei marinai si interessa solo a navigare, quelli Austrin non si lasciano scappare alcuna possibilità di esplorare le terre appena scoperte. Tutti i loro marinai sono esperti nel seguire le tracce e nel sopravvivere nella natura selvaggia e di conseguenza esplorano una piccola zona vicino alla costo di ogni isola che incontrano prima di tornare in mare.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Whilst most sailors stick to sailing, the Austrin can't resist investigating newly discovered lands. All their seamen are experienced in tracking and wilderness survival and so will explore at least a short distance into any island they encouter before putting back out to sea.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHOREPARTY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Shoreparties are summoned from Austrin ships and allow you to explore a landmass more thoroughly than is possible by simply sailing by. They cannot fight, but will move quickly over the terrain for a single turn before returning to their ship.</English>
		<French>Les Marsouins sont issus des navires Austrins et vous permettent d'explorer les côtes plus en profondeur qu'uniquement en les longeant. Ils ne peuvent pas se battre, mais se déplaceront rapidement sur terre pour un tour avec de réembarquer sur leurs navires.</French>
		<German>Shoreparties are summoned from Austrin ships and allow you to explore a landmass more thoroughly than is possible by simply sailing by. They cannot fight, but will move quickly over the terrain for a single turn before returning to their ship.</German>
		<Italian>I Gruppi d'Esplorazione sono creati dalle navi Austrin e permettono di esplorare un terreno più a fondo di quanto si possa fare soltanto circumnavigandolo. Non possono combattere, ma si muovono rapidamente sul terreno per un turno prima di tornare alla loro nave.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shoreparties are summoned from Austrin ships and allow you to explore a landmass more thoroughly than is possible by simply sailing by. They cannot fight, but will move quickly over the terrain for a single turn before returning to their ship.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRACKER</Tag>
		<English>Tracker</English>
		<French>Pisteur</French>
		<German>Fährtensucher</German>
		<Italian>Inseguitore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tracker</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRACKER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Whilst the Explorer travels in search of new discoveries and the unknown, the Tracker knows exactly what it is that he seeks. It might be an orc warband that has pillaged a nearby village or it may be the vanguard of a large enemy army. Whatever the quarry, the tracker will find it long before anyone else even suspects it is there.</English>
		<French>Tandis que l'Explorateur voyage à la recherche de l'inconnu et de nouvelles découvertes, le Pisteur sait exactement ce qu'il recherche. Ce peut être une bande de guerriers orcs qui a pillé un village proche ou l'avant-garde d'une grande armée ennemie. Quelque qoit l'objectif, le Pisteur le trouvera bien avant que qui que ce soit d'autre ne suspecte sa présence.</French>
		<German>Whilst the Explorer travels in search of new discoveries and the unknown, the Tracker knows exactly what it is that he seeks. It might be an orc warband that has pillaged a nearby village or it may be the vanguard of a large enemy army. Whatever the quarry, the tracker will find it long before anyone else even suspects it is there.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre l'Esploratore viaggia in cerca di cose da scoprire e dell'ignoto, l'Inseguitore sa esattamente cosa sta cercando. Potrebbe essere una banda di orchi che hanno saccheggiato un villaggio vicino o potrebbe essere l'avanguardia di un esercito nemico più grande. Qualunque sia la sua preda, l'Inseguitore la troverà ancora prima che chiuque possa sopettare che sia li.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Whilst the Explorer travels in search of new discoveries and the unknown, the Tracker knows exactly what it is that he seeks. It might be an orc warband that has pillaged a nearby village or it may be the vanguard of a large enemy army. Whatever the quarry, the tracker will find it long before anyone else even suspects it is there.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRACKER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>This unit replaces the Ranger but is available earlier and fulfills a different role. The Tracker has the Sentry and Woodsman promotions and can gain the second level of both to make it a solid wilderness explorer, able to spot income threats from a great distance and travel quickly through forests. It also has the Adventurer promotion, granting it a bonus when exploring monster lairs and dungeons.</English>
		<French>Cette unité remplace le Garde Forestier mais est disponible plus tôt et remplit divers rôles. Le Pisteur a les promotions Sentinelle et Forestier et peut prendre le niveau suivant de ces deux promotions pour en faire un solide explorateur de contrées sauvages, capable de repérer de très loin les menaces approchantes et se déplacer rapidement dans les forêts. Il possède également la promotion Aventurier, lui donnant des bonus à l'exploration des tanières de monstres et des donjons.</French>
		<German>This unit replaces the Ranger but is available earlier and fulfills a different role. The Tracker has the Sentry and Woodsman promotions and can gain the second level of both to make it a solid wilderness explorer, able to spot income threats from a great distance and travel quickly through forests. It also has the Adventurer promotion, granting it a bonus when exploring monster lairs and dungeons.</German>
		<Italian>Quest'unità sostitiusce il Ranger ed è disponibile prima ma svolge un ruolo diverso. L'Inseguitore ha le promozioni Sentinella e Taglialegna e può prendere il secondo livello di entrambe rendendolo un solido esploratore delle terre selvagge, capace di avvistare i pericoli da lontano e muoversi velocemente nelle foreste. Ha inoltre la promozione Avventuriero, che gli da un bonus quando esplora le tane dei mostri e i dungeon.</Italian>
		<Spanish>This unit replaces the Ranger but is available earlier and fulfills a different role. The Tracker has the Sentry and Woodsman promotions and can gain the second level of both to make it a solid wilderness explorer, able to spot income threats from a great distance and travel quickly through forests. It also has the Adventurer promotion, granting it a bonus when exploring monster lairs and dungeons.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WINDSWORD</Tag>
		<English>Windsword</English>
		<French>Lame des Vents</French>
		<German>Schwert des Windes</German>
		<Italian>Spada del Vento</Italian>
		<Spanish>Windsword</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WINDSWORD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Windswords are considered to be an old legend by many Erubusians - even amongst the Austrin. They did once exist however, schooled in advanced swordsplay and able to move as unpredicatably as the wind. Inspired by the nature of Tali, the Windswords could keep their foe utterly off guard and scythe through their ranks as the wind cuts through a field of corn. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rumours persist that there is still one person schooled in that ancient art - though Deirdra herself has searched since childhood for him with little success. With the combined resources of the Austrin empire however, perhaps she will have more success...</English>
		<French>Les Lames des Vents sont considérés comme une légende par de nombreu Erebusiens, même parmi les Austrins. Il est cependant avéré qu'ils ont existé, rompus à l'escrime avancée et capables de se déplacer de manière aussi imprévisible que le vent. S'inspirant de la nature de Tali, les Lames des Vents pouvaient tout à fait rester hors de portée de leurs ennemis et faucher leurs ranks comme le vent fauche les blés.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Les rumeurs prétendent qu'il existe toujours une personne rompue à cet art ancien, même si Deirdra elle-même la cherche vainement depuis son enfance. Mais avec les ressources combinées de l'empire Austrin, peut-être aura-t-elle plus de succès...</French>
		<German>The Windswords are considered to be an old legend by many Erubusians - even amongst the Austrin. They did once exist however, schooled in advanced swordsplay and able to move as unpredicatably as the wind. Inspired by the nature of Tali, the Windswords could keep their foe utterly off guard and scythe through their ranks as the wind cuts through a field of corn. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rumours persist that there is still one person schooled in that ancient art - though Deirdra herself has searched since childhood for him with little success. With the combined resources of the Austrin empire however, perhaps she will have more success...</German>
		<Italian>Le Spade del Vento sono considerate da molti Erebusiani una vecchia leggenda - persino tra gli Austrin. Una volta esistevano però, ed erano esperti di uno stile di scherma avanzato e capaci di muoversi in maniera imprevedibile come il vento. Ispirate dalla natura di Tali, le Spade del Vento riuscivano a sorprendere sempre i loro avversari e attraversare i loro ranghi come il vento che passa attraverso le spighe di grano. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Comunque, secondo le dicerie c'è ancora una persona istruita in questa antica arte - sebbene Deirdra stessa l'abbia cercata fin da quando era piccola con scarsi risultati. Forse con le risorse combinate dell'impero Austrin potrebbe avere più successo...</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Windswords are considered to be an old legend by many Erubusians - even amongst the Austrin. They did once exist however, schooled in advanced swordsplay and able to move as unpredicatably as the wind. Inspired by the nature of Tali, the Windswords could keep their foe utterly off guard and scythe through their ranks as the wind cuts through a field of corn. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rumours persist that there is still one person schooled in that ancient art - though Deirdra herself has searched since childhood for him with little success. With the combined resources of the Austrin empire however, perhaps she will have more success...</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WINDSWORD_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Windswords are a national unit and replace the Phalanx of other civilizations. The unit is most notable for its special ability - "Bladewind" - which forces all foes to retreat away from the Windswords flashing blade, taking a small amount of damage in the process. Windswords excel against melee and ranged troops alike - with a 25% bonus against melee and an immunity to first strikes helping the to close with ranged troops.</English>
		<French>La Lame des Vents est une unité nationale qui remplace la Phalange. La particularité de cette unité est sa capacité spéciale, la "Lame du Vent", qui force tous les ennemis à fuir l'epée étincelante de la Lame des Vents, prenant au passage quelques dégâts. Les Lames des Vents sont aussi mortels contre les unités de mélée que les unités à distance, grâce à un bonus de 25% contre les unités de mélée et une immunité aux premières attaques aidant à atteindre les unités à distance.</French>
		<German>The Windswords are a national unit and replace the Phalanx of other civilizations. The unit is most notable for its special ability - "Bladewind" - which forces all foes to retreat away from the Windswords flashing blade, taking a small amount of damage in the process. Windswords excel against melee and ranged troops alike - with a 25% bonus against melee and an immunity to first strikes helping the to close with ranged troops.</German>
		<Italian>Le Spade del Vento sono un'unità nazionale e sostituiscono la Falange delle altre civiltà. Quest'unità è resa particolare dalla loro abilità unica, la "Lama del Vento", che costringe tutti gli avversari ad allontanarsi dalla Spada del Vento, subendo un lieve danno nel frattempo. Le Spade del Vento sono ottime sia contro le unita da combattimento ravvicinato che contro quelle dalla distanza - avendo un bonus del 25% contro quelle da combattimento ravvicinato e l'immunità ai agli attacchi improvvisi che le aiuta ad avvicinarsi a quelle a distanza.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Windswords are a national unit and replace the Phalanx of other civilizations. The unit is most notable for its special ability - "Bladewind" - which forces all foes to retreat away from the Windswords flashing blade, taking a small amount of damage in the process. Windswords excel against melee and ranged troops alike - with a 25% bonus against melee and an immunity to first strikes helping the to close with ranged troops.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
