<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CUALLI_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Cualli</English>
		<French>cualli:cuallie:cuallis:cuallies</French>
		<German>Cuallisch:Cuallischen:Cuallische</German>
		<Italian>Cualli</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cualli</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CUALLI_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Cualli</English>
		<French>Cualli</French>
		<German>Reich der Cualli</German>
		<Italian>Cualli</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cualli</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CUALLI_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Cualli</English>
		<French>Cuallis</French>
		<German>Cualli</German>
		<Italian>Cualli</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cualli</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CUALLI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>When the Lizardman civilization of the Age of Magic fled from Mulcarn's destructive entry to creation, many found refuge in a cave complex near the heart of a volcano. These refugees would later become the Mazatl. There were other survivors however that did not survive through such fortune. In desperation, some of the Lizardmen made pacts with the darker forces of their pantheon, most notably the dark god Agruonn - lord of self and strength. The pact made with Agruonn allowed a group of lizardmen to hibernate in a specially protected chamber beneath the earth, only to awaken when the warmth returned to the land. In exchange, the descendants of these survivors would serve Agruonn's needs.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The "god" that the lizardmen knew as Agruonn is in fact the fallen angel Aeron. The lizardmen he saved from Mulcarn - now known as the Cualli - are bound to his service, with the strongest and most ruthless of their kind being his most favoured servants. Once known as an angel of strength, Aeron's nature now is bloodthirsty and selfish and this is reflected in the nature of the Cualli.</English>
		<French>Quand la civilisation des Hommes-Lézards de l'Âge de la Magie fuirent l'apparition destructrice de Mulcarn, beaucoup trouvèrent refuge dans un complexe de grottes près du c&#156;ur d'un volcan. Ces réfugiés devaient devenir plus tard les Mazatl. Il y eut cependant d'autres survivants qui n'eurent pas tant de chance. Dans leur désespoir, certains hommes-lézards firent un pacte avec les forces les plus sombres de leur panthéon, en particulier le dieu noir Agruonn, seigneur du soi et de la force. Le pacte passé avec Agruonn permit à un groupe d'hommes-lézards d'hiberner dans une chambre souterraine bien protégée, pour ne se réveiller que quand la chaleur serait revenue sur terre. En échange, les descendants de ces survivants devait servir les desseins d'Agruonn.[PARAGRAPH:2]Le "dieu" connu des hommes-lézards comme Agruonn est en réalité l'ange déchu Aéron. Les hommes-lézards qu'il a sauvés de Mulcarn, maintenant connus sous le nom de Cualli, sont à son service, les plus forts et les plus impitoyables d'entre eux étant ses favoris. Autrefois connu comme l'ange de la force, la nature d'Aéron est maintenant égoïste et sanglante, et se reflète dans la nature des Cualli.</French>
		<German>When the Lizardman civilization of the Age of Magic fled from Mulcarn's destructive entry to creation, many found refuge in a cave complex near the heart of a volcano. These refugees would later become the Mazatl. There were other survivors however that did not survive through such fortune. In desperation, some of the Lizardmen made pacts with the darker forces of their pantheon, most notably the dark god Agruonn - lord of self and strength. The pact made with Agruonn allowed a group of lizardmen to hibernate in a specially protected chamber beneath the earth, only to awaken when the warmth returned to the land. In exchange, the descendants of these survivors would serve Agruonn's needs.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The "god" that the lizardmen knew as Agruonn is in fact the fallen angel Aeron. The lizardmen he saved from Mulcarn - now known as the Cualli - are bound to his service, with the strongest and most ruthless of their kind being his most favoured servants. Once known as an angel of strength, Aeron's nature now is bloodthirsty and selfish and this is reflected in the nature of the Cualli.</German>
		<Italian>Quando la civiltà lucertoloide dell'Era della Magia fuggì dalla devastante entrata di Mulcarn nella creazione in molti trovarono rifugio in un complesso di grotte vicine al cuore di un vulcano. Questi profughi diventeranno in seguito i Mazatl. Ci furono però altri sopravvissuti, ma non furono fortunati come gli altri. In preda alla disperazione alcuni lucertoloidi strinsero dei patti con le forze più oscure del loro pantheon, in particolar modo con l'oscuro dio Agruonn - signore dell'ego e della forza. Il patto stretto con Agruonn permise a un gruppo di lucertoloidi di andare in ibernazione in una camera protetta sotto terra, per poi risvegliarsi solo quando il calore sarebbe tornato sulla terra. In cambio, i discendenti di questi sopravvissuti avrebbero servito Agruonn.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Il "dio" che i lucertoloidi conoscevano come Agruonn è in realtà l'angelo caduto Aeron. I lucertoloidi che salvò da Mulcarn - ora conosciuti come Cualli - sono vincolati al suo servizio, i più forti e spietati tra di loro sono i suoi servitori preferiti. Un tempo conosciuto come l'angelo della forza, la natura di Aeron è ora sanguinaria e egoista e questo si riflette sulla natura dei Cualli.</Italian>
		<Spanish>When the Lizardman civilization of the Age of Magic fled from Mulcarn's destructive entry to creation, many found refuge in a cave complex near the heart of a volcano. These refugees would later become the Mazatl. There were other survivors however that did not survive through such fortune. In desperation, some of the Lizardmen made pacts with the darker forces of their pantheon, most notably the dark god Agruonn - lord of self and strength. The pact made with Agruonn allowed a group of lizardmen to hibernate in a specially protected chamber beneath the earth, only to awaken when the warmth returned to the land. In exchange, the descendants of these survivors would serve Agruonn's needs.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The "god" that the lizardmen knew as Agruonn is in fact the fallen angel Aeron. The lizardmen he saved from Mulcarn - now known as the Cualli - are bound to his service, with the strongest and most ruthless of their kind being his most favoured servants. Once known as an angel of strength, Aeron's nature now is bloodthirsty and selfish and this is reflected in the nature of the Cualli.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CUAI_IXL</Tag>
		<English>Cuai-Ixl</English>
		<French>Cuai-Ixl</French>
		<German>Cuai-Ixl</German>
		<Italian>Cuai-Ixl</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cuai-Ixl</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CUAI_IXL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Cuai-Ixl grinned at himself - what a fool Kolshevan had been.  A powerful assassin, yes, but also quite the fool to think that his blade, even that the blades of his fellows, would protect him from the priests of Agruonn forever.  And now, things were moving back to thier rightful place - a powerful priest, Cuai Ixl, as High Ruler, and the fool Kolshevan's head on a pike.</English>
		<French>Cuai-Ixl grinned at himself - what a fool Kolshevan had been.  A powerful assassin, yes, but also quite the fool to think that his blade, even that the blades of his fellows, would protect him from the priests of Agruonn forever.  And now, things were moving back to thier rightful place - a powerful priest, Cuai Ixl, as High Ruler, and the fool Kolshevan's head on a pike.</French>
		<German>Cuai-Ixl grinned at himself - what a fool Kolshevan had been.  A powerful assassin, yes, but also quite the fool to think that his blade, even that the blades of his fellows, would protect him from the priests of Agruonn forever.  And now, things were moving back to thier rightful place - a powerful priest, Cuai Ixl, as High Ruler, and the fool Kolshevan's head on a pike.</German>
		<Italian>Cuai-Ixl sorrise - che stupido che è stato Kolshevan.  Un potente assassino, vero, ma anche abbastanza stupido da pensare che la sua lama, persino le lame dei suoi compagni, l'avrebbero protetto dai sacerdoti di Agruonn per sempre.  Ora le cose stavano tornando al loro giusto posto - un potente sacerdote, Cuai Ixl, come Sommo Sovrano, e la testa dello stupido Kolshevan su una picca.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cuai-Ixl grinned at himself - what a fool Kolshevan had been.  A powerful assassin, yes, but also quite the fool to think that his blade, even that the blades of his fellows, would protect him from the priests of Agruonn forever.  And now, things were moving back to thier rightful place - a powerful priest, Cuai Ixl, as High Ruler, and the fool Kolshevan's head on a pike.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_KOLSEHVAHN</Tag>
		<English>Kolsehvahn</English>
		<French>Kolsehvahn</French>
		<German>Kolsehvahn</German>
		<Italian>Kolsehvahn</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kolsehvahn</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CUALLI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Kolsehvahn is an oddity in the power structure of the Cualli. Every high-ruler before him and all those who surround him have wielded significant magical power, granted by Agruonn. Kolsehvahn does not. He is no doubt a dedicated follower of Agruonn and has led the Cualli in many rituals of mass sacrifice, but he does not favour the use of magic. At one time, early in his rule, this was seen as a sign of weakness and several of the Priests challenged him for leadership. Or rather, they would have if they had not disappeared. Only one of these priests was ever located, lying dead at the foot of a temple with his killer lying dead a short distance away - a black robed lizard carrying a long, sacrificial knife bearing the symbol of Kolsehvahn's line. It is said that Kolsehvahn himself killed the assassin so that his involvement would be obvious - a display of arrogant power.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The fact remains however that Kolsehvahn has wielded power in the Cualli empire for longer than any High-Ruler before him, his safety and his position ensured by an elite cadre of assassins over which he has complete dominion - for now.</English>
		<French>Kolsehvahn est une bizarrerie dans la structure de puissance des Cuallis. Chaque haut-dirigeant avant lui et tous ceux qui l'entourent ont possédé un fort pouvoir magique, donné par Agruonn. Il est sans aucun doute un fidèle d'Agruonn et a guidé les Cuallis dans de nombreux rituels de sacrifices de masse, mais il ne privilégie pas l'utilisation de la magie. Une fois, au début de son règne, c'était vu comme un signe de faiblesse et quelques prêtres l'ont défié pour prendre sa place. Ou plutôt, ils l'auraient fait s'ils n'avaient pas disparus. Seul un de ces prêtres fut un jour localisé, gisant mort au pied d'un temple de même que son meurtrier gisant mort à quelques pas de là : un homme-lézard en robe noire portant une longue lame sacrificielle frappée du symbole de la ligne de Kolsehvhan. Il se dit que Kolsehvahn aurait lui-même tué l'assassin pour que son implication soit claire, telle une démonstration arrogante de pouvoir.[PARAGRAPH:2]Le fait est cependant que Kolsehvahn détient le pouvoir dans l'empire Cualli depuis plus longtemps que n'importe quel haut-dirigeant avant lui, sa sécurité et sa situation protégées par un groupe d'assassins d'élite qui lui sont totalement dévoués, jusque là.</French>
		<German>Kolsehvahn is an oddity in the power structure of the Cualli. Every high-ruler before him and all those who surround him have wielded significant magical power, granted by Agruonn. Kolsehvahn does not. He is no doubt a dedicated follower of Agruonn and has led the Cualli in many rituals of mass sacrifice, but he does not favour the use of magic. At one time, early in his rule, this was seen as a sign of weakness and several of the Priests challenged him for leadership. Or rather, they would have if they had not disappeared. Only one of these priests was ever located, lying dead at the foot of a temple with his killer lying dead a short distance away - a black robed lizard carrying a long, sacrificial knife bearing the symbol of Kolsehvahn's line. It is said that Kolsehvahn himself killed the assassin so that his involvement would be obvious - a display of arrogant power.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The fact remains however that Kolsehvahn has wielded power in the Cualli empire for longer than any High-Ruler before him, his safety and his position ensured by an elite cadre of assassins over which he has complete dominion - for now.</German>
		<Italian>Kolsehvahn è una stranezza nella struttura del potere dei Cualli. Tutti i Sommi Sovrani prima di lui e tutti quelli vicini a loro possedevano un considerevole potere magico, fornitogli da Agruonn. Kolsehvahn non lo possedeva. È senza dubbio un devoto seguace di Agruonn e ha guidato i Cualli in molti sacrifici di massa rituali, ma non apprezza l'uso della magia. Un tempo, all'inizio del suo dominio, questo suo modo di fare veniva visto come un segno di debolezza e diversi sacerdoti lo sfidarono per il dominio. O piuttosto, lo avrebbero fatto se non fossero scomparsi. Solo uno di questi sacerdoti fu ritrovato, morto ai piedi di un tempio con il cadavere del suo assassino la vicino, un lucertoloide con una lunga veste nera che portava un lungo coltello sacrificale che aveva il simbolo della famiglia di Kolsehvahn. Si dice che Kolsehvahn stesso uccise l'assassino cosi che il suo coinvolgimento fosse ovvio, un'arrogante dimostrazione di potere.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]La realtà rimane però che, Kolsehvahn, ha mantenuto il potere nell'impero Cualli più a lungo di qualsiasi Sommo Sovrano prima di lui, la sua incolumità e la sua posizione assicurata da un gruppo di assassini d'elite su cui ha completo potere... Per ora.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kolsehvahn is an oddity in the power structure of the Cualli. Every high-ruler before him and all those who surround him have wielded significant magical power, granted by Agruonn. Kolsehvahn does not. He is no doubt a dedicated follower of Agruonn and has led the Cualli in many rituals of mass sacrifice, but he does not favour the use of magic. At one time, early in his rule, this was seen as a sign of weakness and several of the Priests challenged him for leadership. Or rather, they would have if they had not disappeared. Only one of these priests was ever located, lying dead at the foot of a temple with his killer lying dead a short distance away - a black robed lizard carrying a long, sacrificial knife bearing the symbol of Kolsehvahn's line. It is said that Kolsehvahn himself killed the assassin so that his involvement would be obvious - a display of arrogant power.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The fact remains however that Kolsehvahn has wielded power in the Cualli empire for longer than any High-Ruler before him, his safety and his position ensured by an elite cadre of assassins over which he has complete dominion - for now.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MIHUATL</Tag>
		<English>Mihuatl</English>
		<French>Mihuatl</French>
		<German>Mihuatl</German>
		<Italian>Mihuatl</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mihuatl</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MIHUATL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The battle was won. The lesser race of humanity was routed once again. Mihuatl smiled as he looked upon the dead, Cualli and man alike, strewn among the jungle floor. He loved the distinctive dampness the blood had upon the scales of his feet. He walked slowly across the clearing, in triumph, ignoring the echoes of already won battles as his warriors rounded up the survivors that had not retreated with the routed army.[PARAGRAPH:1]They were to be slaves for the holy ones. Their once proud crowns would be soiled with the stain of subjugation. Mihuatl toyed with the thought of the amusement and diversion that would be had now that the invaders had been defeated.[PARAGRAPH:1]A scream trilled in the air and subsequently a muffled thwack of a club upon a skull, for indeed it was a skull, he thought, for Mihuatl had learned well to decipher such sounds.He relished the feeling of ecstasy he felt when he heard it, and knew that feeling would stay with him throughout the night. Victory was his, was it not?[PARAGRAPH:1]He had proved that his warriors, warriors who were elite among the Cualli, were stronger than the best of these men, who seemed surprised when they were joined in battle. Mihuatl paused for a moment. Who were these men, these humans? It was rare that they should be encountered this deep within the jungles and marshes. They usually were minor scouts, allies of the Mazatl, that sought to explore the Cualli's borderlands. These were easily subjugated by an assassin or hunter from behind, but these men were diferent. More organized, better equipped, and there were far more of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mihuatl's second in command approached, clearing him of his thoughts.[NEWLINE]"Mihuatl! Victory has been achieved in the name of Agruonn!" the officer spoke.[NEWLINE]Mihuatl felt enraged at the name of his god. It was his victory, no one elses. But he knew better than to say such.[NEWLINE]"You shall not speak unless spoken to, lesssser." His hiss spit all of his venom at the officer though none at its true target.[NEWLINE]"I am the chosen of Kolsevahn! He chose me to Master over the lot of you!"[NEWLINE]"Yes, master!"[NEWLINE]His officer was new, one that has been with his army for only this skirmish and was yet to be broken.[NEWLINE]"Do not speak!" In a single motion, his club came undone from his belt and crashed into his officer's face. The skill and precision that Mihuatl put into this coup was something to be marveled at. Unfortunately for the officer, his situation seemed more dire as he fell to the ground, stunned.[NEWLINE]This behavior was unique to Mihuatl, for no other Cualli commanders had the audacity within him to do such things. Mihuatl put a foot at the neck of the officer, who withed on the ground pitifully in pain, and began to choke him.[NEWLINE]"You are nothing to me! I have cleanly defeated you with one swipe of my club! You are nothing! You only exist to serve me. You are my lesser, you should feel honored that I, Mihuatl, greatest commander of all of the Cualli, should have taken you upon his great conquest!" His foot talons began to tear their way into the scales on his officers neck. "Who is your master, whelp?"[PARAGRAPH:1]By now, the commotion had been noticed by warrior and slave alike. The slaves only knew Mihuatl as he was now, but the warriors had seen and felt such pain many times in their career. It was always the second in command that had the worst, sometimes such wounds were lethal and he died, only to be replaced by another. Even if they did fight back, though, Mihuatl was [ITALICS]protected[\ITALICS] by Kolsevahn. If one of them ever raised a weapon to him, he would be found dead, a dagger marked with Kolsevahn's emblem in his corpse.[NEWLINE]Mihuatl's face and posture showed him to be in a mix of rage and pleasure. He leans down and his tongue slivers a whisper to his officers in a seductive and teasing manor.[NEWLINE]"Who is your master, whelp?"[NEWLINE]Mihuatl rose, letting some of the weight from his foot off his officer's neck as he awaited his answer.[NEWLINE]"Y...you...," his officer sputtered, gasping for breath as he attempted to answer his commanding officer.[NEWLINE]However, it was only to be cut short as Mihuatl's temper worsened from the officer's stutter. With one brutal thrust of his foot, he cracked the neck. With this, though, he was still not satisfied. Mihuatl removed his foot and lifted up the body letting all spectators see.[NEWLINE]"Look well at this weakling! He was nothing and this is what remains of him! Now, we move! Kill the slaves that have not been tied and take those ready to the temples. Do not fall behind! Or you will be hunted like the weaklings you are!"[PARAGRAPH:2]This was his victory, no one else. He began the march back to Yayauhqui on his own, his men prepared or not. The city would only open to him, the Victor. He still carried the corpse of his second in command. It was his to do what he wished, and he knew that it belonged in his chambers, where the rest of his past commanders were seated, ready to listen to Mihuatl's achievements, recounted by his truly. For in death, at least they truly listened without interruptions.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The battle was won. The lesser race of humanity was routed once again. Mihuatl smiled as he looked upon the dead, Cualli and man alike, strewn among the jungle floor. He loved the distinctive dampness the blood had upon the scales of his feet. He walked slowly across the clearing, in triumph, ignoring the echoes of already won battles as his warriors rounded up the survivors that had not retreated with the routed army.[PARAGRAPH:1]They were to be slaves for the holy ones. Their once proud crowns would be soiled with the stain of subjugation. Mihuatl toyed with the thought of the amusement and diversion that would be had now that the invaders had been defeated.[PARAGRAPH:1]A scream trilled in the air and subsequently a muffled thwack of a club upon a skull, for indeed it was a skull, he thought, for Mihuatl had learned well to decipher such sounds.He relished the feeling of ecstasy he felt when he heard it, and knew that feeling would stay with him throughout the night. Victory was his, was it not?[PARAGRAPH:1]He had proved that his warriors, warriors who were elite among the Cualli, were stronger than the best of these men, who seemed surprised when they were joined in battle. Mihuatl paused for a moment. Who were these men, these humans? It was rare that they should be encountered this deep within the jungles and marshes. They usually were minor scouts, allies of the Mazatl, that sought to explore the Cualli's borderlands. These were easily subjugated by an assassin or hunter from behind, but these men were diferent. More organized, better equipped, and there were far more of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mihuatl's second in command approached, clearing him of his thoughts.[NEWLINE]"Mihuatl! Victory has been achieved in the name of Agruonn!" the officer spoke.[NEWLINE]Mihuatl felt enraged at the name of his god. It was his victory, no one elses. But he knew better than to say such.[NEWLINE]"You shall not speak unless spoken to, lesssser." His hiss spit all of his venom at the officer though none at its true target.[NEWLINE]"I am the chosen of Kolsevahn! He chose me to Master over the lot of you!"[NEWLINE]"Yes, master!"[NEWLINE]His officer was new, one that has been with his army for only this skirmish and was yet to be broken.[NEWLINE]"Do not speak!" In a single motion, his club came undone from his belt and crashed into his officer's face. The skill and precision that Mihuatl put into this coup was something to be marveled at. Unfortunately for the officer, his situation seemed more dire as he fell to the ground, stunned.[NEWLINE]This behavior was unique to Mihuatl, for no other Cualli commanders had the audacity within him to do such things. Mihuatl put a foot at the neck of the officer, who withed on the ground pitifully in pain, and began to choke him.[NEWLINE]"You are nothing to me! I have cleanly defeated you with one swipe of my club! You are nothing! You only exist to serve me. You are my lesser, you should feel honored that I, Mihuatl, greatest commander of all of the Cualli, should have taken you upon his great conquest!" His foot talons began to tear their way into the scales on his officers neck. "Who is your master, whelp?"[PARAGRAPH:1]By now, the commotion had been noticed by warrior and slave alike. The slaves only knew Mihuatl as he was now, but the warriors had seen and felt such pain many times in their career. It was always the second in command that had the worst, sometimes such wounds were lethal and he died, only to be replaced by another. Even if they did fight back, though, Mihuatl was [ITALICS]protected[\ITALICS] by Kolsevahn. If one of them ever raised a weapon to him, he would be found dead, a dagger marked with Kolsevahn's emblem in his corpse.[NEWLINE]Mihuatl's face and posture showed him to be in a mix of rage and pleasure. He leans down and his tongue slivers a whisper to his officers in a seductive and teasing manor.[NEWLINE]"Who is your master, whelp?"[NEWLINE]Mihuatl rose, letting some of the weight from his foot off his officer's neck as he awaited his answer.[NEWLINE]"Y...you...," his officer sputtered, gasping for breath as he attempted to answer his commanding officer.[NEWLINE]However, it was only to be cut short as Mihuatl's temper worsened from the officer's stutter. With one brutal thrust of his foot, he cracked the neck. With this, though, he was still not satisfied. Mihuatl removed his foot and lifted up the body letting all spectators see.[NEWLINE]"Look well at this weakling! He was nothing and this is what remains of him! Now, we move! Kill the slaves that have not been tied and take those ready to the temples. Do not fall behind! Or you will be hunted like the weaklings you are!"[PARAGRAPH:2]This was his victory, no one else. He began the march back to Yayauhqui on his own, his men prepared or not. The city would only open to him, the Victor. He still carried the corpse of his second in command. It was his to do what he wished, and he knew that it belonged in his chambers, where the rest of his past commanders were seated, ready to listen to Mihuatl's achievements, recounted by his truly. For in death, at least they truly listened without interruptions.</French>
		<German>[TAB]The battle was won. The lesser race of humanity was routed once again. Mihuatl smiled as he looked upon the dead, Cualli and man alike, strewn among the jungle floor. He loved the distinctive dampness the blood had upon the scales of his feet. He walked slowly across the clearing, in triumph, ignoring the echoes of already won battles as his warriors rounded up the survivors that had not retreated with the routed army.[PARAGRAPH:1]They were to be slaves for the holy ones. Their once proud crowns would be soiled with the stain of subjugation. Mihuatl toyed with the thought of the amusement and diversion that would be had now that the invaders had been defeated.[PARAGRAPH:1]A scream trilled in the air and subsequently a muffled thwack of a club upon a skull, for indeed it was a skull, he thought, for Mihuatl had learned well to decipher such sounds.He relished the feeling of ecstasy he felt when he heard it, and knew that feeling would stay with him throughout the night. Victory was his, was it not?[PARAGRAPH:1]He had proved that his warriors, warriors who were elite among the Cualli, were stronger than the best of these men, who seemed surprised when they were joined in battle. Mihuatl paused for a moment. Who were these men, these humans? It was rare that they should be encountered this deep within the jungles and marshes. They usually were minor scouts, allies of the Mazatl, that sought to explore the Cualli's borderlands. These were easily subjugated by an assassin or hunter from behind, but these men were diferent. More organized, better equipped, and there were far more of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mihuatl's second in command approached, clearing him of his thoughts.[NEWLINE]"Mihuatl! Victory has been achieved in the name of Agruonn!" the officer spoke.[NEWLINE]Mihuatl felt enraged at the name of his god. It was his victory, no one elses. But he knew better than to say such.[NEWLINE]"You shall not speak unless spoken to, lesssser." His hiss spit all of his venom at the officer though none at its true target.[NEWLINE]"I am the chosen of Kolsevahn! He chose me to Master over the lot of you!"[NEWLINE]"Yes, master!"[NEWLINE]His officer was new, one that has been with his army for only this skirmish and was yet to be broken.[NEWLINE]"Do not speak!" In a single motion, his club came undone from his belt and crashed into his officer's face. The skill and precision that Mihuatl put into this coup was something to be marveled at. Unfortunately for the officer, his situation seemed more dire as he fell to the ground, stunned.[NEWLINE]This behavior was unique to Mihuatl, for no other Cualli commanders had the audacity within him to do such things. Mihuatl put a foot at the neck of the officer, who withed on the ground pitifully in pain, and began to choke him.[NEWLINE]"You are nothing to me! I have cleanly defeated you with one swipe of my club! You are nothing! You only exist to serve me. You are my lesser, you should feel honored that I, Mihuatl, greatest commander of all of the Cualli, should have taken you upon his great conquest!" His foot talons began to tear their way into the scales on his officers neck. "Who is your master, whelp?"[PARAGRAPH:1]By now, the commotion had been noticed by warrior and slave alike. The slaves only knew Mihuatl as he was now, but the warriors had seen and felt such pain many times in their career. It was always the second in command that had the worst, sometimes such wounds were lethal and he died, only to be replaced by another. Even if they did fight back, though, Mihuatl was [ITALICS]protected[\ITALICS] by Kolsevahn. If one of them ever raised a weapon to him, he would be found dead, a dagger marked with Kolsevahn's emblem in his corpse.[NEWLINE]Mihuatl's face and posture showed him to be in a mix of rage and pleasure. He leans down and his tongue slivers a whisper to his officers in a seductive and teasing manor.[NEWLINE]"Who is your master, whelp?"[NEWLINE]Mihuatl rose, letting some of the weight from his foot off his officer's neck as he awaited his answer.[NEWLINE]"Y...you...," his officer sputtered, gasping for breath as he attempted to answer his commanding officer.[NEWLINE]However, it was only to be cut short as Mihuatl's temper worsened from the officer's stutter. With one brutal thrust of his foot, he cracked the neck. With this, though, he was still not satisfied. Mihuatl removed his foot and lifted up the body letting all spectators see.[NEWLINE]"Look well at this weakling! He was nothing and this is what remains of him! Now, we move! Kill the slaves that have not been tied and take those ready to the temples. Do not fall behind! Or you will be hunted like the weaklings you are!"[PARAGRAPH:2]This was his victory, no one else. He began the march back to Yayauhqui on his own, his men prepared or not. The city would only open to him, the Victor. He still carried the corpse of his second in command. It was his to do what he wished, and he knew that it belonged in his chambers, where the rest of his past commanders were seated, ready to listen to Mihuatl's achievements, recounted by his truly. For in death, at least they truly listened without interruptions.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La battaglia era vinta. La razza inferiore dell'umanità era in rotta ancora una volta. Mihuatl sorrise mentre guardava i morti, sia Cualli che umani, disseminati per la giungla. Amava la particolare umidità del sangue sulle scaglie dei suoi piedi. Camminò lentamente nella radura, in trionfo, ignorando gli echi di battaglie già vinte mentre i suoi guerrieri radunavano i sopravvissuti che non si erano ritirati con l'esercito in rotta.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sarebbero diventati schiavi per i santificati. Le loro corone un tempo splendide sarebbero state macchiate con l'onta della sottomissione. Mihuatl giocherellò con il pensiero del divertimento e dei passatempo che avrebbe avuto ora che gli invasori erano stati sconfitti.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un urlo scosse l'aria per poi essere seguito da un suono smorzato di una clava su un teschio, perché in effetti era un teschio, pensò, visto che Mihuatl aveva imparato a riconoscere tale suono.Assaporò il sentimento di estasi che percepì quando sentì quel suono, sapeva che quel sentimento gli sarebbe rimasto per tutta la notte. La vittoria era sua, no?[PARAGRAPH:1]Aveva dimostrato che i suoi guerrieri, che erano un elite tra i Cualli, erano più forti delle bestie di questi uomini, che sembravano sorpresi quando iniziò la battaglia. Mihuatl si fermò per un momento. Chi erano questi uomini, questi umani? Era raro incontrarli cosi all'interno della giungla e degli acquitrini. Di solito erano esploratori minori, alleati dei Mazatl, che volevano esplorare i confini dei Cualli. Venivano facilmente sottomessi da un assassino o cacciatore da dietro, ma questi uomini erano diversi. Più organizzati, meglio equipaggiati, ed erano in tanti.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il secondo in comnado di Mihuatl si avvicinò, liberandolo dai suoi pensieri.[NEWLINE]"Mihuatl! La vittoria è stata ottenuta nel nome di Agruonn!" disse l'ufficiale.[NEWLINE]Mihuatl si arrabbiò sentendo il nome del suo dio. Era la sua vittoria, non di qualcun'altro. Ma sapeva che era meglio non dirlo.[NEWLINE]"Non devi parlare se non ti viene detto di farlo, sottoposssto." Il suo sibilo pieno di veleno diretto all'ufficiale ma non al suo vero bersaglio.[NEWLINE]"Io sono l'eletto di Kolsevahn! Mi ha scelto per comandarvi!"[NEWLINE]"Si, signore!"[NEWLINE]Il suo ufficiale era nuovo, uno che era stato con il suo esercito solo per questa schermaglia e doveva ancora essere distrutto.[NEWLINE]"Non parlare!" In una singola mossa la sua clava fu liberata dalla cinta e si schiantò sulla faccia dell'ufficiale. L'abilità e la precisione che Mihuatl mise in questo colpo era una cosa da rimanere meravigliati. Sfortunatamente per l'ufficiale, la sua situazione sembrò più terribile mentre cadeva a terra stordito.[NEWLINE]Questo comportamento era unico di Mihuatl, perché nessun altro comandante Cualli aveva l'audacia di fare una cosa simile. Mihuatl mise un piede sul collo dell'ufficiale, che giaceva a terra pietosamente dolorate, e iniziò a strozzarlo.[NEWLINE]"Tu sei niente per me! Ti ho sconfitto tranquillamente con un colpo della mi clava! Tu sei niente! Tu esisti solo per servirmi. Tu sei un mio sottoposto, dovresti sentirti onorato che io, Mihuatl, il più grande comandante di tutti i Cualli, ti porto con me nelle mie grandi conquiste!" Gli artigli del suo piede iniziarono a farsi strada tra le scaglie del collo dell'ufficiale. "Chi è il tuo padrone, moccioso?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Ormai il trambusto era stato notato sia dai guerrieri che dagli schiavi. Gli schiavi conobbero Mihuatl solamente come era adesso, ma i guerrieri avevano visto e sentito tale dolore molte volte nelle loro carriere. Era sempre il secondo in comando che subiva maggiormente, a volte le ferite erano letali e moriva, solo per essere rimpiazzata da un'altro. Anche se si difendevano Mihuatl era [ITALICS]protetto[\ITALICS] da Kolsevahn. Se uno di loro lo aggrediva sarebbe stato trovato morto, con un pugnale con il simbolo di Kolsevahn conficcato nel corpo.[NEWLINE]La faccia di Mihuatl indicava che lui era un mix di arrabbiato e divertito. Si chinò in basso e sussurrò al suo ufficiale in una maniera attraente.[NEWLINE]"Chi è il tuo padrone, moccioso?"[NEWLINE]Mihuatl si alzò, spostando un pò il peso dal suo piede sul collo dell'ufficiale mentre attendeva una sua risposta.[NEWLINE]"T...tu...," l'ufficiale farfugliò, mentre cercava di respirare mentre rispondeva al suo comandante.[NEWLINE]Comunque, venne interrotto presto quando il temperamento di Mihuatl peggiorò visto il balbettare dell'ufficiale. Con un brutale colpo del piede gli spezzò il collo. Nonostante ciò non era ancora soddisfatto però. Mihuatl tolse il piede e sollevò il corpo permettendo a tutti gli spettatori di vederlo.[NEWLINE]"Guardate bene a questo smidollato! Lui era niente è questo è ciò che rimane di lui! Ora muoviamoci! Uccidete gli schiavi che non sono stati legati e portate quelli pronti al templi. Non rimanete indietro! O sarete cacciati come i deboli che siete!"[PARAGRAPH:2]Questa era la sua vittoria e di nessun'altro. Iniziò la marcia di ritorno a Yayauhqui da solo, i suoi uomini pronti o no. La città si sarebbe aperta solo per lui, il Vincitore. Portava ancora con se il cadavere del suo secondo in comando. Poteva farci quello che voleva, e sapeva che sarebbe andato nelle sue camere, dove gli altri passati suoi comandanti erano seduti, pronti ad ascoltare i traguardi raggiunti da Mihuatl raccontati da lui. Perché almeno da morti ascoltano veramente senza interrompere.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The battle was won. The lesser race of humanity was routed once again. Mihuatl smiled as he looked upon the dead, Cualli and man alike, strewn among the jungle floor. He loved the distinctive dampness the blood had upon the scales of his feet. He walked slowly across the clearing, in triumph, ignoring the echoes of already won battles as his warriors rounded up the survivors that had not retreated with the routed army.[PARAGRAPH:1]They were to be slaves for the holy ones. Their once proud crowns would be soiled with the stain of subjugation. Mihuatl toyed with the thought of the amusement and diversion that would be had now that the invaders had been defeated.[PARAGRAPH:1]A scream trilled in the air and subsequently a muffled thwack of a club upon a skull, for indeed it was a skull, he thought, for Mihuatl had learned well to decipher such sounds.He relished the feeling of ecstasy he felt when he heard it, and knew that feeling would stay with him throughout the night. Victory was his, was it not?[PARAGRAPH:1]He had proved that his warriors, warriors who were elite among the Cualli, were stronger than the best of these men, who seemed surprised when they were joined in battle. Mihuatl paused for a moment. Who were these men, these humans? It was rare that they should be encountered this deep within the jungles and marshes. They usually were minor scouts, allies of the Mazatl, that sought to explore the Cualli's borderlands. These were easily subjugated by an assassin or hunter from behind, but these men were diferent. More organized, better equipped, and there were far more of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mihuatl's second in command approached, clearing him of his thoughts.[NEWLINE]"Mihuatl! Victory has been achieved in the name of Agruonn!" the officer spoke.[NEWLINE]Mihuatl felt enraged at the name of his god. It was his victory, no one elses. But he knew better than to say such.[NEWLINE]"You shall not speak unless spoken to, lesssser." His hiss spit all of his venom at the officer though none at its true target.[NEWLINE]"I am the chosen of Kolsevahn! He chose me to Master over the lot of you!"[NEWLINE]"Yes, master!"[NEWLINE]His officer was new, one that has been with his army for only this skirmish and was yet to be broken.[NEWLINE]"Do not speak!" In a single motion, his club came undone from his belt and crashed into his officer's face. The skill and precision that Mihuatl put into this coup was something to be marveled at. Unfortunately for the officer, his situation seemed more dire as he fell to the ground, stunned.[NEWLINE]This behavior was unique to Mihuatl, for no other Cualli commanders had the audacity within him to do such things. Mihuatl put a foot at the neck of the officer, who withed on the ground pitifully in pain, and began to choke him.[NEWLINE]"You are nothing to me! I have cleanly defeated you with one swipe of my club! You are nothing! You only exist to serve me. You are my lesser, you should feel honored that I, Mihuatl, greatest commander of all of the Cualli, should have taken you upon his great conquest!" His foot talons began to tear their way into the scales on his officers neck. "Who is your master, whelp?"[PARAGRAPH:1]By now, the commotion had been noticed by warrior and slave alike. The slaves only knew Mihuatl as he was now, but the warriors had seen and felt such pain many times in their career. It was always the second in command that had the worst, sometimes such wounds were lethal and he died, only to be replaced by another. Even if they did fight back, though, Mihuatl was [ITALICS]protected[\ITALICS] by Kolsevahn. If one of them ever raised a weapon to him, he would be found dead, a dagger marked with Kolsevahn's emblem in his corpse.[NEWLINE]Mihuatl's face and posture showed him to be in a mix of rage and pleasure. He leans down and his tongue slivers a whisper to his officers in a seductive and teasing manor.[NEWLINE]"Who is your master, whelp?"[NEWLINE]Mihuatl rose, letting some of the weight from his foot off his officer's neck as he awaited his answer.[NEWLINE]"Y...you...," his officer sputtered, gasping for breath as he attempted to answer his commanding officer.[NEWLINE]However, it was only to be cut short as Mihuatl's temper worsened from the officer's stutter. With one brutal thrust of his foot, he cracked the neck. With this, though, he was still not satisfied. Mihuatl removed his foot and lifted up the body letting all spectators see.[NEWLINE]"Look well at this weakling! He was nothing and this is what remains of him! Now, we move! Kill the slaves that have not been tied and take those ready to the temples. Do not fall behind! Or you will be hunted like the weaklings you are!"[PARAGRAPH:2]This was his victory, no one else. He began the march back to Yayauhqui on his own, his men prepared or not. The city would only open to him, the Victor. He still carried the corpse of his second in command. It was his to do what he wished, and he knew that it belonged in his chambers, where the rest of his past commanders were seated, ready to listen to Mihuatl's achievements, recounted by his truly. For in death, at least they truly listened without interruptions.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_CUALLI</Tag>
		<English>Cualli Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Cualli</French>
		<German>Palast der Cualli</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo dei Cualli</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cualli Palace</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SACRIFICIAL_ALTAR</Tag>
		<English>Sacrificial Altar</English>
		<French>Autel Sacrificiel</French>
		<German>Opferaltar</German>
		<Italian>Altare Sacrificale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sacrificial Altar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SACRIFICIAL_ALTAR_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows a Priest of Agruonn to sacrifice living units to Empower all priests.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Permet à un Prêtre d'Agruonn de sacrifier une unité vivante pour Renforcer tous les prêtres.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt es einem Priester des Agruonn lebende Einheiten zu opfern, um alle Priester zu kräftigen.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Permette a un Sacerdote di Agruonn di sacrificare unità viventi per potenziare tutti i sacerdoti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows a Priest of Agruonn to sacrifice living units to Empower all priests.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SACRIFICIAL_ALTAR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Sacrificial Altar allows units to be sacrificed to gain a small amount of research and a temporary strength boost for all Priests of Agruonn. The level of this boost is related the level of the unit sacrificed (max. benefit at Level 4+).</English>
		<French>L'Autel Sacrificiel permet de sacrifier des unités pour obtenir un petit gain en recherche et un bonus temporaire de puissance pour tous les Prêtres d'Agruonn. Le bonus en puissance est lié au niveau de l'unité sacrifiée (bénéfice maximum avec une unité niveau 4+).</French>
		<German>Der Opferaltar erlaubt es Einheiten, sich für eine kleine Menge an Forschung und eine vorübergehende Stärkung aller Prister des Agruonn zu opfern. Die Höhe des Zuwachses an Stärke ist vom Level der geopferten Einheit abhängig. (max. Bonus bei Level 4+)</German>
		<Italian>L'Altare Sacrificale permette di sacrificare unità per ottenere una piccola quantita di ricerca e un bonus temporaneo alla forza di tutti i Sacerdoti di Agruonn. La grandezza del bonus dipende dal livello dell'unità sacrificata (massimo beneficio dal 4° lvl in su).</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Sacrificial Altar allows units to be sacrificed to gain a small amount of research and a temporary strength boost for all Priests of Agruonn. The level of this boost is related the level of the unit sacrificed (max. benefit at Level 4+)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_PIT</Tag>
		<English>Slave Pits</English>
		<French>Fosse aux Esclaves</French>
		<German>Sklavengrube</German>
		<Italian>Fosse degli Schiavi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slave Pits</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_PIT_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Slave Pit is created by the Cualli's world spell, and grants 4 free specialists in the city</English>
		<French>La Fosse aux Esclaves est créée grâce au sort mondial Cualli, et confère 4 Spécialistes Gratuits dans la ville</French>
		<German>Slave Pit is created by the Cualli's world spell, and grants 4 free specialists in the city</German>
		<Italian>Le Fosse degli Schiavi vengono create dalla magia globale Cualli, e forniscono 4 specialisti gratuiti alla città</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slave Pit is created by the Cualli's world spell, and grants 4 free specialists in the city</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_PIT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"I WAS sick, sick unto death, with that long agony, and when they at length unbound me, and I was permitted to sit, I felt that my senses were leaving me. The sentence, the dread sentence of death, was the last of distinct accentuation which reached my ears. After that, the sound of the masters voices seemed merged in one dreamy indeterminate hum. This only for a brief period, for presently I heard no more. Yet, for a while, I saw, but with how terrible an exaggeration ! I saw the lips of the black-robed priests. They appeared to me white -- whiter than the sheet upon which I trace these words -- and thin even to grotesqueness; thin with the intensity of their expression of firmness, of immovable resolution, of the stern contempt of our torture. I saw that the decrees of what to me was fate were still issuing from those lips. I saw them writhe with a deadly locution. I saw them fashion the syllables of my name, and I shuddered, because no sound succeeded." [PARAGRAPH]~E.A.P. (almost)</English>
		<French>"J'ÉTAIS malade, malade à en mourir, dans une longue agonie; et quand ils sont finalement venus me détacher et que j'ai eu l'autorisation de m'asseoir, j'ai sensi mes sens me quitter. La sentence, l'épouvantable condamnation à mort, fut le dernier son qui parvint clairement à mes oreilles. Après ça, les sons des voix des maîtres semblaient se mélanger dans un bourdonnement irréel. Ça ne dura qu'un court moment, et je suis maintenant sourd. Pourtant, pendant un moment, j'ai vu, avec une telle exagération ! Je voyais les lèvres des prêtres en robe noire. Ils m'apparaissaient blancs, plus blancs que la feuille sur laquelle j'écris ces mots, et maigres jusqu'au grotesque : Maigres à travers l'intensité de leur expression de fermeté, de résolution immuable, de mépris sévère envers notre torture. Je voyais que mon sort devait être scellé et encore discuté par ces lèvres. Je les ai vues se démener avec une tournure mortelle. Je les voyais épeler les syllabes de mon nom, et j'en frémis, car aucun son ne parvint jusqu'à moi."[PARAGRAPH:1]~E.A.P (approximatif)</French>
		<German>"I WAS sick, sick unto death, with that long agony, and when they at length unbound me, and I was permitted to sit, I felt that my senses were leaving me. The sentence, the dread sentence of death, was the last of distinct accentuation which reached my ears. After that, the sound of the masters voices seemed merged in one dreamy indeterminate hum. This only for a brief period, for presently I heard no more. Yet, for a while, I saw, but with how terrible an exaggeration ! I saw the lips of the black-robed priests. They appeared to me white -- whiter than the sheet upon which I trace these words -- and thin even to grotesqueness; thin with the intensity of their expression of firmness, of immovable resolution, of the stern contempt of our torture. I saw that the decrees of what to me was fate were still issuing from those lips. I saw them writhe with a deadly locution. I saw them fashion the syllables of my name, and I shuddered, because no sound succeeded." [PARAGRAPH]~E.A.P. (almost)</German>
		<Italian>"Io ERO malato, malato da morire, con quella lunga agonia, e quando infine mi slegarono, e mi fu permesso di sedermi, sentii i miei sensi abbandonarmi. La sentenza, la terribile sentenza di morte, fu l'ultima cosa distinta che raggiuse le mie orecchie. Dopo quello il suono delle voci dei miei padroni sembrò fondersi in un brusio indefinito. Questo solo per un momento, perché un momento dopo non sentii più niente. Comunque, per un pò, continuai a vedere, ma con un'esagerazione terribile! Vidi le labbra dei sacerdoti vestiti di nero. Mi sembravano bianche, più bianche delle pagine su cui sto scrivendo queste parole, e talmente sottili da sembrare grottesche; sottili ma con l'intensita dell'espressione della loro fermezza, di una risoluzione inamovibile, del severo disprezzo della nostra tortura. Vidi che il mio destino stava ancora uscendo da quelle labbra. Le vidi muoversi con una locuzione mortale. Le vidi pronunciare le sillabe del mio nome, e tremai, perché nessun'altro suono le seguì." [PARAGRAPH]~E.A.P. (approsimativamente)</Italian>
		<Spanish>"I WAS sick, sick unto death, with that long agony, and when they at length unbound me, and I was permitted to sit, I felt that my senses were leaving me. The sentence, the dread sentence of death, was the last of distinct accentuation which reached my ears. After that, the sound of the masters voices seemed merged in one dreamy indeterminate hum. This only for a brief period, for presently I heard no more. Yet, for a while, I saw, but with how terrible an exaggeration ! I saw the lips of the black-robed priests. They appeared to me white -- whiter than the sheet upon which I trace these words -- and thin even to grotesqueness; thin with the intensity of their expression of firmness, of immovable resolution, of the stern contempt of our torture. I saw that the decrees of what to me was fate were still issuing from those lips. I saw them writhe with a deadly locution. I saw them fashion the syllables of my name, and I shuddered, because no sound succeeded." [PARAGRAPH]~E.A.P. (almost)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_PIT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Slave pits are created in every existing Cualli city when their world spell is cast. The worldspell requires Way of the Wicked.</English>
		<French>Les Fosses aux Esclaves sont créées dans chaque ville Cualli existante quand le sort mondial est lancé. Lancer le sort mondial requiert Voie des Damnés.</French>
		<German>Slave pits are created in every existing Cualli city when their world spell is cast. The worldspell requires Way of the Wicked.</German>
		<Italian>Le Fosse degli Schiavi vengono create in ogni città Cualli sotto il tuo controllo quando la magia globale viene lanciata. La magia globale richiede la tecnologia Via del Male.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slave pits are created in every existing Cualli city when their world spell is cast. The worldspell requires Way of the Wicked.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BLOOD_AND_SACRIFICE</Tag>
		<English>Blood and Sacrifice</English>
		<French>Sang et Sacrifice</French>
		<German>Blut und Opferung</German>
		<Italian>Sangue e Sacrifici</Italian>
		<Spanish>Blood and Sacrifice</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BLOOD_AND_SACRIFICE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Cualli empire is built at the expense of its citizens. The strongest of the Cualli see it as their right to use the weaker as they wish and slavery is a natural result.</English>
		<French>L'empire Cualli est construit au prix de ses citoyens. Les Cuallis les plus forts le voient comme leur droit d'utiliser les plus faibles à leur convenance, et l'escalvage en est le résultat naturel.</French>
		<German>The Cualli empire is built at the expense of its citizens. The strongest of the Cualli see it as their right to use the weaker as they wish and slavery is a natural result.</German>
		<Italian>L'impero Cualli è costruito a spese dei suioi cittadini. Il più forte dei Cualli considera un suo diritto l'usare i più deboli come desidera e la schiavitù ne è il risultato naturale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Cualli empire is built at the expense of its citizens. The strongest of the Cualli see it as their right to use the weaker as they wish and slavery is a natural result.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SLAVE_DRIVE</Tag>
		<English>Slave Drive</English>
		<French>Enrôlement des Esclaves</French>
		<German>Sklavenfang</German>
		<Italian>Raccolta di Schiavi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slave Drive</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SLAVE_DRIVE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Creates slave pits in all current cities, granting +4 citizen specialists</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Crée des Fosses aux Esclaves dans toutes vos villes existantes, donnant +4 spécialistes.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erschafft Sklavengruben in allen derzeitigen Städten, bringt +4 Spezialisten Bürger</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Crea le Fosse degli Schiavi in tutte le città attuali, fonendogli 4 cittadini gratuiti</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Creates slave pits in all current cities, granting +4 citizen specialists</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SLAVE_DRIVE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Slavery is common place in Cualli society, but sometimes there are not enough slaves to complete a task as quickly as the Cualli leaders demand. At these times, the palace guards are sent into the city to "recruit additional workers". Those unfortunate enough to be selected will spend the rest of their lives in the slave pits.</English>
		<French>L'esclavage est monnaie courante dans la société Cualli, mais il n'y a parfois pas assez d'esclaves pour réaliser une tâche aussi vite que le demandent les dirigeants Cualli. Dans ces cas là, les gardes du palais sont envoyés en ville pour "recruter des travailleurs supplémentaires". Les malheureux qui sont sélectionnés passeront le reste de leur vie dans les fosses aux esclaves.</French>
		<German>Slavery is common place in Cualli society, but sometimes there are not enough slaves to complete a task as quickly as the Cualli leaders demand. At these times, the palace guards are sent into the city to "recruit additional workers". Those unfortunate enough to be selected will spend the rest of their lives in the slave pits.</German>
		<Italian>La schiavitù è una cosa comune nella società Cualli, ma a volte non ci sono abbastanza schiavi per completare un opera alla velocità che i sovrani Cualli richedono. In questi casi le guadie del palazzo vengono inviate in città per "reclutare lavoratori addizionali". Gli sfortunati che vengono scelti passeranno il resto delle loro vite nelle Fosse degli Schiavi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slavery is common place in Cualli society, but sometimes there are not enough slaves to complete a task as quickly as the Cualli leaders demand. At these times, the palace guards are sent into the city to "recruit additional workers". Those unfortunate enough to be selected will spend the rest of their lives in the slave pits.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SLAVE_DRIVE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Slave Drive grants +4 free citizen specialists in every city you currently own, providing a small, permanent production boost. New cities do not gain this benefit however, so only cast it once you have founded several cities.</English>
		<French>Enrôlement des Esclaves confère +4 spécialistes gratuits dans chaque ville actuellement qous votre contrôle, conférant un petit boost permanent à la production. Les villes fondées ultérieurement n'en bénéficient toutefois pas. Il est donc conseillé de ne lancer le sort qu'après avoir fondé quelques villes.</French>
		<German>Slave Drive grants +4 free citizen specialists in every city you currently own, providing a small, permanent production boost. New cities do not gain this benefit however, so only cast it once you have founded several cities.</German>
		<Italian>La Raccolta di Schiavi fornisce 4 specialisti cittadini gratuiti in ogni città che controlli quando la lanci, fornendo un piccolo, ma permanente, aumento della produzione. Eventuali nuove città non ottengono questo beneficio però, quindi è consigliabile lanciarla solo dopo aver fondato diverse città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slave Drive grants +4 free citizen specialists in every city you currently own, providing a small, permanent production boost. New cities do not gain this benefit however, so only cast it once you have founded several cities.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIZARD_WORKER_CUALLI</Tag>
		<English>Lizardman Labourer</English>
		<French>Ouvrier Lézard</French>
		<German>Echsenbautrupp</German>
		<Italian>Lizardman Labourer</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lizardman Labourer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIZARD_WORKER_CUALLI_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Lizard workers are slow when compared to those of other races - the leaders of the Cualli have little interest in improving the land for their people. They are able however to construct "Trails", hidden paths which act as roads for Swampdwelling civilizations but provide almost no benefit to others.</English>
		<French>Les ouvriers lézards sont relativement lents comparativement aux autres races, les dirigeants des Cuallis ne se souciant que peu d'améliorer leur terres pour leur peuple. Ils sont cependant capables de construire des "Pistes", qui sont des sentiers cachés agissant comme des routes pour les civilisations habitant dans les marécages, mais ne fournissant pratiquement aucun avantage aux autres.</French>
		<German>Echsenbautrupps sind verglichen mit denen anderer Rassen sehr langsam, aber die Führer der Cualli haben auch wenig Interesse an der Verbesserung des Landes für ihr Volk. Sind sind jedoch in der Lage, "Pfade" anzulegen, verborgene Straßen, die für Dschungelbewohnende Zivilisationen von Nutzen sind, im Gegensatz zu allen anderen Rassen.</German>
		<Italian>Lizard workers are slow when compared to those of other races - the leaders of the Cualli have little interest in improving the land for their people. They are able however to construct "Trails", hidden paths which act as roads for Swampdwelling civilizations but provide almost no benefit to others.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lizard workers are slow when compared to those of other races - the leaders of the Cualli have little interest in improving the land for their people. They are able however to construct "Trails", hidden paths which act as roads for Swampdwelling civilizations but provide almost no benefit to others.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MIQUIZTLI</Tag>
		<English>Miquiztli</English>
		<French>Miquiztli</French>
		<German>Miquiztli</German>
		<Italian>Miquiztli</Italian>
		<Spanish>Miquiztli</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MIQUIZTLI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Miquiztli is darkness. Mizquiztli is death. Miquiztli is the first of the Shadow Priests and the greatest among us. Misquiztli is Agruonn's most favoured servant and the embodiment of his will. Miquiztli is the right hand of Murder." [PARAGRAPH]~From an inscription found in a ruined Temple of Agruonn</English>
		<French>"Miquiztli est les ténèbres. Mizquiztli est la mort. Miquiztli est le premier Prêtre des Ombres et le plus grand d'entre eux. Miquiztli est le serviteur le plus favorisé d'Agruonn et l'incarnation de sa volonté. Miquiztli est le bras droit du Meurtre."[PARAGRAPH:1]~tiré d'une inscription d'un temple en ruines d'Agruonn</French>
		<German>"Miquiztli is darkness. Mizquiztli is death. Miquiztli is the first of the Shadow Priests and the greatest among us. Misquiztli is Agruonn's most favoured servant and the embodiment of his will. Miquiztli is the right hand of Murder." [PARAGRAPH]~From an inscription found in a ruined Temple of Agruonn</German>
		<Italian>"Miquiztli è l'oscurità. Mizquiztli è la morte. Miquiztli è il primo dei Sacerdoti delle Ombre e il più grande tra noi. Misquiztli è il servitore più favorito da Agruonn e l'incarnazione della sua volontà. Miquiztli è la mano destra di Omicidio." [PARAGRAPH]~Tratto da un'iscrizione trovata in un tempio in rovina di Agruonn</Italian>
		<Spanish>"Miquiztli is darkness. Mizquiztli is death. Miquiztli is the first of the Shadow Priests and the greatest among us. Misquiztli is Agruonn's most favoured servant and the embodiment of his will. Miquiztli is the right hand of Murder." [PARAGRAPH]~From an inscription found in a ruined Temple of Agruonn</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MIQUIZTLI_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Miquiztli is the hero unit for the Cualli, though he cannot be built. He must be upgraded from a Level 6 Priest of Agruonn or Level 6 Assassin. Once he has been created, further Level 6 units may become Shadow Priests of Agruonn. Miquiztli is the first and most dangerous of the Shadow Priests, with a substantial bonus to the poison damage he inflicts and the ability to cast the third tier of spells - which are unattainable by other Shadow Priests. This gives him access to Stoneskin, Create Flesh Golem, Summon Phantasm and Shadow-walk - all of which may be very potent if used correctly. </English>
		<French>Miquiztli est le héros des Cuallis, même s'il ne peut être construit. Il doit être amélioré à partir d'un Prêtre ou un Assassin de niveau 6 ou plus. Une fois créé, les unités suivantes à atteindre le niveau 6 pourront devenir des Prêtres des Ombres d'Agruonn. Miquiztli est le premier et le plus dangereux des Prêtres des Ombres, avec un bonus substanciel de dégâts de poison et la capacité à lancer des sorts de rang 3, inaccessibles aux autres Prêtres des Ombres, lui donnant accès à Peau de Pierre, Créer Golem de Chair, Invoquer un Fantasme et Marche des Ombres, chacun d'eux pouvant être très puissant lorsque bien utilisé.</French>
		<German>Miquiztli is the hero unit for the Cualli, though he cannot be built. He must be upgraded from a Level 6 Priest of Agruonn or Level 6 Assassin. Once he has been created, further Level 6 units may become Shadow Priests of Agruonn. Miquiztli is the first and most dangerous of the Shadow Priests, with a substantial bonus to the poison damage he inflicts and the ability to cast the third tier of spells - which are unattainable by other Shadow Priests. This gives him access to Stoneskin, Create Flesh Golem, Summon Phantasm and Shadow-walk - all of which may be very potent if used correctly.</German>
		<Italian>Miquiztli è l'eroe dei Cualli, ma contrariamente agli altri non può essere creato normalmente. Per ottenerlo bisogna migliorare un Sacerdote di Agruonn o un assassino di minimo 6° livello. Una volta creato, ulteriori unità di 6° livello possono diventare Sacerdoti delle Ombre di Agruonn. Miquiztli è il primo e il più pericoloso dei Sacerdoti delle Ombre, con un sostanziale bonus al danno da veleno che infligge e la capacità di lanciare magie di terzo livello, che non sono ottenibili dagli altri Sacerdoti delle Ombre. Questo gli permette di lanciare Pelle di Pietra, Crea Golem di Carne, Evoca Fantasma e Passo D'Ombra, le quali possono essere tutte molto potenti se usate correttamente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Miquiztli is the hero unit for the Cualli, though he cannot be built. He must be upgraded from a Level 6 Priest of Agruonn or Level 6 Assassin. Once he has been created, further Level 6 units may become Shadow Priests of Agruonn. Miquiztli is the first and most dangerous of the Shadow Priests, with a substantial bonus to the poison damage he inflicts and the ability to cast the third tier of spells - which are unattainable by other Shadow Priests. This gives him access to Stoneskin, Create Flesh Golem, Summon Phantasm and Shadow-walk - all of which may be very potent if used correctly.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRIEST_AGRUONN</Tag>
		<English>Priest of Agruonn</English>
		<French>Prêtre d'Agruonn</French>
		<German>Priester des Agruonn</German>
		<Italian>Sacerdote di Agruonn</Italian>
		<Spanish>Priest of Agruonn</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRIEST_AGRUONN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The prayers and sacrifices made by the priests of Agruonn are received by the power humans know as Aeron, the god of blood and murder. He is pleased by the callous way that the Cualli treat their inferiors and has been known to grant great power to a chosen few, allowing them to commit greater acts in his name.</English>
		<French>Les prières et les sacrifices faits par les prêtres d'Agruonn sont destinés au pouvoir que les humains appellent Aéron, dieu du sang et du meurtre. Il apprécie la façon rude dont les Cuallis traitent leurs inférieurs et est connus pour donner de grands pouvoirs aux quelques élus, leur permettant d'accomplir d'encore plus grandes choses en son nom.</French>
		<German>The prayers and sacrifices made by the priests of Agruonn are received by the power humans know as Aeron, the god of blood and murder. He is pleased by the callous way that the Cualli treat their inferiors and has been known to grant great power to a chosen few, allowing them to commit greater acts in his name.</German>
		<Italian>Le preghiere e i sacrifici fatti dai sacerdoti di Agruonn sono diretti al potere che gli umani conoscono come Aeron, il dio del sangue e dell'omicidio. Lui si compiace delle maniere insesibili con cui i Cualli trattano i loro sottoposti ed è risaputo che dona un grande potere a pochi eletti, permettendogli di compiere grandi imprese in suo nome.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The prayers and sacrifices made by the priests of Agruonn are received by the power humans know as Aeron, the god of blood and murder. He is pleased by the callous way that the Cualli treat their inferiors and has been known to grant great power to a chosen few, allowing them to commit greater acts in his name.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRIEST_AGRUONN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Priest of Agruonn are able to cast a number of spells spanning the Divine, Sorcery and Summoning branches of the Body and Shadow trees. They primarily support other combat units using Regeneration, Blur, Haste and Burning Blood. They may also call forth Mistforms to attack without provoking war. [NEWLINE]If a Priest of Agruonn is present in a city with a Sacrificial Altar, he may sacrifice any other living, non-priest unit. This provides an Empower bonus to all Priest units for a short period of time.</English>
		<French>Les Prêtres d'Agruonn sont capables de lancer certains sorts des domaines Divins, Sorcellerie et Invocation des arbres du Corps et de l'Ombre. Ils sont avant tout des supports pour les autres unités de combat, grâce à l'utilisation de Régénération, Flou, Hâte et Sang Bouillonnant. Ils peuvent également invoquer à la chaîne des Formes Brumeuses qui peuvent attaquer sans déclencher de guerre.[NEWLINE]Si un Prêtre d'Agruonn est présent dans une ville disposant d'un Autel Sacrificiel, il peut sacrifier n'importe quelle unité vivante aute qu'un prêtre, ce qui confère à tous les Prêtres le bonus Renforcement pour une courte période.</French>
		<German>Priest of Agruonn are able to cast a number of spells spanning the Divine, Sorcery and Summoning branches of the Body and Shadow trees. They primarily support other combat units using Regeneration, Blur, Haste and Burning Blood. They may also call forth Mistforms to attack without provoking war. [NEWLINE]If a Priest of Agruonn is present in a city with a Sacrificial Altar, he may sacrifice any other living, non-priest unit. This provides an Empower bonus to all Priest units for a short period of time.</German>
		<Italian>I Sacerdoti di Agruonn sono capaci di lanciare varie magie appartenenti alla branca Divina, della Stregoneria e dell'Evocazione della magia del corpo e dell'ombra. Principalmente supportano le altre unità da combattimento usando Rigenerazione, Sfocatura, Rapidità e Sangue Bruciante. Possono anche chiamare dei Nebbiforme per attaccare senza dover dichiarare guerra. [NEWLINE]Se un Sacerdote di Agruonn è in una città con un Altare Sacrificale può sacrificare qualsiasi altra unità vivente che non sia anch'essa un Sacerdote. Farlo fornisce un bonus alla forza di tutti i Sacerdoti per un breve periodo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Priest of Agruonn are able to cast a number of spells spanning the Divine, Sorcery and Summoning branches of the Body and Shadow trees. They primarily support other combat units using Regeneration, Blur, Haste and Burning Blood. They may also call forth Mistforms to attack without provoking war. [NEWLINE]If a Priest of Agruonn is present in a city with a Sacrificial Altar, he may sacrifice any other living, non-priest unit. This provides an Empower bonus to all Priest units for a short period of time.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHADOW_PRIEST_AGRUONN</Tag>
		<English>Shadow Priest of Agruonn</English>
		<French>Prêtre des Ombres d'Agruonn</French>
		<German>Schattenpriester des Agruonn</German>
		<Italian>Sacerdote delle Ombre di Agruonn</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shadow Priest of Agruonn</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHADOW_PRIEST_AGRUONN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Those who please Agruonn greatly - be they of his clergy or a more "subtle" profession - may be allowed to become a Shadow Priest. These murderous individuals have both the cunning of an assassin and the divine abilities of a priest - an unholy union that is sure to bring death to those who stand against the Cualli.</English>
		<French>Ceux qui satisfont particulièrement Agruonn, qu'ils soient du clergé ou d'une profession plus "subtile", peuvent être autorisés à devenir un Prêtre des Ombres. Ces individus meurtriersT ont à la fois l'habileté d'un assassin est les capacités divines d'un prêtre, une union impie assurée de causer la mort  de ceux qui s'opposent aux Cuallis.</French>
		<German>Those who please Agruonn greatly - be they of his clergy or a more "subtle" profession - may be allowed to become a Shadow Priest. These murderous individuals have both the cunning of an assassin and the divine abilities of a priest - an unholy union that is sure to bring death to those who stand against the Cualli.</German>
		<Italian>A coloro che soddisfano abbondantemente Agruonn, siano essi appartenenti al suo clero o a qualche professione più "discreta", può venir permesso di diventare un Sacerdote delle Ombre. Questi individui micidiali hanno sia l'astuzia di un assassino che le abilità divine di un sacerdote, una sacrilega unione che sicuramente portera la morte a coloro che si oppongono ai Cualli.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Those who please Agruonn greatly - be they of his clergy or a more "subtle" profession - may be allowed to become a Shadow Priest. These murderous individuals have both the cunning of an assassin and the divine abilities of a priest - an unholy union that is sure to bring death to those who stand against the Cualli.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHADOW_PRIEST_AGRUONN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Shadow Priests may be created only after Misquiztli has been created. Shadow Priests must be upgraded from a Level 6 unit or greater - they cannot be built directly. This unit may be either a Priest of Agruonn or an Assassin. The Shadow Priest combines the abilities of both lines - being Invisible to most units and able to cast all the spells the priest is able to. It also receives the Empower bonus from Sacrifices, as with the lesser Priests.</English>
		<French>Les Prêtres des Ombres ne peuvent être crées qu'après avoir crée Misquiztli. Les Prêtres des Ombres doivent être améliorés à partir d'une unité de niveau 6 ou plus et ne peuvent être directement construites. Cette unité peut être un Prêtre d'Agruonn ou un Assassin. Le Prêtre des Ombres combines les compétences des deux types, en étant Invisible pour la plupart des des unités et capable de lancer les mêmes sorts qu'un Prêtre. Il reçoit également le bonus de Renforcement des sarifices, comme les Prêtres plus faibles.</French>
		<German>Shadow Priests may be created only after Misquiztli has been created. Shadow Priests must be upgraded from a Level 6 unit or greater - they cannot be built directly. This unit may be either a Priest of Agruonn or an Assassin. The Shadow Priest combines the abilities of both lines - being Invisible to most units and able to cast all the spells the priest is able to. It also receives the Empower bonus from Sacrifices, as with the lesser Priests.</German>
		<Italian>I Sacerdoti delle Ombre possono essere creati solo dopo aver creato Misquiztli. I Sacerdoti delle Ombre devono essere creati migliorando un unità di 6° livello o superiore, non possono essere creati direttamente. L'unità può essere sia un Sacerdote di Agruonn o un Assassino. Il Sacerdote delle Ombre combina le abilità di entrambi i tipi di unità, essendo invisibile alla maggior parte delle unità ed essendo capace di lanciare tutte le magie di cui dispone un sacerdote. Riceve inoltre un bonus dai sacrifici allo stesso modo dei normali sacerdoti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shadow Priests may be created only after Misquiztli has been created. Shadow Priests must be upgraded from a Level 6 unit or greater - they cannot be built directly. This unit may be either a Priest of Agruonn or an Assassin. The Shadow Priest combines the abilities of both lines - being Invisible to most units and able to cast all the spells the priest is able to. It also receives the Empower bonus from Sacrifices, as with the lesser Priests.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
