<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Game Text - Mekara Order -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>	<!-- Name -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MEKARA_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Mekara Order</English>
		<French>L'ordre des Mekara</French>
		<German>Reich des Mekara Orden</German>
		<Italian>Ordine Mekara</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mekara Order</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Short Name -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MEKARA_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Mekara Order</English>
		<French>Mekara</French>
		<German>Mekara Orden</German>
		<Italian>Mekara</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mekara Order</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Adjective -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MEKARA_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Mekaran</English>
		<French>mekarum:mekarum:mekara:mekara</French>
		<German>Mekaranisch:Mekaranischen:Mekaranische</German>
		<Italian>Mekara</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mekaran</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Slave -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPECIALIST_SLAVE</Tag>
		<English>Slave</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Esclave:Esclaves</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Sklave</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Schiavo:Schiavi</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slave</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Shaper's Army -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MEKARA_WORLDSPELL</Tag>
		<English>Shaper's Army</English>
		<French>Armée des Modeleurs</French>
		<German>Des Formers Heerscharen</German>
		<Italian>Esercito del Plasmatore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shaper's Army</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Shaper's Army, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MEKARA_WORLDSPELL_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Turns all Sluga and Slave units under your command into War Sluga</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Turns all Sluga and Slave units under your command into War Sluga</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Verwandelt alle Sluga und Sklaveneinheiten unter deiner F&#252;hrung in Kriegssluga</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Trasforma tutti gli Sluga e gli Schiavi sotto il tuo controllo in Sluga da Guerra</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Turns all Sluga and Slave units under your command into War Sluga</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Shaper's Army, Quote -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_GLOBALSPELL_MEKARA_WORLDSPELL</Tag>
		<English>Turns all [LINK=literal]Sluga[\LINK] and [LINK=literal]Slave[\LINK] units the caster's command into independent [LINK=literal]War Sluga[\LINK]</English>
		<French>Turns all [LINK=literal]Sluga[\LINK] and [LINK=literal]Slave[\LINK] units the caster's command into independent [LINK=literal]War Sluga[\LINK]</French>
		<German>Verwandelt alle [LINK=literal]Sluga[\LINK] und [LINK=literal]Sklave[\LINK]neinheiten des Zaubernden in unabh&#228;ngige  [LINK=literal]Kriegssluga[\LINK]</German>
		<Italian>Trasforma tutti gli [LINK=literal]Sluga[\LINK] e gli [LINK=literal]Schiavi[\LINK] controllati da chi la lancia in [LINK=literal]Sluga da Guerra[\LINK]</Italian>
		<Spanish>Turns all [LINK=literal]Sluga[\LINK] and [LINK=literal]Slave[\LINK] units the caster's command into independent [LINK=literal]War Sluga[\LINK]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Civilopedia Entry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MEKARA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Mekara Order began as a cabal of Amurite mages, united by an common dream: Ascension.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Founded by the necromancer D'tesh, they worked for years in secrecy, experimenting on slaves smuggled in through the black market, as well as occasional undesirables snatched from the streets or prisons. Eventually, internal conflicts started causing tensions within the cabal, with D'tesh unwilling to share the power they sought with the rest, and keeping for himself what might have been the key to their dream: the Gem of Death. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]As the tensions continued to build the Mekara Order eventually tore itself apart from within, with D'tesh leaving to continue his research on his own, reasoning that he had no further use for the Mekara Order with the Gem of Death in his possession, and leaving one of his rivals, Jamal Dahkar, in charge. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Due to this internal conflict, the Mekara Order was exposed to the authorities, who subsequently had them arrested, put on trial and exiled. The remaining members travelled from country to country after that, gaining occasional followers, but more often than not earning the ire of the local peoples.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]After years of wandering, they settled in a region near the Calabim border, where they entered into an arrangements with the local governor. In return for sanctuary, they would teach her the ways of magic, and give her a position of prestige and power within the Mekara Order. Subsequently, the Mekara Order took over the day-to-day affairs of her province, breaking free from the Calabim nation and starting out on their own.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH] Though the people they rule are almost exclusively Calabim, the ones who make the decisions are nearly all Amurites, and all members of the Mekara Order, to whom the commoners are of little consequence. They provide rudimentary security and education, but the only times they take an interest beyond that, is when someone either shows themselves to be extremely competent, or defies them. In either case, they are removed from society, either to be inducted into the Mekara Order, or thrown into the slave pens, to be used as guinea pigs or cheap labor. Those who fit neither category are, for the most part, left to their own devices, as long as they obey the laws.</English>
		<French>The Mekara Order began as a cabal of Amurite mages, united by an common dream: Ascension.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Founded by the necromancer D'tesh, they worked for years in secrecy, experimenting on slaves smuggled in through the black market, as well as occasional undesirables snatched from the streets or prisons. Eventually, internal conflicts started causing tensions within the cabal, with D'tesh unwilling to share the power they sought with the rest, and keeping for himself what might have been the key to their dream: the Gem of Death. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]As the tensions continued to build the Mekara Order eventually tore itself apart from within, with D'tesh leaving to continue his research on his own, reasoning that he had no further use for the Mekara Order with the Gem of Death in his possession, and leaving one of his rivals, Jamal Dahkar, in charge. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Due to this internal conflict, the Mekara Order was exposed to the authorities, who subsequently had them arrested, put on trial and exiled. The remaining members travelled from country to country after that, gaining occasional followers, but more often than not earning the ire of the local peoples.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]After years of wandering, they settled in a region near the Calabim border, where they entered into an arrangements with the local governor. In return for sanctuary, they would teach her the ways of magic, and give her a position of prestige and power within the Mekara Order. Subsequently, the Mekara Order took over the day-to-day affairs of her province, breaking free from the Calabim nation and starting out on their own.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH] Though the people they rule are almost exclusively Calabim, the ones who make the decisions are nearly all Amurites, and all members of the Mekara Order, to whom the commoners are of little consequence. They provide rudimentary security and education, but the only times they take an interest beyond that, is when someone either shows themselves to be extremely competent, or defies them. In either case, they are removed from society, either to be inducted into the Mekara Order, or thrown into the slave pens, to be used as guinea pigs or cheap labor. Those who fit neither category are, for the most part, left to their own devices, as long as they obey the laws.</French>
		<German>Der Mekara Orden enstand aus einer Sekte von Amuritischen Magiern, die in einem gemeinsamen Traum vereint waren: Himmelfahrt.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Vom Nekromant D'tesh gegr&#252;ndet, arbeiteten sie &#252;ber Jahre im Verborgenen. Sie experimentierten sowohl mit auf dem Schwarzmarkt eingeschmuggelten Sklaven, als auch mit AusgestoÃŸenen, die sie manchmal aus Gef&#228;ngnissen holten oder auf der StraÃŸe aufsammelten. Irgendwann kam es aufgrund von internen Konflikten innerhalb der Sekte zu Spannungen. D'tesh war nicht gewillt, die von allen angestrebte Macht zu teilen, und behielt das Einod f&#252;r sich, das f&#252;r alle der Schl&#252;ssel zu ihren Tr&#228;umen h&#228;tte sein k&#246;nnen: Das Juwel des Todes.		[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Als die Spannungen zunahmen, zerbrach der Mekara Orden schlieÃŸlich von innen heraus. D'tesh verlieÃŸ den Orden, um seine Studien allein fortzusetzen. Mit dem Juwel des Todes in seinem Besitz war der Mekara Orden f&#252;r ihn nutzlos geworden, so daÃŸ er Jamal Dahkar, einen seiner Rivalen, als Nachfolger zur&#252;cklieÃŸ. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Aufgrund der internen Reibereien wurden die Beh&#246;rden auf den Mekara Orden aufmerksam, die Mitglieder wurden nach und nach verhafted, verurteiled und verbannt. Die Mitglieder reisten danach durch die Lande und fanden, wenn sie auch wesentlich h&#228;ufiger vor dem Zorn der Einheimischen fliehen muÃŸten, gelegentlich neue Anh&#228;nger.		[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Nach Jahren der Wanderschaft lieÃŸen sie sich nahe der Grenze zu den Calabim nieder, wo sie mit der Herrscherin diesen Gebiets eine Vereinbarung trafen. Im Gegenzug f&#252;r das gebotene Asyl lehrten sie sie die Wege der Magie, gaben ihr eine einflussreiche und angesehene Stellung innerhalb des Mekara Ordens. Nach und nach &#252;bernahm der Orden dadurch die Alltagsgesch&#228;fte ihrer Provinz, sagte sich von dem Reich der Calabim los und wirtschaftete in Zukunft auf eigene Rechnung.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH] Obwohl sich die niedere Bev&#246;lkerung fast ausschlieÃŸlich aus Calabim zusammensetzt, finden sich unter den Entscheidungstr&#228;gern nahezu nur Amuriten und nur solche, denen die Geschicke der einfachen Leute v&#246;llig gleichg&#252;ltig sind. Sie sorgen f&#252;r eine ansatzweise Sicherheit und Ausbildung. Wirkliches Interesse am gemeinen Volk zeigen sie jedoch nur, wenn jemand besonders bef&#228;higt oder besonders widerspenstig scheint. In beiden F&#228;llen werden diese Personen aus der Gesellschaft entfernt, im ersten Fall werden sie in den Mekara Orden eingef&#252;hrt, im zweiten Fall in die Sklavenquartiere geschickt, wo sie als Versuchskaninchen oder als billige Arbeitskraft Verwendung finden. Nur diejenigen, die zu keiner dieser beiden Kategorien zugeh&#246;rig sind, werden, zumindest meistens, in Ruhe und sich selbst &#252;berlassen, solange sie sich an die Gesetze halten.</German>
		<Italian>All'inizio l'Ordine Mekara era una cabala di maghi Amurite, uniti da un sogno comune: l'Ascensione.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Fondata dal necromante D'tesh, agirono per anni in segreto, facendo esperimenti su schiavi presi al mercato nero, ed eventuali persone non gradite prese dalle strade o dalle prigioni. Col tempo si svilupparono dei conflitti interni alla cabala, con D'tesh che non intendeva condividere il potere con gli altri e voleva tenere per se ciò che poteva essere la chiave per i loro obiettivi: la Gemma della Morte. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Col crescere delle tensioni interne alla fine l'Ordine Mekara si frammentò, con D'tesh andandosene per continuare le sue ricerche per conto suo, ritenendo non aver più bisogno dell'Ordine Mekara in quanto possedeva la Gemma della Morte, e lasciando uno dei suoi rivali, Jamal Dahkar, al comando. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]A causa di questo conflitto interno, l'Ordine Mekara fù scoperto dalle autorità, che arrestò, processò ed esiliò i membri della cabala. Questi ultimi viaggiarono da un paese all'altro, guadagnando qualche occasionale seguace, ma più spesso attirando su di loro le ire della popolazione locale.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Dopo anni di girovagare si stabilirono in una regione vicino al confine Calabim, dove conclusero un'accordo con il governatore locale. In cambio di protezione ed asilo gli avrebbero insegnato le vie della magia e dato un ruolo di prestigio e potere all'interno dell'Ordine Mekara. Successivamente l'Ordine Mekara assunse il controllo della provincia, staccandosi dalla nazione Calabim e creandone una loro.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Sebbene la gente che governano sia quasi esclusivamente Calabim, coloro che prendono le decisioni sono quasi tutti Amurite, e tutti membri dell'Ordine Mekara, per i quali i cittadini comuni hanno poca importanza. Forniscono inoltre una rudimentale protezione ed educazione, e le sole volte in cui si interessano in maniera maggiore è quando qualcuno si dimostra estremamente competente, o li sfida. In entrambi i casi, queste persone vengono fatte sparire dalla circolazione, che sia perché vengono introdotti nell'Ordine Mekara, o buttati nelle baracche degli schiavi, per poi venir usati come cavie o manodopera a basso costo. Coloro che non rientrano in nessuna di queste categorie vengono, per la maggior parte, lasciati stare in pace, purché obbediscano alle leggi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Mekara Order began as a cabal of Amurite mages, united by an common dream: Ascension.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Founded by the necromancer D'tesh, they worked for years in secrecy, experimenting on slaves smuggled in through the black market, as well as occasional undesirables snatched from the streets or prisons. Eventually, internal conflicts started causing tensions within the cabal, with D'tesh unwilling to share the power they sought with the rest, and keeping for himself what might have been the key to their dream: the Gem of Death. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]As the tensions continued to build the Mekara Order eventually tore itself apart from within, with D'tesh leaving to continue his research on his own, reasoning that he had no further use for the Mekara Order with the Gem of Death in his possession, and leaving one of his rivals, Jamal Dahkar, in charge. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Due to this internal conflict, the Mekara Order was exposed to the authorities, who subsequently had them arrested, put on trial and exiled. The remaining members travelled from country to country after that, gaining occasional followers, but more often than not earning the ire of the local peoples.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]After years of wandering, they settled in a region near the Calabim border, where they entered into an arrangements with the local governor. In return for sanctuary, they would teach her the ways of magic, and give her a position of prestige and power within the Mekara Order. Subsequently, the Mekara Order took over the day-to-day affairs of her province, breaking free from the Calabim nation and starting out on their own.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH] Though the people they rule are almost exclusively Calabim, the ones who make the decisions are nearly all Amurites, and all members of the Mekara Order, to whom the commoners are of little consequence. They provide rudimentary security and education, but the only times they take an interest beyond that, is when someone either shows themselves to be extremely competent, or defies them. In either case, they are removed from society, either to be inducted into the Mekara Order, or thrown into the slave pens, to be used as guinea pigs or cheap labor. Those who fit neither category are, for the most part, left to their own devices, as long as they obey the laws.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Leader: Jamal, Name -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_JAMAL</Tag>
		<English>Jamal Dahkar</English>
		<French>Jamal Dahkar</French>
		<German>Jamal Dahkar</German>
		<Italian>Jamal Dahkar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Jamal Dahkar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Leader: Jamal, Civilopedia Entry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_JAMAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"It has been several days since I left Junon in the company of these Mekara fellows, and so far, my impression is that I might come to regret my desicion to travel with them. Two of them have spoken to me at length about human and elven anatomy within the last few hours, and the questions they ask makes it quite clear that they don't intend to use what I know for healing. Still, I remain somewhat hopeful that I can sway them in a more... humane direction, given time.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Their ideals are sound, but their methods are questionable at best. Some of the alchemical solutions they have been discussing seem more likely to kill than bring about any improvement, and last night I overheard a discussion about the grafting of new limbs onto living flesh for improved 'performance'. Thankfully, their leader seems much more sensible. He is an interesting man - if it were not for him, I would never have joined with them. He is a former archmage from the Amurite people, and is a man of strong convictions and high ideals. His dream, and his belief in it, is more than fascinating; it is beautiful. Elimination of disease, the slowing of ageing, and near-immortality as far as physical trauma is concerned. Imagine how life could be improved for the people if his dream can be fulfilled![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]I have spoken to him at length about bringing this to the people, and he has agreed that it is a worthwhile endeavour, though he seems to care little for the people themselves. He has offered me a place in the Mekara Order, however, and I have accepted, for now, though I worry about the price his dream. There is something hard and cold inside him, as if there is nothing he feels except for his passion for his quest. I can only hope that he will listen to me."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH] - "Excerpt from the journal of Iram Damarr, on the subject of Jamal Dahkar."</English>
		<French>"It has been several days since I left Junon in the company of these Mekara fellows, and so far, my impression is that I might come to regret my desicion to travel with them. Two of them have spoken to me at length about human and elven anatomy within the last few hours, and the questions they ask makes it quite clear that they don't intend to use what I know for healing. Still, I remain somewhat hopeful that I can sway them in a more... humane direction, given time.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Their ideals are sound, but their methods are questionable at best. Some of the alchemical solutions they have been discussing seem more likely to kill than bring about any improvement, and last night I overheard a discussion about the grafting of new limbs onto living flesh for improved 'performance'. Thankfully, their leader seems much more sensible. He is an interesting man - if it were not for him, I would never have joined with them. He is a former archmage from the Amurite people, and is a man of strong convictions and high ideals. His dream, and his belief in it, is more than fascinating; it is beautiful. Elimination of disease, the slowing of ageing, and near-immortality as far as physical trauma is concerned. Imagine how life could be improved for the people if his dream can be fulfilled![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]I have spoken to him at length about bringing this to the people, and he has agreed that it is a worthwhile endeavour, though he seems to care little for the people themselves. He has offered me a place in the Mekara Order, however, and I have accepted, for now, though I worry about the price his dream. There is something hard and cold inside him, as if there is nothing he feels except for his passion for his quest. I can only hope that he will listen to me."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH] - "Excerpt from the journal of Iram Damarr, on the subject of Jamal Dahkar."</French>
		<German>"Es ist jetzt einige Tage her, daÃŸ ich Junon in der Gesellschaft dieser Mekara Gef&#228;hrten verlassen habe. Bisher macht es den Eindruck, daÃŸ ich es bereuen werde, mit ihnen gereist zu sein. Zwei von ihnen haben mir innerhalb der letzten Stundn ausf&#252;hrlich die menschliche und elfische Anatomie erkl&#228;rt, und die Fragen, die sie mir stellen, machen deutlich, daÃŸ sie meine Heilerf&#228;higkeiten nicht zum Heilen einsetzen wollen. Dennoch habe ich immer noch die Hoffnung, daÃŸ ich ihr Handeln in eine etwas ... humanere Richtung lenken kann, wenn die Zeit es erlaubt.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Ihre Vorstellungen klingen vern&#252;nftig, ihre Methoden sind jedoch, bestenfalls, fragw&#252;rdig. Die, von ihnen diskutierten, alchemistischen L&#246;sungsvorschl&#228;ge scheinen eher von todbringender als von verbessernder Natur. Letzte Nacht habe ich eine Diskussion mitgeh&#246;rt, in der es um das Anbringen von zus&#228;tzlichen K&#246;rperteilen an lebendes Fleisch ging, zur Verbesserung der 'Leistungsf&#228;higkeit'. Zum Gl&#252;ck scheint ihr Anf&#252;hrer vern&#252;nftiger zu sein. Er ist ein interessanter Mann - wenn es ihn nicht g&#228;be, h&#228;tte ich mich ihnen niemals angeschlossen. Er ist ein fr&#252;herer Erzmagier aus dem Volk der Amuriten, ein Mann mit starken &#252;berzeugungen und hohen Idealen. Sein Traum, und sein Vertrauen in diesen, ist mehr als faszinierend; er ist sch&#246;n: Ausrottung von Krankheiten, Verz&#246;gerung des Alterns und eine Beinahe-Unsterblichkeit, soweit es physische Wunden angeht. Stellt Euch vor, wie das Leben sich f&#252;r alle Lebewesen verbessern w&#252;rde, wenn sein Traum wahr w&#252;rde![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Ich habe lang und ausf&#252;hrlich mit ihm dar&#252;ber geredet, den Menschen zu helfen, er hat mir zugestimmt, dass dies ein erstrebenswertes Unterfangen ist, obwohl es den Eindruck macht, dass ihm die Leute selbst dabei gar nicht so wichtig sind. Er bot also mir einen Platz im Mekara Orden an und ich ... ich habe ihn angenommen, soweit, auch wenn ich mir Gedanken um den Preis mache, der f&#252;r seinen Traum zu zahlen ist. Es gibt da etwas Hartes und Kaltes in ihm, als empf&#228;nde er f&#252;r nichts als f&#252;r seinen Auftrag. Ich kann nur hoffen, dass er mir auch in Zukunft zuh&#246;ren wird."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH] - "Auszug aus dem Tagebuch von Iram Damarr, bez&#252;glich Jamal Dahkar."</German>
		<Italian>"Sono passati parecchi giorni da quando ho lasciato Junon in compagnia di questi membri di Mekara e, per ora, ho l'impressione che potrei arrivare a pentirmi della mia decisione di viaggiare con loro. Due di loro hanno parlato con me a lungo dell'anatomia umana e elfica nelle ultime ore, dalle domande che mi hano fatto è chiaro che non intendono usare le mie conoscenze per curare. Tuttavia, rimango leggermente speranzoso di poterli far deviare verso... posizioni più umane, col tempo.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]I loro ideali sono solidi, ma i loro metodi sono discutibili nella migliore delle ipotesi. Alcune delle soluzioni alchemiche di cui stavano discutendo sembravano più portate ad uccidere che a portare qualsivoglia miglioramento, e la scorsa notte ho sentito una discussione riguardante l'innesto di arti aggiuntivi su esseri viventi per un 'rendimento' maggiore. Fortunatamente il loro leader sembra essere molto più ragionevole. È un'uomo molto interessante, non fosse stato per lui non mi sarei mai unito a loro. È un ex arcimago del popolo Amurite, ed è un uomo di forti convinzioni e alti ideali. Il suo sogno, e la sua fede in esso, è più che affascinante; è bellissimo. L'eliminazione delle malattie, il rallentamento dell'invecchiamento, e la quasi immortalità per quanto riguarda i traumi fisici. Immagina come la vita delle persone potrebbe venir migliorata se il suo sogno venisse realizzato![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Gli ho parlato a lungo di come portare questo alla gente, e ha concordato che vale la pena provarci, anche se sembra interessarsi poco alle persone. Mi ha offerto un posto nell'Ordine Mekara però, e io ho accettato, per ora, sebbene mi preoccupo del prezzo del suo sogno. Vi è qualcosa di duro e freddo dentro di lui, come se non provasse nulla oltre la sua passione per la sua impresa. Posso solo sperare che lui mi ascolti."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH] - "Estratto dal diario di Iram Damarr, riguardo Jamal Dahkar."</Italian>
		<Spanish>"It has been several days since I left Junon in the company of these Mekara fellows, and so far, my impression is that I might come to regret my desicion to travel with them. Two of them have spoken to me at length about human and elven anatomy within the last few hours, and the questions they ask makes it quite clear that they don't intend to use what I know for healing. Still, I remain somewhat hopeful that I can sway them in a more... humane direction, given time.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Their ideals are sound, but their methods are questionable at best. Some of the alchemical solutions they have been discussing seem more likely to kill than bring about any improvement, and last night I overheard a discussion about the grafting of new limbs onto living flesh for improved 'performance'. Thankfully, their leader seems much more sensible. He is an interesting man - if it were not for him, I would never have joined with them. He is a former archmage from the Amurite people, and is a man of strong convictions and high ideals. His dream, and his belief in it, is more than fascinating; it is beautiful. Elimination of disease, the slowing of ageing, and near-immortality as far as physical trauma is concerned. Imagine how life could be improved for the people if his dream can be fulfilled![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]I have spoken to him at length about bringing this to the people, and he has agreed that it is a worthwhile endeavour, though he seems to care little for the people themselves. He has offered me a place in the Mekara Order, however, and I have accepted, for now, though I worry about the price his dream. There is something hard and cold inside him, as if there is nothing he feels except for his passion for his quest. I can only hope that he will listen to me."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH] - "Excerpt from the journal of Iram Damarr, on the subject of Jamal Dahkar."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Leader: Zaria, Name -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ZARIA</Tag>
		<English>Zaria Scheras</English>
		<French>Zaria Scheras</French>
		<German>Zaria Scheras</German>
		<Italian>Zaria Scheras</Italian>
		<Spanish>Zaria Scheras</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Leader: Zaria, Civilopedia Entry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ZARIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Iram felt his frustration building ever higher as he watched the Governor of the city. "It is a wonder the people in the city hasn't starved to death due to her excesses.", he thought as he watched the feast laid out below. Outside in the streets there were children starving, and here in the palace there was a lavish banquet of delicacies from all over the known world assembled for the Mekara Order's pleasure. Meanwhile, the Governor herself was reclining in a throne-like chair surrounded by half-dressed slaves. "A disgrace.", he thought to himself as he watched her. Perhaps something could be done about her later, once the Mekara Order was more firmly entrenched?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]The night before, the negotiations between Governor Zaria Scheras, of the Calabim city of Korasch, and Jamal Dahkar, had been concluded. The results of that negotiation was that the Mekara Order was welcome to settle in the city, finally giving the Mekara Order a permanent home - something that had been sorely needed. The Governor had also generously promised to supply the Mekara Order with all the reagents and test subjects they needed from the city's trading partners and prisons. What she got out of it, Jamal had not told Iram, but looking at the woman he imagined it had something to do with new ways to pleasure herself. What Jamal had told him, however, was that soon, she would no longer care what happened to the city, and that the Mekara Order would slowly but surely take control, and that Iram would have a role to fill in the new government, if he wanted it. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]As much as he hoped this would be the case, he didn't think it would be quite that easy. Zaria was a very clever woman, and very good at manipulating or seducing others to get what she wanted. Despite her excesses, she was also, paradoxically, reasonably well-liked by her people, for reasons that Iram couldn't begin to imagine. "I will have to watch her carefully", he thought to himself, as he wandered off, to find his way back to the Mekara Order's camp.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]As Zaria watched the old healer move away, she smiled to herself. "He won't become a problem.", she thought. "Let him try to run the city and care for the people. They will serve me better in the end, if they are healthy and happy." Jamal would provide her with the tools she would need - mastery over mind magic, and even if control over the city would slip out of her grasp for a time, in the end they would all serve her - in the end they would all love her. With what was possibly the first genuine smile that evening, she returned to the feast.</English>
		<French>Iram felt his frustration building ever higher as he watched the Governor of the city. "It is a wonder the people in the city hasn't starved to death due to her excesses.", he thought as he watched the feast laid out below. Outside in the streets there were children starving, and here in the palace there was a lavish banquet of delicacies from all over the known world assembled for the Mekara Order's pleasure. Meanwhile, the Governor herself was reclining in a throne-like chair surrounded by half-dressed slaves. "A disgrace.", he thought to himself as he watched her. Perhaps something could be done about her later, once the Mekara Order was more firmly entrenched?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]The night before, the negotiations between Governor Zaria Scheras, of the Calabim city of Korasch, and Jamal Dahkar, had been concluded. The results of that negotiation was that the Mekara Order was welcome to settle in the city, finally giving the Mekara Order a permanent home - something that had been sorely needed. The Governor had also generously promised to supply the Mekara Order with all the reagents and test subjects they needed from the city's trading partners and prisons. What she got out of it, Jamal had not told Iram, but looking at the woman he imagined it had something to do with new ways to pleasure herself. What Jamal had told him, however, was that soon, she would no longer care what happened to the city, and that the Mekara Order would slowly but surely take control, and that Iram would have a role to fill in the new government, if he wanted it. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]As much as he hoped this would be the case, he didn't think it would be quite that easy. Zaria was a very clever woman, and very good at manipulating or seducing others to get what she wanted. Despite her excesses, she was also, paradoxically, reasonably well-liked by her people, for reasons that Iram couldn't begin to imagine. "I will have to watch her carefully", he thought to himself, as he wandered off, to find his way back to the Mekara Order's camp.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]As Zaria watched the old healer move away, she smiled to herself. "He won't become a problem.", she thought. "Let him try to run the city and care for the people. They will serve me better in the end, if they are healthy and happy." Jamal would provide her with the tools she would need - mastery over mind magic, and even if control over the city would slip out of her grasp for a time, in the end they would all serve her - in the end they would all love her. With what was possibly the first genuine smile that evening, she returned to the feast.</French>
		<German>Iram f&#252;hlte seine Frustration immer gr&#246;ÃŸer werden, w&#228;hrend er die Herrscherin der Stadt beobachtete. "Es ist ein Wunder, dass die Bev&#246;lkerung der Stadt nicht nicht verhungert ist, trotz ihrer Exzesse.", dachte er, als er das Fest in vollem Gange sah. DrauÃŸen, auf der StraÃŸe, verhungerten Kinder und, hier im Palast, wurde zum Vergn&#252;gen des Mekara Ordens ein verschwenderisches Bankett ausgerichtet, mit Delikatessen aus der gesamten, bekannten Welt. W&#228;hrenddessen lehnte sich die Herrscherin selbst in ihrem Thron-&#228;hnlichen Stuhl zur&#252;ck und lieÃŸ sich von ihren halbbekleideten Sklaven umsorgen. "Eine Schande!", dachte er bei sich, w&#228;hrend er sie so beobachtete. Er w&#252;rde sich vielleicht sp&#228;ter mit ihr befassen, wenn der Mekara Orden erst einmal st&#228;rker verankert w&#228;re.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]In der vorangegangenen Nacht waren die Verhandlungen zwischen Zaria Scheras, der Herrscherin der Calabim Stadt Korasch, und Jamal Dahkar, zu einem Abschluss gekommen. Das Ergebnis dieses &#252;bereinkommens war, daÃŸ es dem Mekara Orden erlaubt war, sich in der Stadt niederzulassen, wodurch dem Mekara Orden endlich ein st&#228;ndiges Zuhause beschert wurde, was dringend n&#246;tig geworden war. Die Herrscherin hatte groÃŸz&#252;gig versprochen, den Orden mit allen Reagenzien und Testsubjekten zu versorgen, die sie ben&#246;tigten: &#252;ber die Handelspartner der Stadt bzw. aus den Gef&#228;ngnissen. Was sie daf&#252;r bekommen sollte, hatte Jamal gegen&#252;ber Iram nicht erw&#228;hnt, aber er sich die Frau so ansah, konnte er sich vorstellen, dass es etwas mit neuen M&#246;glichkeiten zu tun hatte, sich Vergn&#252;gen zu bereiten. Jamal hatte ihm vielmehr erkl&#228;rt, dass Zaria sich bald nicht mehr daf&#252;r interessieren w&#252;rde, was mit der Stadt passierte. Dann w&#252;rde der Mekara Orden langsam aber sicher die Kontrolle &#252;bernehmen, und dann w&#252;rde Iram eine Rolle in der neuen Regierung auszuf&#252;llen haben, wenn er denn wollte.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]So sehr er auch hoffte, dass dies der Fall sein w&#252;rde, glaubte er nicht, dass es so einfach sein w&#252;rde. Zaria war eine &#228;uÃŸert kluge Frau, um zu bekommen, was sie wollte, konnte sie andere sehr gut verf&#252;hren oder manipulieren. Trotz all ihrer Ausschweifungen war sie paradoxerweise bei ihrem Volk einigermaÃŸen beliebt, aus Gr&#252;nden, die sich der Vorstellungskraft Irams entzogen. "Ich werde dich sorgf&#228;ltig beobachten m&#252;ssen", dachte er bei sich, als er sich zur&#252;ckzog, um in das Lager des Mekara Ordens zur&#252;ckzufinden.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Als Zaria den alten Heiler weggehen sah, l&#228;chelte sie. "Er wird kein Problem werden.", dacht sie. "Lass ihn ruhig versuchen, die Stadt zu leiten und sich ums Volk zu k&#252;mmern. Sie werden mir dadurch nur besser dienen, wenn sie gesund und gl&#252;cklich sein sollten." Jamal w&#252;rde sie mit der n&#246;tigen Macht ausstatten, der Meisterschaft der Verstandesmagie, und selbst wenn ihr die Kontrolle &#252;ber die Stadt kurzzeitig einmal entgleiten sollte, zum Schluss w&#252;rden alle ihr dienen, w&#252;rden alle sie lieben. Mit vielleicht dem ersten wirklich ernstgemeinten L&#228;cheln dieses Abends, wandte sie sich wieder dem Fest zu.</German>
		<Italian>Iram sentì la sua frustrazione crescere mentre osservava la Governatrice della città. "È un miracolo che i cittadini non siano morti di fame per via dei suoi eccessi.", pensò mentre osservava il banchetto. Fuori, nelle strade, vi erano bambini che morivano di fame, e qui nel palazzo si svolgeva un sontuoso banchetto, con prelibatezze provenienti da ogni parte del mondo conosciuto, in onore dell'Ordine Mekara. Durante ciò, la Governatrice stessa era adagiata su una poltrona simil trono circondata da schiavi mezzo nudi. "Una vergogna.", pensò mentra la osservava. Forse si sarebbe potuto fare qualcosa al suo riguardo in seguito, una volta che l'Ordine Mekara si fosse stabilito più saldamente?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]La notte prima i negoziati tra la Governatrice Zaria Scheras, della città Calabim chiamata Korasch, e Jamal Dahkar, erano stati conclusi. L'esito dei negoziati fù che l'Ordine Mekara fu invitato a stabilirsi nella città, fornendo infine a quest'ultimo una dimora fissa, una cosa da tempo necessaria. La Governatrice aveva anche generosamente promesso di rifornire l'Ordine Mekara di tutti i reagenti e le cavie necessarie dai partner commerciali e dalle prigioni rispettivamente. Jamal non aveva detto a Iram ciò che lei ci guadagnava, ma osservandola Iram pensò che fosse qualcosa che avesse a che fare con nuovi modi di divertirsi. Quello che Jamal gli disse però, era che a breve lei non si sarebbe più preoccupata di ciò che succedeva alla città, e che l'Ordine Mekara avrebbe piano piano preso inevitabilmente il potere, e che Iram avrebbe avuto un ruolo da ricoprire nel nuovo governo, se lui avesse voluto.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Per quanto sperasse che le cose andassero cosi, riteneva che non sarebbero stato cosi facile. Zaria era una donna molto intelligente, e molto brava a manipolare o sedurre gli altri per ottenere ciò che voleva. Nonostante i suoi eccessi, lei era anche, paradossalmente, ragionevolmente apprezzata dalla sua gente per ragioni che Iram non riusciva a immaginare. "Devrò sorvegliarla attentamente", pensò tra sé, mentre si allontanava per tornare al campo dell'Ordine Mekara.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Mentre Zaria osservava il vecchio guaritore allontanarsi, sorrise. "Lui non sarà un problema.", pensò. "Che provi a gestire la città e prendersi cura delle persone. Mi saranno più utili alla fine, se saranno in salute e felici." Jamal gli avrebbe fornito gli strumenti di cui necessitava, la padronanza della magia della mente, e se anche il controllo della città gli sfuggisse di mano per un pò, alla fine tutti avrebbero servito lei, alla fine tutti la avrebbero amata. Con quello che sarebbe potuto essere il primo sorriso sincero della serata tornò al banchetto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Iram felt his frustration building ever higher as he watched the Governor of the city. "It is a wonder the people in the city hasn't starved to death due to her excesses.", he thought as he watched the feast laid out below. Outside in the streets there were children starving, and here in the palace there was a lavish banquet of delicacies from all over the known world assembled for the Mekara Order's pleasure. Meanwhile, the Governor herself was reclining in a throne-like chair surrounded by half-dressed slaves. "A disgrace.", he thought to himself as he watched her. Perhaps something could be done about her later, once the Mekara Order was more firmly entrenched?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]The night before, the negotiations between Governor Zaria Scheras, of the Calabim city of Korasch, and Jamal Dahkar, had been concluded. The results of that negotiation was that the Mekara Order was welcome to settle in the city, finally giving the Mekara Order a permanent home - something that had been sorely needed. The Governor had also generously promised to supply the Mekara Order with all the reagents and test subjects they needed from the city's trading partners and prisons. What she got out of it, Jamal had not told Iram, but looking at the woman he imagined it had something to do with new ways to pleasure herself. What Jamal had told him, however, was that soon, she would no longer care what happened to the city, and that the Mekara Order would slowly but surely take control, and that Iram would have a role to fill in the new government, if he wanted it. [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]As much as he hoped this would be the case, he didn't think it would be quite that easy. Zaria was a very clever woman, and very good at manipulating or seducing others to get what she wanted. Despite her excesses, she was also, paradoxically, reasonably well-liked by her people, for reasons that Iram couldn't begin to imagine. "I will have to watch her carefully", he thought to himself, as he wandered off, to find his way back to the Mekara Order's camp.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]As Zaria watched the old healer move away, she smiled to herself. "He won't become a problem.", she thought. "Let him try to run the city and care for the people. They will serve me better in the end, if they are healthy and happy." Jamal would provide her with the tools she would need - mastery over mind magic, and even if control over the city would slip out of her grasp for a time, in the end they would all serve her - in the end they would all love her. With what was possibly the first genuine smile that evening, she returned to the feast.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Leader: Iram, Name -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_IRAM</Tag>
		<English>Iram Damarr</English>
		<French>Iram Damarr</French>
		<German>Iram Damarr</German>
		<Italian>Iram Damarr</Italian>
		<Spanish>Iram Damarr</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Leader: Iram, Civilopedia Entry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_IRAM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>While Zaria might rule the Mekaran lands on paper, and Jamal rules over all in the Mekara Order, neither of them take an interest in actually ruling the nation. Neither Zaria's hedonistic excesses, or Jamal's devotion to his research, are qualities that people hope to find in their rulers. Better then, to have a compassionate, practical, and fair ruler; which is what Iram Damarr is to them.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Iram Damarr is a former member of the Ordine Medicos, who joined the Mekara Order during it's years of wandering after their exile. A practical and competent man, and talented healer, he quickly found himself well-liked by members of the Mekara Order, who often consulted him on the structure of the human body, and how it might be improved. As their travels continued, he eventually befriended their leader, becoming a sort of advisor to him in practical matters, as well as serving as quartermaster, a position that gave him a great deal of influence, and often lead to the Mekara Order choosing a more humane course of action. That role also effectively made him the de facto leader of their nation, once they eventually settled down, to the great relief of their subjects.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]His own opinions on the Mekara Order's work are mixed. While he disliked the cruel methods they use, he feels that their goal is worthwhile, and that the fruits of their labour will one day bring about a new age for the common people of Erebus.</English>
		<French>While Zaria might rule the Mekaran lands on paper, and Jamal rules over all in the Mekara Order, neither of them take an interest in actually ruling the nation. Neither Zaria's hedonistic excesses, or Jamal's devotion to his research, are qualities that people hope to find in their rulers. Better then, to have a compassionate, practical, and fair ruler; which is what Iram Damarr is to them.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Iram Damarr is a former member of the Ordine Medicos, who joined the Mekara Order during it's years of wandering after their exile. A practical and competent man, and talented healer, he quickly found himself well-liked by members of the Mekara Order, who often consulted him on the structure of the human body, and how it might be improved. As their travels continued, he eventually befriended their leader, becoming a sort of advisor to him in practical matters, as well as serving as quartermaster, a position that gave him a great deal of influence, and often lead to the Mekara Order choosing a more humane course of action. That role also effectively made him the de facto leader of their nation, once they eventually settled down, to the great relief of their subjects.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]His own opinions on the Mekara Order's work are mixed. While he disliked the cruel methods they use, he feels that their goal is worthwhile, and that the fruits of their labour will one day bring about a new age for the common people of Erebus.</French>
		<German>W&#228;hrend Zaria die Mekaranischen Gebiete auf dem Papier lenken mag, und Jamal dem Mekara Orden vorsteht, zeigt keiner der beiden ein Interesse daran, tats&#228;chlich das Volk zu regieren. Weder Zarias hedonistische Exzesse noch Jamals Hingabe f&#252;r seine Forschungen sind Qualit&#228;ten, die ein Volk in einem F&#252;hrer zu finden hofft. Es ist viel besser, einen anteilnehmenden, praktisch denkenden und gerechten Herrscher zu haben. Und genau das ist Imar in ihren Augen.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Iram Damarr ist ein ehemaliges Mitglied des Ordine Medicos, der sich dem Mekara Orden w&#228;hrend dessen Umherziehens nach der Verbannung anschloss. Ein prakitscher und kompetenter Mann, ein talentierter Heiler, er wurde schnell bei den anderen Mitgliedern des Mekara Ordens beliebt, die ihn h&#228;ufig wegen der Beschaffenheit des menschlichen K&#246;rpers und den M&#246;glichkeiten, ihn zu verbessern,  konsultierten. W&#228;hrend der Reise freundete er sich schlieÃŸlich mit deren F&#252;hrer an, wodurch er zu dessen Berater in praktischen Fragen aufstieg. AuÃŸerdem &#252;bernahm er die Position des Quartiermeisters, eine Stellung, die ihm groÃŸen Einfluss einbrachte und daf&#252;r sorgte, dass der Mekara Orden einen humaneren Weg des Handelns einschlug. Nachdem sich der Orden niedergelassen hatte, machte diese Rolle Iram dar&#252;ber hinaus zum eigentlichen F&#252;hrer des Staates, sehr zur Erleichterung der Bev&#246;lkerung.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Seine eigenen Ansichten zur Arbeit des Mekara Ordens sind nicht eindeutig. W&#228;hrend er die grausamen Methoden ablehnt, sp&#252;rt er, dass das groÃŸe Ziel die Anstrengungen lohnt, und dass die Fr&#252;chte ihrer Arbeit eines Tages ein neues Zeitalter f&#252;r die einfachen Menschen von Erebus einl&#228;uten werden.</German>
		<Italian>Anche se sulla carta è Zaria a governare le terre dei Mekara, e Jamal a gestire tutto l'Ordine Mekara, nessuno dei due è interessato a governare la nazione. Né gli eccessi edonistici di Zaria, o la devozione di Jamal alla sua ricerca, sono qualità che la gente spera di trovare nei loro sovrani. Meglio averne uno compassionevole, concreto e giusto; esattamente ciò che Iram Damarr è ai loro occhi.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Iram Damarr è un ex membro dell'Ordine Medicos, che si unì all'Ordine Mekara durante gli anni di girovagare di quest'ultimo dopo essere stato esiliato. Un uomo pratico e competente, oltre ad essere un guaritore di talento, divenne presto apprezzato dai membri dell'Ordine Mekara, i quali spesso chiedevano il suo parere sulla struttura del corpo umano, e su come poterlo migliorare. Durante i loro viaggi fece amicizia con il loro leader, diventando una sorta di consigliere riguardo le questioni pratiche, oltre a servire come quartiermastro, una posizione che gli fornì una grande influenza, e che spesso portò l'Ordine Mekara ad una condotta più umana. Tale ruolo lo rese di fatto il vero leader della nazione, una volta essersi insediati, con grande sollievo dei loro sudditi.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Le sue opinioni sull'operato dell'Ordine Mekara sono miste. Sebbene non gli piacciono i crudeli metodi usati, ritiene che il traguardo sia degno di essere perseguito, e che i frutti del loro lavoro possano, un giorno, iniziare una nuova era per la gente comune di Erebus.</Italian>
		<Spanish>While Zaria might rule the Mekaran lands on paper, and Jamal rules over all in the Mekara Order, neither of them take an interest in actually ruling the nation. Neither Zaria's hedonistic excesses, or Jamal's devotion to his research, are qualities that people hope to find in their rulers. Better then, to have a compassionate, practical, and fair ruler; which is what Iram Damarr is to them.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Iram Damarr is a former member of the Ordine Medicos, who joined the Mekara Order during it's years of wandering after their exile. A practical and competent man, and talented healer, he quickly found himself well-liked by members of the Mekara Order, who often consulted him on the structure of the human body, and how it might be improved. As their travels continued, he eventually befriended their leader, becoming a sort of advisor to him in practical matters, as well as serving as quartermaster, a position that gave him a great deal of influence, and often lead to the Mekara Order choosing a more humane course of action. That role also effectively made him the de facto leader of their nation, once they eventually settled down, to the great relief of their subjects.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]His own opinions on the Mekara Order's work are mixed. While he disliked the cruel methods they use, he feels that their goal is worthwhile, and that the fruits of their labour will one day bring about a new age for the common people of Erebus.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Corgayle -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CORGAYLE</Tag>
		<English>Corgayle</English>
		<French>Corgayle</French>
		<German>Corgayle</German>
		<Italian>Corgayle</Italian>
		<Spanish>Corgayle</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Corgayle, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CORGAYLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As Corgayle entered the room which the city's new master had made into his office, he noticed how sparsely decorated it was. He remembered seeing Governor Zaria's rooms once, back before the Mekara Order had arrived. They had been lavishly decorated - gold and silk; paintings and statues - a picture of wasted wealth that had infuriated him when he considered the squalor that he and his family had been forced to endure for his entire life. This man was clearly a different sort. Corgayle had heard little about him; very little, truth be told, considering that he was the true ruler of the city now. His eyes swept over the man sitting by the desk in front of him. Thin, gaunt, with pale skin and dark hair, shot through with grey. Simple, practical clothes, without any visible adornments. All in all not a man one would expect to be ruling a city, much less a nation. But there was something in the way he held himself, an unmistakable air of command that could not be ignored.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Sit.", the man said, indicating a chair sitting opposite him, his head still lowered as he was reading from a paper lying on the desk. Corgayle sat down in the chair, somewhat apprehensive about what was to come. The man raised his head, looking at Corgayle for the first time. His eyes were hard and cold, with a strange shine to them, as if fires played far behind them. "Iram tells me that you've been causing us trouble.", he said, in a calm tone that betrayed no emotion, "I am Jamal Dahkar, the Master of the Mekara Order", he continued, "and your life belongs to me now."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle shivered under that gaze. "The offer I am about to give you is not one I give to just any criminals that break the laws of my nation." he said, still holding Corgayle's eyes with his own, "I am going to give you the chance to determine the course of your life." Corgayle braced himself for what he knew would come. He had seen it before, during the days when the Governor ruled. Slavery or death. A quick death, or a slow, torturous one. Jamal continued, "The Order will see to your needs; we will see to it that you have everything you could want. In return, we want you to lead our warriors."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle started. He wondered if he'd heard that right, or if it'd just been his imagination. "I led one of the most powerful street-gangs this city has seen", he thought, "I've extorted businesses. I've robbed and killed countless people. And this man is offering me a life of luxury for it? And command over their soldiers?" "What?" he stuttered.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Jamal smiled. "As I said, this is not an offer I would give to just anyone. You have potential; your 'work' in the city clearly shows that." He leaned forward, and his voice grew more intense, "We have need of men like you; intelligent and practical men, who knows how to do what is neccessary." Corgayle was stunned. "Why?", he said, his mind racing. "Our work requires a continous supply of subjects for our experiments." Jamal said, in a calmer, more relaxed tone, "and we want you to get them for us." He smiled, and that smile sent chills down Corgayle's spine. "You will train and lead our forces; you will conduct raids on our enemies, and you will bring them back to us, reasonably intact."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Do I have a choice?", Corgayle asked. Jamal Dahkar simply smiled at him.</English>
		<French>As Corgayle entered the room which the city's new master had made into his office, he noticed how sparsely decorated it was. He remembered seeing Governor Zaria's rooms once, back before the Mekara Order had arrived. They had been lavishly decorated - gold and silk; paintings and statues - a picture of wasted wealth that had infuriated him when he considered the squalor that he and his family had been forced to endure for his entire life. This man was clearly a different sort. Corgayle had heard little about him; very little, truth be told, considering that he was the true ruler of the city now. His eyes swept over the man sitting by the desk in front of him. Thin, gaunt, with pale skin and dark hair, shot through with grey. Simple, practical clothes, without any visible adornments. All in all not a man one would expect to be ruling a city, much less a nation. But there was something in the way he held himself, an unmistakable air of command that could not be ignored.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Sit.", the man said, indicating a chair sitting opposite him, his head still lowered as he was reading from a paper lying on the desk. Corgayle sat down in the chair, somewhat apprehensive about what was to come. The man raised his head, looking at Corgayle for the first time. His eyes were hard and cold, with a strange shine to them, as if fires played far behind them. "Iram tells me that you've been causing us trouble.", he said, in a calm tone that betrayed no emotion, "I am Jamal Dahkar, the Master of the Mekara Order", he continued, "and your life belongs to me now."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle shivered under that gaze. "The offer I am about to give you is not one I give to just any criminals that break the laws of my nation." he said, still holding Corgayle's eyes with his own, "I am going to give you the chance to determine the course of your life." Corgayle braced himself for what he knew would come. He had seen it before, during the days when the Governor ruled. Slavery or death. A quick death, or a slow, torturous one. Jamal continued, "The Order will see to your needs; we will see to it that you have everything you could want. In return, we want you to lead our warriors."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle started. He wondered if he'd heard that right, or if it'd just been his imagination. "I led one of the most powerful street-gangs this city has seen", he thought, "I've extorted businesses. I've robbed and killed countless people. And this man is offering me a life of luxury for it? And command over their soldiers?" "What?" he stuttered.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Jamal smiled. "As I said, this is not an offer I would give to just anyone. You have potential; your 'work' in the city clearly shows that." He leaned forward, and his voice grew more intense, "We have need of men like you; intelligent and practical men, who knows how to do what is neccessary." Corgayle was stunned. "Why?", he said, his mind racing. "Our work requires a continous supply of subjects for our experiments." Jamal said, in a calmer, more relaxed tone, "and we want you to get them for us." He smiled, and that smile sent chills down Corgayle's spine. "You will train and lead our forces; you will conduct raids on our enemies, and you will bring them back to us, reasonably intact."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Do I have a choice?", Corgayle asked. Jamal Dahkar simply smiled at him.</French>
		<German>As Corgayle entered the room which the city's new master had made into his office, he noticed how sparsely decorated it was. He remembered seeing Governor Zaria's rooms once, back before the Mekara Order had arrived. They had been lavishly decorated - gold and silk; paintings and statues - a picture of wasted wealth that had infuriated him when he considered the squalor that he and his family had been forced to endure for his entire life. This man was clearly a different sort. Corgayle had heard little about him; very little, truth be told, considering that he was the true ruler of the city now. His eyes swept over the man sitting by the desk in front of him. Thin, gaunt, with pale skin and dark hair, shot through with grey. Simple, practical clothes, without any visible adornments. All in all not a man one would expect to be ruling a city, much less a nation. But there was something in the way he held himself, an unmistakable air of command that could not be ignored.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Sit.", the man said, indicating a chair sitting opposite him, his head still lowered as he was reading from a paper lying on the desk. Corgayle sat down in the chair, somewhat apprehensive about what was to come. The man raised his head, looking at Corgayle for the first time. His eyes were hard and cold, with a strange shine to them, as if fires played far behind them. "Iram tells me that you've been causing us trouble.", he said, in a calm tone that betrayed no emotion, "I am Jamal Dahkar, the Master of the Mekara Order", he continued, "and your life belongs to me now."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle shivered under that gaze. "The offer I am about to give you is not one I give to just any criminals that break the laws of my nation." he said, still holding Corgayle's eyes with his own, "I am going to give you the chance to determine the course of your life." Corgayle braced himself for what he knew would come. He had seen it before, during the days when the Governor ruled. Slavery or death. A quick death, or a slow, torturous one. Jamal continued, "The Order will see to your needs; we will see to it that you have everything you could want. In return, we want you to lead our warriors."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle started. He wondered if he'd heard that right, or if it'd just been his imagination. "I led one of the most powerful street-gangs this city has seen", he thought, "I've extorted businesses. I've robbed and killed countless people. And this man is offering me a life of luxury for it? And command over their soldiers?" "What?" he stuttered.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Jamal smiled. "As I said, this is not an offer I would give to just anyone. You have potential; your 'work' in the city clearly shows that." He leaned forward, and his voice grew more intense, "We have need of men like you; intelligent and practical men, who knows how to do what is neccessary." Corgayle was stunned. "Why?", he said, his mind racing. "Our work requires a continous supply of subjects for our experiments." Jamal said, in a calmer, more relaxed tone, "and we want you to get them for us." He smiled, and that smile sent chills down Corgayle's spine. "You will train and lead our forces; you will conduct raids on our enemies, and you will bring them back to us, reasonably intact."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Do I have a choice?", Corgayle asked. Jamal Dahkar simply smiled at him.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre Corgayle entrava nella stanza che il nuovo signore della città aveva reso il suo ufficio notò quanto scarsamente decorato fosse. Ricordava di aver visto le stanze della Governatrice Zaria tempo fa, quando l'Ordine Mekara non era ancora arrivato. Quelle erano riccamente decorate, con seta e oro; dipinti e statue, uno spreco di ricchezza che lo aveva fatto infuriare quando considerò lo squallore che lui e la sua famiglia avevano dovuto sopportare per tutta la loro vita. Quest'uomo era chiaramente diverso. Corgayle aveva sentito poco sul suo conto; molto poco veramente, considerando che lui era ora il vero governatore della città. I suoi occhi si posarono sull'uomo seduto alla scrivania di fronte a lui. Magro, scarno, con pelle chiara e capelli scuri, con ciuffi grigi. Abiti semplici e pratici, senza ornamenti visibili. Tutto sommato non uno che ci si aspetterebbe governi una città, tanto meno una nazione. Ma vi era qualcosa nel suo modo di fare, un'inconfondibile aria di comando che non poteva essere ignorata.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Sedete.", l'uomo disse, indicando una sedia davanti a lui, la sua testa ancora china mentre leggeva qualcosa da un foglio sulla scrivania. Corgayle si sedette sulla sedia un pò preoccupato per ciò che sarebbe successo. L'uomo alzò la testa, guardando Corgayle per la prima volta. I suoi occhi erano duri e freddi, con una strana luce in essi, come se vi fosse una fiamma distante dietro. "Iram mi ha detto che ci stai creando dei problemi.", disse, in tono calmo senza alcuna emozione, "Io sono Jamal Dahkar, il Maestro dell'Ordine Mekara", continuò, "e la tua vita appartiene a me ora."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle rabbrividì sotto quello sguardo. "L'offerta che ti sto per fare non è una che farei a qualsiasi criminale che infrange le leggi della mia nazione." disse, mantenendo il contatto visivo con gli occhi di Corgayle, "Ti darò la possibilità di determinare il corso della tua vita." Corgayle si preparò per ciò che sapeva stava arrivando. Ci era già passato, quando regnava la Governatrice. Schiavitù o morte. Una veloce, o una lenta e tortuosa. Jamal continuò, "L'Ordine si occuperebbe dei tuoi bisogni; faremo in modo che tu abbia tutto ciò che potresti volere. In cambio, vogliamo che guidi i nostri guerrieri."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle trasalì. Si chiese se avesse sentito bene, o se fosse stata la sua immaginazione. "Io guido una delle bande di strada più potenti che questa città abbia visto", pensò, "Ho compiuto estorsioni. Ho derubato e ucciso innumerevoli persone. E quest'uomo mi sta offrendo una vita di lusso per questo? E di comandare i suoi soldati?" "Cosa?" balbettò.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Jamal sorrise. "Come ho detto, questa non è un'offerta che farei a chiunque. Hai del potenziale; il tuo 'lavoro' in città lo dimostra chiaramente." Si sporse in avanti, e la sua voce si fece più intensa, "Abbiamo bisogno di uomini come te; uomini intelligenti e concreti, che sanno come fare ciò che è necessario." Corgayle era sbalordito. "Perché?", disse, la sua mente in subbuglio. "Il nostro lavoro richiede un rifornimento costante di esemplari per i nostri esperimenti." Jamal disse, con un tono più calmo e rilassato, "e noi vogliamo che tu li prenda per noi." Sorrise, e quel sorriso fece rabbrividire Corgayle. "Tu addestrerai e guiderai le nostre forze; effettuerai incursioni contro i nostri nemici, e li porterai da noi, ragionevolmente intatti."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Ho scelta?", Corgayle chiese. Jamal Dahkar gli sorrise soltanto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>As Corgayle entered the room which the city's new master had made into his office, he noticed how sparsely decorated it was. He remembered seeing Governor Zaria's rooms once, back before the Mekara Order had arrived. They had been lavishly decorated - gold and silk; paintings and statues - a picture of wasted wealth that had infuriated him when he considered the squalor that he and his family had been forced to endure for his entire life. This man was clearly a different sort. Corgayle had heard little about him; very little, truth be told, considering that he was the true ruler of the city now. His eyes swept over the man sitting by the desk in front of him. Thin, gaunt, with pale skin and dark hair, shot through with grey. Simple, practical clothes, without any visible adornments. All in all not a man one would expect to be ruling a city, much less a nation. But there was something in the way he held himself, an unmistakable air of command that could not be ignored.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Sit.", the man said, indicating a chair sitting opposite him, his head still lowered as he was reading from a paper lying on the desk. Corgayle sat down in the chair, somewhat apprehensive about what was to come. The man raised his head, looking at Corgayle for the first time. His eyes were hard and cold, with a strange shine to them, as if fires played far behind them. "Iram tells me that you've been causing us trouble.", he said, in a calm tone that betrayed no emotion, "I am Jamal Dahkar, the Master of the Mekara Order", he continued, "and your life belongs to me now."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle shivered under that gaze. "The offer I am about to give you is not one I give to just any criminals that break the laws of my nation." he said, still holding Corgayle's eyes with his own, "I am going to give you the chance to determine the course of your life." Corgayle braced himself for what he knew would come. He had seen it before, during the days when the Governor ruled. Slavery or death. A quick death, or a slow, torturous one. Jamal continued, "The Order will see to your needs; we will see to it that you have everything you could want. In return, we want you to lead our warriors."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle started. He wondered if he'd heard that right, or if it'd just been his imagination. "I led one of the most powerful street-gangs this city has seen", he thought, "I've extorted businesses. I've robbed and killed countless people. And this man is offering me a life of luxury for it? And command over their soldiers?" "What?" he stuttered.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Jamal smiled. "As I said, this is not an offer I would give to just anyone. You have potential; your 'work' in the city clearly shows that." He leaned forward, and his voice grew more intense, "We have need of men like you; intelligent and practical men, who knows how to do what is neccessary." Corgayle was stunned. "Why?", he said, his mind racing. "Our work requires a continous supply of subjects for our experiments." Jamal said, in a calmer, more relaxed tone, "and we want you to get them for us." He smiled, and that smile sent chills down Corgayle's spine. "You will train and lead our forces; you will conduct raids on our enemies, and you will bring them back to us, reasonably intact."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Do I have a choice?", Corgayle asked. Jamal Dahkar simply smiled at him.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Corgayle Ascended-->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CORGAYLE_ASCENDED</Tag>
		<English>Corgayle Ascended</English>
		<French>Corgayle Exalté</French>
		<German>Erhabener Corgayle</German>
		<Italian>Corgayle Asceso</Italian>
		<Spanish>Corgayle Ascended</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Corgayle Ascended, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CORGAYLE_ASCENDED_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As the ritual finished, he felt himself dropping to the floor. Dazed, he tried to stand, but only succeeded at the second attempt. He looked down on his body - his body - and wondered who he had become. He was no taller than he had been before, but he was more muscular, and his body felt somehow too flexible, as he moved around, trying to regain his balance. The scars of old wounds he had taken in slave raids over the years were disappearing before his eyes, old aches were fading so quickly he almost thought he'd imagined them all those years.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked up, trying to center himself, and looked at the people assembled around him. Seven figures stood arrayed in front of him, watching him. He heard a voice, trembling slightly with anticipation.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Were we successful?" it asked.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Yes." said another, this one cold and hard as stone. "At least, it would seem so. How do you feel?"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He swung his head in the direction of the second voice, and looked at the figure standing in front of him. Jamal. His vision was clearing up. He could see the seven more clearly now. Rough, practical clothing, few adornments, faces scarred and tired, all but one tense with anticipation. He looked at them, and found that he was "aware" of them in ways he didn't remember. He could hear the beats of their hearts from the other side of the room; could smell their scent, and could "feel" them standing there, even with his eyes closed. He could feel power emanating from them, like waves flowing outward, each one a different flavour. He started to speak.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"I feel...", he began, "...different."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked around, and his eyes caught a chair standing against the nearby wall. He looked at it - "felt" it standing there, like a hard object pressing against his mind. He reached out with his thoughts, and grabbed on to it, and saw it lift into the air. He focused on the chair, pressing aginst it with all the concentration he could muster. The splinters flew halfway across the room, and he registered surprise and excitement on some of the the faces before him.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Good." continued Jamal, stepping forward to examine him more closely, "Your body seems to be regenerating; exellent.", he continued, "We will have to keep you under observation for some time, of course, to make sure there are no adverse side effects. I expect..."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle stopped listening. He looked at the other mages, who were finally starting to relax, realising that they had been successful. Relief, and excitement registered on their faces as they took their leave, and Corgayle cast his mind back to when he had first met this group. He smiled to himself. "They would never have believed that I could come this far." he thought to himself. "Arrogant bastards."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked down at his new body again. "Strange", he thought, "but I can get used to it." As he looked out over the city outside the windows, he considered the path that had taken him to this place. His childhood on the streets of the town where he'd been born; his time training under the sadistic bastard he'd called his father; to the time when he had finally showed him how quickly he learned, and displaced him as the leader of his gang, leaving him in a shallow grave. "No", he thought, and looked at Jamal, "This is my father now". He was no longer the man he had been only an hour ago. He was new. Reborn. Ascended.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]And as that thought crossed his mind, he could feel the memories of his past slipping away, fading. And he smiled.</English>
		<French>As the ritual finished, he felt himself dropping to the floor. Dazed, he tried to stand, but only succeeded at the second attempt. He looked down on his body - his body - and wondered who he had become. He was no taller than he had been before, but he was more muscular, and his body felt somehow too flexible, as he moved around, trying to regain his balance. The scars of old wounds he had taken in slave raids over the years were disappearing before his eyes, old aches were fading so quickly he almost thought he'd imagined them all those years.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked up, trying to center himself, and looked at the people assembled around him. Seven figures stood arrayed in front of him, watching him. He heard a voice, trembling slightly with anticipation.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Were we successful?" it asked.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Yes." said another, this one cold and hard as stone. "At least, it would seem so. How do you feel?"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He swung his head in the direction of the second voice, and looked at the figure standing in front of him. Jamal. His vision was clearing up. He could see the seven more clearly now. Rough, practical clothing, few adornments, faces scarred and tired, all but one tense with anticipation. He looked at them, and found that he was "aware" of them in ways he didn't remember. He could hear the beats of their hearts from the other side of the room; could smell their scent, and could "feel" them standing there, even with his eyes closed. He could feel power emanating from them, like waves flowing outward, each one a different flavour. He started to speak.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"I feel...", he began, "...different."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked around, and his eyes caught a chair standing against the nearby wall. He looked at it - "felt" it standing there, like a hard object pressing against his mind. He reached out with his thoughts, and grabbed on to it, and saw it lift into the air. He focused on the chair, pressing aginst it with all the concentration he could muster. The splinters flew halfway across the room, and he registered surprise and excitement on some of the the faces before him.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Good." continued Jamal, stepping forward to examine him more closely, "Your body seems to be regenerating; exellent.", he continued, "We will have to keep you under observation for some time, of course, to make sure there are no adverse side effects. I expect..."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle stopped listening. He looked at the other mages, who were finally starting to relax, realising that they had been successful. Relief, and excitement registered on their faces as they took their leave, and Corgayle cast his mind back to when he had first met this group. He smiled to himself. "They would never have believed that I could come this far." he thought to himself. "Arrogant bastards."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked down at his new body again. "Strange", he thought, "but I can get used to it." As he looked out over the city outside the windows, he considered the path that had taken him to this place. His childhood on the streets of the town where he'd been born; his time training under the sadistic bastard he'd called his father; to the time when he had finally showed him how quickly he learned, and displaced him as the leader of his gang, leaving him in a shallow grave. "No", he thought, and looked at Jamal, "This is my father now". He was no longer the man he had been only an hour ago. He was new. Reborn. Ascended.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]And as that thought crossed his mind, he could feel the memories of his past slipping away, fading. And he smiled.</French>
		<German>As the ritual finished, he felt himself dropping to the floor. Dazed, he tried to stand, but only succeeded at the second attempt. He looked down on his body - his body - and wondered who he had become. He was no taller than he had been before, but he was more muscular, and his body felt somehow too flexible, as he moved around, trying to regain his balance. The scars of old wounds he had taken in slave raids over the years were disappearing before his eyes, old aches were fading so quickly he almost thought he'd imagined them all those years.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked up, trying to center himself, and looked at the people assembled around him. Seven figures stood arrayed in front of him, watching him. He heard a voice, trembling slightly with anticipation.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Were we successful?" it asked.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Yes." said another, this one cold and hard as stone. "At least, it would seem so. How do you feel?"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He swung his head in the direction of the second voice, and looked at the figure standing in front of him. Jamal. His vision was clearing up. He could see the seven more clearly now. Rough, practical clothing, few adornments, faces scarred and tired, all but one tense with anticipation. He looked at them, and found that he was "aware" of them in ways he didn't remember. He could hear the beats of their hearts from the other side of the room; could smell their scent, and could "feel" them standing there, even with his eyes closed. He could feel power emanating from them, like waves flowing outward, each one a different flavour. He started to speak.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"I feel...", he began, "...different."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked around, and his eyes caught a chair standing against the nearby wall. He looked at it - "felt" it standing there, like a hard object pressing against his mind. He reached out with his thoughts, and grabbed on to it, and saw it lift into the air. He focused on the chair, pressing aginst it with all the concentration he could muster. The splinters flew halfway across the room, and he registered surprise and excitement on some of the the faces before him.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Good." continued Jamal, stepping forward to examine him more closely, "Your body seems to be regenerating; exellent.", he continued, "We will have to keep you under observation for some time, of course, to make sure there are no adverse side effects. I expect..."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle stopped listening. He looked at the other mages, who were finally starting to relax, realising that they had been successful. Relief, and excitement registered on their faces as they took their leave, and Corgayle cast his mind back to when he had first met this group. He smiled to himself. "They would never have believed that I could come this far." he thought to himself. "Arrogant bastards."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked down at his new body again. "Strange", he thought, "but I can get used to it." As he looked out over the city outside the windows, he considered the path that had taken him to this place. His childhood on the streets of the town where he'd been born; his time training under the sadistic bastard he'd called his father; to the time when he had finally showed him how quickly he learned, and displaced him as the leader of his gang, leaving him in a shallow grave. "No", he thought, and looked at Jamal, "This is my father now". He was no longer the man he had been only an hour ago. He was new. Reborn. Ascended.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]And as that thought crossed his mind, he could feel the memories of his past slipping away, fading. And he smiled.</German>
		<Italian>Al termine del rituale si senti venir poggiato sul pavimento. Frastornato cercò di rialzarsi, ma ci riuscì solo al secondo tentativo. Abbassò lo sguardo sul suo corpo, e si chiese chi fosse diventato. Non era più alto di prima, ma era più muscoloso, e il suo corpo sembrava in qualche modo più flessibile mentre cercava di ritrovare l'equilibrio. Le cicatrici di vecchie ferite subite durante le incursioni compiute negli anni stavano svanendo davanti ai suoi occhi, e i dolori dovuti all'età stavano sparendo così rapidamente che quasi pensò se li fosse immaginati per tutti questi anni.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Alzò lo sguardo e guardò le persone che si stavano assemblando attorno a lui. Sette figure gli stavano attorno, guardandolo. Sentì una voce con una leggera vena di eccitazione.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Abbiamo avuto successo?" chiese.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Si." disse un'altro, questa voce fredda e dura come la pietra. "Perlomeno sembrerebbe cosi. Come ti senti?"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Voltò la testa verso la direzione della seconda voce e osservò la figura che aveva di fornte. Jamal. La sua vista si stava schiarendo. Poteva vedere le figure più chiaramente ora. Vestiti pratici, pochi ornamenti, facce stanche e sfregiate, tutte tranne una piene di eccitazione. Le osservò, e si rese conto di essere "cosciente" di loro in una maniera che non si ricordava. Poteva sentire il battito dei loro cuori dalla parte opposta della stanza; poteva sentire il loro odore, e poteva "percepirli" li in piedi, anche con gli occhi chiusi. Poteva sentire il potere emanato da loro, come onde che si allontanano da un epicentro, ognuna con un aroma diverso. Iniziò a parlare.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Mi sento...", iniziò, "...diverso."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Si guardò intorno e vide una sedia poggiata al muro. La guardò, la "percepiva" li, come un oggetto duro che gli preme contro la mente. La raggiunse col pensiero e la afferrò, e la vide sollevarsi in aria. Si concentrò su di essa, pressandola con tutta la concentrazione che riusciva ad avere. I frammenti volarono sino a metà della stanza, e notò sorpresa ed eccitazione in alcune delle facce che aveva davanti.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Bene." continuò Jamal, avvicinandosi per esaminarlo meglio, "Il tuo corpo sembra si stia rigenerando; eccellente.", continuò, "Dovremo tenerti sotto osservazione per un po di tempo, ovviamente, per assicurarci che non vi siano effetti collaterali negativi. Mi aspetto..."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle smise di ascoltare. Osservò gli altri maghi, che stavano infine iniziando a rilassarsi mentre si rendevono conto che avevano avuto successo. Sollievo ed eccitazione erano presenti sulle loro facce quando si congedavano, e Corgayle ripensò a quando aveva incontrato questo gruppo per la prima volta. Sorrise. "Non avrebbero mai creduto che sarei potuto arrivare cosi lontano." pensò. "Bastardi arroganti."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Guardò di nuovo il suo nuovo corpo. "Strano", pensò, "ma mi ci posso abituare." Mentre osservava la città fuori dalla finestra considerò il percorso che lo aveva portato sin qui. La sua infanzia per le strade della città dove era nato; il tempo passato ad addestrarsi con quel sadico bastardo che chiamava padre; sino al momento in cui gli aveva infine dimostrato quanto rapidamente aveva appreso, e lo sostituì come capo della sua banda, lasciandolo in una fossa poco profonda. "No", pensò, e guardò a Jamal, "Lui è mio padre adesso". Non era più l'uomo che era un ora fa. Era nuovo. Rinato. Asceso.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]E mentre quel pensiero gli attraversava la mente percepiva i ricordi del suo passato scivolare via, svanire. E sorrise.</Italian>
		<Spanish>As the ritual finished, he felt himself dropping to the floor. Dazed, he tried to stand, but only succeeded at the second attempt. He looked down on his body - his body - and wondered who he had become. He was no taller than he had been before, but he was more muscular, and his body felt somehow too flexible, as he moved around, trying to regain his balance. The scars of old wounds he had taken in slave raids over the years were disappearing before his eyes, old aches were fading so quickly he almost thought he'd imagined them all those years.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked up, trying to center himself, and looked at the people assembled around him. Seven figures stood arrayed in front of him, watching him. He heard a voice, trembling slightly with anticipation.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Were we successful?" it asked.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Yes." said another, this one cold and hard as stone. "At least, it would seem so. How do you feel?"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He swung his head in the direction of the second voice, and looked at the figure standing in front of him. Jamal. His vision was clearing up. He could see the seven more clearly now. Rough, practical clothing, few adornments, faces scarred and tired, all but one tense with anticipation. He looked at them, and found that he was "aware" of them in ways he didn't remember. He could hear the beats of their hearts from the other side of the room; could smell their scent, and could "feel" them standing there, even with his eyes closed. He could feel power emanating from them, like waves flowing outward, each one a different flavour. He started to speak.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"I feel...", he began, "...different."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked around, and his eyes caught a chair standing against the nearby wall. He looked at it - "felt" it standing there, like a hard object pressing against his mind. He reached out with his thoughts, and grabbed on to it, and saw it lift into the air. He focused on the chair, pressing aginst it with all the concentration he could muster. The splinters flew halfway across the room, and he registered surprise and excitement on some of the the faces before him.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"Good." continued Jamal, stepping forward to examine him more closely, "Your body seems to be regenerating; exellent.", he continued, "We will have to keep you under observation for some time, of course, to make sure there are no adverse side effects. I expect..."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Corgayle stopped listening. He looked at the other mages, who were finally starting to relax, realising that they had been successful. Relief, and excitement registered on their faces as they took their leave, and Corgayle cast his mind back to when he had first met this group. He smiled to himself. "They would never have believed that I could come this far." he thought to himself. "Arrogant bastards."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]He looked down at his new body again. "Strange", he thought, "but I can get used to it." As he looked out over the city outside the windows, he considered the path that had taken him to this place. His childhood on the streets of the town where he'd been born; his time training under the sadistic bastard he'd called his father; to the time when he had finally showed him how quickly he learned, and displaced him as the leader of his gang, leaving him in a shallow grave. "No", he thought, and looked at Jamal, "This is my father now". He was no longer the man he had been only an hour ago. He was new. Reborn. Ascended.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]And as that thought crossed his mind, he could feel the memories of his past slipping away, fading. And he smiled.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Corgayle, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CORGAYLE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>When Corgayle enters the game, he starts out as a mixture between the Bounty Hunter and Assassin units. Once the appropriate techs have been researched, he can spend some turns in training in the capital to add additional skills to his repetoir:[PARAGRAPH:2][TAB]At Tracking he can gain the ability to move through a rival's territory without open borders[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Sorcery he can gain access to rank 1 spells[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Strength of Mind, he can gain access to rank 2 spells[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Divine Essence, he can Ascend, changing into a powerful Immortal/Archmage hybrid unit.</English>
		<French>When Corgayle enters the game, he starts out as a mixture between the Bounty Hunter and Assassin units. Once the appropriate techs have been researched, he can spend some turns in training in the capital to add additional skills to his repetoir:[PARAGRAPH:2][TAB]At Tracking he can gain the ability to move through a rival's territory without open borders[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Sorcery he can gain access to rank 1 spells[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Strength of Mind, he can gain access to rank 2 spells[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Divine Essence, he can Ascend, changing into a powerful Immortal/Archmage hybrid unit.</French>
		<German>When Corgayle enters the game, he starts out as a mixture between the Bounty Hunter and Assassin units. Once the appropriate techs have been researched, he can spend some turns in training in the capital to add additional skills to his repetoir:[PARAGRAPH:2][TAB]At Tracking he can gain the ability to move through a rival's territory without open borders[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Sorcery he can gain access to rank 1 spells[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Strength of Mind, he can gain access to rank 2 spells[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Divine Essence, he can Ascend, changing into a powerful Immortal/Archmage hybrid unit.</German>
		<Italian>Quando Corgayle viene creato inizia come un mix tra l'unità Cacciatore di Taglie e l'unità Assassino. Una volta scoperte certe tecnologie può passare qualche turno ad addestrarsi nella capitale per guadagnare abilità aggiuntive:[PARAGRAPH:2][TAB]Con 'Seguire Tracce' ottiene la capacità di muoversi nei territori avversari senza avere diritto di passaggio[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]Con 'Stregoneria' può ottenere magie di 1° livello[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]Con 'Forza di Volontà' può ottenere magie di 2° livello[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]Con 'Essenza Divina' può Ascendere, diventando una potente unità ibrida Immortale/Arcimago.</Italian>
		<Spanish>When Corgayle enters the game, he starts out as a mixture between the Bounty Hunter and Assassin units. Once the appropriate techs have been researched, he can spend some turns in training in the capital to add additional skills to his repetoir:[PARAGRAPH:2][TAB]At Tracking he can gain the ability to move through a rival's territory without open borders[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Sorcery he can gain access to rank 1 spells[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Strength of Mind, he can gain access to rank 2 spells[PARAGRAPH:1][TAB]At Divine Essence, he can Ascend, changing into a powerful Immortal/Archmage hybrid unit.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Karas -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KARAS</Tag>
		<English>Karas</English>
		<French>Karas</French>
		<German>Karas</German>
		<Italian>Karas</Italian>
		<Spanish>Karas</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Karas, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KARAS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Despite not being a very talented mage, Karas is one of the more prominent members of the Mekara Order. The reason for this is that he is the man who engineered the most vital part of the Sluga; a hive mind, linking groups of Sluga together, sharing their knowledge and skills with each other. This is what the Overseers tap into in order to control them, and to imprint them with useful knowledge and skills. Karas himself is one of the most talented Overseers the Mekara Order has, and as such plays a big role in the Mekaran military.</English>
		<French>Despite not being a very talented mage, Karas is one of the more prominent members of the Mekara Order. The reason for this is that he is the man who engineered the most vital part of the Sluga; a hive mind, linking groups of Sluga together, sharing their knowledge and skills with each other. This is what the Overseers tap into in order to control them, and to imprint them with useful knowledge and skills. Karas himself is one of the most talented Overseers the Mekara Order has, and as such plays a big role in the Mekaran military.</French>
		<German>Despite not being a very talented mage, Karas is one of the more prominent members of the Mekara Order. The reason for this is that he is the man who engineered the most vital part of the Sluga; a hive mind, linking groups of Sluga together, sharing their knowledge and skills with each other. This is what the Overseers tap into in order to control them, and to imprint them with useful knowledge and skills. Karas himself is one of the most talented Overseers the Mekara Order has, and as such plays a big role in the Mekaran military.</German>
		<Italian>Nonostante non sia un mago di grande talento, Karas è uno dei membri più importanti dell'Ordine Mekara. La ragione di ciò è che lui è la persona che ha progettato la parte più importante degli Sluga; la mente alveare, collegando gruppi di Sluga tra di loro facendogli condividere tra loro le loro conoscenze. Questo è ciò che i Supervisori usano per controllarli e per imprimere in loro abilità e conoscenze utili. Karas stesso è uno dei Supervisori più capaci che l'Ordine Mekara ha, e come tale svolge un ruolo importante nell'esercito Mekara.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Despite not being a very talented mage, Karas is one of the more prominent members of the Mekara Order. The reason for this is that he is the man who engineered the most vital part of the Sluga; a hive mind, linking groups of Sluga together, sharing their knowledge and skills with each other. This is what the Overseers tap into in order to control them, and to imprint them with useful knowledge and skills. Karas himself is one of the most talented Overseers the Mekara Order has, and as such plays a big role in the Mekaran military.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Familiar -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FAMILIAR</Tag>
		<English>Familiar</English>
		<French>Familier</French>
		<German>Vertrauter</German>
		<Italian>Famiglio</Italian>
		<Spanish>Familiar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Familiar, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FAMILIAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Created by Mekaran mages to function as laboratory assistants and servants, the Familiars are small, fragile creatures with little in the way of intelligence. They tend to be very loyal to their masters, and will work hard to fulfil their requests, whatever they might be.</English>
		<French>Created by Mekaran mages to function as laboratory assistants and servants, the Familiars are small, fragile creatures with little in the way of intelligence. They tend to be very loyal to their masters, and will work hard to fulfil their requests, whatever they might be.</French>
		<German>Created by Mekaran mages to function as laboratory assistants and servants, the Familiars are small, fragile creatures with little in the way of intelligence. They tend to be very loyal to their masters, and will work hard to fulfil their requests, whatever they might be.</German>
		<Italian>Creati dai maghi Mekara per fungere da assistenti e servitori, i Famigli sono creature piccole e fragili con scarsa intelligenza. Tendono ad essere molto fedeli ai loro padroni, e lavorano duramente per soddisfare le richieste di questi ultimi, qualunque esse siano.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Created by Mekaran mages to function as laboratory assistants and servants, the Familiars are small, fragile creatures with little in the way of intelligence. They tend to be very loyal to their masters, and will work hard to fulfil their requests, whatever they might be.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Sluga -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SLUGA</Tag>
		<English>Sluga</English>
		<French>Sluga</French>
		<German>Sluga</German>
		<Italian>Sluga</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sluga</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Sluga, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SLUGA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>There is no law, written or otherwise, that say that progress has to be aesthetically pleasing; the Sluga certainly aren't. These creatures were created by the Mekara Order, using captured humans and dwarves as a base material, to serve the Mekara Order as a cheap, efficient labour force, and there can be no doubt that they serve their intended function; they are tireless workers, that require neither sleep nor food; they are nearly mindless, but when their minds are linked to a competent Overseer, they are still able to carry out highly complex tasks with great skill; and they are capable of shaping magic channeled through them to the point where they can, given time, make forests grow from empty plains, and turn deserts into lush forests.</English>
		<French>There is no law, written or otherwise, that say that progress has to be aesthetically pleasing; the Sluga certainly aren't. These creatures were created by the Mekara Order, using captured humans and dwarves as a base material, to serve the Mekara Order as a cheap, efficient labour force, and there can be no doubt that they serve their intended function; they are tireless workers, that require neither sleep nor food; they are nearly mindless, but when their minds are linked to a competent Overseer, they are still able to carry out highly complex tasks with great skill; and they are capable of shaping magic channeled through them to the point where they can, given time, make forests grow from empty plains, and turn deserts into lush forests.</French>
		<German>There is no law, written or otherwise, that say that progress has to be aesthetically pleasing; the Sluga certainly aren't. These creatures were created by the Mekara Order, using captured humans and dwarves as a base material, to serve the Mekara Order as a cheap, efficient labour force, and there can be no doubt that they serve their intended function; they are tireless workers, that require neither sleep nor food; they are nearly mindless, but when their minds are linked to a competent Overseer, they are still able to carry out highly complex tasks with great skill; and they are capable of shaping magic channeled through them to the point where they can, given time, make forests grow from empty plains, and turn deserts into lush forests.</German>
		<Italian>Non vi è alcuna legge, scritta o sotto altra forma, che dica che il progresso debba essere bello da vedere; gli Sluga di sicuro non lo sono. Queste creature, create dall'Ordine Mekara usando prigionieri umani e nanici come base, servono l'Ordine Mekara come forza lavoro economica, e non vi è dubbio che svolgano tale ruolo efficentemente; sono degli instancabili lavoratori che non richiedono ne cibo ne riposo; sono quasi senza cervello, ma quando le loro menti vengono collegate a quella di un Supervisore capace possono compiere incarichi complessi con grande abilità; sono capaci di modellare la magia incanalata attreverso di loro fino al punto che possono far crescere foreste da pianure spoglie e trasformare i deserti in lussureggianti foreste se dato sufficente tempo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>There is no law, written or otherwise, that say that progress has to be aesthetically pleasing; the Sluga certainly aren't. These creatures were created by the Mekara Order, using captured humans and dwarves as a base material, to serve the Mekara Order as a cheap, efficient labour force, and there can be no doubt that they serve their intended function; they are tireless workers, that require neither sleep nor food; they are nearly mindless, but when their minds are linked to a competent Overseer, they are still able to carry out highly complex tasks with great skill; and they are capable of shaping magic channeled through them to the point where they can, given time, make forests grow from empty plains, and turn deserts into lush forests.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Sluga, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SLUGA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Sluga have neither build orders nor work rates without an Overseer unit. The Overseer's command productions give them both, as well as providing them with terraforming capabilities once the appropriate techs have been researched (note that the Sluga MUST be commanded by an Overseer to get these Build Orders).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Agriculture and Calendar together unlock Farms, Plantations, Cottages and Wineries[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Mining and Masonry together unlock Mines, Quarries and Forts[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Animal Husbandry and Hunting together unlock Camps, Yarangas and Pastures[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Construction unlocks Windmills, Watermills and Lumbermills</English>
		<French>The Sluga have neither build orders nor work rates without an Overseer unit. The Overseer's command productions give them both, as well as providing them with terraforming capabilities once the appropriate techs have been researched (note that the Sluga MUST be commanded by an Overseer to get these Build Orders).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Agriculture and Calendar together unlock Farms, Plantations, Cottages and Wineries[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Mining and Masonry together unlock Mines, Quarries and Forts[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Animal Husbandry and Hunting together unlock Camps, Yarangas and Pastures[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Construction unlocks Windmills, Watermills and Lumbermills</French>
		<German>The Sluga have neither build orders nor work rates without an Overseer unit. The Overseer's command productions give them both, as well as providing them with terraforming capabilities once the appropriate techs have been researched (note that the Sluga MUST be commanded by an Overseer to get these Build Orders).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Agriculture and Calendar together unlock Farms, Plantations, Cottages and Wineries[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Mining and Masonry together unlock Mines, Quarries and Forts[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Animal Husbandry and Hunting together unlock Camps, Yarangas and Pastures[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Construction unlocks Windmills, Watermills and Lumbermills</German>
		<Italian>Gli Sluga non hanno ne ritmo di lavoro ne possono costruire senza un'unità Supervisore. Il comando del Supervisore gli da entrambi, oltre a fornirgli capacità di terraformazione una volta scoperte certe tecnologie (ricorda che gli Sluga DEVONO essere comandati da un Supervisore per poter costruire).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Agricoltura e Calendario insieme sbloccano le Fattorie, le Piantagioni, le Villette e le Aziende Vinicole[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Estrazione mineraria e Muratura insieme sbloccano le Miniere, le Cave e le Fortezze[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Allevamento di animali e Caccia insieme sbloccano i Campi, le Yaranga e i Pascoli[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Costruzione sblocca i Mulini a Vento, i Mulini ad Acqua e le Segherie</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Sluga have neither build orders nor work rates without an Overseer unit. The Overseer's command productions give them both, as well as providing them with terraforming capabilities once the appropriate techs have been researched (note that the Sluga MUST be commanded by an Overseer to get these Build Orders).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Agriculture and Calendar together unlock Farms, Plantations, Cottages and Wineries[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Mining and Masonry together unlock Mines, Quarries and Forts[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Animal Husbandry and Hunting together unlock Camps, Yarangas and Pastures[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Construction unlocks Windmills, Watermills and Lumbermills</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Battle Sluga -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BATTLE_SLUGA</Tag>
		<English>Battle Sluga</English>
		<French>Sluga de combat</French>
		<German>Schlachtsluga</German>
		<Italian>Sluga da Battaglia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Battle Sluga</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- War Sluga -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WAR_SLUGA</Tag>
		<English>War Sluga</English>
		<French>Sluga de guerre</French>
		<German>Kriegssluga</German>
		<Italian>Sluga da Guerra</Italian>
		<Spanish>War Sluga</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Battle Sluga, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BATTLE_SLUGA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In general, Sluga are not well suited for battle; they are slow, unintelligent, and with very poor reflexes. Therefore, they were initially dismissed as a potential military force. This changed when an Overseer by the name of Karas appeared in the Mekaran ranks. He was the first to succeed in rebuilding a Sluga to compensate for their inherent weaknesses, and so created the Battle Sluga. While additional training is required to handle the strain of controlling them, they serve well as rank-and-file soldiers for the Mekara Order.</English>
		<French>In general, Sluga are not well suited for battle; they are slow, unintelligent, and with very poor reflexes. Therefore, they were initially dismissed as a potential military force. This changed when an Overseer by the name of Karas appeared in the Mekaran ranks. He was the first to succeed in rebuilding a Sluga to compensate for their inherent weaknesses, and so created the Battle Sluga. While additional training is required to handle the strain of controlling them, they serve well as rank-and-file soldiers for the Mekara Order.</French>
		<German>In general, Sluga are not well suited for battle; they are slow, unintelligent, and with very poor reflexes. Therefore, they were initially dismissed as a potential military force. This changed when an Overseer by the name of Karas appeared in the Mekaran ranks. He was the first to succeed in rebuilding a Sluga to compensate for their inherent weaknesses, and so created the Battle Sluga. While additional training is required to handle the strain of controlling them, they serve well as rank-and-file soldiers for the Mekara Order.</German>
		<Italian>In generale gli Sluga non sono portati al combattimento; sono lenti, privi di intelligenza e con riflessi molto scarsi. Pertanto inizialmente furono scartati come potenziale forza militare. Tutto questo cambiò quando un Sorvegliante di nome Karas comparve tra i ranghi Mekara. Lui riuscì per primo nel ricostruire uno Sluga in modo da compensare le sue innate debolezze, creando cosi gli Sluga da Battaglia. Sebbene sia richesto un addestramento supplementare per gestirli si sono rivelati utili come soldati per l'Ordine Mekara.</Italian>
		<Spanish>In general, Sluga are not well suited for battle; they are slow, unintelligent, and with very poor reflexes. Therefore, they were initially dismissed as a potential military force. This changed when an Overseer by the name of Karas appeared in the Mekaran ranks. He was the first to succeed in rebuilding a Sluga to compensate for their inherent weaknesses, and so created the Battle Sluga. While additional training is required to handle the strain of controlling them, they serve well as rank-and-file soldiers for the Mekara Order.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Battle Sluga, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BATTLE_SLUGA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Battle Sluga line of units function like the regular Sluga in many respects; they are both useless without a commanding Overseer, and they don't get XP on their own. However, while the regular Sluga are made for construction, these are made for war. There are three tiers of Battle Sluga; the Battle Sluga, the War Sluga and the Behemoth. The Battle Sluga is made the same way Sluga are, by sacrificing a Slave in a city that has a Mage Guild, and are available at Alteration. The War Sluga are available as their upgrade at Sorcery, and the Behemoth can be created through a city spell at Arcane Lore.</English>
		<French>The Battle Sluga line of units function like the regular Sluga in many respects; they are both useless without a commanding Overseer, and they don't get XP on their own. However, while the regular Sluga are made for construction, these are made for war. There are three tiers of Battle Sluga; the Battle Sluga, the War Sluga and the Behemoth. The Battle Sluga is made the same way Sluga are, by sacrificing a Slave in a city that has a Mage Guild, and are available at Alteration. The War Sluga are available as their upgrade at Sorcery, and the Behemoth can be created through a city spell at Arcane Lore.</French>
		<German>The Battle Sluga line of units function like the regular Sluga in many respects; they are both useless without a commanding Overseer, and they don't get XP on their own. However, while the regular Sluga are made for construction, these are made for war. There are three tiers of Battle Sluga; the Battle Sluga, the War Sluga and the Behemoth. The Battle Sluga is made the same way Sluga are, by sacrificing a Slave in a city that has a Mage Guild, and are available at Alteration. The War Sluga are available as their upgrade at Sorcery, and the Behemoth can be created through a city spell at Arcane Lore.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Sluga da combattimento funzionano come i normali Sluga sotto molti aspetti; sono entrambi inutili senza un Supervisore che li comanda, e non ottengono PE per conto loro. Tuttavia, mentre gli Sluga normali sono fatti per costruire questi sono fatti per combattere. Ci sono tre livelli di Sluga da combattimento; gli Sluga da Battaglia, gli Sluga da Guerra e i Behemoth. Gli Sluga da Battaglia si creano come i normali Sluga, ovvero sacrficando uno Schiavo in una città con il Laboratorio del Modellatore, e si sbloccano con la tecnologia Alterazione. Gli Sluga da Guerra sono il loro miglioramento e si sbloccano con la tecnologia Stregoneria, e i Behemoth possono essere creati usando una magia nelle città una volta scoperta la tecnologia Conoscenza Arcana.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Battle Sluga line of units function like the regular Sluga in many respects; they are both useless without a commanding Overseer, and they don't get XP on their own. However, while the regular Sluga are made for construction, these are made for war. There are three tiers of Battle Sluga; the Battle Sluga, the War Sluga and the Behemoth. The Battle Sluga is made the same way Sluga are, by sacrificing a Slave in a city that has a Mage Guild, and are available at Alteration. The War Sluga are available as their upgrade at Sorcery, and the Behemoth can be created through a city spell at Arcane Lore.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Behemoth Sluga -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BEHEMOTH_SLUGA</Tag>
		<English>Behemoth:Behemoths</English>
		<French>Béhémoth:Béhémoths</French>
		<German>Behemoth:Behemoth</German>
		<Italian>Behemoth</Italian>
		<Spanish>Behemoth:Behemoths</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Behemoth Sluga, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BEHEMOTH_SLUGA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>While the Battle Sluga were constructed to serve as rank-and-file soldiers, the Behemoths were created to essentially be living siege engines. Massive constructs, made by fusing together multiple slaves into one being, they are made to strike fear into the hearts of the Mekara Order's enemies.</English>
		<French>While the Battle Sluga were constructed to serve as rank-and-file soldiers, the Behemoths were created to essentially be living siege engines. Massive constructs, made by fusing together multiple slaves into one being, they are made to strike fear into the hearts of the Mekara Order's enemies.</French>
		<German>While the Battle Sluga were constructed to serve as rank-and-file soldiers, the Behemoths were created to essentially be living siege engines. Massive constructs, made by fusing together multiple slaves into one being, they are made to strike fear into the hearts of the Mekara Order's enemies.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre gli Sluga da Combattimento sono fatti per essere normali soldati i Behemoth sono creati per essere delle macchine d'assedio viventi. Costrutti enormi creati fondendo più schiavi in un unico essere, il loro scopo è quello di incutere paura ai nemici dell'Ordine Mekara.</Italian>
		<Spanish>While the Battle Sluga were constructed to serve as rank-and-file soldiers, the Behemoths were created to essentially be living siege engines. Massive constructs, made by fusing together multiple slaves into one being, they are made to strike fear into the hearts of the Mekara Order's enemies.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Behemoth Sluga, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BEHEMOTH_SLUGA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>While the Battle Sluga can be either built or created by sacrificing a slave, the Behemoth can only be created through the Create Behemoth city spell, castable at Arcane Lore, which requires 4 units to be sacrificed. They must all be placed in the city for the spell to be castable, and they must all be of the Slave, Sluga, Battle Sluga or War Sluga unitclasses. The spell will give preference to slaves and regular sluga, and will only use Battle or War Sluga when nothing else is available.</English>
		<French>While the Battle Sluga can be either built or created by sacrificing a slave, the Behemoth can only be created through the Create Behemoth city spell, castable at Arcane Lore, which requires 4 units to be sacrificed. They must all be placed in the city for the spell to be castable, and they must all be of the Slave, Sluga, Battle Sluga or War Sluga unitclasses. The spell will give preference to slaves and regular sluga, and will only use Battle or War Sluga when nothing else is available.</French>
		<German>While the Battle Sluga can be either built or created by sacrificing a slave, the Behemoth can only be created through the Create Behemoth city spell, castable at Arcane Lore, which requires 4 units to be sacrificed. They must all be placed in the city for the spell to be castable, and they must all be of the Slave, Sluga, Battle Sluga or War Sluga unitclasses. The spell will give preference to slaves and regular sluga, and will only use Battle or War Sluga when nothing else is available.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre gli Sluga da combattimento possono essere costruiti o creati sacrificando uno Schiavo i Behemoth possono essere creati solo attraverso la magia da città 'Crea Behemoth', lanciabile dopo aver scoperto la tecnologia 'Conoscenza Arcana', che richiede di sacrificare 4 unità. Queste devono essere tutte presenti nella città per rendere lanciabile la magia, e devono essere Schiavi o Sluga (non importa il tipo). La magia consuma in maniera preferenziale gli Schiavi e gli Sluga normali, consumando Sluga da Battaglia o da Guerra quando non vi è altro a disposizione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>While the Battle Sluga can be either built or created by sacrificing a slave, the Behemoth can only be created through the Create Behemoth city spell, castable at Arcane Lore, which requires 4 units to be sacrificed. They must all be placed in the city for the spell to be castable, and they must all be of the Slave, Sluga, Battle Sluga or War Sluga unitclasses. The spell will give preference to slaves and regular sluga, and will only use Battle or War Sluga when nothing else is available.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OVERSEER</Tag>
		<English>Overseer:Overseers</English>
		<French>Overseer:Overseers</French>
		<German>Aufseher:Aufseher</German>
		<Italian>Supervisore:Supervisori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Overseer:Overseers</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OVERSEER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>On their own, the Sluga are, despite their great endurance and strength, barely capable of conscious thought. While this does make them incapable of betrayal or disobedience, it also makes them useless. As a way to utilize their physical capabilities without granting them greater autonomy, the Mekara Order began training Overseers, who are skilled and experienced craftsmen, loyal to the Mekara Order, whose minds are augmented to the point where they can take control over the Sluga, once a link between them has been established. This link gives the Sluga access to the memories and skills of their Overseer, and ensures that the Overseer will always remain in control of any Sluga assigned to him.</English>
		<French>On their own, the Sluga are, despite their great endurance and strength, barely capable of conscious thought. While this does make them incapable of betrayal or disobedience, it also makes them useless. As a way to utilize their physical capabilities without granting them greater autonomy, the Mekara Order began training Overseers, who are skilled and experienced craftsmen, loyal to the Mekara Order, whose minds are augmented to the point where they can take control over the Sluga, once a link between them has been established. This link gives the Sluga access to the memories and skills of their Overseer, and ensures that the Overseer will always remain in control of any Sluga assigned to him.</French>
		<German>On their own, the Sluga are, despite their great endurance and strength, barely capable of conscious thought. While this does make them incapable of betrayal or disobedience, it also makes them useless. As a way to utilize their physical capabilities without granting them greater autonomy, the Mekara Order began training Overseers, who are skilled and experienced craftsmen, loyal to the Mekara Order, whose minds are augmented to the point where they can take control over the Sluga, once a link between them has been established. This link gives the Sluga access to the memories and skills of their Overseer, and ensures that the Overseer will always remain in control of any Sluga assigned to him.</German>
		<Italian>Da soli gli Sluga sono a malapena capaci di ragionare, nonostante abbiano una grande forza e resistenza. Sebbene questo li renda incapaci di tradire o disobbedire li rende anche inutili. Per fare in modo di utilizzare le loro capacità fisiche senza dargli maggiore autonomia l'Ordine Mekara iniziò ad addestrare dei Supervisori, i quali sono artigiani abili ed esperti e fedeli all'Ordine Mekara, le cui menti sono state potenziate sino al punto in cui possono controllare gli Sluga una volta che sia stato stabilito un collegamento. Questo collegamento fornisce agli Sluga accesso ai ricordi e alle abilità del loro Supervisore, e assicura che il Supervisore abbia sempre il controllo degli Sluga asseggniatigli.</Italian>
		<Spanish>On their own, the Sluga are, despite their great endurance and strength, barely capable of conscious thought. While this does make them incapable of betrayal or disobedience, it also makes them useless. As a way to utilize their physical capabilities without granting them greater autonomy, the Mekara Order began training Overseers, who are skilled and experienced craftsmen, loyal to the Mekara Order, whose minds are augmented to the point where they can take control over the Sluga, once a link between them has been established. This link gives the Sluga access to the memories and skills of their Overseer, and ensures that the Overseer will always remain in control of any Sluga assigned to him.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OVERSEER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Overseer funtions both as a worker, and as a commander for Slave and Sluga units. The command skills he can aquire improves their workrate (to a greater degree with the Sluga), as well as providing new Build Orders for the Sluga.</English>
		<French>The Overseer funtions both as a worker, and as a commander for Slave and Sluga units. The command skills he can aquire improves their workrate (to a greater degree with the Sluga), as well as providing new Build Orders for the Sluga.</French>
		<German>The Overseer funtions both as a worker, and as a commander for Slave and Sluga units. The command skills he can aquire improves their workrate (to a greater degree with the Sluga), as well as providing new Build Orders for the Sluga.</German>
		<Italian>Il Supervisore funziona sia come lavoratore che come comandante per Schiavi e Sluga. Le abilità di comando che può acquisire migliorano il loro ritmo di lavoro (in misura maggiore con gli Sluga) oltre a permettere agli Sluga di contruire.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Overseer funtions both as a worker, and as a commander for Slave and Sluga units. The command skills he can aquire improves their workrate (to a greater degree with the Sluga), as well as providing new Build Orders for the Sluga.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Combat Overseer -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COM_OVERSEER</Tag>
		<English>Combat Overseer:Combat Overseers</English>
		<French>Combat Overseer:Combat Overseers</French>
		<German>Kampfaufseher:Kampfaufseher</German>
		<Italian>Supervisore da Combattimento:Supervisori da Combattimento</Italian>
		<Spanish>Combat Overseer:Combat Overseers</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Combat Overseer, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COM_OVERSEER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>With the creation of the Battle Sluga, a need for new Overseers to command them appeared. This need was met by the Combat Overseers. These mages were not only given training in how to dominate the psychic link between individual Sluga, but also given extensive combat training, which they can imprint on to any Battle Sluga they are linked to.</English>
		<French>With the creation of the Battle Sluga, a need for new Overseers to command them appeared. This need was met by the Combat Overseers. These mages were not only given training in how to dominate the psychic link between individual Sluga, but also given extensive combat training, which they can imprint on to any Battle Sluga they are linked to.</French>
		<German>With the creation of the Battle Sluga, a need for new Overseers to command them appeared. This need was met by the Combat Overseers. These mages were not only given training in how to dominate the psychic link between individual Sluga, but also given extensive combat training, which they can imprint on to any Battle Sluga they are linked to.</German>
		<Italian>In seguito alla creazione degli Sluga da Battaglia fù necessario un nuovo tipo di Supervisore per comandarli. Questa necessità fù soddisfatta dai Supervisori da Combattimento. Questi maghi non solo furono addestrati a gestire il legame psichico tra gli Sluga, ma vennero anche addestrati a combattere, in modo da imprimere negli Sluga a loro collegati queste conoscenze.</Italian>
		<Spanish>With the creation of the Battle Sluga, a need for new Overseers to command them appeared. This need was met by the Combat Overseers. These mages were not only given training in how to dominate the psychic link between individual Sluga, but also given extensive combat training, which they can imprint on to any Battle Sluga they are linked to.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Sluga Commander -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SLUGA_COMMANDER</Tag>
		<English>Sluga Commander:Sluga Commanders</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Commandant de Sluga:Commandants de Sluga</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Sluga Gebieter:Sluga Gebieter</German>
		<Italian>Comandante di Sluga:Comandanti di Sluga</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sluga Commander:Sluga Commanders</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Sluga Commander, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SLUGA_COMMANDER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>While frequent drills and extensive training can make someone a competent warrior, only experience will make a good tactician and leader. This is what sets these Combat Overseers apart from the rest; they have led Sluga in battle, and they have survived. This experience gives them an edge in combat, and it makes them more adept at controlling the Sluga assigned to them.</English>
		<French>While frequent drills and extensive training can make someone a competent warrior, only experience will make a good tactician and leader. This is what sets these Combat Overseers apart from the rest; they have led Sluga in battle, and they have survived. This experience gives them an edge in combat, and it makes them more adept at controlling the Sluga assigned to them.</French>
		<German>While frequent drills and extensive training can make someone a competent warrior, only experience will make a good tactician and leader. This is what sets these Combat Overseers apart from the rest; they have led Sluga in battle, and they have survived. This experience gives them an edge in combat, and it makes them more adept at controlling the Sluga assigned to them.</German>
		<Italian>Sebbene frequenti esercitazioni e allenamenti possono rendere qualcuno un guerriero competente, solo l'esperienza può rendere buoni tattici e leader. Questo è quello che differenzia questi Supervisori dagli altri; loro hanno guidato gli Sluga in battaglia, e sono sopravvisuti. L'esperienza ottenuta gli da un vantaggio in combattimento rendendoli maggiormente capaci di gestire gli Sluga assegnatigli.</Italian>
		<Spanish>While frequent drills and extensive training can make someone a competent warrior, only experience will make a good tactician and leader. This is what sets these Combat Overseers apart from the rest; they have led Sluga in battle, and they have survived. This experience gives them an edge in combat, and it makes them more adept at controlling the Sluga assigned to them.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Conscript -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CONSCRIPT</Tag>
		<English>Conscript:Conscripts</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Conscrit:Conscrits</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Rekrut:Rekruten</German>
		<Italian>Coscritto:Coscritti</Italian>
		<Spanish>Conscript:Conscripts</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Conscript, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CONSCRIPT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>While in many cultures military service is entered into willingly, for one reason or another - usually to do with wealth, power or prestige - not all who serve in such armies do so of their own free will.</English>
		<French>While in many cultures military service is entered into willingly, for one reason or another - usually to do with wealth, power or prestige - not all who serve in such armies do so of their own free will.</French>
		<German>While in many cultures military service is entered into willingly, for one reason or another - usually to do with wealth, power or prestige - not all who serve in such armies do so of their own free will.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre in molte culture il servizio militare viene prestato di propria volontà per varie ragioni, di solito legate alla ricchezza, al potere o al prestigio, non tutti quelli che servono in tali eserciti lo fanno volontariamente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>While in many cultures military service is entered into willingly, for one reason or another - usually to do with wealth, power or prestige - not all who serve in such armies do so of their own free will.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Militia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MILITIA</Tag>
		<English>Militia</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Milicien:Miliciens</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Miliz</German>
		<Italian>Miliziano:Miliziani</Italian>
		<Spanish>Militia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Militia, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MILITIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Professional armies are not the only way to handle defence of a nation, though they tend to be more reliable.</English>
		<French>Professional armies are not the only way to handle defence of a nation, though they tend to be more reliable.</French>
		<German>Professional armies are not the only way to handle defence of a nation, though they tend to be more reliable.</German>
		<Italian>Un esercito professionale non è l'unico strumento per difendere una nazione, sebbene tenda ad essere quello più affidabile.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Professional armies are not the only way to handle defence of a nation, though they tend to be more reliable.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Militia, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MILITIA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Available once the Magistrate's Office has been built, the Militia and Militia Crossbowman units are the basic defensive units of the Mekara Order. They are generally weaker than their equivalent units in other civs (Axeman and Archer, respectively), but in return they have no upkeep cost.</English>
		<French>Available once the Magistrate's Office has been built, the Militia and Militia Crossbowman units are the basic defensive units of the Mekara Order. They are generally weaker than their equivalent units in other civs (Axeman and Archer, respectively), but in return they have no upkeep cost.</French>
		<German>Available once the Magistrate's Office has been built, the Militia and Militia Crossbowman units are the basic defensive units of the Mekara Order. They are generally weaker than their equivalent units in other civs (Axeman and Archer, respectively), but in return they have no upkeep cost.</German>
		<Italian>Disponibili dopo aver costruito l'Ufficio del Magistrato, il Miliziano e il Balestriere Miliziano sono le unità difensive di base dell'Ordine Mekara. Sono generalmente più deboli dei loro equivalenti delle altre civiltà (Guerriero con Ascia e Arciere, rispettivamente), ma in compenso non hanno costi di manuntenzione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Available once the Magistrate's Office has been built, the Militia and Militia Crossbowman units are the basic defensive units of the Mekara Order. They are generally weaker than their equivalent units in other civs (Axeman and Archer, respectively),but in return they have no upkeep cost.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Militia Crossbowman -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MILITIA_CROSSBOWMAN</Tag>
		<English>Militia Crossbowman:Militia Crossbowmen</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Milicien Arbalétrier:Miliciens Arbalétriers</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Armbrust Miliz:Armbrust Milizen</German>
		<Italian>Balestriere Miliziano:Balestriere Miliziano</Italian>
		<Spanish>Militia Crossbowman:Militia Crossbowmen</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Militia Crossbowman, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MILITIA_CROSSBOWMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>While the crossbow may require more advanced technology than the bow, it does have significant advantages. Ease of use combined with considerable stopping power can easily make this weapon turn the tide of a battle, epecially when deployed in large numbers.</English>
		<French>While the crossbow may require more advanced technology than the bow, it does have significant advantages. Ease of use combined with considerable stopping power can easily make this weapon turn the tide of a battle, epecially when deployed in large numbers.</French>
		<German>While the crossbow may require more advanced technology than the bow, it does have significant advantages. Ease of use combined with considerable stopping power can easily make this weapon turn the tide of a battle, epecially when deployed in large numbers.</German>
		<Italian>Sebbene la balestra possa richiedere una tecnologia più avanzata rispetto all'arco essa ha vantaggi significativi. La sua facilità d'uso unita al considerevole potere d'arresto gli permette facilmente di cambiare le sorti di una battaglia, in particolar modo quando dispiegata in gran numero.</Italian>
		<Spanish>While the crossbow may require more advanced technology than the bow, it does have significant advantages. Ease of use combined with considerable stopping power can easily make this weapon turn the tide of a battle, epecially when deployed in large numbers.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Mounted Militia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOUNTED_MILITIA</Tag>
		<English>Mounted Militia</English>
		<French>Milice montée</French>
		<German>Mounted Militia</German>
		<Italian>Miliziano a Cavallo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mounted Militia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Skirmisher -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SKIRMISHER</Tag>
		<English>Skirmisher:Skirmishers</English>
		<French>Tirailleur:Tirailleurs</French>
		<German>Skirmisher:Skirmishers</German>
		<Italian>Schermagliatore:Schermagliatori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Skirmisher:Skirmishers</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Gladiator -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GLADIATOR</Tag>
		<English>Gladiator:Gladiators</English>
		<French>Gladiateur:Gladiateurs</French>
		<German>Gladiator:Gladiatoren</German>
		<Italian>Gladiatore:Gladiatori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gladiator:Gladiators</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Gladiator, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GLADIATOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Enslaved and trained to fight for other people's amusement, the life of the gladiator in the Mekaran arenas is hardly a pleasant one. However, despite it's hardships, it has it's appeal to some; the admiration of the crowds, good food and a clean bed, the occasional reward for a particularly spectacular show, and the promise of winning both your freedom and a well-paid position in the military all mean that the gladiator stables are rarely short on fresh bodies to choose from, even among the Mekara Order's free subjects.</English>
		<French>Enslaved and trained to fight for other people's amusement, the life of the gladiator in the Mekaran arenas is hardly a pleasant one. However, despite it's hardships, it has it's appeal to some; the admiration of the crowds, good food and a clean bed, the occasional reward for a particularly spectacular show, and the promise of winning both your freedom and a well-paid position in the military all mean that the gladiator stables are rarely short on fresh bodies to choose from, even among the Mekara Order's free subjects.</French>
		<German>Enslaved and trained to fight for other people's amusement, the life of the gladiator in the Mekaran arenas is hardly a pleasant one. However, despite it's hardships, it has it's appeal to some; the admiration of the crowds, good food and a clean bed, the occasional reward for a particularly spectacular show, and the promise of winning both your freedom and a well-paid position in the military all mean that the gladiator stables are rarely short on fresh bodies to choose from, even among the Mekara Order's free subjects.</German>
		<Italian>Ridotto in schiavitù e addestrato a combattere per il divertimento altrui non rende di certo piacevole la vita da gladiatore nelle arene Mekara. Tuttavia, nonostante tali difficoltà, ha il suo fascino per alcuni; l'ammirazione della folla, buon cibo e un letto pulito, l'occasionale ricompensa per un'esibizione ben riuscita, e la possibilità di vincere sia la libertà che una posizione ben retribuita nell'esercito unita a tutto il resto porta ad avere raramente penuria di persone tra cui scegliere, persino tra i sudditi liberi dell'Ordine Mekara.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Enslaved and trained to fight for other people's amusement, the life of the gladiator in the Mekaran arenas is hardly a pleasant one. However, despite it's hardships, it has it's appeal to some; the admiration of the crowds, good food and a clean bed, the occasional reward for a particularly spectacular show, and the promise of winning both your freedom and a well-paid position in the military all mean that the gladiator stables are rarely short on fresh bodies to choose from, even among the Mekara Order's free subjects.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Gladiator, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GLADIATOR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Gladiator is a fast melee unit, specializing in attacking and defending cities. Every fight it wins will also generate culture for the nearest city. Recruiting the Gladiator unit requires that you have a Slave unit available. Once you do, placing it in a city with the Colosseum building lets it enter into the arena, granting it a promotion that holds it for a number of turns with a chance of it dying every turn. If it survives the games, it will change into a Gladiator.</English>
		<French>The Gladiator is a fast melee unit, specializing in attacking and defending cities. Every fight it wins will also generate culture for the nearest city. Recruiting the Gladiator unit requires that you have a Slave unit available. Once you do, placing it in a city with the Colosseum building lets it enter into the arena, granting it a promotion that holds it for a number of turns with a chance of it dying every turn. If it survives the games, it will change into a Gladiator.</French>
		<German>The Gladiator is a fast melee unit, specializing in attacking and defending cities. Every fight it wins will also generate culture for the nearest city. Recruiting the Gladiator unit requires that you have a Slave unit available. Once you do, placing it in a city with the Colosseum building lets it enter into the arena, granting it a promotion that holds it for a number of turns with a chance of it dying every turn. If it survives the games, it will change into a Gladiator.</German>
		<Italian>Il Gladiatore è una rapida unità da mischia, specializzata nell'attaccare e difendere città. Inoltre ogni combattimento che vince genera cultura per la città più vicina. Per reclutare un Gladiatore è necessario avere uno Schiavo, stanziarlo in una città con il Colosseo e farlo partecipare ai giochi. Ciò gli farà guadagnare una promozione che lo blocca per un certo numero di turni, ogni turno c'è una probabilità che venga ucciso. Se sopravvive ai giochi verrà trasformato in un Gladiatore.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Gladiator is a fast melee unit, specializing in attacking and defending cities. Every fight it wins will also generate culture for the nearest city. Recruiting the Gladiator unit requires that you have a Slave unit available. Once you do, placing it in a city with the Colosseum building lets it enter into the arena, granting it a promotion that holds it for a number of turns with a chance of it dying every turn. If it survives the games, it will change into a Gladiator.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Ascendant -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ASCENDANT</Tag>
		<English>Ascendant:Ascendants</English>
		<French>Ascendant:Ascendants</French>
		<German>Aufstrebender:Aufstrebende</German>
		<Italian>Asceso:Ascesi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ascendant:Ascendants</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Ascendant, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ASCENDANT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Ascended are the culmination of the Mekara Order's vision of creating a better human: They are stronger, faster and smarter than humans. They don't age, are resistant to magic, immune to diesease, and nearly invulnerable to damage, and have strong telekinetic powers. However, this transformation comes at a cost. The ritual required to bring about this change invariably corrupts the mind of the subject, leaving them with very few memories of their earlier life.</English>
		<French>The Ascended are the culmination of the Mekara Order's vision of creating a better human: They are stronger, faster and smarter than humans. They don't age, are resistant to magic, immune to diesease, and nearly invulnerable to damage, and have strong telekinetic powers. However, this transformation comes at a cost. The ritual required to bring about this change invariably corrupts the mind of the subject, leaving them with very few memories of their earlier life.</French>
		<German>The Ascended are the culmination of the Mekara Order's vision of creating a better human: They are stronger, faster and smarter than humans. They don't age, are resistant to magic, immune to diesease, and nearly invulnerable to damage, and have strong telekinetic powers. However, this transformation comes at a cost. The ritual required to bring about this change invariably corrupts the mind of the subject, leaving them with very few memories of their earlier life.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Ascesi sono il culmine della visione dell'Ordine Mekara per il miglioramento dell'essere umano: Sono più forti, più veloci e più intelligenti rispetto ai normali umani. Non invecchiano, sono resistenti alla magia, immuni alle malattie, sono quasi invulnerabili e hanno forti poteri telecinetici. Tuttavia, questa trasformazione non è priva di effetti negativi. Il rituale richiesto per la trasformazione corrompe invariabilmente la mente del soggetto, lasciandogli pochissimi ricordi della loro vità precedente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Ascended are the culmination of the Mekara Order's vision of creating a better human: They are stronger, faster and smarter than humans. They don't age, are resistant to magic, immune to diesease, and nearly invulnerable to damage, and have strong telekinetic powers. However, this transformation comes at a cost. The ritual required to bring about this change invariably corrupts the mind of the subject, leaving them with very few memories of their earlier life.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Ascendant, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ASCENDANT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Ascendants can be created, through a unit ability, from any unit of level 10 or above, once the Divine Essence tech has been researched. This creates an Ascendant unit, with no experience or promotions, ready to be used. [NEWLINE] Having access to rank 1 and 2 spells, as well as high strength and immortality, these units are a very powerful hybrid berween mages and Immortals. They also have a ranged attack, which can be upgraded at levels 8 and 12.</English>
		<French>Ascendants can be created, through a unit ability, from any unit of level 10 or above, once the Divine Essence tech has been researched. This creates an Ascendant unit, with no experience or promotions, ready to be used. [NEWLINE] Having access to rank 1 and 2 spells, as well as high strength and immortality, these units are a very powerful hybrid berween mages and Immortals. They also have a ranged attack, which can be upgraded at levels 8 and 12.</French>
		<German>Ascendants can be created, through a unit ability, from any unit of level 10 or above, once the Divine Essence tech has been researched. This creates an Ascendant unit, with no experience or promotions, ready to be used. [NEWLINE] Having access to rank 1 and 2 spells, as well as high strength and immortality, these units are a very powerful hybrid berween mages and Immortals. They also have a ranged attack, which can be upgraded at levels 8 and 12.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Ascesi possono venir creati, attraverso l'utilizzo di un'abilità, da qualsiasi unità di 10° livello o superiore, una volta scoperta la tecnologia Essenza Divina. Fare ciò crea un'unità Asceso, senza esperienza o promozioni, pronta all'uso. [NEWLINE] Avendo accesso a magie di 1° e 2° livello, oltre ad avere una forza elevata e Immortalità, li rende una potente via di mezzo tra maghi e Immortali. Hanno inoltre un attacco a distanza, che può essere migliorato al 8° e 12° livello.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ascendants can be created, through a unit ability, from any unit of level 10 or above, once the Divine Essence tech has been researched. This creates an Ascendant unit, with no experience or promotions, ready to be used. [NEWLINE] Having access to rank 1 and 2 spells, as well as high strength and immortality, these units are a very powerful hybrid berween mages and Immortals. They also have a ranged attack, which can be upgraded at levels 8 and 12.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Bounty Hunter -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOUNTY_HUNTER</Tag>
		<English>Bounty Hunter:Bounty Hunters</English>
		<French>Chasseur de primes:Chasseurs de primes</French>
		<German>Kopfgeldj&#228;ger:Kopfgeldj&#228;ger</German>
		<Italian>Cacciatore di Taglie:Cacciatori di Taglie</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bounty Hunter:Bounty Hunters</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Bounty Hunter, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOUNTY_HUNTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>While many men hunt animals, for sport or for food, few men find similar pleasure in hunting other people. These men have made that hunt their life. They find criminals and bring them to justice, and 'procure' cheap labour where needed, all for a reasonable fee.</English>
		<French>While many men hunt animals, for sport or for food, few men find similar pleasure in hunting other people. These men have made that hunt their life. They find criminals and bring them to justice, and 'procure' cheap labour where needed, all for a reasonable fee.</French>
		<German>While many men hunt animals, for sport or for food, few men find similar pleasure in hunting other people. These men have made that hunt their life. They find criminals and bring them to justice, and 'procure' cheap labour where needed, all for a reasonable fee.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre molte persone cacciano gli animali, che sia per sport o per cibarsene, vi è un numero ristretto di persone che preferisce dare la caccia ai loro simili. Queste persone hanno fatto della caccia la loro vita. Esse trovano i criminali e li consegnao alla giustizia, e 'procurano' manodopera a basso costo quando necessario, tutto questo a un costo ragionevole.</Italian>
		<Spanish>While many men hunt animals, for sport or for food, few men find similar pleasure in hunting other people. These men have made that hunt their life. They find criminals and bring them to justice, and 'procure' cheap labour where needed, all for a reasonable fee.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Bounty Hunter, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOUNTY_HUNTER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Bounty Hunter and it's upgrade, the Slave Hunter, make up the main Recon line of the Mekara Order. They are the only professional military units the Mekara Order has access to, and unlike their equivalents in other civs, they are focused on fighting other troops, rather than animals and beasts. They trade the ability to capture animals for a chance to capture defeated enemies as slaves. The Slave Hunter can also pillage some enemy improvement for slaves.</English>
		<French>The Bounty Hunter and it's upgrade, the Slave Hunter, make up the main Recon line of the Mekara Order. They are the only professional military units the Mekara Order has access to, and unlike their equivalents in other civs, they are focused on fighting other troops, rather than animals and beasts. They trade the ability to capture animals for a chance to capture defeated enemies as slaves. The Slave Hunter can also pillage some enemy improvement for slaves.</French>
		<German>The Bounty Hunter and it's upgrade, the Slave Hunter, make up the main Recon line of the Mekara Order. They are the only professional military units the Mekara Order has access to, and unlike their equivalents in other civs, they are focused on fighting other troops, rather than animals and beasts. They trade the ability to capture animals for a chance to capture defeated enemies as slaves. The Slave Hunter can also pillage some enemy improvement for slaves.</German>
		<Italian>Il Cacciatore di Taglie e il suo upgrade, il Cacciatore di Schiavi, compongono la parte principale delle unità da ricognizione dell'Ordine Mekara. Sono le uniche unità militari professioniste disponibili all'Ordine Mekara e, diversamente dalle loro equivalenti delle altre civiltà, esse si concentrano nel combattere altre unità umane piuttosto che animali e bestie. Sostituiscono la capacità di catturare gli animali con la probabilità di catturare come schiavi i nemici sconfitti. Il Cacciatore di Schiavi può anche saccheggiare alcuni miglioramenti nemici per ottenere schiavi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Bounty Hunter and it's upgrade, the Slave Hunter, make up the main Recon line of the Mekara Order. They are the only professional military units the Mekara Order has access to, and unlike their equivalents in other civs, they are focused on fighting other troops, rather than animals and beasts. They also trade the ability to capture animals for a chance to capture defeated enemies as slaves. The Slave Hunter can also pillage some enemy improvement for slaves.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Slave Hunter -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SLAVE_HUNTER</Tag>
		<English>Slave Hunter:Slave Hunters</English>
		<French>Chasseur d'esclaves:Chasseurs d'esclaves</French>
		<German>Sklavenj&#228;ger:Sklavenj&#228;ger</German>
		<Italian>Cacciatore di Schiavi:Cacciatori di Schiavi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slave Hunter:Slave Hunters</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Slave Hunter, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SLAVE_HUNTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The laboratories of the Mekara Order always need more test subjects, and it falls to these men to procure them - by any means neccessary. While regular bounty hunters deals with criminals and fugitives, these men take the craft to a whole new level. Large-scale raids on settlements, guerilla warfare, and even attacks on cities and fortresses are just some of the things these men will do to provide their masters with suitable materials with which to build the new human race.</English>
		<French>The laboratories of the Mekara Order always need more test subjects, and it falls to these men to procure them - by any means neccessary. While regular bounty hunters deals with criminals and fugitives, these men take the craft to a whole new level. Large-scale raids on settlements, guerilla warfare, and even attacks on cities and fortresses are just some of the things these men will do to provide their masters with suitable materials with which to build the new human race.</French>
		<German>The laboratories of the Mekara Order always need more test subjects, and it falls to these men to procure them - by any means neccessary. While regular bounty hunters deals with criminals and fugitives, these men take the craft to a whole new level. Large-scale raids on settlements, guerilla warfare, and even attacks on cities and fortresses are just some of the things these men will do to provide their masters with suitable materials with which to build the new human race.</German>
		<Italian>I laboratori dell'Ordine Mekara hanno sempre bisogno di nuovi soggetti per i test, e sono questi uomini che li procurano, con qualsiasi mezzo. Mentre i Cacciatori di Taglie hanno a che fare con criminali e fuggitivi, questi uomini portano la loro professione ad un altro livello. Incursioni su larga scala contro insediamenti, guerriglia, e persino attacchi contro città e fortezze sono solo alcune delle cose che questi uomini compiono per portare ai loro capi persone idonee con cui costruire una nuova razza umana.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The laboratories of the Mekara Order always need more test subjects, and it falls to these men to procure them - by any means neccessary. While regular bounty hunters deals with criminals and fugitives, these men take the craft to a whole new level. Large-scale raids on settlements, guerilla warfare, and even attacks on cities and fortresses are just some of the things these men will do to provide their masters with suitable materials with which to build the new human race.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Raid Commander -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RAIDER</Tag>
		<English>Raid Commander:Raid Commanders</English>
		<French>Raid Commander:Raid Commanders</French>
		<German>Raid Commander:Raid Commanders</German>
		<Italian>Comandante dell'Incursione:Comandanti dell'Incursione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Raid Commander:Raid Commanders</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Raid Commander, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RAIDER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Mekaran military is almost exclusively focused on hit-and-run warfare. This kind of strategy requires great coordination and tactical skill, which is something only a few can truly achieve. Those few that do almost invariably rise to become the commanders leading large-scale raids on the Order's enemies.</English>
		<French>The Mekaran military is almost exclusively focused on hit-and-run warfare. This kind of strategy requires great coordination and tactical skill, which is something only a few can truly achieve. Those few that do almost invariably rise to become the commanders leading large-scale raids on the Order's enemies.</French>
		<German>The Mekaran military is almost exclusively focused on hit-and-run warfare. This kind of strategy requires great coordination and tactical skill, which is something only a few can truly achieve. Those few that do almost invariably rise to become the commanders leading large-scale raids on the Order's enemies.</German>
		<Italian>L'esercito Mekara si concentra quasi esclusivamente su tattiche mordi e fuggi. Questo tipo di strategia richiede una grande coordinazione e abilità tattica, caratteristiche che in pochi riescono a sviluppare. I pochi che ci riescono quasi sempre diventano i comandanti di incursioni su larga scala contro i nemici dell'Ordine.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Mekaran military is almost exclusively focused on hit-and-run warfare. This kind of strategy requires great coordination and tactical skill, which is something only a few can truly achieve. Those few that do almost invariably rise to become the commanders leading large-scale raids on the Order's enemies.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Raid Commander, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RAIDER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Fast, strong, and able to command a large number of units over a large area, the Raid Commander can turn the tide of any battle.</English>
		<French>Fast, strong, and able to command a large number of units over a large area, the Raid Commander can turn the tide of any battle.</French>
		<German>Fast, strong, and able to command a large number of units over a large area, the Raid Commander can turn the tide of any battle.</German>
		<Italian>Veloci, forti, e capaci di comandare un grande numero di unità a grande distanza, il Comandante dell'incursione può ribaltare l'esito di qualsiasi battaglia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Fast, strong, and able to command a large number of units over a large area, the Raid Commander can turn the tide of any battle.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Agent -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AGENT</Tag>
		<English>Agent:Agents</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Agent:Agents</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Agent:Agenten</German>
		<Italian>Agente:Agenti</Italian>
		<Spanish>Agent:Agents</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Agent, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AGENT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Zaria Scheras was never your usual Calabim governor. Whereas most of her peers preferred to rule through intimidation and military strength, she always favoured a more subtle approach. Her Agents could be found in every city and village in her domain, strategically placed to find any and all who conspire against her. Highly skilled at avoiding detection, and strong enough to escape if they failed, Zaria often used them against her fellow Governors, to advance her political standing. With the coming of the Mekara Order and the establishment of the new Mekaran nation, their services are in more demand than ever, and their numbers have grown considerably. They have also found new ways to utilize their vampyric nature, drawing life from those they kill in battle, growing stronger with every foe they slay.</English>
		<French>Zaria Scheras was never your usual Calabim governor. Whereas most of her peers preferred to rule through intimidation and military strength, she always favoured a more subtle approach. Her Agents could be found in every city and village in her domain, strategically placed to find any and all who conspire against her. Highly skilled at avoiding detection, and strong enough to escape if they failed, Zaria often used them against her fellow Governors, to advance her political standing. With the coming of the Mekara Order and the establishment of the new Mekaran nation, their services are in more demand than ever, and their numbers have grown considerably. They have also found new ways to utilize their vampyric nature, drawing life from those they kill in battle, growing stronger with every foe they slay.</French>
		<German>Zaria Scheras was never your usual Calabim governor. Whereas most of her peers preferred to rule through intimidation and military strength, she always favoured a more subtle approach. Her Agents could be found in every city and village in her domain, strategically placed to find any and all who conspire against her. Highly skilled at avoiding detection, and strong enough to escape if they failed, Zaria often used them against her fellow Governors, to advance her political standing. With the coming of the Mekara Order and the establishment of the new Mekaran nation, their services are in more demand than ever, and their numbers have grown considerably. They have also found new ways to utilize their vampyric nature, drawing life from those they kill in battle, growing stronger with every foe they slay.</German>
		<Italian>Zaria Scheras non è mai stata la classica governatrice Calabim. Laddove i suoi pari preferivano governare attraverso l'intimidazione e la potenza militare lei ha sempre preferito un approccio più discreto. I suoi Agenti sono presenti in ogni città e villaggio dei suoi domini, in posizioni strategiche per scoprire chiunque conspiri contro di lei. Esperti nel non farsi scoprire, e sufficentemente forti per scappare se fallissero, Zaria li usava spesso contro gli altri governatori per migliorare la sua posizione. Con l'arrivo dell'Ordine Mekara e l'istituzione della nuova nazione Mekara i loro servizi sono più richiesti che mai, e i loro numeri sono cresciuti considerevolmente. Hanno inoltre trovato nuovi modi di utilizzare la loro natura vampirica, assorbendo la vita delle persone che uccidono in battaglia, diventando più forti con ogni nemico che uccidono.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Zaria Scheras was never your usual Calabim governor. Whereas most of her peers preferred to rule through intimidation and military strength, she always favoured a more subtle approach. Her Agents could be found in every city and village in her domain, strategically placed to find any and all who conspire against her. Highly skilled at avoiding detection, and strong enough to escape if they failed, Zaria often used them against her fellow Governors, to advance her political standing. With the coming of the Mekara Order and the establishment of the new Mekaran nation, their services are in more demand than ever, and their numbers have grown considerably. They have also found new ways to utilize their vampyric nature, drawing life from those they kill in battle, growing stronger with every foe they slay.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Adjunct -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ADJUNCT</Tag>
		<English>Adjunct:Adjuncts</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Adjointe:Adjointes</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Ergebene:Ergebene</German>
		<Italian>Assistente:Assistenti</Italian>
		<Spanish>Adjunct:Adjuncts</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Adjunct, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ADJUNCT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Zaria's network of agents is almost entirely autonomous, with Zaria rarely taking an interest in their activities unless she wants some specific task done. When that happens, these men and women are the ones she calls upon. They are the most senior agents in the network, and the ones who are mostly running the operation. Their skills as assassins and spies is singular, and they are unquestioningly loyal to their mistress.</English>
		<French>Zaria's network of agents is almost entirely autonomous, with Zaria rarely taking an interest in their activities unless she wants some specific task done. When that happens, these men and women are the ones she calls upon. They are the most senior agents in the network, and the ones who are mostly running the operation. Their skills as assassins and spies is singular, and they are unquestioningly loyal to their mistress.</French>
		<German>Zaria's network of agents is almost entirely autonomous, with Zaria rarely taking an interest in their activities unless she wants some specific task done. When that happens, these men and women are the ones she calls upon. They are the most senior agents in the network, and the ones who are mostly running the operation. Their skills as assassins and spies is singular, and they are unquestioningly loyal to their mistress.</German>
		<Italian>La rete di agenti di Zaria è quasi completamente autonoma, con Zaria che raramente si interessa alle loro attività a meno che non voglia che una particolare azione venga compiuta. Quando ciò avviene questi uomini e donne sono coloro che chiama. Loro sono gli agenti più esperti, e anche quelli che si occupano principalmente dell'operazione. La loro abilità come assassini e spie è eccezionale, e sono indiscutibilmente leali alla loro signora.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Zaria's network of agents is almost entirely autonomous, with Zaria rarely taking an interest in their activities unless she wants some specific task done. When that happens, these men and women are the ones she calls upon. They are the most senior agents in the network, and the ones who are mostly running the operation. Their skills as assassins and spies is singular, and they are unquestioningly loyal to their mistress.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Caretaker -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CARETAKER</Tag>
		<English>Caretaker:Caretakers</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Infirmière:Infirmières</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Betreuer:Betreuer</German>
		<Italian>Infermiera:Infermiere</Italian>
		<Spanish>Caretaker:Caretakers</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Caretaker, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CARETAKER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Caretakers are a organization of healers created by Zaria Scheras, in order to see to the needs of her subjects. This was in no way an altruistic act on her part, however. As she prefers to rule through love and deception, rather than fear and intimidation, she has made considerable efforts to make herself appear a generous and kind ruler in the eyes of her subjects. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Caretakers are highly trained in their craft, and carefully indoctrinated to spread the fable of the kind and just Zaria. They are also given some training in self-defence, as they often travel in the countryside, where the roads are not safe.</English>
		<French>The Caretakers are a organization of healers created by Zaria Scheras, in order to see to the needs of her subjects. This was in no way an altruistic act on her part, however. As she prefers to rule through love and deception, rather than fear and intimidation, she has made considerable efforts to make herself appear a generous and kind ruler in the eyes of her subjects. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Caretakers are highly trained in their craft, and carefully indoctrinated to spread the fable of the kind and just Zaria. They are also given some training in self-defence, as they often travel in the countryside, where the roads are not safe.</French>
		<German>The Caretakers are a organization of healers created by Zaria Scheras, in order to see to the needs of her subjects. This was in no way an altruistic act on her part, however. As she prefers to rule through love and deception, rather than fear and intimidation, she has made considerable efforts to make herself appear a generous and kind ruler in the eyes of her subjects. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Caretakers are highly trained in their craft, and carefully indoctrinated to spread the fable of the kind and just Zaria. They are also given some training in self-defence, as they often travel in the countryside, where the roads are not safe.</German>
		<Italian>Le Infermiere sono un'organizzazione di guaritrici creata da Zaria Scheras, in modo da soddisfare i bisogni dei suoi sudditi. Questo, però, non è stato minimamente un atto d'altruismo da parte sua. In quanto lei preferisce governare attraverso l'amore e l'inganno piuttosto che la paura e l'intimidazione ha fatto parecchi sforzi per apparire ai suoi sudditi come una regnante generosa e gentile. [PARAGRAPH:1]Le Infermiere sono altamente istruite nella loro professione, e accuratamente indottrinate per diffondere la favola della gentile e giusta Zaria. Ricevono inoltre un minimo di addestramento per auto difesa, in quanto spesso girano per la nazione e le strade non sono sempre sicure.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Caretakers are a organization of healers created by Zaria Scheras, in order to see to the needs of her subjects. This was in no way an altruistic act on her part, however. As she prefers to rule through love and deception, rather than fear and intimidation, she has made considerable efforts to make herself appear a generous and kind ruler in the eyes of her subjects. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Caretakers are highly trained in their craft, and carefully indoctrinated to spread the fable of the kind and just Zaria. They are also given some training in self-defence, as they often travel in the countryside, where the roads are not safe.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Caretaker Matron -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CARETAKER_MATRON</Tag>
		<English>Caretaker Matron:Caretaker Matrons</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Infirmière en chef:Infirmières en chef</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Oberbetreuerin:Oberbetreuerinnen</German>
		<Italian>Capo Infermiera</Italian>
		<Spanish>Caretaker Matron:Caretaker Matrons</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Caretaker Matron, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CARETAKER_MATRON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In order to ensure that all Caretakers are her loyal and devoted servants, the higher orders of the organization - among others, the ones responsible for training - is exclusively made up of her vampyric servants. They conceal their nature from the citizens of the nation, while doing their outmost to project an image of benevolence and altruism. With few exceptions, they don't appear often in public, preferring to keep the company of those who are severely ill or dying. After all, noone would be too surprised if one of them died a bit ahead of schedule...</English>
		<French>In order to ensure that all Caretakers are her loyal and devoted servants, the higher orders of the organization - among others, the ones responsible for training - is exclusively made up of her vampyric servants. They conceal their nature from the citizens of the nation, while doing their outmost to project an image of benevolence and altruism. With few exceptions, they don't appear often in public, preferring to keep the company of those who are severely ill or dying. After all, noone would be too surprised if one of them died a bit ahead of schedule...</French>
		<German>In order to ensure that all Caretakers are her loyal and devoted servants, the higher orders of the organization - among others, the ones responsible for training - is exclusively made up of her vampyric servants. They conceal their nature from the citizens of the nation, while doing their outmost to project an image of benevolence and altruism. With few exceptions, they don't appear often in public, preferring to keep the company of those who are severely ill or dying. After all, noone would be too surprised if one of them died a bit ahead of schedule...</German>
		<Italian>Al fine di assicurarsi che tutte le Infermiere siano sue devote e fedeli servitrici tutti i ranghi più alti dell'organizzazione, tra cui quelli che si occupano dell'addestramento, sono ricoperti esclusivamente dalle sue servitrici vampiro. Esse nascondono la loro natura dai cittadini della nazione mentre fanno del loro meglio per proiettare un'immagine di altruismo e benevolenza. Con poche eccezioni, non appaiono spesso in pubblico, preferendo tenere compagnia a coloro che sono gravemente malati o morenti. Dopotutto, nessuno rimarrebbe sorpreso se uno di loro morisse un pò prima del previsto...</Italian>
		<Spanish>In order to ensure that all Caretakers are her loyal and devoted servants, the higher orders of the organization - among others, the ones responsible for training - is exclusively made up of her vampyric servants. They conceal their nature from the citizens of the nation, while doing their outmost to project an image of benevolence and altruism. With few exceptions, they don't appear often in public, preferring to keep the company of those who are severely ill or dying. After all, noone would be too surprised if one of them died a bit ahead of schedule...</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Shaper -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHAPER</Tag>
		<English>Shaper</English>
		<French>Modeleur</French>
		<German>Former</German>
		<Italian>Plasmatore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shaper</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Shaper, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHAPER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The core tenet of the Mekara Order is that of self-improvement through magic, and as such many it's initiates devote most their time to experimentation with different forms of life (mainly slaves, but also animals of different kinds), to, through controlled exposure to different types of mana or alchemical solutions, find methods to bring about such improvement.</English>
		<French>The core tenet of the Mekara Order is that of self-improvement through magic, and as such many it's initiates devote most their time to experimentation with different forms of life (mainly slaves, but also animals of different kinds), to, through controlled exposure to different types of mana or alchemical solutions, find methods to bring about such improvement.</French>
		<German>The core tenet of the Mekara Order is that of self-improvement through magic, and as such many it's initiates devote most their time to experimentation with different forms of life (mainly slaves, but also animals of different kinds), to, through controlled exposure to different types of mana or alchemical solutions, find methods to bring about such improvement.</German>
		<Italian>Il principio fondamentale dell'Ordine Mekara è quello del miglioramento personale attraverso la magia, pertanto molti dei suoi iniziati passano la maggior parte del loro tempo sperimentando con diverse forme di vita (principalmente schiavi, ma anche con animali di diversi tipi) per trovare modi per migliorarle, attraverso esposizioni controllate a diversi tipi di mana o soluzioni alchemiche.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The core tenet of the Mekara Order is that of self-improvement through magic, and as such many it's initiates devote most their time to experimentation with different forms of life (mainly slaves, but also animals of different kinds), to, through controlled exposure to different types of mana or alchemical solutions, find methods to bring about such improvement.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Shaper, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHAPER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Under Construction</English>
		<French>Under Construction</French>
		<German>In Vorbereitung. Haha.</German>
		<Italian>In costruzione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Under Construction</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- High Mage -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HIGHMAGE</Tag>
		<English>High Mage</English>
		<French>Grand Mage</French>
		<German>Hoher Magier</German>
		<Italian>Mago Supremo</Italian>
		<Spanish>High Mage</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- High Mage, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HIGHMAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>While the Mekara Order is, in theory, ruled by it's current Master, in practice it is a mostly democratic organization, ruled by an elected council. Members of this council are known as High Mages, and are responsible for making sure that the Mekara Order's members can continue their research in resonable peace (and also to supervise them to make sure that no-one can betray the Mekara Order, like D'tesh did). The High Mages are almost exlusively Amurites, and tend to be the most powerful and talented of the Mekara Order's mages.</English>
		<French>While the Mekara Order is, in theory, ruled by it's current Master, in practice it is a mostly democratic organization, ruled by an elected council. Members of this council are known as High Mages, and are responsible for making sure that the Mekara Order's members can continue their research in resonable peace (and also to supervise them to make sure that no-one can betray the Mekara Order, like D'tesh did). The High Mages are almost exlusively Amurites, and tend to be the most powerful and talented of the Mekara Order's mages.</French>
		<German>While the Mekara Order is, in theory, ruled by it's current Master, in practice it is a mostly democratic organization, ruled by an elected council. Members of this council are known as High Mages, and are responsible for making sure that the Mekara Order's members can continue their research in resonable peace (and also to supervise them to make sure that no-one can betray the Mekara Order, like D'tesh did). The High Mages are almost exlusively Amurites, and tend to be the most powerful and talented of the Mekara Order's mages.</German>
		<Italian>Sebbene l'Ordine Mekara sia, in teoria, governato dal Maestro corrente, in pratica è un'organizzazione prevalentemente democratica, governata da un consiglio eletto. I membri di questo consiglio sono conosciuti come Maghi Supremi, e si assicurano che i membri dell'Ordine Mekara possano continuare le loro ricerche in pace (oltre a supervisionarli in modo da assicurarsi che nessuno tradisca l'Ordine Mekara come ha fatto D'tesh). I Maghi Supremi sono quasi esclusivamente Amurite, e tendono ad essere i più potenti e talentuosi maghi dell'Ordine Mekara.</Italian>
		<Spanish>While the Mekara Order is, in theory, ruled by it's current Master, in practice it is a mostly democratic organization, ruled by an elected council. Members of this council are known as High Mages, and are responsible for making sure that the Mekara Order's members can continue their research in resonable peace (and also to supervise them to make sure that no-one can betray the Mekara Order, like D'tesh did). The High Mages are almost exlusively Amurites, and tend to be the most powerful and talented of the Mekara Order's mages.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Sluga Innate Abilities -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SLUGA_ABILITIES</Tag>
		<English>Sluga Innate Abilities</English>
		<French>Sluga Innate Abilities</French>
		<German>Sluga angeborene Eigenschaften</German>
		<Italian>Abilità Sluga Innate</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sluga Innate Abilities</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer Promotion Unlocker -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SLAVE_OVERSEER_ABILITIES</Tag>
		<English>Overseer Promotion Unlocker</English>
		<French>Overseer Promotion Unlocker</French>
		<German>Aufseher Bef&#246;rderungen Freigeschaltet</German>
		<Italian>Sbloccatore Promozione Sorvegliante</Italian>
		<Spanish>Overseer Promotion Unlocker</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Urban -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_ANIMALBLOCKER</Tag>
		<English>Urban</English>
		<French>Urbain</French>
		<German>St&#228;dtisch</German>
		<Italian>Urbano</Italian>
		<Spanish>Urban</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Movement Range[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Movement Range[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Movement Range[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Ritmo di lavoro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Raggio di Movimento[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Ritmo di Lavoro</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Movement Range[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Skilled Overseer I -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SKILLED_OVERSEER1</Tag>
		<English>Skilled Overseer I</English>
		<French>Skilled Overseer I</French>
		<German>Geschulter Aufseher I</German>
		<Italian>Supervisore Abile I</Italian>
		<Spanish>Skilled Overseer I</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Skilled Overseer I, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SKILLED_OVERSEER1_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Ritmo di Lavoro</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Skilled Overseer II -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SKILLED_OVERSEER2</Tag>
		<English>Skilled Overseer II</English>
		<French>Skilled Overseer II</French>
		<German>Geschulter Aufseher II</German>
		<Italian>Supervisore Abile II</Italian>
		<Spanish>Skilled Overseer II</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Skilled Overseer II, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SKILLED_OVERSEER2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Ritmo di Lavoro</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Skilled Overseer III -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SKILLED_OVERSEER3</Tag>
		<English>Skilled Overseer III</English>
		<French>Skilled Overseer III</French>
		<German>Geschulter Aufseher III</German>
		<Italian>Supervisore Abile III</Italian>
		<Spanish>Skilled Overseer III</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Skilled Overseer III, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SKILLED_OVERSEER3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_PRODUCTION] alla città in cui sono stanziati</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Skilled Overseer IV -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SKILLED_OVERSEER4</Tag>
		<English>Skilled Overseer IV</English>
		<French>Skilled Overseer IV</French>
		<German>Geschulter Aufseher IV</German>
		<Italian>Supervisore Abile IV</Italian>
		<Spanish>Skilled Overseer IV</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Skilled Overseer IV, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SKILLED_OVERSEER4_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Ritmo di Lavoro</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Skilled Overseer V -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SKILLED_OVERSEER5</Tag>
		<English>Skilled Overseer V</English>
		<French>Skilled Overseer V</French>
		<German>Geschulter Aufseher V</German>
		<Italian>Supervisore Abile V</Italian>
		<Spanish>Skilled Overseer V</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Skilled Overseer V, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SKILLED_OVERSEER5_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_PRODUCTION] alla città in cui sono stanziati</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+40% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Farming -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_FARMING</Tag>
		<English>Farming</English>
		<French>Farming</French>
		<German>Nahrungsanbau</German>
		<Italian>Coltivazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Farming</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Farming, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_FARMING_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Farm, Winery, Plantation, Cottage</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Farm, Winery, Plantation, Cottage</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Farm, Winery, Plantation, Cottage</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Può costruire Fattorie, Azienda Vinicola, Piantagione e Villetta</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Farm, Winery, Plantation, Cottage</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Stoneworking -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_MINING</Tag>
		<English>Stoneworking</English>
		<French>Stoneworking</French>
		<German>Steinarbeiten</German>
		<Italian>Lavorazione della Pietra</Italian>
		<Spanish>Stoneworking</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Stoneworking, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_MINING_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Mine, Quarry, Fort</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Mine, Quarry, Fort</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Mine, Quarry, Fort</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Può costruire Miniera, Cava e Fortezza</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Mine, Quarry, Fort</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Animal Husbandry -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_ANIMALS</Tag>
		<English>Animal Husbandry</English>
		<French>Animal Husbandry</French>
		<German>Tierhaltung</German>
		<Italian>Allevamento di Animali</Italian>
		<Spanish>Animal Husbandry</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Animal Husbandry, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_ANIMALS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Camp, Yaranga, Pasture</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Camp, Yaranga, Pasture</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Camp, Yaranga, Pasture</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Può costruire Campo, Yaranga e Pascolo</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Camp, Yaranga, Pasture</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Construction -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_CONSTRUCTION</Tag>
		<English>Construction</English>
		<French>Construction</French>
		<German>Konstruktion</German>
		<Italian>Costruzione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Construction</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Construction, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_CONSTRUCTION_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Windmill, Watermill, Lumbermill</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Windmill, Watermill, Lumbermill</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Windmill, Watermill, Lumbermill</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Ritmo di Lavoro[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Può costruire Mulino a Vento, Mulino ad Acqua e Segheria</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Work Rate[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Work Rate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Can build Windmill, Watermill, Lumbermill</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Endurance -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_ENDURANCE</Tag>
		<English>Endurance</English>
		<French>Endurance</French>
		<German>Ausdauer</German>
		<Italian>Resistenza</Italian>
		<Spanish>Endurance</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Endurance, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_ENDURANCE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga and Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Movement Range[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Work Rate</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga and Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Movement Range[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Work Rate</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga and Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Movement Range[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Work Rate</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutte le unità Sluga e Schiavo comandate i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Raggio di Movimento[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Ritmo di Lavoro</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives all commanded Sluga and Slave units the following bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Movement Range[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Work Rate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Artisan I -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_ARTISAN1</Tag>
		<English>Artisan I</English>
		<French>Artisan I</French>
		<German>Kunsthandwerker I</German>
		<Italian>Artigiano I</Italian>
		<Spanish>Artisan I</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Artisan I, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_ARTISAN1_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Makes all commanded Slave and Sluga units give +1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Makes all commanded Slave and Sluga units give +1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Makes all commanded Slave and Sluga units give +1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Tutte le unità Schiavo e Sluga comandate forniscono +1[ICON_PRODUCTION] alla città in cui sono stanziate</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Makes all commanded Slave and Sluga units give +1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Artisan II -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_ARTISAN2</Tag>
		<English>Artisan II</English>
		<French>Artisan II</French>
		<German>Kunsthandwerker II</German>
		<Italian>Artigiano II</Italian>
		<Spanish>Artisan II</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Overseer, Artisan II, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_ARTISAN2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Makes all commanded Slave and Sluga units give +1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Makes all commanded Slave and Sluga units give +1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Makes all commanded Slave and Sluga units give +1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Tutte le unità Schiavo e Sluga comandate forniscono +1[ICON_PRODUCTION] alla città in cui sono stanziate</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Makes all commanded Slave and Sluga units give +1[ICON_PRODUCTION] to the city they are stationed in</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Casting 'Spring' -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_SPRING_CASTING</Tag>
		<English>Channeling 'Spring'</English>
		<French>Channeling 'Spring'</French>
		<German>'Fr&#252;hling' zaubern</German>
		<Italian>Incanalare 'Sorgente'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Channeling 'Spring'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Casting 'Scorch' -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_SCORCH_CASTING</Tag>
		<English>Channeling 'Scorch'</English>
		<French>Channeling 'Scorch'</French>
		<German>'Versengen' zaubern</German>
		<Italian>Incanalare 'Bruciatura'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Channeling 'Scorch'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Casting 'Bloom' -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_OVERSEER_BLOOM_CASTING</Tag>
		<English>Channeling 'Bloom'</English>
		<French>Channeling 'Bloom'</French>
		<German>'Bl&#252;te' zaubern</German>
		<Italian>Incanalare 'Fioritura'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Channeling 'Bloom'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Iron Will -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ASCENDED_RANGED1</Tag>
		<English>Iron Will</English>
		<French>Iron Will</French>
		<German>Eiserner Wille</German>
		<Italian>Volontà di Ferro</Italian>
		<Spanish>Iron Will</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Psionic Mastery -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ASCENDED_RANGED2</Tag>
		<English>Psionic Mastery</English>
		<French>Psionic Mastery</French>
		<German>Psionen Meisterschaft</German>
		<Italian>Padronanza Psionica</Italian>
		<Spanish>Psionic Mastery</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Lifedrinker -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_LIFEDRINKER</Tag>
		<English>Lifedrinker</English>
		<French>Lifedrinker</French>
		<German>Lebenskrafttrinker</German>
		<Italian>Assorbire vita</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lifedrinker</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Lifedrinker, Help-->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_LIFEDRINKER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the unit +1% Strength after every victory against living units</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the unit +1% Strength after every victory against living units</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the unit +1% Strength after every victory against living units</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce all'unità +1% Forza dopo ogni vittoria contro unità viventi</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the unit +1% Strength after every victory against living units</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Lifedrinker, pyHelp-->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_LIFEDRINKER</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]So far, the unit has killed %d1 units, giving it +%d2% Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]So far, the unit has killed %d1 units, giving it +%d2% Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]So far, the unit has killed %d1 units, giving it +%d2% Strength</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Finora l'unità ha ucciso %d1 unità, guadagnando +%d2% Forza</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]So far, the unit has killed %d1 units, giving it +%d2% Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Vampiric Strength -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_VAMPIRIC_STRENGTH</Tag>
		<English>Vampiric Strength</English>
		<French>Vampiric Strength</French>
		<German>Vampirische St&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>Forza Vampirica</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vampiric Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Shroud -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SHROUD</Tag>
		<English>Shroud</English>
		<French>Shroud</French>
		<German>Verschleierung</German>
		<Italian>Velo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shroud</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Fighting in the Arena -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_WARGAMES_HELD</Tag>
		<English>Fighting in the Arena</English>
		<French>Fighting in the Arena</French>
		<German>In der Arena k&#228;mpfend</German>
		<Italian>Combattendo nell'Arena</Italian>
		<Spanish>Fighting in the Arena</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Gladiator -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEKARA_GLADIATOR</Tag>
		<English>Gladiator</English>
		<French>Gladiator</French>
		<German>Gladiator</German>
		<Italian>Gladiatore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gladiator</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Dying -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_WARGAMES_LOSER</Tag>
		<English>Dying</English>
		<French>Dying</French>
		<German>Sterbend</German>
		<Italian>Morente</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dying</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Dying -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_WARGAMES_WINNER</Tag>
		<English>Winning</English>
		<French>Winning</French>
		<German>Siegend</German>
		<Italian>Vittorioso</Italian>
		<Spanish>Winning</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Spring -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_OVERSEER_SPRING</Tag>
		<English>Casting 'Spring' through minions.</English>
		<French>Casting 'Spring' through minions.</French>
		<German>Zaubere 'Fr&#252;hling' durch Untergebene</German>
		<Italian>Lanciando 'Sorgente' attraverso servitori.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Casting 'Spring' through minions.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Scorch -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_OVERSEER_SCORCH</Tag>
		<English>Casting 'Scorch' through minions.</English>
		<French>Casting 'Scorch' through minions.</French>
		<German>Zaubere 'Versengen' durch Untergebene</German>
		<Italian>Lanciando 'Bruciatura' attraverso servitori.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Casting 'Scorch' through minions.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Overseer, Bloom -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_OVERSEER_BLOOM</Tag>
		<English>Casting 'Bloom' through minions.</English>
		<French>Casting 'Bloom' through minions.</French>
		<German>Zaubere 'Bl&#252;te' durch Untergebene</German>
		<Italian>Lanciando 'Fioritura' attraverso servitori.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Casting 'Bloom' through minions.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Corgayle, Learn 'Sneak' -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_CORGAYLE_SNEAK</Tag>
		<English>Learn 'Sneak'</English>
		<French>Apprendre 'Infiltration'</French>
		<German>Lerne 'Schleichen'</German>
		<Italian>Apprendi 'Furtività'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Learn 'Sneak'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Corgayle, Learn 'Channeling I' -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_CORGAYLE_CHANNELING1</Tag>
		<English>Learn 'Channeling I'</English>
		<French>Apprendre 'Canalisation I'</French>
		<German>Lerne 'Kanalisieren I'</German>
		<Italian>Apprendi 'Incanalare I'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Learn 'Channeling I'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Corgayle, Learn 'Channeling II' -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_CORGAYLE_CHANNELING2</Tag>
		<English>Learn 'Channeling II'</English>
		<French>Apprendre 'Canalisation II'</French>
		<German>Lerne 'Kanalisieren II'</German>
		<Italian>Apprendi 'Incanalare II'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Learn 'Channeling II'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Ascension -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_CORGAYLE_ASCENSION</Tag>
		<English>Ascension (Corgayle)</English>
		<French>Ascension (Corgayle)</French>
		<German>Aufstieg (Corgayle)</German>
		<Italian>Ascensione (Corgayle)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ascension (Corgayle)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Ascension -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_ASCENSION</Tag>
		<English>Ascension</English>
		<French>Ascension</French>
		<German>Aufstieg</German>
		<Italian>Ascensione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ascension</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Enter Arena -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_ENTER_ARENA</Tag>
		<English>Enter Arena</English>
		<French>Entrer dans l'Arène</French>
		<German>Arena betreten</German>
		<Italian>Entra nell'Arena</Italian>
		<Spanish>Enter Arena</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Enter Arena, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_ENTER_ARENA_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Turns the unit into a Gladiator, and enters it into the Arena.[NEWLINE][SPACE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]A Gladitorial Games building will be creted for the duration of the games, giving happiness and culture.[NEWLINE][SPACE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]The games have a 45% chance to end each turn: 20% through the unit dying, and 25% by the unit winning, in which case it becomes free to move again.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Turns the unit into a Gladiator, and enters it into the Arena.[NEWLINE][SPACE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]A Gladitorial Games building will be creted for the duration of the games, giving happiness and culture.[NEWLINE][SPACE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]The games have a 45% chance to end each turn: 20% through the unit dying, and 25% by the unit winning, in which case it becomes free to move again.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Turns the unit into a Gladiator, and enters it into the Arena.[NEWLINE][SPACE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]A Gladitorial Games building will be creted for the duration of the games, giving happiness and culture.[NEWLINE][SPACE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]The games have a 45% chance to end each turn: 20% through the unit dying, and 25% by the unit winning, in which case it becomes free to move again.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Trasforma l'unità in un Gladiatore, e la fa entrare nell'Arena.[NEWLINE][SPACE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Un edificio chiamato Giochi Gladiatori verrà creato per la durata dei giochi, che fornisce felicità e cultura.[NEWLINE][SPACE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Ogni turno i giochi hanno una probabilità del 45% di concludersi: 20% con la morte dell'unità, e 25% con la vittoria dell'unità, nel cui caso diventa di nuovo libera di muoversi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Turns the unit into a Gladiator, and enters it into the Arena.[NEWLINE][SPACE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]A Gladitorial Games building will be creted for the duration of the games, giving happiness and culture.[NEWLINE][SPACE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]The games have a 45% chance to end each turn: 20% through the unit dying, and 25% by the unit winning, in which case it becomes free to move again.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Mekaran Palace -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_MEKARA</Tag>
		<English>Mekaran Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Mekaran</French>
		<German>Palast des Mekara Orden</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo Mekara</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mekaran Palace</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Mekaran Palace, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_MEKARA_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Augmente de 2 la limite d'Esclaves</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il limite di Schiavi di 2</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Slaver's Market -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET</Tag>
		<English>Slaver's Market</English>
		<French>Marché aux Esclaves</French>
		<German>Sklavenmarkt</German>
		<Italian>Mercato degli Schiavisti</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slaver's Market</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Slaver's Market, Pedia -->
	<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Slavery has always been a part of Calabim society to some extent; the Calabim nobility has never been very interested in basic human freedoms. The arrival of the Mekarans in Korash, and their subsequent rise to power, only exaserbated the problem. With harsh new laws and enslavement as a common punishment, the trade in slaves grew dramatically, becoming a central part of their economy. This resulted in slave markets cropping up in most larger settlements, with the so-called Fleshmarket in Deselen being the most significant.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]While a large portion of the slave trade is connected to the Order's mages, many of the wealthier citizens have also taken to owning slaves, resulting in a booming trade for bounty hunters and slavers.</English>
		<French>Slavery has always been a part of Calabim society to some extent; the Calabim nobility has never been very interested in basic human freedoms. The arrival of the Mekarans in Korash, and their subsequent rise to power, only exaserbated the problem. With harsh new laws and enslavement as a common punishment, the trade in slaves grew dramatically, becoming a central part of their economy. This resulted in slave markets cropping up in most larger settlements, with the so-called Fleshmarket in Deselen being the most significant.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]While a large portion of the slave trade is connected to the Order's mages, many of the wealthier citizens have also taken to owning slaves, resulting in a booming trade for bounty hunters and slavers.</French>
		<German>Slavery has always been a part of Calabim society to some extent; the Calabim nobility has never been very interested in basic human freedoms. The arrival of the Mekarans in Korash, and their subsequent rise to power, only exaserbated the problem. With harsh new laws and enslavement as a common punishment, the trade in slaves grew dramatically, becoming a central part of their economy. This resulted in slave markets cropping up in most larger settlements, with the so-called Fleshmarket in Deselen being the most significant.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]While a large portion of the slave trade is connected to the Order's mages, many of the wealthier citizens have also taken to owning slaves, resulting in a booming trade for bounty hunters and slavers.</German>
		<Italian>La schiavitù ha sempre fatto parte della società Calabim in una certa misura; la nobiltà Calabim non si è mai interessata alle basilari libertà umane. L'arrivo dei Mekara a Korash, e la loro successiva ascesa al potere, ha solo esacerbato il problema. Con la promulgazione di nuove rigide leggi e la schiavitù come punizione il commercio di schiavi crebbe notevolmente, divenendo una parte centrale della loro economia. Questo portò alla nascita di mercati di schiavi nella maggior parte degli insediamenti più grandi, con il cosidetto Mercato dei Corpi di Deselen che è il più conosciuto.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Sebbene un'ampia porzione del commercio di schiavi è collegata ai maghi dell'Ordine ci sono anche molti ricchi cittadini che hanno iniziato a possedere schiavi, che ha portato a un aumento degli affari per Cacciatori di taglie e Schiavisti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slavery has always been a part of Calabim society to some extent; the Calabim nobility has never been very interested in basic human freedoms. The arrival of the Mekarans in Korash, and their subsequent rise to power, only exaserbated the problem. With harsh new laws and enslavement as a common punishment, the trade in slaves grew dramatically, becoming a central part of their economy. This resulted in slave markets cropping up in most larger settlements, with the so-called Fleshmarket in Deselen being the most significant.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]While a large portion of the slave trade is connected to the Order's mages, many of the wealthier citizens have also taken to owning slaves, resulting in a booming trade for bounty hunters and slavers.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Slaver's Market, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLAVE_MARKET_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 4</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Augmente de 4 la limite d'Esclaves</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 4</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il limite di Schiavi di 4</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 4</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Shaper's Laboratory -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHAPER_LAB</Tag>
		<English>Shaper's Laboratory</English>
		<French>Laboratoire des Modeleurs</French>
		<German>Des Formers Laboratorium</German>
		<Italian>Laboratorio del Plasmatore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shaper's Laboratory</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Shaper's Laboratory, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHAPER_LAB_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>While the Shapers of the Mekara Order are often thought of as monstrous, it is worth remembering that for many of them, the ultimate goal is the improvement of life for all humans, and that under Iram Damarr's guidance, they have come far indeed in fighting disease and illness. However, as anyone who have actually seen the inside of one of their laboratories will attest - they might strive to bring about a brave new world, but their methods are doubtlessly twisted.</English>
		<French>While the Shapers of the Mekara Order are often thought of as monstrous, it is worth remembering that for many of them, the ultimate goal is the improvement of life for all humans, and that under Iram Damarr's guidance, they have come far indeed in fighting disease and illness. However, as anyone who have actually seen the inside of one of their laboratories will attest - they might strive to bring about a brave new world, but their methods are doubtlessly twisted.</French>
		<German>While the Shapers of the Mekara Order are often thought of as monstrous, it is worth remembering that for many of them, the ultimate goal is the improvement of life for all humans, and that under Iram Damarr's guidance, they have come far indeed in fighting disease and illness. However, as anyone who have actually seen the inside of one of their laboratories will attest - they might strive to bring about a brave new world, but their methods are doubtlessly twisted.</German>
		<Italian>Anche se i Plasmatori dell'Ordine Mekara sono visti spesso come mostri vale la pena ricordare che per la maggior parte di loro l'obiettivo ultimo è il miglioramento della vita per tutti gli esseri umani, e che, sotto la guida di Iram Damarr, hanno effettivamente raggiunto grandi traguardi nella lotta alle malattie e infermità. Tuttavia chiunque abbia visto l'interno di uno dei loro laboratori può attestare che loro possono anche sforzarsi per creare un mondo migliore, ma che i loro metodi sono senza dubbio perversi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>While the Shapers of the Mekara Order are often thought of as monstrous, it is worth remembering that for many of them, the ultimate goal is the improvement of life for all humans, and that under Iram Damarr's guidance, they have come far indeed in fighting disease and illness. However, as anyone who have actually seen the inside of one of their laboratories will attest - they might strive to bring about a brave new world, but their methods are doubtlessly twisted.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Shaper's Laboratory, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHAPER_LAB_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Increases the spawn rate of Aspirants[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Lets Healers and Elders in the city increase the spawn rate of Aspirants</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Augmente de 2 la limite d'Esclaves[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Increases the spawn rate of Aspirants[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Lets Healers and Elders in the city increase the spawn rate of Aspirants</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Increases the spawn rate of Aspirants[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Lets Healers and Elders in the city increase the spawn rate of Aspirants</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il limite di Schiavi di 2[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il ritmo di generazione degli Aspiranti[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Permette ai Guaritori e Anziani di aumentare il ritmo di generazione degli Aspiranti</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Increases the spawn rate of Aspirants[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Lets Healers and Elders in the city increase the spawn rate of Aspirants</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Colosseum -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COLOSSEUM</Tag>
		<English>Colosseum</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Colisée:Colisées</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Kolosseum</German>
		<Italian>Colosseo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Colosseum</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Colosseum, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COLOSSEUM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Violence and bloodshed will always hold a certain appeal for those who will never have to experience it firsthand. Since the Mekaran cities have such a large slave population bloodsport and gladitorial games were inevitable. [PARAGRAPH:1]They fill many functions: Entertainment for the people, military training for the soldiers, and a chance for commoners and slaves to improve their lives. If they survive, that is.</English>
		<French>Violence and bloodshed will always hold a certain appeal for those who will never have to experience it firsthand. Since the Mekaran cities have such a large slave population bloodsport and gladitorial games were inevitable. [PARAGRAPH:1]They fill many functions: Entertainment for the people, military training for the soldiers, and a chance for commoners and slaves to improve their lives. If they survive, that is.</French>
		<German>Gewalt und BlutvergieÃŸen wird immer eine besondere Anziehungskraft auf jene aus&#252;ben, die sie nicht aus erster Hand erfahren. Da die Mekaranischen St&#228;dte groÃŸe Sklavenmengen beherbergen, war die Entwicklung von Gladiatorenspielen letztendlich abzusehen und unausweichlich.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie erf&#252;llen viele Aufgaben: Unterhaltung f&#252;r das Volk, Ausbildung f&#252;r die Soldaten und die Chance f&#252;r das gemeine Volk und Sklaven, in der Gesellschaft aufzusteigen. Nat&#252;rlich nur, wenn man &#252;berlebt.</German>
		<Italian>La violenza e gli spargimenti di sangue hanno sempre un certo fascino per chi non dovrà mai sperimentarli in prima persona. Siccome le città dei Mekara hanno un cosi grande numero di schiavi sport sanguinosi e giochi gladiatori erano inevitabili. [PARAGRAPH:1]Questi soddisfano molte necessità: intrattenimento per la popolazione, addestramento per i soldati, e la possibilità per i cittadini comuni e gli schiavi di migliorare le loro vite. Se sopravvivono, ovviamente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Violence and bloodshed will always hold a certain appeal for those who will never have to experience it firsthand. Since the Mekaran cities have such a large slave population bloodsport and gladitorial games were inevitable. [PARAGRAPH:1]They fill many functions: Entertainment for the people, military training for the soldiers, and a chance for commoners and slaves to improve their lives. If they survive, that is.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Colosseum, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COLOSSEUM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Colosseum replaces the Theatre building, providing reduced culture and losing some happiness bonuses. In exchange, it gives additional XP to all land units created in the city. Slaves can also be entered into gladitorial games, which provides a temporary happiness and culture boost, as well as having a chance of creating the Gladiator unit.</English>
		<French>The Colosseum replaces the Theatre building, providing reduced culture and losing some happiness bonuses. In exchange, it gives additional XP to all land units created in the city. Slaves can also be entered into gladitorial games, which provides a temporary happiness and culture boost, as well as having a chance of creating the Gladiator unit.</French>
		<German>Das Colosseum ersetzt das Geb&#228;ude Theater, es bringt etwas weniger Kultur und hat weniger Zufriedenheitsboni. Daf&#252;r gibt es jedoch allen, in dieser Stadt ausgebildeten, Landeinheiten zus&#228;tzliche Erfahrungspunkte. Dar&#252;berhinaus k&#246;nnen Sklaven in die Gladiatorenspiele "integriert" werden, was zu vr&#252;bergehender Zufriedenheit und Kulturzunahme f&#252;hrt. AuÃŸerdem besteht die Chance, daÃŸ dabei aus einem Sklaven eine Einheit Gladiator hervorgeht.</German>
		<Italian>Il Colosseo sostituisce il teatro, ma fornisce meno cultura e felicità. In compenso fornisce PE aggiuntivi a tutte le unità terrestri create in città. Gli Schiavi possono essere fatti entrare in giochi gladiatori, che forniscono felicità e cultura aggiuntivi temporanei, oltre ad avere la possibilità di creare l'unità Gladiatore.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Colosseum replaces the Theatre building, providing reduced culture and losing some happiness bonuses. In exchange, it gives additional XP to all land units created in the city. Slaves can also be entered into gladitorial games, which provides a temporary happiness and culture boost, as well as having a chance of creating the Gladiator unit.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Colosseum, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COLOSSEUM_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Augmente de 2 la limite d'Esclaves</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il limite di Schiavi di 2</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Gladitorial Games -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WARGAMES</Tag>
		<English>Gladitorial Games</English>
		<French>Gladitorial Games</French>
		<German>Gladiatorenspiele</German>
		<Italian>Giochi Gladiatori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gladitorial Games</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Gladitorial Games, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WARGAMES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>This city is currently hosting gladitorial games. This spectacle will surely impress the people of the city!</English>
		<French>This city is currently hosting gladitorial games. This spectacle will surely impress the people of the city!</French>
		<German>Diese Stadt veranstaltet derzeit Gladiatorenspiele. Dieses Spektakel wird mit Sicherheit die Bewohner der Stadt beeindrucken!</German>
		<Italian>Questa città sta attualmente ospitando dei giochi gladiatori. Lo spettacolo impressionerà sicuramente la popolazione della città!</Italian>
		<Spanish>This city is currently hosting gladitorial games. This spectacle will surely impress the people of the city!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Magistrate's Office -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MAGISTRATES_OFFICE</Tag>
		<English>Magistrate's Office</English>
		<French>Bureau du magistrat</French>
		<German>Amtsitz des Magistraten</German>
		<Italian>Ufficio del Magistrato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Magistrate's Office</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Magistrate's Office, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MAGISTRATES_OFFICE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The offices of the local Magistrates are central to every Mekaran settlement. It houses the bureaucratic machine that binds their society together; it organises the local militia; it is where the courts convene to settle legal disputes. Despite their importance, however, they tend to be grey, dull places.</English>
		<French>The offices of the local Magistrates are central to every Mekaran settlement. It houses the bureaucratic machine that binds their society together; it organises the local militia; it is where the courts convene to settle legal disputes. Despite their importance, however, they tend to be grey, dull places.</French>
		<German>Die Amtsitze der &#246;rtlichen Magistrate sind zentral in jeder Mekara Siedlung gelegen. Sie beherbergen die b&#252;rokratische Maschinerie, die ihre Gesellschaft zusammenh&#228;lt. Sie organisieren die &#246;rtliche Miliz, kl&#228;ren an Gerichtstagen die juristischen Streitereien. Trotz ihrer Bedeutung sind es meist graue, glanzlose &#246;rtlichkeiten.</German>
		<Italian>Gli uffici dei Magistrati locali sono fondamentali per ogni insediamento Mekara. Essi ospitano la macchina burocratica che lega insieme la loro società; organizza la milizia locale; ed è dove i tribunali si riuniscono per risolvere le dispute legali. Eppure nonostante la loro importanza tendono ad essere luoghi grigi e scarni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The offices of the local Magistrates are central to every Mekaran settlement. It houses the bureaucratic machine that binds their society together; it organises the local militia; it is where the courts convene to settle legal disputes. Despite their importance, however, they tend to be grey, dull places.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Slave Pens -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PAGAN_TEMPLE_MEKARA</Tag>
		<English>Slave Pens</English>
		<French>Slave Pens</French>
		<German>Sklavenquartiere</German>
		<Italian>Baracche degli Schiavi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slave Pens</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Slave Pens, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PAGAN_TEMPLE_MEKARA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Slave Pens building provides additional production to a city, as well as allowing it to construct Sluga. It also allows the player to settle captured slaves as Citizen specialists, increasing production further.</English>
		<French>The Slave Pens building provides additional production to a city, as well as allowing it to construct Sluga. It also allows the player to settle captured slaves as Citizen specialists, increasing production further.</French>
		<German>Die Sklavenquartiere erzeugen zus&#228;tzliche Produktion in der Stadt, auÃŸerdem erlauben sie die Erschaffung von Sluga. Es macht auch die Eingliederung von gefangenen Sklaven als spezialisierte B&#252;rger m&#246;glich, wodurch die Produktion weiter ansteigen kann.</German>
		<Italian>L'edificio Baracche degli Schiavi fornisce produzione aggiuntiva alla città, oltre a permettere la creazione di Sluga. Permette inoltre di assegnare Schiavi alla città come specialisti, aumentandone la produzione ulteriormente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Slave Pens building provides additional production to a city, as well as allowing it to construct Sluga. It also allows the player to settle captured slaves as Citizen specialists, increasing production further.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Slave Pens, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PAGAN_TEMPLE_MEKARA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Slavery is often frowned upon by society, despite the fact that many of the world's nations practice it in one form or another - prison labour, for instance. Despite it being disliked, it does have some benefits; it provides a less final punishment to those who commit capital crimes, it provides the authorities with cheap labour, and it gives a very visible way of showing people what happens to those who don't follow the law.</English>
		<French>Slavery is often frowned upon by society, despite the fact that many of the world's nations practice it in one form or another - prison labour, for instance. Despite it being disliked, it does have some benefits; it provides a less final punishment to those who commit capital crimes, it provides the authorities with cheap labour, and it gives a very visible way of showing people what happens to those who don't follow the law.</French>
		<German>Sklaverei wird von der Gesellschaft oft missbilligt, trotz der Tatsache, dass viele V&#246;lker der Welt sie auf die eine oder die andere Art praktizieren - Zwangsarbeit, beispielsweise. Obwohl sie nicht besonders beliebt ist, ist sie doch sehr n&#252;tzlich. F&#252;r Schwerverbecher ist sie eine nicht ganz so endg&#252;ltige Strafe wie der Tod, sie versorgt die Oberen mit billiger Arbeitskraft und zeigt den Leuten auf sehr anschauliche Weise, was passiert, wenn sie sich nicht an die Gesetze halten.</German>
		<Italian>La schiavitù è spesso malvista dalla società, nonostante il fatto che venga praticata da molte nazioni del mondo anche se in forme differenti, come il lavoro forzato per esempio. Anche se non piace essa porta dei vantaggi: una punizione meno definitiva per chi compie crimini capitali, da accesso alle autorità a manodopera a basso costo ed è una maniera molto visibile con cui mostrare cosa succede a chi non segue la legge.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slavery is often frowned upon by society, despite the fact that many of the world's nations practice it in one form or another - prison labour, for instance. Despite it being disliked, it does have some benefits; it provides a less final punishment to those who commit capital crimes, it provides the authorities with cheap labour, and it gives a very visible way of showing people what happens to those who don't follow the law.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Slave Pens, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PAGAN_TEMPLE_MEKARA_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows Slaves to be settled in the city[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Base limit is one slave settled for every 4 population[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Allows Slaves to be settled in the city[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Base limit is one slave settled for every 4 population[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Allows Slaves to be settled in the city[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Base limit is one slave settled for every 4 population[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Permette di assegnare Schiavi alla città[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Il limite iniziale è 1 Schiavo assegnato ogni 4 unità di popolazione[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il limite di Schiavi di 2</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows Slaves to be settled in the city[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Base limit is one slave settled for every 4 population[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Increases the Slave limit by 2</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Ritualist -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEKARA_RITUALIST</Tag>
		<English>Ritualist</English>
		<French>Ritualist</French>
		<German>Ritualist</German>
		<Italian>Ritualista</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ritualist</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Augmented -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEKARA_AUGMENTED</Tag>
		<English>Augmented</English>
		<French>Augmented</French>
		<German>Verbessert</German>
		<Italian>Potenziato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Augmented</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Prepared For Ritual -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEKARA_RITUAL</Tag>
		<English>Prepared For Ritual</English>
		<French>Prepared For Ritual</French>
		<German>F&#252;r Ritual vorbereitet</German>
		<Italian>Preparato per il Rituale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Prepared For Ritual</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Ritual Target -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MEKARA_RITUAL_TARGET</Tag>
		<English>Ritual Target</English>
		<French>Ritual Target</French>
		<German>Ziel des Rituals</German>
		<Italian>Bersaglio del Rituale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ritual Target</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Aspect of the Beserker -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RITUAL_AUG_OFFENCE</Tag>
		<English>Aspect of the Beserker</English>
		<French>Aspect of the Beserker</French>
		<German>Aspekt des Beserkers</German>
		<Italian>Aspetto del Berserker</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aspect of the Beserker</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Aspect of the Protector -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RITUAL_AUG_DEFENCE</Tag>
		<English>Aspect of the Protector</English>
		<French>Aspect of the Protector</French>
		<German>Aspekt des Besch&#252;tzers</German>
		<Italian>Aspetto del Protettore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aspect of the Protector</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Aspect of the Assassin -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RITUAL_AUG_ASSASSIN</Tag>
		<English>Aspect of the Assassin</English>
		<French>Aspect of the Assassin</French>
		<German>Aspekt des Meuchelm&#246;rders</German>
		<Italian>Aspetto dell'Assassino</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aspect of the Assassin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Prepare Augmentation Ritual -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RITUAL_PREPARATION</Tag>
		<English>Prepare Augmentation Ritual</English>
		<French>Prepare Augmentation Ritual</French>
		<German>Verst&#228;rkungsritual verbereiten</German>
		<Italian>Prepara Rituale di Potenziamento</Italian>
		<Spanish>Prepare Augmentation Ritual</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Abandon Ritual -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RITUAL_ABANDON</Tag>
		<English>Abandon Ritual</English>
		<French>Abandon Ritual</French>
		<German>Ritual aufgeben</German>
		<Italian>Abbandona il Rituale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Abandon Ritual</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Designate Ritual Target -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RITUAL_TARGET_DESIGNATE</Tag>
		<English>Designate Ritual Target</English>
		<French>Designate Ritual Target</French>
		<German>Ziel des Rituals benennen</German>
		<Italian>Designa il Bersaglio del Rituale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Designate Ritual Target</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Withdraw from Ritual -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RITUAL_TARGET_WITHDRAW</Tag>
		<English>Withdraw from Ritual</English>
		<French>Soustraire au Rituel</French>
		<German>Vom Ritual zur&#252;ckziehen</German>
		<Italian>Ritirati dal Rituale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Withdraw from Ritual</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Conduct Experiments -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SHAPER_EXPERIMENTS</Tag>
		<English>Conduct Experiments</English>
		<French>Mener des expériences</French>
		<German>Experimente durchf&#252;hren</German>
		<Italian>Conduci Esperimenti</Italian>
		<Spanish>Conduct Experiments</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Conduct Experiments, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SHAPER_EXPERIMENTS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Grants a Shaper or High Mage increased passive XP gain for 3 turns, at the cost of a slave.</English>
		<French>Grants a Shaper or High Mage increased passive XP gain for 3 turns, at the cost of a slave.</French>
		<German>Bei Opferung eines Sklaven wird einem Former oder einem Hohen Magier f&#252;r 3 Runden ein erh&#246;hter, passiver XP Erwerb erm&#246;glicht.</German>
		<Italian>Fornisce, sacrificando uno Schiavo, PE passivi aggiuntivi a un Plasmatore o Mago Supremo per 3 turni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grants a Shaper or High Mage increased passive XP gain for 3 turns, at the cost of a slave.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Experimenting -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SHAPER_EXPERIMENTS</Tag>
		<English>Experimenting</English>
		<French>Experimenting</French>
		<German>Experimentierend</German>
		<Italian>Sperimentado</Italian>
		<Spanish>Experimenting</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Settle Slave -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SETTLE_SLAVE</Tag>
		<English>Settle Slave</English>
		<French>Settle Slave</French>
		<German>Sklave eingliedern</German>
		<Italian>Assegna Schiavo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Settle Slave</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Enslave Worker -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SLAVE_CONVERSION</Tag>
		<English>Enslave Worker</English>
		<French>Asservir l'ouvrier</French>
		<German>Enslave Worker</German>
		<Italian>Schiavizzare Lavoratore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Enslave Worker</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Enslave Dissidents -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_ENSLAVE_DISSIDENTS</Tag>
		<English>Enslave Dissidents</English>
		<French>Asservir les Dissidents</French>
		<German>Enslave Dissidents</German>
		<Italian>Schiavizzare Dissidenti</Italian>
		<Spanish>Enslave Dissidents</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Enslave Dissidents Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_ENSLAVE_DISSIDENTS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Converts an angry citizen into a Slave[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Causes temporary unhappiness in the city</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Converts an angry citizen into a Slave[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Causes temporary unhappiness in the city</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Converts an angry citizen into a Slave[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Causes temporary unhappiness in the city</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Trasforma un cittadino arrabiato in uno Schiavo[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Crea dello scontento temporaneo nella città</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Converts an angry citizen into a Slave[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Causes temporary unhappiness in the city</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Create Sluga -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SLUGA_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>Create Sluga</English>
		<French>Créer un Sluga</French>
		<German>Erschaffe Sluga</German>
		<Italian>Crea Sluga</Italian>
		<Spanish>Create Sluga</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Create Battle Sluga -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_BATTLE_SLUGA_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>Create Battle Sluga</English>
		<French>Create Battle Sluga</French>
		<German>Erschaffe Schlachtsluga</German>
		<Italian>Crea Sluga da Battaglia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Create Battle Sluga</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Create Behemoth -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_BEHEMOTH_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>Create Behemoth</English>
		<French>Créer Béhémoth</French>
		<German>Erschaffe Behemoth</German>
		<Italian>Crea Behemoth</Italian>
		<Spanish>Create Behemoth</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Create Behemoth, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_BEHEMOTH_CREATION_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifices 4 Slave units to create a Behemoth unit[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sluga, Battle Sluga or War Sluga will be used if not enough slaves are available[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can only by cast by a civ lead by Jamal Dahkar</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifices 4 Slave units to create a Behemoth unit[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sluga, Battle Sluga or War Sluga will be used if not enough slaves are available[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can only by cast by a civ lead by Jamal Dahkar</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Opfert 4 Einheiten Sklave f&#252;r die Erschaffung einer Behemoth Einheit[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Bei unzureichenden Sklavenmengen werden Sluga, Schlachtsluga oder Kriegssluga verwendet.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Kann nur gezaubert werden, wenn Jamal Dahkar der Anf&#252;hrer ist.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifica 4 Schiavi per creare un Behemoth[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sluga, Sluga da Battaglia o Sluga da Guerra verranno usati se non vi sono Schiavi sufficenti[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Può essere lanciata solo quando il leader è Jamal Dahkar</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifices 4 Slave units to create a Behemoth unit[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sluga, Battle Sluga or War Sluga will be used if not enough slaves are available[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can only by cast by a civ lead by Jamal Dahkar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Ruthless Trait Promo -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TRAIT_RUTHLESS</Tag>
		<English>Ruthless</English>
		<French>Impitoyable</French>
		<German>Ruchlos</German>
		<Italian>Spietato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ruthless</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Leaderless -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_LEADERLESS_SLUGA</Tag>
		<English>Leaderless</English>
		<French>Leaderless</French>
		<German>F&#252;hrerlos</German>
		<Italian>Senza guida</Italian>
		<Spanish>Leaderless</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COM_OVERSEER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows commanded Battle Sluga to have combat strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Allows commanded Battle Sluga to have combat strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt den befehligten Schlachtsluga die Bef&#246;rderung Kampfst&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Permette agli Sluga da combattimento comandati di avere forza da combattimento</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows commanded Battle Sluga to have combat strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Close Combat Training -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MELEE_BASIC</Tag>
		<English>Close Combat Training</English>
		<French>Close Combat Training</French>
		<German>Nahkampfausbildung</German>
		<Italian>Addestramento al Combattimento Ravvicinato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Close Combat Training</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Close Combat Training, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MELEE_BASIC_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Attack Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Defence Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Attack Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Defence Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die folgenden Boni auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Angriffst&#228;rke[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Verteidigungsst&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Forza d'Attacco[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Forza di Difesa</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Attack Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Defence Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Combat Drill I -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MELEE_1</Tag>
		<English>Combat Drill I</English>
		<French>Combat Drill I</French>
		<German>Kampferfahrung I</German>
		<Italian>Esercitazione di Combattimento I</Italian>
		<Spanish>Combat Drill I</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Combat Drill I, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MELEE_1_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Extra First Strike[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% vs Mounted units[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Combat Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 First Strike[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% vs Mounted units[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Combat Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die folgenden Boni auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Erstangriff[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% gegen Berittene Einheiten[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Kampfst&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]1 'Attacco Improvviso' supplementare[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% vs Unità Montata[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% di Forza</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 First Strike[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% vs Mounted units[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Combat Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Combat Drill II -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MELEE_2</Tag>
		<English>Combat Drill II</English>
		<French>Combat Drill II</French>
		<German>Kampferfahrung II</German>
		<Italian>Esercitazione di Combattimento II</Italian>
		<Spanish>Combat Drill II</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Combat Drill II, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MELEE_2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 First Strikes Chances[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% vs Mounted units[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Combat Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 First Strikes Chances[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% vs Mounted units[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Combat Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die folgenden Boni auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Chancen auf Erstangriffe[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% gegen Berittene Einheiten[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Kampfst&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 possibilità di 'Attacco Improvviso' supplementare[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% vs Unità Montate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% di forza</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 First Strikes Chances[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% vs Mounted units[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% Combat Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Combat Drill III -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MELEE_3</Tag>
		<English>Combat Drill III</English>
		<French>Combat Drill III</French>
		<German>Kampferfahrung III</German>
		<Italian>Esercitazione di Combattimento III</Italian>
		<Spanish>Combat Drill III</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Combat Drill III, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MELEE_3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Extra First Strikes[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% vs Mounted units[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Suffers 20% less Collateral Damage[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Combat Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Extra First Strikes[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% vs Mounted units[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Suffers 20% less Collateral Damage[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Combat Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die folgenden Boni auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Zus&#228;tzliche Erstangriffe[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% gegen Berittene Einheiten[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Erleidet 20% weniger Kollateralschaden [NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Kampfst&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 'Attacchi Improvvisi' supplementari[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% vs Unità Montate[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]20% in meno di Danni Collaterali subiti[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% di forza</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Extra First Strikes[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+20% vs Mounted units[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Suffers 20% less Collateral Damage[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+10% Combat Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Close Combat Mastery -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MELEE_MASTER</Tag>
		<English>Close Combat Mastery</English>
		<French>Close Combat Mastery</French>
		<German>Nahkampfmeisterschaft</German>
		<Italian>Padronanza del Combattimento Ravvicinato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Close Combat Mastery</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Close Combat Mastery, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MELEE_MASTER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Attack Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Defence Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Attack Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Defence Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die folgenden Boni auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Angriffst&#228;rke[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Verteidigungsst&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Forza d'Attacco[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Forza di Difesa</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Attack Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Defence Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Ranged Training -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_RANGED_BASIC</Tag>
		<English>Ranged Training</English>
		<French>Ranged Training</French>
		<German>Fernkampftraining</German>
		<Italian>Addestramento al Combattimento a Distanza</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ranged Training</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Ranged Training, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_RANGED_BASIC_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +3[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 30%[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Operational Range</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +3[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 30%[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Operational Range</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die folgenden Boni auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Fernkampfangriff +3[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Erh&#246;ht Schadenslimit f&#252;r Fernagriff +30%[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Operational Range</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta l'Attacco a Distanza di +3[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il limite di danno massimo a distanza del 30%[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Raggio d'Azione</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +3[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 30%[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Operational Range</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Ranged Expertise I -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_RANGED_1</Tag>
		<English>Ranged Expertise I</English>
		<French>Ranged Expertise I</French>
		<German>Fernkampferfahrung I</German>
		<Italian>Abile nel Combattimento a Distanza I</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ranged Expertise I</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Ranged Expertise I, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_RANGED_1_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 10%</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 10%</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die folgenden Boni auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Fernkampfangriff +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Schadenslimit f&#252;r Fernangriff +10%</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta l'Attacco a Distanza di +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il limite di danno massimo a distanza del 10%</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 10%</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Ranged Expertise II -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_RANGED_2</Tag>
		<English>Ranged Expertise II</English>
		<French>Ranged Expertise II</French>
		<German>Fernkampferfahrung II</German>
		<Italian>Abile nel Combattimento a Distanza II</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ranged Expertise II</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Ranged Expertise II, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_RANGED_2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 10%</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 10%</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die folgenden Boni auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Fernkampfangriff +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Schadenslimit f&#252;r Fernangriff +10%</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta l'Attacco a Distanza di +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il limite di danno massimo a distanza del 10%</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 10%</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Ranged Expertise III -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_RANGED_3</Tag>
		<English>Ranged Expertise III</English>
		<French>Ranged Expertise III</French>
		<German>Fernkampferfahrung III</German>
		<Italian>Abile nel Combattimento a Distanza III</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ranged Expertise III</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Ranged Expertise III, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_RANGED_3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 10%</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 10%</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die folgenden Boni auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Fernkampfangriff +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Schadenslimit f&#252;r Fernangriff +10%</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta l'Attacco a Distanza di +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il limite di danno massimo a distanza del 10%</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +1[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 10%</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Ranged Mastery -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_RANGED_MASTER</Tag>
		<English>Ranged Mastery</English>
		<French>Ranged Mastery</French>
		<German>Fernkampfmeisterschaft</German>
		<Italian>Padronanza del Combattimento a Distanza</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ranged Mastery</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Ranged Mastery, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_RANGED_MASTER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +2[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 15%</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +2[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 15%</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt folgende Boni auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Fernkampfangriff +2[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Schadenslimit f&#252;r Fernangriff +15%</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta l'Attacco a Distanza di +2[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il limite di danno massimo a distanza del 15%</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances Ranged Combat Attack by +2[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Enhances damage limit for ranged combat by 15%</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Celerity -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_CELERITY1</Tag>
		<English>Celerity</English>
		<French>Célérité</French>
		<German>Celerity</German>
		<Italian>Celerità</Italian>
		<Spanish>Celerity</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_CELERITY1_OVERSEER</Tag>
		<English>Celerity</English>
		<French>Célérité</French>
		<German>Celerity</German>
		<Italian>Celerità</Italian>
		<Spanish>Celerity</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Enhanced Celerity -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_CELERITY2</Tag>
		<English>Enhanced Celerity</English>
		<French>Célérité accrue</French>
		<German>Enhanced Celerity</German>
		<Italian>Celerità Migliorata</Italian>
		<Spanish>Enhanced Celerity</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_CELERITY2_OVERSEER</Tag>
		<English>Enhanced Celerity</English>
		<French>Célérité accrue</French>
		<German>Enhanced Celerity</German>
		<Italian>Celerità Migliorata</Italian>
		<Spanish>Enhanced Celerity</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Regeneration -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_REGENERATION</Tag>
		<English>Regeneration</English>
		<French>Regeneration</French>
		<German>Regeneration</German>
		<Italian>Rigenerazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Regeneration</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Regeneration, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_REGENERATION_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a spell which applies the Regenerating promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a spell which applies the Regenerating promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt die magische &#252;bertragung der Regeneration Bef&#246;rderung auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Ti permette di lanciare una magia che applica la promozione Rigenerazione a tutti gli Sluga da Battaglia comandati</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a spell which applies the Regenerating promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Regeneration, Casting -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_REGENERATION_CASTING</Tag>
		<English>Cast 'Regeneration'</English>
		<French>Cast 'Regeneration'</French>
		<German>Zaubere 'Regeneration'</German>
		<Italian>Lancia 'Rigenerazione'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cast 'Regeneration'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Regeneration, Casting, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_REGENERATION_CASTING_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Applies the Regenerating promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Applies the Regenerating promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die Regeneration Bef&#246;rderung auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Applica la promozione Rigenerazione a tutti gli Sluga da Battaglia comandati</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Applies the Regenerating promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Sustained Regeneration -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_REGENERATION2</Tag>
		<English>Sustained Regeneration</English>
		<French>Sustained Regeneration</French>
		<German>Anhaltende Regeneration</German>
		<Italian>Rigenerazione Costante</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sustained Regeneration</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Stoneskin -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_STONESKIN</Tag>
		<English>Stoneskin</English>
		<French>Stoneskin</French>
		<German>Steinhaut</German>
		<Italian>Pelle di Pietra</Italian>
		<Spanish>Stoneskin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Stoneskin, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_STONESKIN_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a spell which applies the Stoneskin promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a spell which applies the Stoneskin promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt die magische &#252;bertragung der Steinhaut Bef&#246;rderung auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Ti permette di lanciare una magia che applica la promozione Pelle di Pietra a tutti gli Sluga da Battaglia comandati</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a spell which applies the Stoneskin promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Stoneskin, Casting -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_STONESKIN_CASTING</Tag>
		<English>Cast 'Stoneskin'</English>
		<French>Cast 'Stoneskin'</French>
		<German>Zaubere 'Steinhaut'</German>
		<Italian>Lancia 'Pelle di Pietra'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cast 'Stoneskin'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Stoneskin, Casting, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_STONESKIN_CASTING_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Applies the Stoneskin promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Applies the Stoneskin promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die Steinhaut Bef&#246;rderung auf alle befehligten Schlachtsluga</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Applica la promozione Pelle di Pietra a tutti gli Sluga da Battaglia comandati</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Applies the Stoneskin promotion to all commanded Battle Sluga</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Maelstrom -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MAELSTROM</Tag>
		<English>Maelstrom</English>
		<French>Maelstrom</French>
		<German>Mahlstrom</German>
		<Italian>Maelstrom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Maelstrom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Maelstrom, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MAELSTROM_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a 1-tile version of the 'Maelstrom' spell through commanded Battle Sluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Does 20% to 40% damage, and targets all units; allies included</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a 1-tile version of the 'Maelstrom' spell through commanded Battle Sluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Does 20% to 40% damage, and targets all units; allies included</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt das Zaubern eine 1-Feld Version des 'Mahlstrom' Zaubers durch die befehligte Schlachtsluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Macht 20% to 40% Schaden, trifft neben feindlichen auch verb&#252;ndete Einheiten</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Ti permette di lanciare una versione che colpisce a 1 quadrato di distanza della magia 'Maelstrom' attraverso gli Sluga da Battaglia comandati[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fa tra il 20% e il 40% di danno e colpisce tutte le unità, alleati inclusi</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a 1-tile version of the 'Maelstrom' spell through commanded Battle Sluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Does 20% to 40% damage, and targets all units; allies included</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Maelstrom, Casting -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MAELSTROM_CASTING</Tag>
		<English>Cast 'Maelstrom'</English>
		<French>Cast 'Maelstrom'</French>
		<German>Zaubere 'Mahlstrom'</German>
		<Italian>Lancia 'Maelstrom'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cast 'Maelstrom'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Controlled Maelstrom -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MAELSTROM2</Tag>
		<English>Controlled Maelstrom</English>
		<French>Controlled Maelstrom</French>
		<German>Kontrollierter Mahlstrom</German>
		<Italian>Maelstrom Controllato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Controlled Maelstrom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Controlled Maelstrom, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MAELSTROM2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a 1-tile version of the 'Maelstrom' spell through commanded Battle Sluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Does 30% to 60% damage, and only targets enemies</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a 1-tile version of the 'Maelstrom' spell through commanded Battle Sluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Does 30% to 60% damage, and only targets enemies</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt das Zaubern einer 1-Feld Version des 'Mahlstrom' Zaubers durch die befehligte Schlachtsluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Macht 30% to 60% Schaden, jedoch nur auf feindliche Einheiten</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Ti permette di lanciare una versione che colpisce a 1 quadrato di distanza della magia 'Maelstrom' attraverso gli Sluga da Battaglia comandati[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fa tra il 30% e il 60% di danno e colpisce solo i nemici</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to cast a 1-tile version of the 'Maelstrom' spell through commanded Battle Sluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Does 30% to 60% damage, and only targets enemies</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Controlled Maelstrom, Casting -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MAELSTROM2_CASTING</Tag>
		<English>Cast 'Controlled Maelstrom'</English>
		<French>Cast 'Controlled Maelstrom'</French>
		<German>Zaubere 'Kontrollierter Mahlstrom'</German>
		<Italian>Lancia 'Maelstrom Controllato'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cast 'Controlled Maelstrom'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Combat Overseer, Controlled Maelstrom, Casting, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_COM_OVERSEER_MAELSTROM2_CASTING_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Casts a 1-tile version of the 'Maelstrom' spell through commanded Battle Sluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Does 30% to 60% damage, and only targets enemies</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Casts a 1-tile version of the 'Maelstrom' spell through commanded Battle Sluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Does 30% to 60% damage, and only targets enemies</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Zaubert eine 1-Feld Version des 'Mahlstrom' Zaubers durch die befehligte Schlachtsluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Macht 30% to 60% Schaden, jedoch nur auf feindliche Einheiten</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Lancia una versione che colpisce a 1 quadrato di distanza della magia 'Maelstrom' attraverso gli Sluga da Battaglia comandati[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fa tra il 30% e il 60% di danno e colpisce solo i nemici</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Casts a 1-tile version of the 'Maelstrom' spell through commanded Battle Sluga[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Does 30% to 60% damage, and only targets enemies</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Massive Unit -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_DOUBLE_GC_REQUIREMENT</Tag>
		<English>Massive Unit</English>
		<French>Massive Unit</French>
		<German>Massive Einheit</German>
		<Italian>Unità Massiccia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Massive Unit</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Karas, Sluga Master -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_KARAS_SLUGA_MASTER</Tag>
		<English>Sluga Master</English>
		<French>Sluga Master</French>
		<German>Sluga Meister</German>
		<Italian>Signore degli Sluga</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sluga Master</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Karas, Sluga Master, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_KARAS_SLUGA_MASTER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Attack Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Defence Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Extra First Strikes[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Suffers 20% less Collateral Damage</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Attack Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Defence Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Extra First Strikes[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Suffers 20% less Collateral Damage</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#252;bertr&#228;gt die folgenden Boni auf alle kommandierten Schlachtsluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Angriffsst&#228;rke[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Verteigungsst&#228;rke[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Zus&#228;tzliche Erstangriffe[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Erleidet 20% weniger Kollateralschaden</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce a tutti gli Sluga da combattimento comandati i seguenti bonus:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Forza d'Attacco[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Forza di Difesa[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 'Attacchi Improvvisi' supplementari[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]20% in meno di Danni Collaterali subiti</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives the following bonuses to all commanded Battle Sluga:[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Attack Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Defence Strength[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Extra First Strikes[NEWLINE][SPACE][ICON_BULLET]Suffers 20% less Collateral Damage</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Psionic Link -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SLUGA_PSIONIC_LINK</Tag>
		<English>Psionic Link</English>
		<French>Psionic Link</French>
		<German>Psi-Verbindung</German>
		<Italian>Legame Psionico</Italian>
		<Spanish>Psionic Link</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Independent -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_INDEPENDENT</Tag>
		<English>Independent</English>
		<French>Indépendant</French>
		<German>Unabh&#228;ngig</German>
		<Italian>Independente</Italian>
		<Spanish>Independent</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Strength Percent -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_STR_PER</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% St&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% di Forza</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Offensive Strength Percent -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_STR_PER_OFF</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Offensive Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Offensive Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Angriffst&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Forza d'Attacco</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Offensive Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Defensive Strength Percent -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_STR_PER_DEF</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Defensive Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Defensive Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Verteidigungsst&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Forza di Difesa</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Defensive Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Attack Strength -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_STR_OFF</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Attack Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Attack Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Angriffsst&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Forza d'Attacco</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Attack Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Defensive Strength -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_STR_DEF</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Defense Strength</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Defense Strength</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Verteidigungst&#228;rke</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Forza di Difesa</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Defense Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, City Attack Percent -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_STR_PER_OFFCITY</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% City Attack</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% City Attack</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Stadtangriff</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Attacco contro Città</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% City Attack</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, City Defence Percent -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_STR_PER_DEFCITY</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% City Defence</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% City Defence</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Stadtverteidigung</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Difesa in Città</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% City Defence</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Hill Defence Percent -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_STR_PER_DEFHILL</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Hill Defence</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Hill Defence</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% H&#252;gelverteidigung</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Difesa in Collina</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Hill Defence</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, First Strike Chances -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_FSCHANCE</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Extra First Strike Chances</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Extra First Strike Chances</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Zus&#228;tzliche Erstangriffe</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 possibilità di 'Attacco Improvviso' supplementare</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Extra First Strike Chances</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, First Strikes -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_FS</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Extra First Strikes</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Extra First Strikes</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Zus&#228;tzlicher Erstangriff</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 'Attacchi Improvvisi' supplementari</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Extra First Strikes</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Defensive Strikes -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_DS</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% chance to do %d2% damage to units attacking this unit's stack</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% chance to do %d2% damage to units attacking this unit's stack</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Einheiten die diesen Einheitenstapel angreifen, erleiden mit %d1% Chance, %d2% Schaden</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% di probabilità di fare %d2% di danno alle unità che attaccano il gruppo di questa unità</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% chance to do %d2% damage to units attacking this unit's stack</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Heal Rate -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_HEALRATE</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Heals Extra %d1% Damage/Turn in All Territories</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Heals Extra %d1% Damage/Turn in All Territories</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Heilt zus&#228;tzlich %d1% Schaden/Runde in allen Gebieten</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Cura il %d1% supplementare Danno/turno in tutti i territori</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Heals Extra %d1% Damage/Turn in All Territories</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Heal While Moving -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_HEALMOVE</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can Heal While Moving</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Can Heal While Moving</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Heilt w&#228;hrend der Bewegung</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Permette la cura in movimento</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Can Heal While Moving</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Heal After Combat -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_HEALCOMBAT</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Heals %d1% after combat</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Heals %d1% after combat</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Heilt %d1% nach Kampf</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Cura del %d1% dopo il combattimento</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Heals %d1% after combat</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Withdraw -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_WITHDRAW</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Withdrawal Chance</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Withdrawal Chance</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% R&#252;ckzugschance</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% possibilità di ritirarsi</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1% Withdrawal Chance</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Terrain Movement Cost -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_TERRCOST</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Terrain Movement Cost</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Terrain Movement Cost</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Terrain Bewegungskosten</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Costo di Movimento del Terreno</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Terrain Movement Cost</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Movement Range -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_MOVES</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Movement Range</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Movement Range</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Bewegungsradius</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Raggio di Movimento</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%d1 Movement Range</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Aspect of the Beserker Special -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_OFF_SPECIAL</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can Attack Multiple Times per Turn</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Can Attack Multiple Times per Turn</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann mehrmals pro Runde angreifen</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Permette di attaccare più volte durante lo stesso turno</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Can Attack Multiple Times per Turn</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Aspect of the Protector Special -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_DEF_SPECIAL</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Cold Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Death Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Fire Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Holy Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Lightning Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Poison Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Unholy Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Guards against enemy Marksman units[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Doubles the unit's fortification bonus</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Cold Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Death Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Fire Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Holy Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Lightning Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Poison Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Unholy Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Guards against enemy Marksman units[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Doubles the unit's fortification bonus</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]+50% Widerstand gegen K&#228;lte[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Widerstand gegen Tod[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Widerstand gegen Feuer[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Widerstand gegen Heilig [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Widerstand gegen Blitz[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Widerstand gegen Gift[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Widerstand gegen Unheilig[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sch&#252;tzt gegen Scharfsch&#252;tzen[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Verdoppelt den Verschanzungsbonus der Einheit</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]+50% di resistenza al Danno da Freddo[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% di resistenza al Danno da Morte[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% di resistenza al Danno da Fuoco[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% di resistenza al Danno Sacro[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% di resistenza al Danno da Fulmini[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% di resistenza al Danno da Veleno[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% di resistenza al Danno Sacrilego[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Protegge dalle unità con Marksman[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Raddoppia il bonus di fortificazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Cold Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Death Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Fire Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Holy Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Lightning Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Poison Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50% Resistance to Unholy Damage[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Guards against enemy Marksman units[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Doubles the unit's fortification bonus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, Aspect of the Assassin Special -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_EVA_SPECIAL</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]No Combat Penalty for Attacking from Sea[ICON_BULLET]No Combat Penalty for Crossing River[ICON_BULLET]+1 Visibility Range[ICON_BULLET]Gives the unit the ability to fly</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]No Combat Penalty for Attacking from Sea[ICON_BULLET]No Combat Penalty for Crossing River[ICON_BULLET]+1 Visibility Range[ICON_BULLET]Gives the unit the ability to fly</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Keine Abzug bei Angriff von See.[ICON_BULLET]Keine Abz&#252;ge bei Angriff &#252;ber Fl&#252;sse[ICON_BULLET]+1 Sichtweite[ICON_BULLET]Verleiht der Einheit die F&#228;higkeit zu fliegen</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Nessuna penalità quando si attacca dal mare[ICON_BULLET]Nessuna penalità quando si attacca attraversando un fiume[ICON_BULLET]+1 Raggio di Visuale[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce all'unità la capacità di volare</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]No Combat Penalty for Attacking from Sea[ICON_BULLET]No Combat Penalty for Crossing River[ICON_BULLET]+1 Visibility Range[ICON_BULLET]Gives the unit the ability to fly</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Augmentation Help, New Line -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_AUG_NEWLINE</Tag>
		<English>[NEWLINE]</English>
		<French>[NEWLINE]</French>
		<German>[NEWLINE]</German>
		<Italian>[NEWLINE]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[NEWLINE]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Building - Shaper Cabal, Name -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHAPER_CABAL</Tag>
		<English>Shaper Cabal</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Cabale des Modeleurs:Cabales des Modeleurs</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Shaper Cabal</German>
		<Italian>Cabala del Plasmatore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shaper Cabal</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Building - Shaper Cabal, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHAPER_CABAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As much a place of experimentation and discovery as a place for mages to be trained in their craft, the Shaper Cabal provides one of the few ways to truly advance in Mekaran society. Though they are the sites of many of the experiments that give the Order its dark reputation, the Mekaran people still flock towards them, hoping to be taken on as apprentices.</English>
		<French>As much a place of experimentation and discovery as a place for mages to be trained in their craft, the Shaper Cabal provides one of the few ways to truly advance in Mekaran society. Though they are the sites of many of the experiments that give the Order its dark reputation, the Mekaran people still flock towards them, hoping to be taken on as apprentices.</French>
		<German>As much a place of experimentation and discovery as a place for mages to be trained in their craft, the Shaper Cabal provides one of the few ways to truly advance in Mekaran society. Though they are the sites of many of the experiments that give the Order its dark reputation, the Mekaran people still flock towards them, hoping to be taken on as apprentices.</German>
		<Italian>Tanto un luogo di sperimentazione e scoperta quanto un luogo per i maghi in cui addestrarsi nella loro arte, la Cabala del Plasmatore fornisce uno dei pochi modi con cui poter veramente scalare la società Mekara. Sebbene siano i siti di molti degli esperimenti che danno all'Ordine la sua tetra reputazione il popolo Mekara continua ad accorrervi, nella speranza di essere presi come apprendisti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>As much a place of experimentation and discovery as a place for mages to be trained in their craft, the Shaper Cabal provides one of the few ways to truly advance in Mekaran society. Though they are the sites of many of the experiments that give the Order its dark reputation, the Mekaran people still flock towards them, hoping to be taken on as apprentices.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Building - Shaper Cabal, Help -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHAPER_CABAL_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the rate at which Aspirants are generated.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the rate at which Aspirants are generated.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the rate at which Aspirants are generated.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il ritmo al quale gli Aspiranti vengono generati.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the rate at which Aspirants are generated.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Unit - Custodian, Name -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CUSTODIAN</Tag>
		<English>Custodian:Custodians</English>
		<French>Dépositaire:Dépositaires</French>
		<German>Custodian:Custodians</German>
		<Italian>Custode:Custodi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Custodian:Custodians</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Unit - Custodian, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CUSTODIAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A volonteer militia drawn together by Iram Damarr, the Custodians are better trained and more organized than the regular standing forces of the Mekara nation.</English>
		<French>A volonteer militia drawn together by Iram Damarr, the Custodians are better trained and more organized than the regular standing forces of the Mekara nation.</French>
		<German>A volonteer militia drawn together by Iram Damarr, the Custodians are better trained and more organized than the regular standing forces of the Mekara nation.</German>
		<Italian>Una milizia volontaria istituita da Iram Damarr, i Custodi sono meglio addestrati e più organizzati delle classiche forze militari della nazione Mekara.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A volonteer militia drawn together by Iram Damarr, the Custodians are better trained and more organized than the regular standing forces of the Mekara nation.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Unit - Sharpshooter, Name -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHARPSHOOTER</Tag>
		<English>Sharpshooter:Sharpshooters</English>
		<French>Tireur d'Élite:Tireurs d'Élite</French>
		<German>Sharpshooter:Sharpshooters</German>
		<Italian>Tiratore Scelto:Tiratore Scelto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sharpshooter:Sharpshooters</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Unit - Sharpshooter, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHARPSHOOTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>With extensive training and experience at both hunting and war, these highly skilled archers are a deadly force on any battlefield.</English>
		<French>With extensive training and experience at both hunting and war, these highly skilled archers are a deadly force on any battlefield.</French>
		<German>With extensive training and experience at both hunting and war, these highly skilled archers are a deadly force on any battlefield.</German>
		<Italian>Con un ampio allenamento ed esperienza sia nella caccia che nella guerra questi abili arcieri sono letali su qualsiasi campo di battaglia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>With extensive training and experience at both hunting and war, these highly skilled archers are a deadly force on any battlefield.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Unit - Aspirant, Name -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ASPIRANT</Tag>
		<English>Aspirant:Aspirants</English>
		<French>Aspirant:Aspirants</French>
		<German>Aspirant:Aspirants</German>
		<Italian>Aspirante:Aspiranti</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aspirant:Aspirants</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Unit - Aspirant, Pedia -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ASPIRANT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>However you look at it, the core creed of the Mekara Order is the fulfilment of human potential, and the expansion of its innate abilities. Most of the Order's members take the position that the end goal is all that is relevant, but some would argue otherwise. Iram Damarr is one of those who do. Not content to wait or search for the final form of humanity promised by the Order, he has begun using the extensive body of knowledge regarding human enhancement to gradually improve the human condition. With volunteers from the civilian population and the militia, he has given rise to the Aspirant - an enhanced human being that is the stepping stone towards true Ascension.</English>
		<French>However you look at it, the core creed of the Mekara Order is the fulfilment of human potential, and the expansion of its innate abilities. Most of the Order's members take the position that the end goal is all that is relevant, but some would argue otherwise. Iram Damarr is one of those who do. Not content to wait or search for the final form of humanity promised by the Order, he has begun using the extensive body of knowledge regarding human enhancement to gradually improve the human condition. With volunteers from the civilian population and the militia, he has given rise to the Aspirant - an enhanced human being that is the stepping stone towards true Ascension.</French>
		<German>However you look at it, the core creed of the Mekara Order is the fulfilment of human potential, and the expansion of its innate abilities. Most of the Order's members take the position that the end goal is all that is relevant, but some would argue otherwise. Iram Damarr is one of those who do. Not content to wait or search for the final form of humanity promised by the Order, he has begun using the extensive body of knowledge regarding human enhancement to gradually improve the human condition. With volunteers from the civilian population and the militia, he has given rise to the Aspirant - an enhanced human being that is the stepping stone towards true Ascension.</German>
		<Italian>L'obiettivo dell'Ordine Mekara è il raggiungimento dell'apice del potenziale umano e l'espansione delle sue capacità innate. La maggior parte dei membri dell'Ordine ritiene che l'unica cosa rilevante sia il raggiungimento di tale obiettivo, mentre altri sostengono il contrario. Iram Damarr è uno di loro. Non intenzionato ad aspettare o cercare la forma finale promessa dall'Ordine ha iniziato ad usare la grande mole di conoscenza relativa al potenziamento del corpo umano per migliorare gradualmente la condizione umana. Con volontari provenienti dalla popolazione civile e dalla milizia ha dato origine all'Aspirante, un'essere umano potenziato che è il primo passo verso la vera Ascensione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>However you look at it, the core creed of the Mekara Order is the fulfilment of human potential, and the expansion of its innate abilities. Most of the Order's members take the position that the end goal is all that is relevant, but some would argue otherwise. Iram Damarr is one of those who do. Not content to wait or search for the final form of humanity promised by the Order, he has begun using the extensive body of knowledge regarding human enhancement to gradually improve the human condition. With volunteers from the civilian population and the militia, he has given rise to the Aspirant - an enhanced human being that is the stepping stone towards true Ascension.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Unit - Aspirant, Strategy -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ASPIRANT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Aspirant is Iram Damarr's signature unit. Sharing many characteristics with the Grigori Adventurer, it is a unit that can be upgraded into any other unit, spawned through a civilization counter, at a rate determined by the amount of Shaper Cabals and Laboratories present in the empire. In addition to the normal abilities of the unit it is promoted into, it also has a number of innate enhancements, determined by Iram's traits.</English>
		<French>The Aspirant is Iram Damarr's signature unit. Sharing many characteristics with the Grigori Adventurer, it is a unit that can be upgraded into any other unit, spawned through a civilization counter, at a rate determined by the amount of Shaper Cabals and Laboratories present in the empire. In addition to the normal abilities of the unit it is promoted into, it also has a number of innate enhancements, determined by Iram's traits.</French>
		<German>The Aspirant is Iram Damarr's signature unit. Sharing many characteristics with the Grigori Adventurer, it is a unit that can be upgraded into any other unit, spawned through a civilization counter, at a rate determined by the amount of Shaper Cabals and Laboratories present in the empire. In addition to the normal abilities of the unit it is promoted into, it also has a number of innate enhancements, determined by Iram's traits.</German>
		<Italian>L'Aspirante è l'unità distintiva di Iram Damarr. Essa condivide molti tratti con l'Avventuriero Grigori, può venir migliorata in qualsiasi altra unità e viene generata attraverso un contatore specifico ad un ritmo determinato dal numero di Cabale e Laboratori del Plasmatore presenti nell'impero. In aggiunta alle normali capacità dell'unità in cui viene migliorata possiede anche dei potenziamenti innati determinati dai tratti di Iram.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Aspirant is Iram Damarr's signature unit. Sharing many characteristics with the Grigori Adventurer, it is a unit that can be upgraded into any other unit, spawned through a civilization counter, at a rate determined by the amount of Shaper Cabals and Laboratories present in the empire. In addition to the normal abilities of the unit it is promoted into, it also has a number of innate enhancements, determined by Iram's traits.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Aspirant, Core Promo -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ASPIRANT</Tag>
		<English>Aspirant</English>
		<French>Aspirant</French>
		<German>Aspirant</German>
		<Italian>Aspirante</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aspirant</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Aspirant, Tier 1 -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ASPIRANT_1</Tag>
		<English>Aspirant - Innate resistance to Disease and Magic</English>
		<French>Aspirant - Innate resistance to Disease and Magic</French>
		<German>Aspirant - Innate resistance to Disease and Magic</German>
		<Italian>Aspirante - Resistenza Innata alle Malattie e alla Magia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aspirant - Innate resistance to Disease and Magic</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Aspirant, Tier 2 -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ASPIRANT_2</Tag>
		<English>Aspirant - Enhanced Strength</English>
		<French>Aspirant - Enhanced Strength</French>
		<German>Aspirant - Enhanced Strength</German>
		<Italian>Aspirante - Forza Migliorata</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aspirant - Enhanced Strength</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Aspirant, Tier 3 -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ASPIRANT_3</Tag>
		<English>Aspirant - Enhanced Toughness and Regeneration</English>
		<French>Aspirant - Enhanced Toughness and Regeneration</French>
		<German>Aspirant - Enhanced Toughness and Regeneration</German>
		<Italian>Aspirante - Costituzione Migliorata e Rigenerazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aspirant - Enhanced Toughness and Regeneration</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>  <!-- Secondary UnitCombat: Melee -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ASCENDANT_MELEE</Tag>
		<English>Secondary UnitCombat: Melee</English>
		<French>Secondary UnitCombat: Melee</French>
		<German>Secondary UnitCombat: Melee</German>
		<Italian>UnitCombat Secondaria: Mischia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Secondary UnitCombat: Melee</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
		<TEXT>  <!-- Create Behemoth, Help -->  <!-- Mekara V2 text Start -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_BEHEMOTH_CREATION_V2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifices 4 Slave units to create a Behemoth unit[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can only by cast by a civ lead by Jamal Dahkar</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifices 4 Slave units to create a Behemoth unit[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can only by cast by a civ lead by Jamal Dahkar</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifices 4 Slave units to create a Behemoth unit[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can only by cast by a civ lead by Jamal Dahkar</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifices 4 Slave units to create a Behemoth unit[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can only by cast by a civ lead by Jamal Dahkar</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifices 4 Slave units to create a Behemoth unit[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can only by cast by a civ lead by Jamal Dahkar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Prepare Augmentation Ritual -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RITUAL_PREPARATION_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Click on another unit in the stack and use their "Designate Target Spell" to choose who to buff[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Berserker needs Body and Force mana to use[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Protector needs Earth and Law mana to use[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Assassin needs Shadow and Air mana to use</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Click on another unit in the stack and use their "Designate Target Spell" to choose who to buff[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Berserker needs Body and Force mana to use[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Protector needs Earth and Law mana to use[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Assassin needs Shadow and Air mana to use</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Click on another unit in the stack and use their "Designate Target Spell" to choose who to buff[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Berserker needs Body and Force mana to use[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Protector needs Earth and Law mana to use[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Assassin needs Shadow and Air mana to use</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Click on another unit in the stack and use their "Designate Target Spell" to choose who to buff[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Berserker needs Body and Force mana to use[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Protector needs Earth and Law mana to use[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Assassin needs Shadow and Air mana to use</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Click on another unit in the stack and use their "Designate Target Spell" to choose who to buff[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Berserker needs Body and Force mana to use[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Protector needs Earth and Law mana to use[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Assassin needs Shadow and Air mana to use</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Augmentation Berserker -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RITUAL_AUG_OFFENCE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Berserker needs Body and Force mana to use</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Berserker needs Body and Force mana to use</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Berserker needs Body and Force mana to use</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Berserker needs Body and Force mana to use</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Berserker needs Body and Force mana to use</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Augmentation Protector -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RITUAL_AUG_DEFENCE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Protector needs Earth and Law mana to use</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Protector needs Earth and Law mana to use</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Protector needs Earth and Law mana to use</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Protector needs Earth and Law mana to use</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Protector needs Earth and Law mana to use</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Augmentation Assassin -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RITUAL_AUG_ASSASSIN_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Assassin needs Shadow and Air mana to use</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Assassin needs Shadow and Air mana to use</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Assassin needs Shadow and Air mana to use</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Assassin needs Shadow and Air mana to use</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Assassin needs Shadow and Air mana to use</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Conduct Experiments -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SHAPER_EXPERIMENTS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Kills the Slave and gives the Shaper some experience</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Kills the Slave and gives the Shaper some experience</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kills the Slave and gives the Shaper some experience</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Kills the Slave and gives the Shaper some experience</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Kills the Slave and gives the Shaper some experience</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Enslaver Trait -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TRAIT_ENSLAVERS_SHORT</Tag>
		<English>Slv</English>
		<French>Slv</French>
		<German>Slv</German>
		<Italian>Slv</Italian>
		<Spanish>Slv</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Enslaver Trait -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TRAIT_ENSLAVERS</Tag>
		<English>Enslavers</English>
		<French>Enslavers</French>
		<German>Enslavers</German>
		<Italian>Enslavers</Italian>
		<Spanish>Enslavers</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>	<!-- Enslaver Trait -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TRAIT_ENSLAVERS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants [LINK=PROMOTION_SLAVER_MEKARA]Slaver[\LINK] to all units</English>
		<French>[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants [LINK=PROMOTION_SLAVER_MEKARA]Slaver[\LINK] to all units</French>
		<German>[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants [LINK=PROMOTION_SLAVER_MEKARA]Slaver[\LINK] to all units</German>
		<Italian>[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants [LINK=PROMOTION_SLAVER_MEKARA]Slaver[\LINK] to all units</Italian>
		<Spanish>[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants [LINK=PROMOTION_SLAVER_MEKARA]Slaver[\LINK] to all units</Spanish>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>	<!-- Sluga Bloom V2 -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_BLOOM_MEKARA_V2</Tag>
		<English>Overseer Spell: Bloom</English>
		<French>Overseer Spell: Bloom</French>
		<German>Overseer Spell: Bloom</German>
		<Italian>Overseer Spell: Bloom</Italian>
		<Spanish>Overseer Spell: Bloom</Spanish>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>	<!-- Sluga Scorch V2 -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SCORCH_MEKARA_V2</Tag>
		<English>Overseer Spell: Scorch</English>
		<French>Overseer Spell: Scorch</French>
		<German>Overseer Spell: Scorch</German>
		<Italian>Overseer Spell: Scorch</Italian>
		<Spanish>Overseer Spell: Scorch</Spanish>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>	<!-- Sluga Spring V2 -->
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SPRING_MEKARA_V2</Tag>
		<English>Overseer Spell: Spring</English>
		<French>Overseer Spell: Spring</French>
		<German>Overseer Spell: Spring</German>
		<Italian>Overseer Spell: Spring</Italian>
		<Spanish>Overseer Spell: Spring</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
