<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CALABIM_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Calabim</English>
		<French>calabion:calabionne:calabions:calabionnes</French>
		<German>Calabimisch</German>
		<Italian>Calabim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Calabim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CALABIM_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Calabim</English>
		<French>Calabim</French>
		<German>Reich der Calabim</German>
		<Italian>Calabim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Calabim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CALABIM_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Calabim</English>
		<French>Calabions</French>
		<German>Calabim</German>
		<Italian>Calabim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Calabim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CALABIM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Calabim's main strength lies in their vampire units, which gain great power by feasting on citizens in their cities. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Age of Ice almost spelt the end of the vampires. When the vast sheets spread over the once-fertile land, their main source of food, humanity, started to become scarce and ever more concentrated in small tribes. Fearing a fate worse than death-the shadowy almost-death of a vampire deprived of fresh nourishment for centuries-most vampires tried to cling to the ever-shrinking communities of survivors. A lone vampire trapped in a small group of people quickly switches from hunter to prey. One by one, the vampires were dispatched to the afterlife.[PARAGRAPH:1]Of those few vampires who escaped the hunters, most took to a feral existence, living off whatever inferior blood they could scavenge in the wild, preying off the occasional human unfortunate enough to be caught alone. But some wise few realized that the only path to survival lay in making the natural transition from parasite to master. [PARAGRAPH:1]Led by the ancient siblings Alexis and Flauros, a small group of surviving vampires "adopted" a rag-tag tribe of humans. Using their powers as immortals, unaffected by cold, or exhaustion, gifted with incredible vision and speed, they made sure the tribe had plenty of food. And all they asked in return was an endless, expendable resource: A few drops of blood. But a vampire's powers are not restricted to supernatural senses and strength-their great power is in the mind.[PARAGRAPH:1]Slowly but surely, using their natural powers of guile and persuasion, and dangling the "Dark Gift" as bait to lure the best and strongest humans into helping them, the vampires wormed their way to the top of their little society. Few wished to oppose them and risk losing their valuable hunting skills. Those who did had accidents, or simply disappeared.[PARAGRAPH:1]When the humans finally realized what was happening, it was too late. They were trapped in a hellish situation, little more than cattle for a growing class of parasitic nobility, and they had been trapped there of their own free will.[PARAGRAPH:1]Now, Flauros and Alexis are the Grand Prince and Princess of a depraved and hopeless society of bloodpets and slaves, controlled by the Grand Broods, the vampire families that rule each city as their own personal estate farms, living in decadent luxury, and sating their lust for blood at will. The Calabim are the apex of vampire evolution, an abomination that is the natural enemy of all holy nations.</English>
		<French>Le principal atout des Calabims réside dans leurs unités vampiriques, qui obtiennent une grande puissance en dévorant les citoyens de leurs villes.[PARAGRAPH:1]L'Âge de Glace a failli marquer la fin des vampires. Quand le gel commença à se répandre sur les terres autrefois fertiles, leur principale source de nourriture, les hommes, commença à se faire rare et toujours plus concentrés en petites tribus. Craignant un sort pire que la mort (l'ombre de la presque mort d'un vampire privé de nourriture pour des siècles), la plupart des vampires tentèrent de se rattacher aux communautés toujours plus petites de survivants. Un vampire seul coincé dans un petit groupe de survivants passe rapidement du statut de chasseur à celui de chassé. Un par un, les vampires furent expédiés dans l'après-vie.[PARAGRAPH:1]Des quelques vampires qui échappèrent aux chasseurs, la plupart choisirent une vie sauvage, survivant grâce à n'importe quel sang inférieur qu'ils pouvaient glaner dans les contrées sauvages, chassant à l'occasion l'homme assez malchanceux pour être découvert seul. Mais un petit nombre d'entre eux réalisa que le seul chemin de la survie passait par la transition naturelle de parasite à maitre.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mené par les anciens frère et s&#156;ur Alexis et Flauros, un petit groupe de vampires survivants "adoptèrent" une tribu humaine loqueteuse. Utilisant leurs pouvoir en tant qu'immortels, insensibles au froid ou à la fatigue, dotés d'une vision et d'une vitesse incroyable, ils firent en sorte que la tribu possède toujours bien assez de nourriture. Et tout ce qu'ils demandaient en retour était une ressource sans fin dont la tribu pouvait se passer : quelques gouttes de sang. Mais les pouvoirs d'un vampire ne sont pas limités à des sens et une force surnaturels, leur grand pouvoir est mental.[PARAGRAPH:1]Doucement mais sûrement, utilisant leurs capacités naturelles d'astuce et de persuasion, et faisant miroiter le "Sombre Don" comme appât pour pousser les meilleurs et le plus forts des hommes à les servir, les vampires s'insinuèrent jusqu'au sommet de leur petite société. Peu souhaitaient s'opposer à eux au risque de perdre leurs indispensables talents de chasse. Ceux qui osèrent furent victimes d'accidents, ou disparurent simplement.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quand les humains prirent conscience de ce qui se passait, il était trop tard. Ils étaient pris au piège d'une situation désastreuse, à peine plus que du bétail pour une classe croissante de nobles parasites, et ils s'y étaient eux même pris au piège.[PARAGRAPH:1]Aujourd'hui, Fleuros et Alexis sont le Grand Prince et la Grande Princesse d'une société dépravée et sans espoir de familiers sanguins et d'esclaves, sous le contrôle des Grandes Couvées, les familles vampires qui dirigent chaque ville comme si elles étaient leurs propres fermes personnelles, vivant dans un luxe décadent, et assouvissant à volonté leur soif de sang. Les Calabims sont au sommet de l'évolution des vampires, une abomination faisant office d'ennemi naturel de toutes les nations saintes.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Hauptstärke der Calabim liegt in ihren Vampireinheiten, die mit der Technologie "Feudalismus" zur Verfügung stehen und die durch durch das Verschlingen von Bürgern der eigenen Städte große Stärke erlangen können.[PARAGRAPH:1]Das Zeitalter des Eises bedeutete für die Vampire fast das Ende. Als sich das Eis über das einst fruchtbare Land ausbreitete, begann ihre Hauptnahrungsquelle, die Menschheit, immer knapper zu werden und sich zu immer kleineren Stämmen zusammenzufinden. Da sie ein schlimmeres Schicksal als den Tod fürchteten, nämlich den schattenhaften Beinahe-Tod eines Vampires, der frischer Nahrung für Jahrhunderte beraubt wird, versuchten die meisten Vampire, sich an die immer kleiner werdenden Gemeinschaften der Überlebenden zu klammern. Aber ein einzelner Vampir, der von einer kleinen Gruppe von Menschen gefangen wurde, wurde schnell vom Jäger zum Gejagten. Einer nach dem anderen wurde so ins Jenseits befördert.[PARAGRAPH:1]Von den wenigen Vampiren, die den Jägern entwischen konnten, fristeten die meisten ein Dasein als Wilde, ernährten sich von dem minderwertigen Blut, das sie in der Wildnis ergattern konnten, und machten gelegentlich Jagd  auf einen Menschen, der zu seinem Unglück allein unterwegs war. Aber einige wenige weise Vampire begriffen, dass der einzige Weg zu überleben darin lag, die natürliche Wandlung vom Parasiten zum Herren und Meister zu vollziehen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Eine kleine Gruppe von überlebenden Vampiren, die von den Geschwistern Alexis und Flauros geführt wurde, "adoptierten" einen bunt gemischten Stamm von Menschen. Indem sie ihre Fähigkeiten als Unsterbliche benutzten, gefeit gegen Kälte oder Ermüdung und ausgestattet mit unglaublicher Weitsicht und Geschwindigkeit, stellten sie sicher, dass der Stamm über reichlich Nahrung verfügte. Und als einzige Gegenleistung verlangten sie einen im Überfluss zur Verfügung stehenden und verzichtbaren Rohstoff: ein paar Tropfen Blut. Aber die Kräfte eines Vampirs sind nicht nur auf übernatürliche Sinne und Stärke beschränkt, ihre eigentliche Stärke ist ihr Geist.[PARAGRAPH:1]Indem sie ihre angeborenen Fähigkeiten der List und der Überredung einsetzten und die besten und stärksten Menschen mit der "Dunklen Gabe" als Belohnung für deren Hilfe köderten, stiegen die Vampire langsam aber sicher zu den Anführern ihrer kleinen Gesellschaft auf. Einzelne wollten sich ihnen widersetzen und riskierten, ihre wertvollen Fähigkeiten als Jäger zu verlieren. Jene, die es tatsächlich versuchten, erlitten Unfälle oder verschwanden ganz einfach.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als die Menschen schließlich begriffen, was vor sich ging, war es schon zu spät. Sie waren in einer höllischen Lage gefangen, kaum mehr als Vieh für eine wachsende Schicht von parasitären Adeligen, und ihr eigener freier Wille hatte sie in diese Situation gebracht.[PARAGRAPH:1]Inzwischen sind Flauros und Alexis der Großprinz und die Großprinzessin einer verkommenen und hoffnungslosen Gesellschaft von Blutdienern und Sklaven geworden, die von den Großen Bruten kontrolliert wird, den Vampirfamilien, die jede Stadt wie ihre eigenen Gutshöfe beherrschen, in dekadentem Luxus schwelgen und ihren Blutdurst nach Belieben stillen. Die Calabim sind der Gipfel der vampirischen Evolution, eine Abscheulichkeit, die der natürliche Feind einer jeden heiligen Nation ist.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il principale punto di forza dei Calabim sono le loro unità di Vampiri, che possono ottenere una grande forza banchettando con i cittadini delle loro città. [PARAGRAPH:1]L'Era del Ghiaccio portò i vampiri sull'orlo dell'estinzione. Quando la neve coprì le terre un tempo fertili la loro fonte principale di cibo, ovvero l'umanità, iniziò a scarseggiare ed essere concetrata in piccole tribù. Temendo un destino peggiore della morte, che è la quasi morte subita dai vampiri privati di nutrimento fresco per secoli, la maggior parte dei vampiri cercarono di infiltrarsi nelle comunità sempre più piccole di sopravvissuti. Tuttavia un singolo vampiro all'interno di un piccolo gruppo di persone passa rapidamente da predatore a preda. E cosi, uno ad uno, i vampiri furono spediti nell'aldilà.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dei pochi vampiri che sfuggirono ai cacciatori la maggior parte si inselvatichì, sopravvivendo nutrendosi di qualsiasi sangue riuscivano a trovare nelle terre selvagge, con l'occassionale umano tanto sfortunato da essere preso da solo. Altri invece realizzarono che l'unico modo per sopravvivere consisteva nel compiere la naturale trasformazione da parassiti a governanti. [PARAGRAPH:1]Guidati dagli antichi sorella e fratello Alexis e Flauros, un piccolo gruppo di vampiri superstiti "adottò" una sgangherata tribù umana. Usando i loro poteri da immortali, non subendo gli effetti del freddo e della fatica e possedendo un'incredibile vista e velocità, si assicurarono che la tribù avesse un ingente quantita di cibo. Tutto ciò che chiesero in cambio fu una risorsa infinita ed economica: Qualche goccia di sangue. Però i poteri dei vampiri non si limitano a una forza e dei sensi sovranaturali, la loro più grande forza è la mente.[PARAGRAPH:1]I vampiri, lentamente ma inesorabilmente, si fecero strada sino all'apice della loro piccola società usando le loro doti naturali di persuasione e inganno, oltre ad usare il "Dono Oscuro" come esca per convincere gli umani più forti e capaci ad aiutarli. Erano pochi coloro che volevano opporsi a loro e cosi facendo rischiare di perdere le loro preziose capacità predatorie. Coloro che gli si opposero ebbero degli incidenti, o semplicemente svanirono nel nulla.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quando gli umani infine capirono cosa stava accadendo era ormai troppo tardi. Erano intrappolati in una situazione infernale, poco più che del bestiame per una crescente classe nobiliare parassita, ed erano finiti in questa situazione di loro spontanea volontà.[PARAGRAPH:1]Adesso, Flauros e Alexis sono i Gran Principe e Principessa di una società depravata e disperata composta da Famigli di Sangue e schiavi, controllata dalle Grandi Casate dei vampiri, che governano le città come fossero i loro allevamenti personali, vivendo in un lusso decadente e soddisfando la loro sete di sangue quando vogliono. I Calabim sono l'apice dell'evoluzione vampiresca, un'abominio che è il nemico naturale di tutte le nazioni sante.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Calabim's main strength lies in their vampire units, which gain great power by feasting on citizens in their cities. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Age of Ice almost spelt the end of the vampires. When the vast sheets spread over the once-fertile land, their main source of food, humanity, started to become scarce and ever more concentrated in small tribes. Fearing a fate worse than death-the shadowy almost-death of a vampire deprived of fresh nourishment for centuries-most vampires tried to cling to the ever-shrinking communities of survivors. A lone vampire trapped in a small group of people quickly switches from hunter to prey. One by one, the vampires were dispatched to the afterlife.[PARAGRAPH:1]Of those few vampires who escaped the hunters, most took to a feral existence, living off whatever inferior blood they could scavenge in the wild, preying off the occasional human unfortunate enough to be caught alone. But some wise few realized that the only path to survival lay in making the natural transition from parasite to master. [PARAGRAPH:1]Led by the ancient siblings Alexis and Flauros, a small group of surviving vampires "adopted" a rag-tag tribe of humans. Using their powers as immortals, unaffected by cold, or exhaustion, gifted with incredible vision and speed, they made sure the tribe had plenty of food. And all they asked in return was an endless, expendable resource: A few drops of blood. But a vampire's powers are not restricted to supernatural senses and strength-their great power is in the mind.[PARAGRAPH:1]Slowly but surely, using their natural powers of guile and persuasion, and dangling the "Dark Gift" as bait to lure the best and strongest humans into helping them, the vampires wormed their way to the top of their little society. Few wished to oppose them and risk losing their valuable hunting skills. Those who did had accidents, or simply disappeared.[PARAGRAPH:1]When the humans finally realized what was happening, it was too late. They were trapped in a hellish situation, little more than cattle for a growing class of parasitic nobility, and they had been trapped there of their own free will.[PARAGRAPH:1]Now, Flauros and Alexis are the Grand Prince and Princess of a depraved and hopeless society of bloodpets and slaves, controlled by the Grand Broods, the vampire families that rule each city as their own personal estate farms, living in decadent luxury, and sating their lust for blood at will. The Calabim are the apex of vampire evolution, an abomination that is the natural enemy of all holy nations.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CALABIM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Strategy:
[NEWLINE]The Calabim use their people like cattle, exploiting and abusing them as cannon fodder and food for their vampiric masters.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Calabim signature unit, the [LINK=UNIT_VAMPIRE]Vampire[\LINK], is unlocked with [LINK=TECH_FEUDALISM]Feudalism[\LINK], once you research that, the calabim's true potential opens up as vampires are able to [LINK=SPELL_FEAST]feast[\LINK] on the populations of their cities for experience.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Vampires are able to share their [LINK=SPELL_GIFT_VAMPIRISM]"gift"[\LINK] to any unit you control of level 6+ (4+ if a [LINK=UNIT_MOROI]Moroi[\LINK]). this allows for many powerful options, but what vampires really excel at is Arcane units. with enough experience an [LINK=UNIT_ARCHMAGE]Archmage[\LINK] can wield the power of gods and bring Erebus to its knees, but be careful not to die early or you will have to start over.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Vampires need a lot of food, this means a lot of people; so the Calabim want to prioritize buildings that store food for growth, like their [LINK=BUILDING_BREEDING_PIT]Breeding Pit[\LINK]. Other options like the [LINK=BUILDING_TOWER_OF_COMPLACENCY]Tower of Complacency[\LINK] or [LINK=BUILDING_CITY_OF_A_THOUSAND_SLUMS]City of a Thousand Slums[\LINK] allow you to make one gigantic feeding city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Calabim will grow very large cities but with a focus on food they lack production and will have a lot of unhappy people, this is where the [LINK=BUILDING_GOVERNORS_MANOR]Governor's Manor[\LINK] comes in, giving 1 production per 1 population. A good choice is also using [LINK=CIVIC_SLAVERY]Slavery[\LINK], sacrificing population to finish units or buildings.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Calabim Hero is [LINK=UNIT_LOSHA]Losha[\LINK], a deadly vampire duchess who gains immortality from slaying enemies.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Their world spell [LINK=SPELL_RIVER_OF_BLOOD]River of Blood[\LINK] can be used early on to quickly get your cities up to speed, as well as setting other civs back several turns.</English>
		<French>[H2]Stratégie :[\H2][PARAGRAPH:1]Vos vampires, disponibles après la découverte du [LINK=TECH_FEUDALISM]Féodalisme[\LINK] peuvent être nourris soit en mettant en places quelques grandes villes-fermes, soit simplement en prenant des villes ennemies et en dévorant l'ensemble de la population (bon appétit !). Répandez le don à autant d'unités que possible (vos Moroï peuvent recevoir le [LINK=SPELL_GIFT_VAMPIRISM]Don du Vampire[\LINK] plus rapidement que vos autres unités, qui ont pour ça généralement besoin d'atteindre le niveau 6) pour leur permettre l'accès à cette méthode simple d'apprentissage. Grâce à leur bâtiment unique qu'est la [LINK=BUILDING_BREEDING_PIT]Fosse d'Élevage[\LINK], les Calabims profitent de synergies avec la doctrine [LINK=CIVIC_SLAVERY]Esclavage[\LINK]; chaque fois que vous n'utilisez pas vos citoyens comme nourriture pour vos vampires, ils peuvent être sacrifiés pour accélérer la production. Vos citoyens pourraient se sentir quelque peu mécontents, mais resteront heureusement productifs grâce à la présence d'un [LINK=BUILDING_GOVERNORS_MANOR]Manoir du Gouverneur[\LINK] dans la ville.</French>
		<German>Strategie: Ihre Vampire (durch Feudalismus erreichbar) können entweder durch den Bau großer Bauern-Städte, oder einfach durch die Eroberung von feindlichen Städten und das Verschlingen derer gesamten Bewohner genährt werden (Guten Appetit). Verteilen Sie dieses Geschenk auf so viele Einheiten wie Sie können (Ihre Moroi Einheiten können Vampirismus früher als andere Einheiten annehmen), und übernehmen Sie die Welt. Mit ihrer einzigartigen Aufzuchtgrube können die Calabim auch Synergien mit den Schatten der Tiefe und dem Aschfahlen Schleier eingehen, da die einzigartigen Regierungsformen dieser Religionen den Gebrauch von Sklavenarbeit erlauben - wann immer Ihre Bürger nicht als Vampirfutter verwendet werden, können sie für Produktion verheizt werden. (Ihre Bürger könnten ein bisschen unzufrieden sein, aber sie werden sowieso bald genug tot sein.)</German>
		<Italian>[H2]Strategia:[\H2]I tuoi vampiri (disponibili con il [LINK=TECH_FEUDALISM]Feudalesimo[\LINK]) possono nutrirsi sia attraverso citta-allevamento create apposta per questo che consumando l'intera popolazione delle città nemiche conquistate (bon appetit). Diffondi il dono a quante più delle tue unità puoi (i Moroi possono ricevere il vampirismo prima delle altre unit?, che normalmente richiede che l'unit? sia minimo di 6° livello) per permettere ad altri tipi di unità di accedere a questo semplice modo di acquisire esperienza. Inoltre con uno dei loro edifici unici, la Fossa d'Alimentazione, i Calabim sinergizzano bene con la forma di governo Schiavitù; quando i cittadini non vengono usati come cibo per i vampiri possono essere sacrificati per ottenere martelli. (I tuoi cittadini potrebbero essere un pò maldisposti, ma continuerebbero ad essere produttivi con un Maniero del Governatore in città.)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Estrategia: Los vampiros (disponibles por el Feudalismo) pueden ser alimentados tanto con un par de ciudades grandes de granjas como simplemente atacando ciudades enemigas y alimentarse con la población entera (bon appetit). Propagad el don en tantas unidades como sea posible (los Moroi consiguen vampirismo antes que cualquier otra unidad) y conquistad el mundo. Con su edificio único, el Pozo de Alimentación, los Calabim también sintonizan con los Octópodos Supremos y el Velo Ceniciento, pues las doctrinas únicas de estas religiones permiten las labores esclavistas - Cuando los ciudadanos no están siendo usados como alimento vampírico, pueden ser eliminados para la producción. (Los ciudadanos pueden sentirse un poco infelices, pero habrían muerto tarde o temprano de todas formas.)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALEXIS</Tag>
		<English>Alexis</English>
		<French>Alexis</French>
		<German>Alexis</German>
		<Italian>Alexis</Italian>
		<Spanish>Alexis</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALEXIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]Born during the fifth generation of men Haborym was a beautiful, stubborn and fierce warrior for her people. Her life had been violent, as it was for most people of her age. Eventually she found happiness with a man who she married, and together they had a beautiful daughter named Morgryn. Eight years later she was pregnant again. [PARAGRAPH]They were happy until the day her husband was killed. Haborym was so shocked by her husband's death that she went into labor and gave birth to her son. The birth and the trauma of losing her husband left Haborym sick and depressed. It awakened in Morgryn an affinity for Death magic, on top of the Body and Spirit affinity she had from birth. The young Morgryn took care of her mother and baby brother until the night both children disappeared. Haborym and the rest of her village searched for them, but they were never found. Losing her children right after husband broke Haborym. She began hunting at the edge of other human villages, stealing children. She was insane and most died in her care (though it would often take weeks for her to notice). When Haborym died she became a demoness. Sometimes humans leave their babies at the edge of the Umbrawood for elves to find and raise. But usually it is Haborym that finds them. She appears as a crazed, beautiful demoness with eight breasts. And she usually has babies swaddled to her, living or dead. [PARAGRAPH]There is only one person who knows what happened to Haborym's children. The one who kidnapped them, Os-Gabella. She renamed them Alexis and Flauros. Even they don't know who their mother is, although Alexis may rememberif hears the name Morgryn. [PARAGRAPH:2]The adopted daughter of Os-Gabella would become the queen and progenitor of the vampires. Raised by an immortal mother, she was faced with her own mortality and unwilling to accept that she would be the first in the Bair of Lacuna to die. To get her over her fear of death, Os-Gabella took her to the crude villages of early men and showed her how they lived and died. Wishing to examine this death more closely, Alexis came to the village at night and killed a shepherd. [PARAGRAPH:1]The shepherd's death didn't answer her questions: she saw no spirit leaving his body and his body grew cool, but if his life went anywhere she couldn't see the change. Alexis had access to the teaching of Ceridwen, who had built the Bair of Lacuna and had surrounded it in runes that keep the unwelcome from entering it from other planes, and those imprisoned within it from leaving through the same means. These last runes Alexis used at the site of her 2nd killing, a young acolyte of Lugus named Lanthis. [PARAGRAPH:1]Lanthis lay dying but unable to die within Alexis's ring of runes, his spirit unable to escape to the vault. Cut and battered within the circle, Lanthis writhed in agony while Alexis watched. When she tired of watching, Alexis stepped into the circle and allowed Lanthis's spirit an escape, into her. To transition the spirit she touched him, kissing him on his blood soaked forehead. At that moment, at that taste of blood, the first vampire was born. Alexis did not become possessed by the spirit, but consumed it and thereby extended her own mortal lifespan. [PARAGRAPH:1]Over the next few centuries, she shared the secret with her brother and they parted from their immortal mother and began hunting men in a variety of guises. One life could extend their own for 20-30 years so they didn't hunt often but they were a legendary threat to men from creation. [PARAGRAPH:1]Besides her brother, Alexis herself would raise only 6 more vampires: Ravana the Hunter, Baobhan the Beautiful, Stolas the Dark Sorcerer, Danag the Devout of Aeron, Valas the Vagrant, and Churel her (former) King Consort. These would go on to lead autonomous Clans with their own peculiar customs, but all owe fealty to Queen Alexis. [PARAGRAPH:1]Being raised as a new vampire requires complete supplication to one's maker. That supplication is eternal, and makes it impossible for them to resist the spells of their immediate liege lord. This bond is not inherited and losing a lord does not impact the vampire. To ensure their vassals' vassals respect the hierarchy, some clans require additional binding rituals. Clan Stolas demands their initiates to be bound to demons, despite Flauros's contempt for the Infernal. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Magic, Alexis joined the Coven of the Black Candle to help the corrupted Kylorin follow Ceridwen's command to perform the Ritual of Endless Night. Her mother was in the Coven as well, but neither knew it as all its members wore Masks enchanted by Esus himself (who defied the Compact and pretended to be Wode in order to join the Coven too) that perfectly hid their identities. (Hers was a crude mask of strips of flesh sewn together into a face. It was later stolen by Wode, and after his death remains hidden deep below the ruins of Patria. ) The ritual requires seven archmages to channel the dominions of Force, Nature, Shadow, Dimensional, Entropy, Sun and Metamagic. Alexis had no affinity in any of those, but was enlisted to force Gastrius to participate. She had hundreds of vampires disguised as Patrian soldiers slip into his Duchy to attempt to capture Gastrius. They were detected, so in a panic Gastrius began awakening the latent magical talent in all those around him. Many were overwhelmed by the power and became uncontrollable, some went mad, most gained terrifying powers (one gained the ability to speak to birds, which wasn't much help when being attacked by a vampire horde). The battle between awakened spellcasters and vampires was brutal with heavy casualties on both sides. Many of the awakened escaped but Gastrius didn't. He was captured by the masked Alexis and she shattered his body, trapping his soul so that she could use his power for the ritual. [PARAGRAPH:1]The 'Endless Night' they summoned end after only 7 years, but that was enough time to hunt The Empyrean to extinction. The worship of Lugus would not return for over 600 years. [PARAGRAPH:1]After Kylorin repented his sins Alexis would go on to lead the Calabim as one of the strongest factions in the Patrian Civil War, but they struggled to survive the Age of Ice and have not yet regained their former glory.</English>
		<French>Fille adoptive d'Os-Gabella et grande s&#156;ur de Flauros, Alexis est la reine et la première des vampires.  Elevée par une mère immortelle, elle a été confrontée à sa propre mortalité et à son refus d'être la première du Bair de Lacuna à mourir. Pour surmonter sa peur de la mort, Os-Gabella l'emmena dans les modestes villages des premiers hommes et lui montra comment ils vivaient et mouraient. Voulant examiner la mort de plus près, Alexis de rendit au village de nuit et tua un berger.[PARAGRAPH:1]La mort du berger n'apporta pas de réponse à ses questions, elle ne vit aucun esprit sortir de son corps, qui était devenu froid mais si une vie en était sorti, elle n'avait pas remarqué de différence.  Alexis eut accès aux enseignements de Ceridwen, celui qui bâtit le Bair de Lacuna et l'entoura de runes qui empêchaient les intrus d'y pénétrer depuis d'autres plans, et de même que ceux emprisonnés ici d'en sortir. Alexis utilisa ces mêmes runes pour commetre son second meurtre, celui d'un jeune acolyte de Lugus nommé Lanthis.[PARAGRAPH:1]Lanthis était mourant, mais incapable de mourir à l'intérieur du cercle de runes d'Alexis, car son esprit ne parvenait pas à s'en aller dans l'Au-Delà. Tailladé et battu à l'intérieur du cercle, Lanthis se débattait dans son agonie tandis qu'Alexis l'observait. Lorsqu'elle fut lasse d'observer, Alexis fit un pas dans le cercle et fournit à l'esprit de Lanthis une possibilité de fuite, en elle.  Pour permettre la transition, elle le toucha, embrassant son front recouvert de sang. À cet instant, à la découverte du goût du sang, le premier vampire était né.  Alexis ne fut pas possédée par cet esprit, elle le consomma et sa vie mortelle s'en trouva rallongée.[PARAGRAPH:1]Au cours des quelques siècles suivants elle partagea le secret avec son frère et ils quittèrent leur mère immortelle pour partir à la chasse à l'homme sous différents aspects. Une vie pouvait rallonger la leur de 20-30 ans donc ils ne chassaient pas souvent mais ils étaient une menace légendaire pour tous les hommes de la création.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Adoptierte Tochter von Os-Gabella und der älteren Schwester von Flauros ist Alexis sowohl Königin, als auch erste unter den Vampiren. Großgezogen von einer unsterblichen Mutter, wurde sie mit ihrer eigenen Sterblichkeit konfrontiert und war nicht Willens als erstes Wesen im Bair of Lacuna zu sterben. Um ihr die Angst vor dem Tode zu nehmen, nahm Os-Gabella sie daraufhin mit zu einem Barbarendorf und zeigte ihr das dortige Leben und Sterben. Um den Tod jedoch genauer untersuchen zu können, kam Alexis nachts zurück in das Dorf, um einen Schäfer zu töten und zu untersuchen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Des Schäfers Tod beantwortete keine ihrer Fragen: kein sichtbarer Geist verließ den Körper, dieser wurde nur kalt. Ob sein Lebenshauch entwich um irgendwohin zu gehen, sie konnte es nicht erkennen. Alexis hatte jedoch Zugang zu den Lehren von Ceridwen, die den Bair von Lacuna gebaut und diesen mit Schutzrunen versehen hatte. Diese Runen verwehrten den nicht Willkommenen den Zutritt aus anderen Sphären und den dort Gefangenen das Verlassen. Diese Runen verwendete Alexis nun bei ihrer zweiten Tötung. Der eines jungen Gefolgsmannes des Lugus namens Lanthis.[PARAGRAPH:1]Lanthis lag im Sterben, war aber innerhalb des von Alexis errichteten Schutzringes aus Runen unfähig zum Tode, seiner Seele war es nicht möglich den Körper zu verlassen. Alexis schaute zu wie sich Lanthis in Todesqualen innerhalb des Schutzringes wand. Als sie des Zuschauens müde war trat sie in den Ring und ermöglichte dadurch Lanthis` Seele die Flucht - in ihren Körper. Um die Überleitung der Seele zu ermöglichen berührte sie ihn, küsste ihn auf seine blutgetränkte Stirn. In diesem Moment, mit dem Geschmack des Blutes wurde der erste Vampir geboren. Die Seele des Lanthis beherrschte Alexis nicht, die Seele wurde durch Alexis vielmehr verbraucht und verlängerte ihr sterbliches Leben.[PARAGRAPH:1]Über die nächsten Jahrhunderte teilte Alexis ihr Geheimnis mit ihrem Bruder und die beiden trennten sich von ihrer unsterblichen Mutter und begannen in einer Vielzahl von Erscheinungen Menschen zu jagen. Ein Leben verlängerte ihr eigenes um 20-30 Jahre und obwohl sie somit nicht oft jagen mussten wurden sie zu einer sagenumwobenen Gefahr für die Menschen der Schöpfung.</German>
		<Italian>[PARAGRAPH:1]Born during the fifth generation of men Haborym was a beautiful, stubborn and fierce warrior for her people. Her life had been violent, as it was for most people of her age. Eventually she found happiness with a man who she married, and together they had a beautiful daughter named Morgryn. Eight years later she was pregnant again. [PARAGRAPH]They were happy until the day her husband was killed. Haborym was so shocked by her husband's death that she went into labor and gave birth to her son. The birth and the trauma of losing her husband left Haborym sick and depressed. It awakened in Morgryn an affinity for Death magic, on top of the Body and Spirit affinity she had from birth. The young Morgryn took care of her mother and baby brother until the night both children disappeared. Haborym and the rest of her village searched for them, but they were never found. Losing her children right after husband broke Haborym. She began hunting at the edge of other human villages, stealing children. She was insane and most died in her care (though it would often take weeks for her to notice). When Haborym died she became a demoness. Sometimes humans leave their babies at the edge of the Umbrawood for elves to find and raise. But usually it is Haborym that finds them. She appears as a crazed, beautiful demoness with eight breasts. And she usually has babies swaddled to her, living or dead. [PARAGRAPH]There is only one person who knows what happened to Haborym's children. The one who kidnapped them, Os-Gabella. She renamed them Alexis and Flauros. Even they don't know who their mother is, although Alexis may rememberif hears the name Morgryn. [PARAGRAPH:2]The adopted daughter of Os-Gabella would become the queen and progenitor of the vampires. Raised by an immortal mother, she was faced with her own mortality and unwilling to accept that she would be the first in the Bair of Lacuna to die. To get her over her fear of death, Os-Gabella took her to the crude villages of early men and showed her how they lived and died. Wishing to examine this death more closely, Alexis came to the village at night and killed a shepherd. [PARAGRAPH:1]The shepherd's death didn't answer her questions: she saw no spirit leaving his body and his body grew cool, but if his life went anywhere she couldn't see the change. Alexis had access to the teaching of Ceridwen, who had built the Bair of Lacuna and had surrounded it in runes that keep the unwelcome from entering it from other planes, and those imprisoned within it from leaving through the same means. These last runes Alexis used at the site of her 2nd killing, a young acolyte of Lugus named Lanthis. [PARAGRAPH:1]Lanthis lay dying but unable to die within Alexis's ring of runes, his spirit unable to escape to the vault. Cut and battered within the circle, Lanthis writhed in agony while Alexis watched. When she tired of watching, Alexis stepped into the circle and allowed Lanthis's spirit an escape, into her. To transition the spirit she touched him, kissing him on his blood soaked forehead. At that moment, at that taste of blood, the first vampire was born. Alexis did not become possessed by the spirit, but consumed it and thereby extended her own mortal lifespan. [PARAGRAPH:1]Over the next few centuries, she shared the secret with her brother and they parted from their immortal mother and began hunting men in a variety of guises. One life could extend their own for 20-30 years so they didn't hunt often but they were a legendary threat to men from creation. [PARAGRAPH:1]Besides her brother, Alexis herself would raise only 6 more vampires: Ravana the Hunter, Baobhan the Beautiful, Stolas the Dark Sorcerer, Danag the Devout of Aeron, Valas the Vagrant, and Churel her (former) King Consort. These would go on to lead autonomous Clans with their own peculiar customs, but all owe fealty to Queen Alexis. [PARAGRAPH:1]Being raised as a new vampire requires complete supplication to one's maker. That supplication is eternal, and makes it impossible for them to resist the spells of their immediate liege lord. This bond is not inherited and losing a lord does not impact the vampire. To ensure their vassals' vassals respect the hierarchy, some clans require additional binding rituals. Clan Stolas demands their initiates to be bound to demons, despite Flauros's contempt for the Infernal. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Magic, Alexis joined the Coven of the Black Candle to help the corrupted Kylorin follow Ceridwen's command to perform the Ritual of Endless Night. Her mother was in the Coven as well, but neither knew it as all its members wore Masks enchanted by Esus himself (who defied the Compact and pretended to be Wode in order to join the Coven too) that perfectly hid their identities. (Hers was a crude mask of strips of flesh sewn together into a face. It was later stolen by Wode, and after his death remains hidden deep below the ruins of Patria. ) The ritual requires seven archmages to channel the dominions of Force, Nature, Shadow, Dimensional, Entropy, Sun and Metamagic. Alexis had no affinity in any of those, but was enlisted to force Gastrius to participate. She had hundreds of vampires disguised as Patrian soldiers slip into his Duchy to attempt to capture Gastrius. They were detected, so in a panic Gastrius began awakening the latent magical talent in all those around him. Many were overwhelmed by the power and became uncontrollable, some went mad, most gained terrifying powers (one gained the ability to speak to birds, which wasn't much help when being attacked by a vampire horde). The battle between awakened spellcasters and vampires was brutal with heavy casualties on both sides. Many of the awakened escaped but Gastrius didn't. He was captured by the masked Alexis and she shattered his body, trapping his soul so that she could use his power for the ritual. [PARAGRAPH:1]The 'Endless Night' they summoned end after only 7 years, but that was enough time to hunt The Empyrean to extinction. The worship of Lugus would not return for over 600 years. [PARAGRAPH:1]After Kylorin repented his sins Alexis would go on to lead the Calabim as one of the strongest factions in the Patrian Civil War, but they struggled to survive the Age of Ice and have not yet regained their former glory.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Hija adoptiva de Os-Gabella y hermana mayor de Flauros, Alexis es la reina y la primera vampiro.  Alzada por una madre inmortal, se enfrentó a su propia mortalidad y poco dispuesta a aceptar que que ella fuera la primera en morir en el Bair de Lacuna.  Para hacerle terminar su temor a la muerte, Os-Gabella la llevó a las ordinarias aldeas de los humanos primitivos y le enseñó cómo vivían y morían.  Deseosa de examinar esta muerte más de cerca, Alexis fue a la aldea por la noche y mató a un pastor.[PARAGRAPH:1]La muerte del pastor no respondió a sus preguntas: no vió ningún espíritu dejando su cuerpo y éste se enfrió, pero si su vida se fue a alguna parte no pudo ver el cambio.  Alexis tenía acceso a las enseñanzas de Ceridwen, quien construyó el Bair de Lacuna y lo rodeó de runas que evitan que no entre ningún inoportuno desde otros planos, y que aquellos aprisionados dentro no puedan irse por los mismos medios.  Alexis usó estas runas en el lugar de su segundo asesinato, un joven acólito de Lugus llamado Lanthis.[PARAGRAPH:1]Lanthis yace muriendo pero incapaz de morir dentro del anillo de runas de Alexis, su espíritu incapaz de escapar de la caja.  Cortado y magullado dentro del círculo, Lanthis se retorcía en ña agonía mientras Alexis observaba.  Cuando se cansó de observar, Alexis entró en el círculo y permitió al espíritu de Lanthis escapar, dentro ella.  Para transferir el espíritu, ella le tocó, besándole en su frente ensangrentada.  En ese momento, con esa degustación de sangre, nació el primer vampiro.  Alexis no fue poseída por el espíritu, ella lo consumió y su vida mortal se extendió a causa de ello.[PARAGRAPH:1]Siglos más tarde, compartió el secreto con su hermano y se separaron de su madre inmortal para empezar a cazar a los hombres de toda clase de formas.  Una vida podía extender las suyas unos 20-30 años, así que no cazaron demasiado, pero fueron una legendaria amenaza para los hombres de la creación.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIJAH</Tag>
		<English>Elijah Arnauld</English>
		<French>Elijah Arnauld</French>
		<German>Elijah Arnauld</German>
		<Italian>Elijah Arnauld</Italian>
		<Spanish>Elijah Arnauld</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIJAH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Elijah entered his throne room, as always the same herald (or not; Elijah didn't care, he only cared that someone announced him, even if there was no one to hear it) recited the pompous annunciation: "Count Elijah Arnauld, gracious sovereign of the fief of Itos and benevolent ruler of its people, loyal retainer to the Calabim crown".[NEWLINE]
He elegantly walked toward his throne. It was made of black marble, just like a great part of the high-ceilinged throne room; it also had columns with white and black marble in an elegant pattern, and each column had an angel sculpted near the top; Elijah sense of aesthetics was ironic indeed. Behind the throne hung the banners of the Calabim to the left and right, with the Arnauld heraldic crest dwarfing the others in the center. [NEWLINE]
He sat down and, almost immediately, a female servant appeared almost out of nowhere to serve him an elegant crystal cup on a golden tray, which obviously contained blood.
"Any news from the Royal court?" Elijah questioned, in regal tone.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"Nothing to note, Lord Elijah. Lady Alexis has rejected the Kuriotates' peace proposal, and Lord Flauros has been quite occupied these last months; some say he's preparing a great festival for-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
Elijah interrupted his servant, "Enough, it seems clear that Alexis is again beheading, or rather biting, our enemies' ambassadors. I don't know why she commits such a vulgar act, like those Doviello beasts. Seeing the ambassador retired, his mission failed, and his reprimand incoming, is a much more pleasant sensation."[NEWLINE]
"And why drink blood directly from the Cattle? Don't the mortals have others milk their animals? It's so much more pleasant to drink blood in this way," he said, pausing to take a sip from his cup. "Aaah, refreshing indeed. So delicious are things when you obligate others to do them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And Flauros, he's just like a child. He toys around with his people, his food,  like he is a puppeteer, a role more befitting that jester that the Balseraphs call a ruler. Maybe he's one of them after all!" He laughed in a profound, elegant way.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"Such murderous and capricious examples of our race are these rulers. Behind all that royalty, and pomposity, there are only beasts that obey their lowest instincts; is this the way they demonstrate our superiority over the Cattle? Fools, let them stay in their hedonistic ways. Let them think they're in control. For when the time comes, the name of Arnauld shall be the one to be heard all over the Calabim Empire, and beyond its boundaries. One day, the living, the dead, even the divine shall come under my rule! For the only one suited to reign, is I!" Elijah stood up as he pronounced this last sentence.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And again, he does it," thought his scribe. "Such a dominant ruler he is, that he reminds us of it every day."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And he's really convincing, if only he had the power he thirsts for..."
		</English>
		<French>Elijah entered his throne room, as always the same herald (or not; Elijah didn't care, he only cared that someone announced him, even if there was no one to hear it) recited the pompous annunciation: "Count Elijah Arnauld, gracious sovereign of the fief of Itos and benevolent ruler of its people, loyal retainer to the Calabim crown".[NEWLINE]
He elegantly walked toward his throne. It was made of black marble, just like a great part of the high-ceilinged throne room; it also had columns with white and black marble in an elegant pattern, and each column had an angel sculpted near the top; Elijah sense of aesthetics was ironic indeed. Behind the throne hung the banners of the Calabim to the left and right, with the Arnauld heraldic crest dwarfing the others in the center. [NEWLINE]
He sat down and, almost immediately, a female servant appeared almost out of nowhere to serve him an elegant crystal cup on a golden tray, which obviously contained blood.
"Any news from the Royal court?" Elijah questioned, in regal tone.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"Nothing to note, Lord Elijah. Lady Alexis has rejected the Kuriotates' peace proposal, and Lord Flauros has been quite occupied these last months; some say he's preparing a great festival for-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
Elijah interrupted his servant, "Enough, it seems clear that Alexis is again beheading, or rather biting, our enemies' ambassadors. I don't know why she commits such a vulgar act, like those Doviello beasts. Seeing the ambassador retired, his mission failed, and his reprimand incoming, is a much more pleasant sensation."[NEWLINE]
"And why drink blood directly from the Cattle? Don't the mortals have others milk their animals? It's so much more pleasant to drink blood in this way," he said, pausing to take a sip from his cup. "Aaah, refreshing indeed. So delicious are things when you obligate others to do them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And Flauros, he's just like a child. He toys around with his people, his food,  like he is a puppeteer, a role more befitting that jester that the Balseraphs call a ruler. Maybe he's one of them after all!" He laughed in a profound, elegant way.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"Such murderous and capricious examples of our race are these rulers. Behind all that royalty, and pomposity, there are only beasts that obey their lowest instincts; is this the way they demonstrate our superiority over the Cattle? Fools, let them stay in their hedonistic ways. Let them think they're in control. For when the time comes, the name of Arnauld shall be the one to be heard all over the Calabim Empire, and beyond its boundaries. One day, the living, the dead, even the divine shall come under my rule! For the only one suited to reign, is I!" Elijah stood up as he pronounced this last sentence.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And again, he does it," thought his scribe. "Such a dominant ruler he is, that he reminds us of it every day."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And he's really convincing, if only he had the power he thirsts for..."
		</French>
		<German>Elijah entered his throne room, as always the same herald (or not; Elijah didn't care, he only cared that someone announced him, even if there was no one to hear it) recited the pompous annunciation: "Count Elijah Arnauld, gracious sovereign of the fief of Itos and benevolent ruler of its people, loyal retainer to the Calabim crown".[NEWLINE]
He elegantly walked toward his throne. It was made of black marble, just like a great part of the high-ceilinged throne room; it also had columns with white and black marble in an elegant pattern, and each column had an angel sculpted near the top; Elijah sense of aesthetics was ironic indeed. Behind the throne hung the banners of the Calabim to the left and right, with the Arnauld heraldic crest dwarfing the others in the center. [NEWLINE]
He sat down and, almost immediately, a female servant appeared almost out of nowhere to serve him an elegant crystal cup on a golden tray, which obviously contained blood.
"Any news from the Royal court?" Elijah questioned, in regal tone.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"Nothing to note, Lord Elijah. Lady Alexis has rejected the Kuriotates' peace proposal, and Lord Flauros has been quite occupied these last months; some say he's preparing a great festival for-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
Elijah interrupted his servant, "Enough, it seems clear that Alexis is again beheading, or rather biting, our enemies' ambassadors. I don't know why she commits such a vulgar act, like those Doviello beasts. Seeing the ambassador retired, his mission failed, and his reprimand incoming, is a much more pleasant sensation."[NEWLINE]
"And why drink blood directly from the Cattle? Don't the mortals have others milk their animals? It's so much more pleasant to drink blood in this way," he said, pausing to take a sip from his cup. "Aaah, refreshing indeed. So delicious are things when you obligate others to do them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And Flauros, he's just like a child. He toys around with his people, his food,  like he is a puppeteer, a role more befitting that jester that the Balseraphs call a ruler. Maybe he's one of them after all!" He laughed in a profound, elegant way.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"Such murderous and capricious examples of our race are these rulers. Behind all that royalty, and pomposity, there are only beasts that obey their lowest instincts; is this the way they demonstrate our superiority over the Cattle? Fools, let them stay in their hedonistic ways. Let them think they're in control. For when the time comes, the name of Arnauld shall be the one to be heard all over the Calabim Empire, and beyond its boundaries. One day, the living, the dead, even the divine shall come under my rule! For the only one suited to reign, is I!" Elijah stood up as he pronounced this last sentence.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And again, he does it," thought his scribe. "Such a dominant ruler he is, that he reminds us of it every day."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And he's really convincing, if only he had the power he thirsts for..."
		</German>
		<Italian>Elijah entered his throne room, as always the same herald (or not; Elijah didn't care, he only cared that someone announced him, even if there was no one to hear it) recited the pompous annunciation: "Count Elijah Arnauld, gracious sovereign of the fief of Itos and benevolent ruler of its people, loyal retainer to the Calabim crown".[NEWLINE]
He elegantly walked toward his throne. It was made of black marble, just like a great part of the high-ceilinged throne room; it also had columns with white and black marble in an elegant pattern, and each column had an angel sculpted near the top; Elijah sense of aesthetics was ironic indeed. Behind the throne hung the banners of the Calabim to the left and right, with the Arnauld heraldic crest dwarfing the others in the center. [NEWLINE]
He sat down and, almost immediately, a female servant appeared almost out of nowhere to serve him an elegant crystal cup on a golden tray, which obviously contained blood.
"Any news from the Royal court?" Elijah questioned, in regal tone.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"Nothing to note, Lord Elijah. Lady Alexis has rejected the Kuriotates' peace proposal, and Lord Flauros has been quite occupied these last months; some say he's preparing a great festival for-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
Elijah interrupted his servant, "Enough, it seems clear that Alexis is again beheading, or rather biting, our enemies' ambassadors. I don't know why she commits such a vulgar act, like those Doviello beasts. Seeing the ambassador retired, his mission failed, and his reprimand incoming, is a much more pleasant sensation."[NEWLINE]
"And why drink blood directly from the Cattle? Don't the mortals have others milk their animals? It's so much more pleasant to drink blood in this way," he said, pausing to take a sip from his cup. "Aaah, refreshing indeed. So delicious are things when you obligate others to do them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And Flauros, he's just like a child. He toys around with his people, his food,  like he is a puppeteer, a role more befitting that jester that the Balseraphs call a ruler. Maybe he's one of them after all!" He laughed in a profound, elegant way.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"Such murderous and capricious examples of our race are these rulers. Behind all that royalty, and pomposity, there are only beasts that obey their lowest instincts; is this the way they demonstrate our superiority over the Cattle? Fools, let them stay in their hedonistic ways. Let them think they're in control. For when the time comes, the name of Arnauld shall be the one to be heard all over the Calabim Empire, and beyond its boundaries. One day, the living, the dead, even the divine shall come under my rule! For the only one suited to reign, is I!" Elijah stood up as he pronounced this last sentence.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And again, he does it," thought his scribe. "Such a dominant ruler he is, that he reminds us of it every day."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And he's really convincing, if only he had the power he thirsts for..."
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>Elijah entered his throne room, as always the same herald (or not; Elijah didn't care, he only cared that someone announced him, even if there was no one to hear it) recited the pompous annunciation: "Count Elijah Arnauld, gracious sovereign of the fief of Itos and benevolent ruler of its people, loyal retainer to the Calabim crown".[NEWLINE]
He elegantly walked toward his throne. It was made of black marble, just like a great part of the high-ceilinged throne room; it also had columns with white and black marble in an elegant pattern, and each column had an angel sculpted near the top; Elijah sense of aesthetics was ironic indeed. Behind the throne hung the banners of the Calabim to the left and right, with the Arnauld heraldic crest dwarfing the others in the center. [NEWLINE]
He sat down and, almost immediately, a female servant appeared almost out of nowhere to serve him an elegant crystal cup on a golden tray, which obviously contained blood.
"Any news from the Royal court?" Elijah questioned, in regal tone.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"Nothing to note, Lord Elijah. Lady Alexis has rejected the Kuriotates' peace proposal, and Lord Flauros has been quite occupied these last months; some say he's preparing a great festival for-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
Elijah interrupted his servant, "Enough, it seems clear that Alexis is again beheading, or rather biting, our enemies' ambassadors. I don't know why she commits such a vulgar act, like those Doviello beasts. Seeing the ambassador retired, his mission failed, and his reprimand incoming, is a much more pleasant sensation."[NEWLINE]
"And why drink blood directly from the Cattle? Don't the mortals have others milk their animals? It's so much more pleasant to drink blood in this way," he said, pausing to take a sip from his cup. "Aaah, refreshing indeed. So delicious are things when you obligate others to do them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And Flauros, he's just like a child. He toys around with his people, his food,  like he is a puppeteer, a role more befitting that jester that the Balseraphs call a ruler. Maybe he's one of them after all!" He laughed in a profound, elegant way.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"Such murderous and capricious examples of our race are these rulers. Behind all that royalty, and pomposity, there are only beasts that obey their lowest instincts; is this the way they demonstrate our superiority over the Cattle? Fools, let them stay in their hedonistic ways. Let them think they're in control. For when the time comes, the name of Arnauld shall be the one to be heard all over the Calabim Empire, and beyond its boundaries. One day, the living, the dead, even the divine shall come under my rule! For the only one suited to reign, is I!" Elijah stood up as he pronounced this last sentence.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And again, he does it," thought his scribe. "Such a dominant ruler he is, that he reminds us of it every day."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]

"And he's really convincing, if only he had the power he thirsts for..."
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_FLAUROS</Tag>
		<English>Flauros Alexis</English>
		<French>Flauros Alexis</French>
		<German>Flauros Alexis</German>
		<Italian>Flauros Alexis</Italian>
		<Spanish>Flauros Alexis</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_FLAUROS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]"Do you have a name?" the Chamberlain asked her. He had the signs of nobility: the dull yellow eyes, the pale complexion, and most of all, the perpetual sneer. She held back a shudder.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Taerry, sir," the young lady murmured.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Listen close, girl. Don't give him your name unless he asks. Don't call him anything but My Lord or Master. And if you ever want to see you family again, do everything he asks. Are we clear?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes sir," she replied, and the Chamberlain turned away without another glance at her, shutting the door as he did. Taerry allowed herself a few furtive glances around the bedroom as she sat on the very corner of the bed. It was filled with extravagances she didn't even know existed. She noticed silk sheets and curtains, tapestries centuries old and still vibrant, furniture carved from ancient fir trees imported from half the world away, and a tall mirror coated in pristine silver. Taerry know she was out of place as she looked at herself in the mirror, huddled small and dirty in her wool gown.[PARAGRAPH:1]The door opened suddenly, drawing her attention sharply to him. He made the rest of the room seem as ordinary as the dirt on her boots. He was handsome in a way she had never seen before in the weary folk of her village or the arrogant nobles that lorded it over them. With piercing eyes and a tall, sleek frame, he looked like he stepped out of an earlier time, when men were one step removed from the gods themselves. And he carried himself the same way, with an air that simply acknowledged the rest of the world as belonging to him with no need to prove it.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taerry felt all the smaller when he stood facing down at her. "Hello child. Don't be afraid," he said. "I'm sure you have heard all sorts of stories about me."[PARAGRAPH:1]"No, milord."[PARAGRAPH:1]He smiled. "I saw you working in the field, my dear, and asked for you to be brought here. Living in the castle, as I do, can be very isolating. It is not good for a ruler to forget what his people are like. What's your name?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Taerry, milord."[PARAGRAPH:1]"And have you a family, Taerry?" he asked, putting a hand on her shoulder. She started involuntarily at his touch, and his eyes narrowed sharply. "I asked you not to be afraid, Taerry."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Milord, I'm not, it's just... I've not been with a man alone before. Since mother died and my father sent the suitors away so I could help the little ones, I mean."[PARAGRAPH:1]He grasped her other shoulder now, forcing her to look him in the eyes. "Ah, Taerry, relax. Forget about that now. You don't need to worry about suitors or your parents any more."[PARAGRAPH:1]She wanted to protest, but she saw the menace in her eyes. "Yes, Milord."[PARAGRAPH:1]The pain wasn't as bad as she'd been told it would be. After a bit, she let her mind wander, imagining that she was not being taken in this King's bedroom, but rather in her own humble, flee-ridden bed, and that this man was not her King, taking royal prerogative, but her husband-[PARAGRAPH:1]She let out a sharp gasp of pain. "Master, stop!" The pain in her neck intensified and she felt her blood pour down her neck. She cried again, thrashing around, desperate to get away. The man gave no response to her plea for mercy. At last she fell silent, and the world faded to black around her.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Chamberlain met him as he open the door to his bedroom, clad in a silk robe. On the bed behind him lay a young girl, her skin drained of all color, lying in a puddle of blood. Flauros wiped his mouth.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Is she still alive, Milord?" asked the Chamberlain greedily.[PARAGRAPH:1]"As much as she ever was. Do with it as you will."[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis noted his unkempt appearance with a sneer as he walked into the throne room and slouched into his throne. "Must you play with your food, brother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Alexis, if you are around until the end of world, you won't have lived a day in your life with that attitude. Food is to be savored, and there is no flavor quite as exquisite as a maiden with that heady mix of emotions as she's plucked. So did I miss the Kuriotate ambassador?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, just. He offered peace, naturally."[PARAGRAPH:1]"And you sent him home with a 'no'?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I'm sure the baby King will deduce the answer when his ambassador fails to return. I'd never dream of wasting the food, even if it smells like horse."[PARAGRAPH:1]"See, sister dear? I have my games, and you have yours."</English>
		<French>"As-tu un nom ?" lui demanda le chambellan. Il arborait les signes de la noblesse : les yeux jaune mat, le teint pâle, et par-dessus tout, un ricanement perpétuel. Elle retint un frisson.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Taerry, monsieur," murmura la jeune femme.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Écoute attentivement, ma fille. Ne lui donne pas ton nom sauf s'il te le demande. Ne l'appelle pas autrement que Monseigneur ou Maître. Et si tu veux avoir une chance de revoir un jour ta famille, fais tout ce qu'il te demande. Sommes-nous bien d'accord ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oui monsieur," répondit-elle, et le chambellan se retourna sans un dernier regard, fermant la porte tout en le lançant. Taerry se permit quelques rapides coups d'oeil autour de la chambre, tandis qu'elle s'asseyait au coin du lit. Il était bourré de fioritures qu'elles n'imaginait même pas. Elle repéra des draps de soie, ainsi que des rideaux, des tapisseries vieux de plusieurs siècles et pourtant toujours brillants, de mobilier taillé à partir de pommes de pin importés depuis la moitié du monde, et un grand miroir éncadré d'argent pur. Taerry sut qu'elle n'était pas à sa place en se regardant dans le miroir ratatinée et sale dans sa robe en laine.[PARAGRAPH:1]La porte s'ouvrit soudainement, attirant son attention directement sur lui. Il rendait le reste de la pièce aussi ordinaire que la terre sur ses bottes. Il était d'une beauté jamais vue chez les gens fatigués de son village ou les nobles arrogants qui les dirigeaient. Des yeux perçants, une silhouette grande et douce, il donnait l'impression de sortir d'un autre temps, quand les hommes n'étaient qu'à un pas des dieux. Et il se tenait de la même manière, avec la tranquille certitude que le monde lui appartenait et qu'il n'avait nul besoin de le prouver.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taerry se sentit minuscule quand il se tourna vers elle. "Bonjour mon enfant. N'aie pas peur," dit-il. "Je suissûr que tu as entendu toutes sortes d'histoires me concernant."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non, seigneur."[PARAGRAPH:1]Il sourit. "Je t'ai vue travailler dans les champs, ma chère, et ai demandé à ce que tu sois amenée ici. Vivre dans le château, comme je le fais, peut faire se sentir seul. Il n'est pas bon pour un dirigeant d'oublier à quoi ressemble son peuple. Quel est ton nom ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Taerry, seigneur."[PARAGRAPH:1]As-tu une famille Taerry ?" demanda-t-il, posant une main sur son épaule. Elle sursauta involontairement à son contact, et ses yeux s'étrécirent. "Je t'ai demandé de ne pas être inquiètes, Taerry."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Seigneur, je ne suis pas, c'est juste... Je suis encore vierge. Parce que ma mère est morte et que mon père a écarté mes prétendants pour que je puisse m'occuper des plus jeunes, je veux dire."[PARAGRAPH:1]Il saisissait maintenant son autre épaule, la forçant à le regarder dans les yeux. "Ah, Taerry, détends-toi. Oublie tout ça maintenant. Tu n'as plus besoin de t'inquiéter de tes prétendants ou de tes parents maintenant."[PARAGRAPH:1]Elle voulut protester, mais vit la menace dans ses yeux. "Oui, seigneur."[PARAGRAPH:1]La douleur n'était pas si intense que ce qu'on lui avait dit. Rapidement, elle laissa son esprit errer, imaginant qu'elle n'avait pas été emmenée dans la chambre de ce Roi, mais plutôt dans son propre lit humble et sans puces, et que cet homme n'était pas son Roi, faisant usage des prérogatives royales, mais son mari.[PARAGRAPH:1]Elle laissa échapper un cri aigu de douleur. "Maître, stop !" La douleur dans sa nuque s'intensifia et elle sentit le sentit s'écouler le long de sa nuque. Elle cria à nouveau, se débattant désespérément pour s'échapper. L'homme ne réagit pas à ses supplications. Finalement, elle se tut, et le monde s'obscurcit autour d'elle.[PARAGRAPH:2]Le chambellan vint à sa rencontre quand il ouvrit la porte de sa chambre, vêtu d'une robe en soie. Sur le lit derrière lui gisait une jeune femme, sa peau drainée de toute couleur, étendue dans une flaque de sang. Flauros s'essuya la bouche.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Est-elle encore en vie, Monseigneur ?" demanda le chambellan avec gourmandise.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Autant qu'elle l'a jamais été. Fais en ce que tu veux."[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis nota son allure débraillée avec un ricanement, tandis qu'il pénétrait dans la salle du trône et s'affalait dans son trône. "Dois-tu jouer avec ta nourriture, mon frère ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Alexis, même si tu restes jusqu'à la fin du monde, tu n'auras pas vécu un seul jour de ta vie avec cette attitude. La nourriture doit être savourée, et il n'existe pas d'arôme plus exquis qu'une vierge avec ce mélange d'émotions dans sa tête tandis qu'elle est cueillie. Donc, ai-je manqué l'ambassadeur Kuriotate ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oui, à l'instant. Il a offert la paix, naturellement."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Et tu l'as renvoyé chez lui avec un 'non' ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Je suis sûre que le gamin Roi déduira la réponse quand son ambassadeur échouera à rentrer. Je n'ai jamais imaginé gâcher de la nourriture, même si elle sent le cheval."[PARAGRAPH:1]" Tu vois, ma chère s&#156;ur ? J'ai mes jeux, et tu as les tiens."</French>
		<German>[TAB]"Hast Du einen Namen?" fragte sie der Kammermeister. Er trug die Zeichen des Adelsgeschlechts: die trüben gelben Augen, die helle Hautfarbe, und am meisten den immerwährenden Spott. Sie unterdrückte ein Schaudern.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Taerry, mein Herr," murmelte die junge Frau.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hör gut zu, junges Mädchen. Nenne niemals deinen Namen, bevor er dich fragt. Nenne ihn nicht anders als Mein Lord oder Mein Herrscher. Und wenn du jemals deine Familie wiedersehen willst, tust du alles was von dir verlangt wird. Verstehen wir uns?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ja Herr," antwortete sie, und der Kammermeister drehte sich um ohne sie weiter zu beachten und schloß die Tür. Taerry erlaubte sich ein paar heimliche Blicke, als sie auf der äußersten Ecke des Bettes saß. Es war mit Dingen verziert, von denen sie nicht einmal wusste, dass sie überhaupt existieren. Sie bemerkte Seidentücher und -Gardinen, jahrhunderte alte Wandteppiche, die immer noch strahlten, Möbelstücke, die aus altem Tannenholz geschnitzt wurden, welches eine halbe Welt weit entfernt war, und einen kleinen Spiegel, der mit feinem Silber überzogen war. Taerry wusste, dass sie fehle am Platze war, als sie sich im Spiegel betrachtete, zusammengekauert in ihrem Wollmantel.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Tür öffnete sich plötzlich, damit zog er ihre Aufmerksamkeit auf ihn. Gegen ihn wirkte der Rest des Raumes so gewöhnlich wie der Schmutz an ihren Stiefeln. Er wirkte auf eine Weise attraktiv, wie sie niemals zuvor einen aus ihrem geschwächten Volk sah, oder wie sie die arroganten Adeligen sah, die über sie herrschten. Mit durchdringendem Blick und seinem geschmeidigen Schritt sah er wie jemand aus, der aus einer früheren Zeit kam, als die Menschen nur einen Schritt von den Göttern entfernt waren. Und er strahlte etwas aus, dass den Rest der Welt wissen lies, dass sie ihm gehört, ohne es weiter begründen zu müssen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taerry fühlte sich kleiner, als er auf sie herab sah. "Hallo, Kind. Hab keine Angst," sagte er. "Ich bin sicher, du hast allerhand Geschichten über mich gehört."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Nein, Mein Herr."[PARAGRAPH:1]Er lächelte. "Ich sah dich auf den Feldern arbeiten, mein Liebes, und du verlangtest, hierher gebracht zu werden. Das Leben in einem Schloss, wie ich es führe, kann sehr isolierend sein. Es ist nicht gut für einen Herrscher zu vergessen, was in seinem Volk vor sich geht. Wie lautet dein Name?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Taerry, mein Herr."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Und hast du eine Familie, Taerry?" fragte er, während er seine Hand auf ihre Schulter legte. Sie erschrak unwillkürlich ob seiner Berührung, und seine Augen kniffen sich zusammen. "Ich bat dich, keine Angst zu haben, Taerry."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mein Herr, es ist nur... ich war noch nie mit einem Mann allein. Seit Mutter starb und mein Vater die Freier wegschickte, damit ich den Kleinen helfen konnte, meine ich."[PARAGRAPH:1]Er ergriff nun ihre andere Schulter, damit sie ihm in die Augen sehen musste. "Ach Taerry, entspanne dich. Vergiss das jetzt. Du musst dir keine Sorgen mehr um Freier oder deine Eltern machen."[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie wollte protestieren, doch sie sah die Drohung in seinen Augen. "Ja, mein Herr."[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Schmerz war nicht so schlimm, wie ihr erzählt wurde. Nach einer Weile lies sie Ihren Geist umherwandern, sie stellte sich vor, dass sie nicht gerade im Schlafzimmer des Königs genommen wurde, sondern viel mehr in ihrem eigenen bescheidenen Bett von ihrem Ehemann, und nicht von ihrem König, der das königliche Vorrecht ausübte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie lies einen kurzen Seufzer entweichen. "Meister, stop!" Der Schmerz in ihrem Hals wurde stärker und sie fühlte ihr Blut den Hals herunterlaufen. Sie schrie wieder, um sich schlagend, verzweifelt versuchte sie zu entkommen. Der Mann gab ihrer Bitte nach Gnade nicht nach. Zum Schluss wurde alles ruhig, und die Welt verschwand im Schwarz um sie herum.[PARAGRAPH:2]Der Kammermeister traf ihn, als er die Tür zu seinem Schlafzimmer öffnete, gekleidet in einer seidenen Robe. Im Bett hinter ihm befand sich ein junges Mädchen, ihre Haut hatte jede Farbe verloren, welches in einer Blutlache lag. Flauros wischte sich den Mund ab. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Lebt sie noch, mein Herr?" fragte der Kammermeister gierig.[PARAGRAPH:1]"So viel, wie sie immer schon lebte. Mach mit ihr, was du willst."[PARAGRAPH:1] Alexis bemerkte seine ungepflegte Gestalt mit Spott, als er in den Thronsaal schritt und sich auf den Thron fletzte. "Musst du denn mit deiner Nahrung spielen, Bruder?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Alexis, wenn du dich bis ans Ende der Welt herumtreibst, würdest du nicht diese Einstellung haben. Nahrung sollte genossen werden, es gibt keinen besseren Geschmack als ein Mädchen mit einer guten Mischung an Gefühlen, wenn sie ausgesaugt wird. Habe ich den Kuriotatischen Botschafter verpasst?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ja, gerade eben. Er bot wie immer Frieden an."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Und du hast ihm mit einem 'Nein' nach Hause geschickt?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Ich bin sicher, der kleine König wird sich die Antwort denken können, wenn sein Botschafter nicht zurückkehrt. Ich würde niemals Nahrung verschwenden, selbst wenn sie wie ein Pferd stinkt."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Siehst du, Schwesterherz? Ich habe meine Spiele, und du deine."</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]"Hai un nome?" il Ciambellano chiese alla ragazza. Lui aveva i tratti dei nobili: gli occhi giallo opaco, la carnagione pallida, e soprattutto, un ghigno perpetuo. Lei trattenne un brivido.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Taerry, signore" mormorò la ragazzina.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ascolta attentamente, ragazza. Non dire il tuo nome a meno che lui non te lo chieda. Non chiamarlo in nessun altro modo oltre Mio Signore. E se vuoi rivedere la tua famiglia di nuovo fai tutto ciò che chiede. Ci siamo capiti?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Si signore" lei rispose e il Ciambellano si voltò senza degnarla di un'altro sguardo chiudendo le porte mentre si voltava. Taerry diede qualche occhiata furtiva nella stanza da letto mentre si sedeva su un'angolo del letto. Era pieno di stravaganze di cui non ne sapeva nemmeno l'esistenza. Notò lenzuola e tende di seta, arazzi vecchi di secoli ma ancora vivaci, mobili scolpiti da antichi abeti importati da mezzo mondo e uno specchio alto rivestito di puro argento. Taerry sapeva di essere fuori luogo mentre si guardava allo specchio, rannicchiata e sporca nella sua veste di lana.[PARAGRAPH:1]La porta si aprì improvvisamente, attirando la sua attenzione su di lui. Lui faceva apparire il resto della stanza come un qualcosa comune come la terra sugli stivali di lei. Possedeva una bellezza che lei non aveva mai visto prima tra le fiacche persone del suo villaggio o negli arroganti nobili che li governavano. Con degli occhi penetranti e un fisico alto ed elegante sembrava provenire da un tempo remoto, da quando gli uomini erano ad un passo dagli dei stessi. E aveva lo stesso portamento, con una certezza che il mondo gli apparteneva che non aveva bisogno di dimostrazioni.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taerry si sentì ancor più piccola quando lui si mise davanti a lei. "Ciao piccolina. Non aver paura" disse. "Sono sicuro che hai sentito un sacco di storie su di me."[PARAGRAPH:1]"No, mio signore."[PARAGRAPH:1]Lui sorrise. "Ti ho visto lavorare nei campi, mia cara, e ho chiesto che tu venissi portata qui. Vivere in un castello, come faccio io, può essere molto isolante. Non è bene per un governante dimenticare come è la sua gente. Qual'è il tuo nome?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Taerry, mio signore."[PARAGRAPH:1]"E hai una famiglia, Taerry?" lui chiese, poggiandogli una mano sulla sua spalla. Lei sussultò involontariamente al suo tocco, e i suoi occhi si strinsero bruscamente. "Ti ho chiesto di non essere spaventata, Taerry."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mio signore, non lo sono, è solo che... Non sono mai stata da sola con un'uomo prima d'ora. Intendo sin da quando mia madre è morta e mio padre a mandato via tutti i miei corteggiatori cosi che io potessi aiutare i più piccoli."[PARAGRAPH:1]Lui afferrò l'altra sua spalla ora, obbligandola a guardarlo negli occhi. "Ah, Taerry, rilassati. Dimenticati di quello ora. Non devi più preoccuparti dei corteggiatori o dei tuoi genitori."[PARAGRAPH:1]Lei voleva protestare, ma vide la minaccia nei suoi occhi. "Si, mio signore."[PARAGRAPH:1]Il dolore non era cosi elevato come gli era stato detto. Dopo un pò lasciò vagare la sua mente, immaginando che lei non era stata portata in questa stanza da letto del Re, ma invece nel suo modesto letto, e che quell'uomo non era il suo Re, che rivendicava una sua prerogativa, ma suo marito-[PARAGRAPH:1]Gli sfuggì un rantolo di dolore. "Signore, basta!". Il dolore nel collo si intensificò e senti il suo sangue scorrergli sul collo. Pianse di nuovo, agitandosi disperata per allontanarsi. L'uomo non rispose alla sua richiesta di pietà. Alla fine lei svenne.[PARAGRAPH:2]Il Ciambellano lo incontrò, quando aprì le porte della sua stanza da letto, vestito con una veste di seta. Sul letto dietro di lui giaceva, in una pozza di sangue, una ragazzina che aveva la pelle priva di qualsiasi colore. Flauros si asciugò la bocca.[PARAGRAPH:1]"È ancora viva, Mio signore?" chiese avidamente il Ciambellano.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Come non le è mai stata. Fanne quello che vuoi."[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis sogghignò notando l'aspetto trasandato di Flauros mentre lui entrava nella sala del trono per poi accasciarsi sul suo trono. "Devi prorpio giocare col tuo cibo, fratello?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Alexis, con tale atteggiamento è come se non hai vissuto neppure un giorno, nonostante vivrai sino alla fine di tutto. Il cibo va gustato, e non vi è niente di più squisito di quello di una fanciulla con il particolare mix di emozioni dopo che viene ingannata. Quindi, mi sono perso l'ambasciatore Kuriotate?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Si, esatto. Ha offerto la pace, ovviamente."[PARAGRAPH:1]"E lo hai rispedito a casa con un 'no'?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sono sicura che il Re bambino intuirà la risposta quando non vedra il suo ambasciatore fare ritorno. Non mi sognerei mai di sprecare del cibo, persino se puzza come un cavallo."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Vedi, cara sorella? Io ho i miei giochi, e tu hai i tuoi."</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]"Do you have a name?" the Chamberlain asked her. He had the signs of nobility: the dull yellow eyes, the pale complexion, and most of all, the perpetual sneer. She held back a shudder.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Taerry, sir," the young lady murmured.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Listen close, girl. Don't give him your name unless he asks. Don't call him anything but My Lord or Master. And if you ever want to see you family again, do everything he asks. Are we clear?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes sir," she replied, and the Chamberlain turned away without another glance at her, shutting the door as he did. Taerry allowed herself a few furtive glances around the bedroom as she sat on the very corner of the bed. It was filled with extravagances she didn't even know existed. She noticed silk sheets and curtains, tapestries centuries old and still vibrant, furniture carved from ancient fir trees imported from half the world away, and a tall mirror coated in pristine silver. Taerry know she was out of place as she looked at herself in the mirror, huddled small and dirty in her wool gown.[PARAGRAPH:1]The door opened suddenly, drawing her attention sharply to him. He made the rest of the room seem as ordinary as the dirt on her boots. He was handsome in a way she had never seen before in the weary folk of her village or the arrogant nobles that lorded it over them. With piercing eyes and a tall, sleek frame, he looked like he stepped out of an earlier time, when men were one step removed from the gods themselves. And he carried himself the same way, with an air that simply acknowledged the rest of the world as belonging to him with no need to prove it.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taerry felt all the smaller when he stood facing down at her. "Hello child. Don't be afraid," he said. "I'm sure you have heard all sorts of stories about me."[PARAGRAPH:1]"No, milord."[PARAGRAPH:1]He smiled. "I saw you working in the field, my dear, and asked for you to be brought here. Living in the castle, as I do, can be very isolating. It is not good for a ruler to forget what his people are like. What's your name?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Taerry, milord."[PARAGRAPH:1]"And have you a family, Taerry?" he asked, putting a hand on her shoulder. She started involuntarily at his touch, and his eyes narrowed sharply. "I asked you not to be afraid, Taerry."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Milord, I'm not, it's just... I've not been with a man alone before. Since mother died and my father sent the suitors away so I could help the little ones, I mean."[PARAGRAPH:1]He grasped her other shoulder now, forcing her to look him in the eyes. "Ah, Taerry, relax. Forget about that now. You don't need to worry about suitors or your parents any more."[PARAGRAPH:1]She wanted to protest, but she saw the menace in her eyes. "Yes, Milord."[PARAGRAPH:1]The pain wasn't as bad as she'd been told it would be. After a bit, she let her mind wander, imagining that she was not being taken in this King's bedroom, but rather in her own humble, flee-ridden bed, and that this man was not her King, taking royal prerogative, but her husband-[PARAGRAPH:1]She let out a sharp gasp of pain. "Master, stop!" The pain in her neck intensified and she felt her blood pour down her neck. She cried again, thrashing around, desperate to get away. The man gave no response to her plea for mercy. At last she fell silent, and the world faded to black around her.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Chamberlain met him as he open the door to his bedroom, clad in a silk robe. On the bed behind him lay a young girl, her skin drained of all color, lying in a puddle of blood. Flauros wiped his mouth.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Is she still alive, Milord?" asked the Chamberlain greedily.[PARAGRAPH:1]"As much as she ever was. Do with it as you will."[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis noted his unkempt appearance with a sneer as he walked into the throne room and slouched into his throne. "Must you play with your food, brother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Alexis, if you are around until the end of world, you won't have lived a day in your life with that attitude. Food is to be savored, and there is no flavor quite as exquisite as a maiden with that heady mix of emotions as she's plucked. So did I miss the Kuriotate ambassador?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, just. He offered peace, naturally."[PARAGRAPH:1]"And you sent him home with a 'no'?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I'm sure the baby King will deduce the answer when his ambassador fails to return. I'd never dream of wasting the food, even if it smells like horse."[PARAGRAPH:1]"See, sister dear? I have my games, and you have yours."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BREEDING_PIT</Tag>
		<English>Breeding Pit</English>
		<French>Fosse d'Élevage</French>
		<German>Aufzuchtgrube</German>
		<Italian>Fossa d'alimentazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pozo de Alimentación</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BREEDING_PIT_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Increases food prduction of the city, but lower its health by one</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Augmente la production de nourriture de la ville, mais diminue la santé de un</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Increases food prduction of the city, but lower its health by one</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Aumenta il cibo prodotto dalla città, ma ne abbassa la sanità di 1</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Increases food prduction of the city, but lower its health by one</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BREEDING_PIT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases the food available to the city, making it grow faster. Little care is given to the nutritional value or method of delivery of the food, however, and the health of the city is lowered by one.</English>
		<French>Augmente la nourriture disponible pour la ville, la faisant se développer plus rapidement. On n'y prête cependant que peu d'attention à la valeur nutritionnelle ou à la méthode de livraison, et la santé de la ville se trouve de fait réduite de 1.</French>
		<German>Erhöht die zur Verfügung stehende Nahrungsmenge der Stadt, so dass sie schneller wächst. Dem Nährwert und der Art der Nahrungsbeschaffung wird wenig Bedeutung zugemessen, daher wird die Gesundheit der Stadt um 1 gesenkt.</German>
		<Italian>Aumenta il cibo prodotto dalla città facendola crescere più velocemente. Viene data poca attenzione al valore nutrizionale o al metodo di diffusione del cibo comportando cosi un abbassamento della sanità della città di 1.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Incrementa la cantidad de comida disponible para la ciudad, haciéndola crecer con más rapidez. Sin embargo, se le da poco cuidado al valor nutricional o el método de entrega de la comida, y la salud de la ciudad se reduce en 1.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GOVERNORS_MANOR</Tag>
		<English>Governor's Manor</English>
		<French>Manoir du Gouverneur</French>
		<German>Gruft des Grafen</German>
		<Italian>Maniero del Governatore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Terrenos del Gobernante</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GOVERNORS_MANOR_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Reduces war weariness.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Provides production equal to total unhappiness.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Diminue la lassitude due à la guerre.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fournit autant de production que de mécontentement dans la ville.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Reduces war weariness.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Provides production equal to total unhappiness.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Riduce la stanchezza della guerra.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce una quantita di martelli uguale al valore di infelicità.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Reduces war weariness.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Provides production equal to total unhappiness.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GOVERNORS_MANOR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Governor's Manor is the Calabim version of the Courthouse. It doesn't reduce maintenance as much as a typical courthouse but it reduces war weariness and provides [ICON_PRODUCTION] equal to total unhappiness ([ICON_UNHAPPY]) in the city.</English>
		<French>Le Manoir du Gouverneur est la version Calabim du [LINK=BUILDING_COURTHOUSE]Tribunal[\LINK]. Il ne réduit pas le coût d'entretien comme un tribunal classique mais il réduit la Lassitude due à la Guerre et fournit autant de [ICON_PRODUCTION] qu'il y a de mécontentement total ([ICON_UNHAPPY]) dans la ville.</French>
		<German>Die Gruft des Grafen ist die Calabim version des Gerichtes.  Sie reduziert nicht den Stadtunterhalt wie ein normales Gericht aber es reduziert die Lustlosigkeit und provides [ICON_PRODUCTION] equal to total unhappiness ([ICON_UNHAPPY]) in the city.</German>
		<Italian>Il Maniero del Governatore è la versione Calabim del Tribunale. Non riduce il mantenimento quanto un normale tribunale ma riduce la stanchezza della guerra e fornisce [ICON_PRODUCTION] in quantità pari al valore totale di infelicità ([ICON_UNHAPPY]) della città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Governor's Manor is the Calabim version of the Courthouse. It doesn't reduce maintenance as much as a typical courthouse but it reduces war weariness and provides [ICON_PRODUCTION] equal to total unhappiness ([ICON_UNHAPPY]) in the city.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_CALABIM</Tag>
		<English>Calabim Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Calabim</French>
		<German>Palast der Calabim</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo dei Calabim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Calabim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_VAMPIRE</Tag>
		<English>Vampirism</English>
		<French>Vampirisme</French>
		<German>Vampirismus</German>
		<Italian>Vampiro</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vampirism</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FEAST</Tag>
		<English>Feast</English>
		<French>Festin</French>
		<German>Blutopfer</German>
		<Italian>Banchetto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Feast</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FEAST_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Reduces the population of the city and grants experience to the Vampire</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Réduit la population de la ville et confère de l'expérience au Vampire</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Reduziert die Bevölkerung einer Stadt zur Stärkung des Vampirs.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Riduce la popolazione della città di 1 e fornisce esperienza al vampiro</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Reduces the population of the city and grants experience to the Vampire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FEAST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Awaken to darkness, arise from the earth,[PARAGRAPH:1]One vampire's bite brings another one's birth.[PARAGRAPH:1]A vampire wakes with a passionate need[PARAGRAPH:1]To hunt those alive to capture and feed[PARAGRAPH:1]He stalks in the night like a primitive beast,[PARAGRAPH:1]And what once was alive will soon be deceased.[PARAGRAPH:1]So when the sunlight disappears from the sky,[PARAGRAPH:1]Watch well the shadows if you don't want to die."[PARAGRAPH:2]-Victoria Boatwright</English>
		<French>Éveillé des ténèbres, relevé de la terre, [PARAGRAPH:1]La morsure d'un vampire donne naissance à un autre.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un vampire s'éveille avec un besoin dévorant[PARAGRAPH:1]De chasser les vivants pour les capturer et se nourrir[PARAGRAPH:1]Il se fond dans la nuit telle une bête primitive,[PARAGRAPH:1]Et ce qui était vivant sera bientôt décédé.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donc quand la lumière du jour disparait,[PARAGRAPH:1]Surveille bien les ombres si tu ne veux pas mourir."[PARAGRAPH:2]Victoria Boatwright</French>
		<German>[TAB]Erwacht in Dunkelheit, der Erde entstiegen[PARAGRAPH.1]Geboren durch einen Vampirbiss und doch im Jenseits geblieben.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Vampir ist von dem Gedanken besessen,[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Lebenden zu jagen um sie zu fangen und zu essen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er schleicht durch die Nacht wie ein primitives Biest,[PARAGRAPH:1]Und krank wird bald sein wer das Leben genießt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wenn also das Sonnenlicht vom Himmel weicht,[PARAGRAPH:1]Beobachte die Schatten, oder du hast bald das Jenseits erreicht[PARAGRAPH:2] - Victoria Boatwright</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Risvegliati nell'oscurita, sorgi dalla terra,[PARAGRAPH:1]Il morso di un vampiro porta alla nascita di un'altro.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un vampiro si risveglia con un bisogno travolgente[PARAGRAPH:1]Cacciare i vivi per catturarli e nutrirsene[PARAGRAPH:1]Si aggira nella notte come una bestia primitiva,[PARAGRAPH:1]E quello che un tempo era vivo sarà presto morto.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quindi quando la luce del sole scompare dal cielo,[PARAGRAPH:1]Presta attenzione alle ombre se non vuoi morire."[PARAGRAPH:2]-Victoria Boatwright</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Awaken to darkness, arise from the earth,[PARAGRAPH:1]One vampire's bite brings another one's birth.[PARAGRAPH:1]A vampire wakes with a passionate need[PARAGRAPH:1]To hunt those alive to capture and feed[PARAGRAPH:1]He stalks in the night like a primitive beast,[PARAGRAPH:1]And what once was alive will soon be deceased.[PARAGRAPH:1]So when the sunlight disappears from the sky,[PARAGRAPH:1]Watch well the shadows if you don't want to die."[PARAGRAPH:2]-Victoria Boatwright</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FEED</Tag>
		<English>Feed</English>
		<French>Se nourrir</French>
		<German>Futter</German>
		<Italian>Nutrirsi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Feed</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FEED_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifice a Bloodpet to heal the vampire and allow it to attack again</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Tue un familier sanguin oiur soigner le vampire et lui permettre d'attaquer à nouveau</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Tötet eine eigene Einheit zur Regeneration des Vampirs.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifica un Famiglio di Sangue per curare il vampiro e permettergli di attacare di nuovo</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Sacrifice a Bloodpet to heal the vampire and allow it to attack again</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FEED_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Writhing bodies clad in black[NEWLINE]Flow past me as I stare.[NEWLINE]Like beacons on a stormy sea[NEWLINE]The lights around them flare.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Leather, velvet, metal, lace -[NEWLINE]These ornaments they don,[NEWLINE]Yet their necks remain unclothed[NEWLINE]For me to gaze upon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Swirling through the smoke-filled air,[NEWLINE]The music lifts their soul.[NEWLINE]Succumbing to this sonic drug,[NEWLINE]Their minds have lost control.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I pull my cloak in close to me[NEWLINE]And drift into the crowd.[NEWLINE]I search each ghoulish painted face[NEWLINE]As death looms like a cloud.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]My angel's face appears to me[NEWLINE]Amidst the swaying mass.[NEWLINE]I glide to her through sound and haze,[NEWLINE]Ignoring those I pass.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]My eyes fixate upon her skin -[NEWLINE]So smooth, so soft, so white...[NEWLINE]Her naked arms flail wildly.[NEWLINE]She waltzes with the night.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I reach out, and I touch her hair[NEWLINE]Which has fallen in her eyes.[NEWLINE]She sees me for the first time now[NEWLINE]And jumps back in surprise.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I grasp her hand and pull her near.[NEWLINE]She's powerless to my touch.[NEWLINE]I feel her warmth flow into me.[NEWLINE]I want her blood so much.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]But I can bring no harm to her,[NEWLINE]Despite my deadly urge.[NEWLINE]As I stand there with my love,[NEWLINE]My heaven and hell converge.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I cannot make her who I am[NEWLINE]To live eternally,[NEWLINE]Feeding off the innocent[NEWLINE]As they die painfully.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And so I share a final dance[NEWLINE]With her before I go.[NEWLINE]I kiss her lips once, turn away,[NEWLINE]And let my hunger grow.</English>
		<French>Des corps tremblants vêtus de noir[NEWLINE]Me passent devant tandis que je regarde dans le vide.[NEWLINE]Comme les phares sur une mer déchaînée[NEWLINE]Les lumières autour d'eux vacillent.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Cuir, velours, métal, dentelle[NEWLINE]Ces ornements qu'ils vêtissent,[NEWLINE]Et pourtant leurs nuques demeurent nues[NEWLINE]Pour que je les fixe.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Tournoyant dans l'air enfumé,[NEWLINE]la musique élève leurs âmes.[NEWLINE]Succombant à cette drogue sonique,[NEWLINE]Leurs esprits ont perdu les contrôle.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Je tire mon manteau vers moi[NEWLINE]Et dérive dans la foule.[NEWLINE]Je cherche chaque visage peint à la vampire[NEWLINE]Tandis que la mort flotte telle un nuage.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Le visage de mon ange m'apparait[NEWLINE]Au milieu de la masse entraînante.[NEWLINE]Je glisse vers elle à travers le son et la brume,[NEWLINE]Ignorant ceux que je croise.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mes yeux fixés sur sa peau,[NEWLINE]Si lisse, si douce, si blanche...[NEWLINE]Ses bras nus s'agitent sauvagement.[NEWLINE]Elle valsa avec la nuit.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]J'y arrive, et je touche ses cheveux[NEWLINE]qui lui étaient tombés dans les yeux.[NEWLINE]Elle me voit maintenant pour la première fois[NEWLINE]Et fait un bond en arrière de surprise.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Je lui attrape la main et la tire à moi.[NEWLINE]Elle est sans force à mon contact.[NEWLINE]Je sens sa chaleur couler en moi.[NEWLINE]Je veux tellement son sang.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mais je ne peux lui faire de mal,[NEWLINE]Malgré mon besoin pressant.[NEWLINE]Tandis que je me tiens là avec mon amour,[NEWLINE]Mon paradis et mon enfer se rejoignent.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Je ne peux faire d'elle ce que je suis[NEWLINE]Pour vivre éternellement,[NEWLINE]Se nourissant d'innocents[NEWLINE]Tandis qu'ils meurent douloureusement.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Et donc je partage une dernière dance[NEWLINE]Avec elle avant de partir.[NEWLINE]Je lui embrasse les lèvres une fois, me retourne,[NEWLINE]et laisse ma faim grandir.</French>
		<German>Verdunkelt schwarze Leibermassen[NEWLINE]Ziehen vorbei an meinem Gesicht[NEWLINE]Wie Leuchtfeuer bei stürmischer See[NEWLINE]So wild flackert heut ihr Licht[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Leder, Samt, Metall und Spitze[NEWLINE]Und Manches Kleinod tragen sie[NEWLINE]Doch ist der Hals stets unbedeckt[NEWLINE]Genug bekomm ich davon nie[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ein Wirbeln durch die schwangre Luft[NEWLINE]Die Musik erhebt ihre Seelen[NEWLINE]Ergeben und vom Wohlklang verführt[NEWLINE]Mag sie die Macht ihres Geistes zu schmählen[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ich werfe mir den Mantel um[NEWLINE]Begebe mich hinein ins Fleisch[NEWLINE]Die blassen Gesichter betrachte ich[NEWLINE]Wie manch fahler Wolke gleich[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Eines Engels Gesicht erkenne ich[NEWLINE]Unter all jenen die hier stehn[NEWLINE]Zwäng mich vorbei an Lärm und Dunst[NEWLINE]Will niemand von denen sehn[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mein Blick von ihrer Haut gebannt[NEWLINE]So bleich, so weich, so sacht[NEWLINE]Ihre blanken Arme entschwinden nun[NEWLINE]Sie tanzt mit in die finstre Nacht[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ihr Seidenes Haar berühre ich[NEWLINE]Das ihr schönes Gesicht bedeckt[NEWLINE]Erstaunt macht sie einen Satz zurück[NEWLINE]Endlich, sie hat mich entdeckt[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ihre zarte Hand ergreife ich[NEWLINE]Und ziehe sie heran[NEWLINE]Ihr Blut dröhnt laut und warm herinnen[NEWLINE]Die große Gier schlägt an[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Und doch vermag ich es nicht[NEWLINE]Das ihr Blut wird meins[NEWLINE]So steh ich mit ihr[NEWLINE]Himmel und Hölle werden eins[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Kann nicht zu den meinen sie machen[NEWLINE]Ewiglich zu sein[NEWLINE]Von den Lebenden zu zehren[NEWLINE]Die dem Tod fallen anheim[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Einen letzten Tanz verbring ich mit ihr[NEWLINE]Noch einmal bevor ich geh[NEWLINE]Küss ich ihre Lippen ganz sacht[NEWLINE]Mein Verlangen ich wachsen seh.</German>
		<Italian>Corpi vestiti di nero che si contorcevano[NEWLINE]Mi passavano affianco mentre guardavo.[NEWLINE]Come fari in un mare in tempesta[NEWLINE]Le luci intorno a loro brillano.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Cuoio, velluto, metallo, pizzo -[NEWLINE]Questi gli ornamenti che indossano,[NEWLINE]Eppure i loro colli restano scoperti[NEWLINE]Per me da guardare.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Vorticando nell'aria piena di fumo,[NEWLINE]La musica elevava le loro anime.[NEWLINE]Soccombendo a questa droga sonora,[NEWLINE]Avevano perso il controllo delle loro menti.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strinsi il mantello vicino a me[NEWLINE]E mi mossi tra la folla.[NEWLINE]Guardai tutte le facce cupe[NEWLINE]Come la morte che aleggia come una nuvola.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Il volto del mio angelo mi apparve[NEWLINE]In mezzo alla massa che si agitava.[NEWLINE]Mi diressi verso di lei attraverso il suono e la foschia,[NEWLINE]Ignorando coloro che sorpassavo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I miei occhi fissati sulla sua pelle -[NEWLINE]Cosi liscia, cosi soffice, cosi bianca...[NEWLINE]Agitava selvaggiamente le sue braccia scoperte.[NEWLINE]Danzava con la notte.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]La raggiunsi, e toccai i suoi capelli[NEWLINE]Che erano caduti davanti ai suoi occhi.[NEWLINE]Mi vide per la prima volta ora[NEWLINE]E inditreggio sorpresa.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Gli presi la mano e la tirai vicino a me.[NEWLINE]Era impotente al mio tocco.[NEWLINE]Sentii il suo calore fluire in me.[NEWLINE]Volevo il suo sangue cosi tanto.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ma non potevo fargli del male,[NEWLINE]Nonostante il mio impulso mortale.[NEWLINE]E mentre stavo li con il mio amore,[NEWLINE]Il mio paradiso e inferno si unirono.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Non potevo renderla ciò che io sono[NEWLINE]Per vivere in eterno,[NEWLINE]Nutrendosi degli innoccenti[NEWLINE]Mentre muoiono dolorosamente.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]E cosi condivisi un'ultima danza[NEWLINE]Con lei prima che me ne andassi.[NEWLINE]Baciai le sue labbra una volta poi mi allontanai,[NEWLINE]E lasciai crescere la mia fame.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Writhing bodies clad in black[NEWLINE]Flow past me as I stare.[NEWLINE]Like beacons on a stormy sea[NEWLINE]The lights around them flare.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Leather, velvet, metal, lace -[NEWLINE]These ornaments they don,[NEWLINE]Yet their necks remain unclothed[NEWLINE]For me to gaze upon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Swirling through the smoke-filled air,[NEWLINE]The music lifts their soul.[NEWLINE]Succumbing to this sonic drug,[NEWLINE]Their minds have lost control.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I pull my cloak in close to me[NEWLINE]And drift into the crowd.[NEWLINE]I search each ghoulish painted face[NEWLINE]As death looms like a cloud.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]My angel's face appears to me[NEWLINE]Amidst the swaying mass.[NEWLINE]I glide to her through sound and haze,[NEWLINE]Ignoring those I pass.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]My eyes fixate upon her skin -[NEWLINE]So smooth, so soft, so white...[NEWLINE]Her naked arms flail wildly.[NEWLINE]She waltzes with the night.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I reach out, and I touch her hair[NEWLINE]Which has fallen in her eyes.[NEWLINE]She sees me for the first time now[NEWLINE]And jumps back in surprise.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I grasp her hand and pull her near.[NEWLINE]She's powerless to my touch.[NEWLINE]I feel her warmth flow into me.[NEWLINE]I want her blood so much.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]But I can bring no harm to her,[NEWLINE]Despite my deadly urge.[NEWLINE]As I stand there with my love,[NEWLINE]My heaven and hell converge.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I cannot make her who I am[NEWLINE]To live eternally,[NEWLINE]Feeding off the innocent[NEWLINE]As they die painfully.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And so I share a final dance[NEWLINE]With her before I go.[NEWLINE]I kiss her lips once, turn away,[NEWLINE]And let my hunger grow.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_GIFT_VAMPIRISM</Tag>
		<English>Gift Vampirism</English>
		<French>Don du Vampirisme</French>
		<German>Vampirbiss</German>
		<Italian>Bacio di Sangue</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gift Vampirism</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_GIFT_VAMPIRISM_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Gives living units of at least 6th level the [LINK=PROMOTION_VAMPIRE]Vampire[\LINK] promotion.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]for non Calabim the level requirement is 8.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Donne à une unité vivante de niveau 6 la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_VAMPIRE]Vampire[\LINK].</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Verleiht einer lebenden Einheit die Vampirismus-Beförderung, vorausgesetzt sie hat Erfahrungsstufe 6 erreicht.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce alle unita viventi di almeno 6° livello la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_VAMPIRE]Vampiro[\LINK].</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Gives living units of at least 6th level the [LINK=PROMOTION_VAMPIRE]Vampire[\LINK] promotion</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_GIFT_VAMPIRISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>This ability can be used to spread vampirism to other units in the tile. To be worthy of vampirism the unit must be alive and at least 6th level. The Moroi are an exception to this and can receive vampirism at 4th level.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]for non Calabim the level requirement is 8.</English>
		<French>Cette capacité peut être utilisée pour répandre le vampirisme aux autres unités de la pile. Pour être digne d'être un vampire, l'unité doit être vivante et au moins de niveau 6. Les Moroïs sont une exception et peuvent recevoir le vampirisme au niveau 4.</French>
		<German>Diese Fähigkeit kann benutzt werden, um andere Einheiten auf demselben Geländefeld mit Vampirismus zu infizieren. Um mit Vampirismus infiziert zu werden, muss die Einheit lebendig und mindestens Level 6 sein. Die Moroi bilden eine Ausnahme, sie können Vampirismus schon mit Level 4 erhalten.</German>
		<Italian>Quest'abilità può essere usata per diffondere il vampirismo alle altre unità nella casella. Per essere degni del vampirismo un unità deve essere vivente di minimo 6° livello. I Moroi sono un'eccezione a questa regola e possono riceverlo dal 4° livello.</Italian>
		<Spanish>This ability can be used to spread vampirism to other units in the tile. To be worthy of vampirism the unit must be alive and at least 6th level. The Moroi are an exception to this and can receive vampirism at 4th level.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RIVER_OF_BLOOD</Tag>
		<English>River of Blood</English>
		<French>Rivière de Sang</French>
		<German>Flüsse von Blut</German>
		<Italian>Fiume di Sangue</Italian>
		<Spanish>River of Blood</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RIVER_OF_BLOOD_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Reduces the Population in all non-Calabim cities[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Increases the Population of all Calabim cities</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Diminue la population dans toutes les villes non-Calabim[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Augmente la Population dans toutes les villes Calabim</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Reduziert die Bevölkerung in allen nicht-Calabim städten[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Erhöht die Bevölkerung aller Calabim Städte</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Riduce la popolazione di tutte le città non Calabim di 2 (gli Eredi, i D'tesh e gli Infernali ne sono immuni)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Aumenta la popolazione di tutte le città Calabim di 2</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Reduces the Population in all non-Calabim cities[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Increases the Population of all Calabim cities</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BLOODPET</Tag>
		<English>Bloodpet</English>
		<French>Familier Sanguin</French>
		<German>Blutdiener</German>
		<Italian>Famiglio di Sangue</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bloodpet</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BLOODPET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Bloodpets fit into the Calabim human social ladder somewhere between the oppressed peasant and the favored Moroi. They are kept around the Vampiric governors to do all sorts of menial tasks, not the least of which is to serve as cannon fodder. Due to their closer association with the ruling class they are spared the feasting of their peers, but are the first ones to be fed on in a pinch.</English>
		<French>Les Familiers de Sang se situent dans l'échelle sociale humaine Calabim quelque part entre le paysan opprimé et le Moroï favorisé. Ils sont gardés près des gouverneurs vampiriques pour toutes sortes de menues tâches, et servir de chair à canon n'est pas la moindre. À cause de leurs contacts étroits avec la classe dirigeante, ils sont épargnés par les festins de leurs pairs, mais sont les premiers à être mangés en cas de besoin.</French>
		<German>Blutdiener stehen in der sozialen Ordnung der Menschen bei den Calabim irgendwo zwischen den unterdrückten Bauern und den bevorzugten Moroi. Sie werden von den Vampirgrafen gehalten, um alle möglichen Arten von niedrigen Aufgaben auszuführen, wobei ihr Dienst als Kanonenfutter nicht der gringste ist. Auf Grund ihrer engeren Beziehung mit der herrschenden Klasse, werden sie vom Festschmaus ihrer Herren ausgespart, sind aber die ersten, die in einer Notlage verspeist werden.</German>
		<Italian>I Famigli di Sangue si posizionano nella società umana Calabim tra gli oppressi popolani e i prediletti Moroi. Vengono usati dai governanti Vampiri per compiere ogni tipo di lavoro servile, non ultimo quello di fare da carne da cannone. Vista la loro vicinanza alla classe dirigente vengono risparmiati dai banchetti che vengono fatti sui loro simili, ma sono i primi di cui si nutrono in caso di necessità.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bloodpets fit into the Calabim human social ladder somewhere between the oppressed peasant and the favored Moroi. They are kept around the Vampiric governors to do all sorts of menial tasks, not the least of which is to serve as cannon fodder. Due to their closer association with the ruling class they are spared the feasting of their peers, but are the first ones to be fed on in a pinch.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BLOODPET_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>As good as any warrior at early defense and exploration, when fed upon by a vampire using "feed" the vampire will be granted an extra movement and ability to attack again.</English>
		<French>Aussi bon que n'importe quel guerrier dans la défense et l'exploration précoce, en nourrissant un Vampire qui utilise [LINK=SPELL_FEED]Se Nourrir[\LINK], ce dernier gagne un point de mouvement supplémentaire et la capacité d'attaquer à nouveau.</French>
		<German>So gut wie jeder andere Krieger für die frühe Verteidigung und Erkundung, wird es einem Vampir, wenn er es mit der "Futter" Fähigkeit verspeist einen zusätzlichen Bewegungspunkt und die Fähigkeit nochmals anzugreifen garantieren.</German>
		<Italian>Utile come prima difesa ed esplorazione, come qualsiasi guerriero, la sua pecularietà è che può venir sacrificato per nutrire un vampiro attraverso l'abilità "Nutrirsi", fare ciò fornisce al vampiro un punto movimento extra e la possibilità di attaccare di nuovo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>As good as any warrior at early defense and exploration, when fed upon by a vampire using "feed" the vampire will be granted an extra movement and ability to attack again.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BRUJAH</Tag>
		<English>Brujah</English>
		<French>Brujah</French>
		<German>Brujah</German>
		<Italian>Brujah</Italian>
		<Spanish>Brujah</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BRUJAH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Vampires don't tend to shy away from brutality, but most prefer manipulation and petty cruelty to outright savagery. Not the Brujah, however. After leading enough battles, the veneer of civilization that the Calabim have adopted as a survival scheme since the Age of Ice crumbles away. They revel in the carnage of battle, even risking their immortal lives against odd in which Vampire lords would be content to send in fodder after fodder. Their results are hard to argue with, however.</English>
		<French>Les vampires ne s'enfuient pas devant la brutalité, mais la plupart préfère la manipulation et les cruautés mesquines pour satisfaire leur sauvagerie. Mais pas le Brujah. Après avoir dirigé suffisamment de combats, l'illusion de la civilisation que les Calabims ont adopté comme mode de survie depuis l'Âge de Glace tombe en miettes. Ils se complaisent dans les carnages du combat, risquant même leurs vies immortelles inutilement, tandis qu'un Seigneur Vampire se contenterait d'envoyer troupes après troupes. Leurs résultats sont difficiles à contester cependant.</French>
		<German>Vampire neigen nicht dazu, vor Brutalität zurückzuschrecken, aber die meisten bevorzugen Manipulation und unscheinbare Grausamkeit um ihre Wildheit zu verbergen. So jedoch nicht die Brujah. Nachdem genug Schlachten geschlagen wurden fiel der Deckmantel der Zivilisation, den die Calabim als Überlebensvorlage seit der Zeit des Eises übernommen haben, von ihnen ab. Sie ergötzen sich am Blutbad der Schlacht und riskieren sogar ihre Unsterblichkeit für diese seltsamen Riten, bei denen jeder Vampirfürst mit dem Entsenden von Vieh zufrieden wäre. Trotz allem kann man kaum über ihre Ergebnisse klagen.</German>
		<Italian>I vampiri non sono estranei alla violenza, ma la maggior parte preferisce la manipolazione e l'intimidazione alla sola ferocia. Non i Brujah però. Dopo aver condotto abbastanza battaglie la facciata di civilizzazione, che i Calabim hanno adottato durante l'Era del Ghiaccio per sopravvivere, svannisce. Loro godono della carneficina delle battaglie, rischiando persino le loro vite immortali affrontando situazioni in cui perfino un Signore dei Vampiri sarebbe contento di mandare altre truppe sacrificabili. I loro risultati però sono difficili da controbattere.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vampires don't tend to shy away from brutality, but most prefer manipulation and petty cruelty to outright savagery. Not the Brujah, however. After leading enough battles, the veneer of civilization that the Calabim have adopted as a survival scheme since the Age of Ice crumbles away. They revel in the carnage of battle, even risking their immortal lives against odd in which Vampire lords would be content to send in fodder after fodder. Their results are hard to argue with, however.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BRUJAH_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Brujah are functionally identical to Berserkers, causing collateral damage to four other units when attacking stacks. They also start with the vampire promotion and the abilities that come with it, as well as first level death and body spells.</English>
		<French>Les Brujah ont le même fonctionnement que les Berserks, infligeant des dommages collatéraux à quatre autres unités en attaquant une pile. Ils commencent également avec la promotion vampire et les capacités qui viennent avec, de même que les sorts de premier niveau de la magie de mort et de corps.</French>
		<German>Brujahs sind von ihrer Funktion her identisch mit Berserkern: beim Angriff auf einen Einheitenstapel verursachen sie Kollateralschaden an vier weiteren Einheiten. Außerdem beginnen sie als Vampire und verfügen über die zugehörigen Fähigkeiten, sowie über die jeweils erste Stufe der Todes- und Körpermagie.</German>
		<Italian>I Brujah sono funzionalmente identici ai Berserkers, causando danni collaterali ad altre quattro unità quando attaccano i gruppi. Però in più possiedono da subito la promozione Vampiro e tutte le abilità che essa comporta, oltre a poter lanciare le magie di primo livello della magia del corpo e della morte.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Brujah are functionally identical to Berserkers, causing collateral damage to four other units when attacking stacks. They also start with the vampire promotion and the abilities that come with it, as well as first level death and body spells.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LOSHA</Tag>
		<English>Losha Valas Alexis</English>
		<French>Losha Valas Alexis</French>
		<German>Losha Valas Alexis</German>
		<Italian>Losha Valas Alexis</Italian>
		<Spanish>Losha Valas Alexis</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LOSHA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Three generals sat in the antechamber, awaiting their summons to the throne room. One, a battle hardened veteran, sat cold and stoic while the second man, younger and newer to his position, fidgeted nervously. The woman yawned and gazed out the window. Soon the doors opened and they were ushered in and arrayed themselves before the dual thrones. The guards left, leaving the three alone with Alexis and Flauros.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis arose at once, walking swiftly towards them. "You three were ordered to hold our new settlement of Pavu'nar! Yet before you even returned to me, like beaten dogs, my scouts have informed me that our city is ruined! Tell me what happened and why I shouldn't consume- -why I shouldn't have you killed." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Sheol, your report first," Flauros interjected. He still slouched on his throne but his gaze narrowed upon the younger man. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes Master, Mistress. We...on Perdion's orders we split our command into three upon reaching the town. I took charge of the hunters. We headed for the hills and forests, finding the enemy well before they neared Pavu'nar. My, um, I broke my units into small groups to harass the enemy as they marched, and dispatched the scouts with information on their numbers and makeup back to Losha and Perdion. I continued to pick off the enemy through the month as they laid siege to the town. Then, the gates of the town opened! I had not force enough to beat the enemy, Masters...I must report that it was Losha and Perdion that failed you."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You all failed, fool," Alexis snarled. She stomped back to her throne and sat, withering Sheol with her glare. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Perdion, pray continue the tale," Flauros said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"It is as Sheol said, Masters, though I must place the blame squarely on Losha's shoulders. I took the shock troops and left her the archers and the settlers to arrange defense of the town. She should easily have been able to hold out all season, though the number of the enemy turned out to be larger than we expected. I returned to nearby Acaia to gather more forces, and was on my way back when I received the news the settlement had been razed. I left my men garrisoned there and returned when summoned. So clearly Losha cost us the battle," the general finished, stepping back and bowing his head.[PARAGRAPH:1]Flauros smiled. "Losha, it appears as I have often told my sister: the weaker sex lacks judgment as well as strength. But please, tell your story, and we shall see."[PARAGRAPH:1]Losha calmly began. "It is as they say, my prince and princess, though they underestimate the numbers of your foes. They had many times the number we set out with. In a battle we might have taken them, but the deaths of our troops would have been a great loss. So I decided that the loss of the settlers was preferable to battle." [PARAGRAPH:1]"How dare you! You were ordered to hold the settlement!" [PARAGRAPH:1]"My Mistress, I have the orders here with me. It says, stop the invading army when they reach our town of Pavu'nar.' That is what I did." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Losha, you just said that you lost the settlers." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh did I forget to mention? Before I abandoned the town-and its annoying inhabitants-to the enemy, I poisoned the food stores, and the wine, and the water." [PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis blinked; Flauros sat upright in his throne. "Sheol, Perdion, you may leave, your orders will be forthcoming. Losha, stay." The young man skittered out, and the older man followed, but not before giving Losha a cruel smile. [PARAGRAPH:1]"So have I angered my Masters?" Losha asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Dear Losha," Alexis said with a smile, "you have redeemed yourself utterly. Come, we have a gift for you."</English>
		<French>Trois généraux s'assirent dans l'antichambre, attendant leur convocation dans la salle du trône. L'un d'eux, un vétéran endurci par les batailles, restait calme et stoïque tandis que le second, plus jeune et récemment promu, remuait nerveusement. La femme bailla et regarda au travers de la fenêtre. Bientôt les portes s'ouvrirent et ils furent introduits et s'alignèrent devant le double trône. Les gardes se retirèrent, les laissant tous trois seuls avec Alexis et Flauros.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis se leva d'un coup, marchant rapidement autour d'eux. Vous trois étiez chargé de protéger notre nouvelle implantation de Pavu'nar ! Et pourtant, avant même de revenir vers moi, comme des chiens battus, mes éclaireurs m'ont informé que notre ville est en ruine ! Dites moi ce qui s'est passé et pourquoi je ne devrais pas consommer - pourquoi je ne devrais pas vous faire tuer."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sheol, d'abord votre rapport," intervint Flauros. Il était toujours affalé sur son trône, mais son regard toisait narquoisement le plus jeune.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oui Maître, Maîtresse. Nous... Sur ordre de Perdion, nous avons séparé notre formation en trois en arrivant en ville. J'ai pris la tête des chasseurs. Nous avons parcouru les collines et les forêts, trouvant l'ennemi bien avant qu'il n'approche de Pavu'nar. Mon, hum, j'ai séparé mes troupes en petits groupes pour qu'ils harassent l'ennemi tandis qu'il marchait, et répartit les écaireurs avec les renseignemetns sur leur nombre et les renvoya à Losha et Perdion. J'ai continué de harasser l'ennemi tout au long du mois, tandis qu'ils organisaient le siège de la ville. Puis les portes de la ville se sont ouvertes ! Je n'avais pas assez de forces pour vaincre l'ennemi, Maîtres... Je dois vous informer que ce sont Perdion et Losha qui vous ont déçus."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Vous avez tous échoué imbécile," gronda Alexis. Elle tapait du pied en retournatn sur son trône et s'assit, fusillant Sheol du regard.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Perdion, continuez le récit," dit Flauros.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tout s'est déroulé comme l'a dit Sheol, Maîtres, même si je dois rejetter entièrement la faute sur Losha. J'ai pris les troupes de choc et lui ai laissé les archers et les colons pour organiser les défenses de la ville. Elle aurait dû être capable de tenir le siège toute la saison, même si les ennemis étaient plus nombreux de prévu. Je suis retourné près d'Acaia pour rassembler plus de forces, et étais sur le chemin du retour quand j'ai appris la nouvelle que le camp avait été rasé. J'ai laissé mes hommes en garnison là-bas et suis revenu quand j'ai été convoqué. Donc clairement Losha nous a fait perdre la bataille," finit le général, reculant et courbant la tête.[PARAGRAPH:1]Flauros sourit."Losha, tout semble être comme je le dis souvent à ma s&#156;ur : le sexe faible manque de jugement autant que de force. Mais s'il vous plait, racontez-moi votre histoire, et nous verrons."[PARAGRAPH:1]Losha commença calmement. "Tout s'est déroulé comme ils l'ont dit, mes prince et princesse, même s'ils sous-estiment le nombre de vos ennemis. Ils étaient plusieurs fois plus nombreux que nous. En combat nous aurions pu les vaincre, mais les morts de nos troupes auraient une grande perte. J'ai donc décidé que la perte des colons était préférable à la bataille."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Comment osez-vous ! Vous aviez ordre de garder le campement !"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ma Maîtresse, j'ai les ordres sur moi. Ils disent, 'Stoppez l'invasion quand ils atteignent la ville de Pavu'nar.' C'est ce que j'ai fait."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Losha, vous venez de dire que vous avez perdu les colons."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, j'ai oublié de le mentionner ? Avant d'abandonner la ville (et ses habitants barbants) à l'ennemi, j'ai empoisonné les réserves de vivre, de même que le vin et l'eau."[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis scilla; Flauros bondit sur son siège. "Sheol, Perdion, vous pouvez partir, vos ordres suivront sous peu. Losha, reste." Le jeune homme rampa dehors, et le plus vieux suivit, mais pas avant d'avoir souri cruellement à Losha.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ainsi j'ai fâché mes Maîtres ?" demanda Losha.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Chère Losha," dit Alexis avec un sourire, "tu t'es complètement rachetée. Viens, nous avons un présent pour toi."</French>
		<German>Drei Generäle saßen im Vorzimmer, während sie ihre Vorladung zum Thronsaal erwarteten. Der erste, ein kampferprobter Veteran, saß kühl und stoisch da, der zweite hingegen, jünger und neuer in seiner Position, fuchtelte nervös herum. Die Frau gähnte und starrte aus dem Fenster. Kurz darauf öffneten sich die Türen, sie wurden hinein geleitet und stellten sich vor den zwei Thronen hin. Die Wachen gingen fort und ließen die drei mit Alexis und Flauros allein.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis erhob sich zugleich und schritt schnell auf sie zu. "Ihr drei solltet unsere neue Siedlung Pavu'nar halten! Gerade bevor ihr wie begossene Pudel zu mir zurück gekehrt seid, wurde ich von meinen Kundschaftern darüber informiert, dass unsere Stadt vernichtet wurde! Berichtet mir, was passiert ist, und warum ich euch nicht sofort verzehren... warum ich euch nicht sofort töten sollte."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sheol, dein Bericht zuerst," unterbrach sie Flauros. Er flätzte sich immer noch auf seinen Thron, aber sein Blick wanderte zu dem jüngeren Mann.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ja, Meister und Meisterin. Wir... auf Perdions Befehl hin teilten wir das Kommando unter uns dreien auf, als wir die Stadt erreichten. Ich sollte mich um die Jäger kümmern. Wir stoßen zu den Hügeln und den Wäldern vor, und wir fanden den Feind ein gutes Stück vor Pavu'nar. Mein... äh, ich teilte meine Einheiten in kleine Gruppen auf, um den Feind über unsere wahre Stärke im unklaren zu lassen. Dann schickte ich die Kundschafter mit Informationen über ihre Stärke zu Losha und Perdion. Während des Monats der Belagerung setzte ich mein Vorhaben fort, den Feind anzugreifen. Dann öffneten sich die Stadttore! Ich hatte nicht genug Kraft, um den Feind zu schlagen, Meister... Ich muss euch berichten, dass es Losha und Perdion waren, die euch enttäuschten."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ihr habt alle versagt, ihr Narren," knurrte Alexis. Sie stapfte zurück zu ihrem Thron und setzte sich, während sie Sheol mit ihrem Blick aussaugte. [PARAGRAPH:1] "Perdion, fahre mit der Geschichte fort," sagte Flauros.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Es war so, wie Sheol es berichtete, Meister, obwohl ich die Schuld allein Losha anlasten muss. Ich nahm die Stoßtruppen, während ich ihr die Bogenschützen und die Siedler überlies, um die Stadtverteidigung aufzubauen. Sie hätte leicht die ganze Jahreszeit aushalten können, obwohl der Feind zahlenmäßig stärker war, als wir vermuteten. Ich kehrte ins benachbarte Acaia zurück, um mehr Streitkräfte zu sammeln, und auf meinem Rückweg erfuhr ich, dass die Siedlung ausgelöscht wurde. Ich ließ meine Männer dort Stellung nehmen und kehrte hierher zurück, als ich vorgeladen wurde. So ist klar, dass Losha uns den Sieg kostete", schloss der General, schritt zurück und verbeugte sich.[PARAGRAPH:1]Flauros lächelte. "Losha, es scheint so zu sein, wie ich schon meiner Schwester oft sagte: dem schwächeren Geschlecht fehlt Urteilsvermögen ebenso wie Stärke. Aber bitte, erzähle deine Geschichte, wir werden sehen."[PARAGRAPH:1]Losha fing ruhig an. "Es ist so, wie sie sagen, mein Prinz und meine Prinzessin, obwohl sie die Anzahl unserer Widersacher unterschätzten. Sie hatten ein Vielfaches unserer Truppenstärke. In einem Kampf hätten wir sie vielleicht überwältigen können, aber der Tod unserer Truppen wäre ein großer Verlust gewesen. Deshalb entschied ich, dass der Verlust unserer Siedler das kleinere Übel als der Kampf wäre." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Wie kannst du es wagen! Du hattest den Befehl, die Siedlung zu halten!" [PARAGRAPH:1] "Meisterin, ich habe diese Befehle hier bei mir. Dort steht 'haltet das angreifende Heer auf, wenn sie die Stadt Pavu'nar erreichen.' Das habe ich getan."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Losha, du hast eben gesagt, dass du die Siedler verloren hast."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, vergas ich zu erwähnen, dass ich, bevor ich die Stadt - und ihre nervigen Bewohner - zurückließ, die Nahrungslager, den Wein und das Wasser vergiftet habe?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis blinzelte; Flauros saß kerzengerade in seinem Thron. "Sheol, Perdion, ihr könnt gehen, eure Befehle werden euch mitgeteilt. Losha, bleib hier." Der junge Mann stürzte davon, der ältere folgte ihm, aber nicht ohne Losha zuvor noch grausam anzulächeln. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Habe ich meine Gebieter verärgert?" fragte Losha.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Liebe Losha," sagte Alexis mit einem lächeln, "du hast dich vollständig rehabilitiert. Komm, wir haben ein Geschenk für dich."</German>
		<Italian>Tre generali erano seduti nell'anticamera in attesa di essere convocati nella sala del trono. Uno, un veterano temprato dalla battaglia, sedeva freddo e stoico mentre il secondo uomo, più giovane e da poco promosso, era particolarmente nervoso. Il terzo generale, una donna, sbadigliò e guardo fuori dalla finestra. Poco dopo le porte si aprirono e vennerò fatti entrare per poi disporsi da soli davanti ai due troni. Le guardie lasciarono la stanza lasciando i tre generali da soli con Alexis e Flauros.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis si alzò subito camminando rapidamente verso di loro. "Vi era stato ordinato di difendere il nostro nuovo insediamento di Pavu'nar! Eppure ancor prima che voi tornaste da me, come cani bastonati, i miei ricognitori mi hanno informato che l'insediamento è in rovina! Ditemi cosa è successo e perché non dovrei consumare... perché non dovrei farvi uccidere." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Sheol, fai rapporto tu per primo," Flauros intervenne. Era ancora accasciato sul suo trono ma il suo sguardo era fisso sul giovane generale. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Si Signore, Signora. Noi... su ordini di Perdion ci dividemmo in tre tronconi dopo aver raggiunto la città. Io presi il comando dei cacciatori. Ci diriggemmo verso le colline e le foreste, trovammo i nemici molto prima che potessero avvicinarsi a Pavu'nar. Il mio, um, io ho diviso le mie unità in piccoli gruppi per tormentare il nemico mentre marciavano e inviai dei ricognitori a Losha e Perdion con le informazioni riguardanti la composizione e il numero dei nemici. Continuai ad infliggere perdite ai nemici per tutto il mese d'assedio della città. Poi le porte della città furono aperte! Non avevo abbastanza uomini per sconfiggere il nemico, miei Signori... Devo riferire che sono stati Losha e Perdion a fallire."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Avete fallito tutti, stupido!" Alexis ringhiò. Poi tornò al suo trono e vi si sedette, fulminando Sheol con lo sguardo. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Perdion, prego continua la storia," Flauros disse.[PARAGRAPH:1]"È come ha detto Sheol, Signore, anche se devo dare completamente la colpa a Losha. Io presi sotto il mio comando le truppe d'assalto, lasciando a lei gli arcieri e i coloni per organizzare la difesa della città. Sarebbe dovuta riuscire a resistere per intere stagioni, nonostante il numero di nemici si dimostrò più alto di quanto previsto. Io tornai alla vicina Acaia per radunare più truppe, ed ero sulla via del ritorno quando ricevetti notizie che l'isediamento era stato raso al suolo. Lasciai i miei uomini a guarnigione e tornai quando venni convocato. Pertanto è stata Losha a perdere la battaglia," il generale finì, indietreggiò e chinò la testa.[PARAGRAPH:1]Flauros sorrise. "Losha, sembra che, come ho detto spesso a mia sorella: il sesso debole manca di giudizio oltre che di forza. Ma per favore, dicci la tua storia, poi decideremo."[PARAGRAPH:1]Losha iniziò tranquillamente. "È come dicono loro, mio Principe e Principessa, anche se loro sottovalutavano il numero dei vostri nemici. Erano parecchie volte il numero che pensavamo. In una battaglia avremmo potuto batterli, ma le nostre perdite sarebbero state ingenti. Cosi ho deciso che la perdita dei coloni era preferibile alla battaglia." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Come osi! Ti era stato ordinato di difendere l'insediamento!" [PARAGRAPH:1]"Mia Signora, ho gli ordini qui con me. Dicono, 'Fermate l'esercito nemico quando raggiunge la nostra città di Pavu'nar.' E questo è ciò che ho fatto." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Losha, hai appena detto che hai perso i coloni." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh mi sono dimenticata di dirlo? Prima di lasciare la città, e i suoi fastidiosi abitanti, al nemico ho avvelenato le scorte di cibo, e il vino, e l'acqua." [PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis sbattè gli occhi; Flauros si sedette correttamente sul suo trono. "Sheol, Perdion, potete andare, a breve avrete nuovi ordini. Losha, rimani." Il giovane uscì rapidamente e quello anziano lo seguì, ma non prima di sorridere crudelmente a Losha. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Quindi ho fatto infuriare i miei Signori?" Losha chiese.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Cara Losha," Alexis disse con un sorriso, "ti sei completamente riscattata. Vieni, abbiamo un dono per te."</Italian>
		<Spanish>Three generals sat in the antechamber, awaiting their summons to the throne room. One, a battle hardened veteran, sat cold and stoic while the second man, younger and newer to his position, fidgeted nervously. The woman yawned and gazed out the window. Soon the doors opened and they were ushered in and arrayed themselves before the dual thrones. The guards left, leaving the three alone with Alexis and Flauros.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis arose at once, walking swiftly towards them. "You three were ordered to hold our new settlement of Pavu'nar! Yet before you even returned to me, like beaten dogs, my scouts have informed me that our city is ruined! Tell me what happened and why I shouldn't consume- -why I shouldn't have you killed." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Sheol, your report first," Flauros interjected. He still slouched on his throne but his gaze narrowed upon the younger man. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes Master, Mistress. We...on Perdion's orders we split our command into three upon reaching the town. I took charge of the hunters. We headed for the hills and forests, finding the enemy well before they neared Pavu'nar. My, um, I broke my units into small groups to harass the enemy as they marched, and dispatched the scouts with information on their numbers and makeup back to Losha and Perdion. I continued to pick off the enemy through the month as they laid siege to the town. Then, the gates of the town opened! I had not force enough to beat the enemy, Masters...I must report that it was Losha and Perdion that failed you."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You all failed, fool," Alexis snarled. She stomped back to her throne and sat, withering Sheol with her glare. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Perdion, pray continue the tale," Flauros said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"It is as Sheol said, Masters, though I must place the blame squarely on Losha's shoulders. I took the shock troops and left her the archers and the settlers to arrange defense of the town. She should easily have been able to hold out all season, though the number of the enemy turned out to be larger than we expected. I returned to nearby Acaia to gather more forces, and was on my way back when I received the news the settlement had been razed. I left my men garrisoned there and returned when summoned. So clearly Losha cost us the battle," the general finished, stepping back and bowing his head.[PARAGRAPH:1]Flauros smiled. "Losha, it appears as I have often told my sister: the weaker sex lacks judgment as well as strength. But please, tell your story, and we shall see."[PARAGRAPH:1]Losha calmly began. "It is as they say, my prince and princess, though they underestimate the numbers of your foes. They had many times the number we set out with. In a battle we might have taken them, but the deaths of our troops would have been a great loss. So I decided that the loss of the settlers was preferable to battle." [PARAGRAPH:1]"How dare you! You were ordered to hold the settlement!" [PARAGRAPH:1]"My Mistress, I have the orders here with me. It says, stop the invading army when they reach our town of Pavu'nar.' That is what I did." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Losha, you just said that you lost the settlers." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh did I forget to mention? Before I abandoned the town-and its annoying inhabitants-to the enemy, I poisoned the food stores, and the wine, and the water." [PARAGRAPH:1]Alexis blinked; Flauros sat upright in his throne. "Sheol, Perdion, you may leave, your orders will be forthcoming. Losha, stay." The young man skittered out, and the older man followed, but not before giving Losha a cruel smile. [PARAGRAPH:1]"So have I angered my Masters?" Losha asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Dear Losha," Alexis said with a smile, "you have redeemed yourself utterly. Come, we have a gift for you."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LOSHA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Losha is the Calabim hero and a powerful vampire in her own right. But even beyond this she gains the [LINK=PROMOTION_IMMORTAL]Immortal[\LINK] promotion each time she defeats a living unit in combat, meaning she is very difficult to kill if she is kept fed.</English>
		<French>Losha est l'héroïne Calabim et de plus une puissante vampire. Mais bien au-delà de ça, elle gagne la promotion Immortel à chaque fois qu'elle gagne un combat contre une unité vivante, ce qui signifie qu'elle est très difficile à tuer tant qu'elle reste nourrie.</French>
		<German>Losha ist die Heldin der Calabim und eine mächtige Vampirin die ihres gleichen sucht. Aber darüber hinaus bekommt sie, jedes mal wenn sie eine lebende Einheit im Kampf besiegt die Unsterblichkeits-Beförderung, das bedeutet dass sie sehr schwer zu töten ist wenn sie gesättigt ist.</German>
		<Italian>Losha è l'eroe Calabim e un potente vampiro di per se. Inoltre ottiene la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_IMMORTAL]Immortale[\LINK] ogni volta che uccide un'unità vivente in combattimento, rendendola difficile da uccidere se continua a nutrirsi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Losha is the Calabim hero and a powerful vampire in her own right. But even beyond this she gains the Immortal promotion each time she defeats a living unit in combat, meaning she is very difficult to kill if she is kept fed.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LOSHA_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>Losha is the Calabim hero and a powerful vampire in her own right. But even beyond this she gains the Immortal promotion each time she defeats a living unit in combat, meaning she is very difficult to kill if she is kept fed.</English>
		<French>Losha est l'héroïne Calabim et de plus une puissante vampire. Mais bien au-delà de ça, elle gagne la promotion Immortel à chaque fois qu'elle gagne un combat contre une unité vivante, ce qui signifie qu'elle est très difficile à tuer tant qu'elle reste nourrie.</French>
		<German>Losha ist die Heldin der Calabim und eine mächtige Vampirin die ihres gleichen sucht. Aber darüber hinaus bekommt sie, jedes mal wenn sie eine lebende Einheit im Kampf besiegt die Unsterblichkeits-Beförderung, das bedeutet dass sie sehr schwer zu töten ist wenn sie gesättigt ist.</German>
		<Italian>Losha è l'eroe Calabim e un potente vampiro di per se. Inoltre ottiene la promozione Immortale ogni volta che uccide un'unità vivente in combattimento, rendendola difficile da uccidere se continua a nutrirsi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Losha is the Calabim hero and a powerful vampire in her own right. But even beyond this she gains the Immortal promotion each time she defeats a living unit in combat, meaning she is very difficult to kill if she is kept fed.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOROI</Tag>
		<English>Moroi</English>
		<French>Moroï</French>
		<German>Moroi</German>
		<Italian>Moroi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Moroi</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOROI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Fed on the blood of vampires, the Moroi are capable of achieving great bursts of strength. They can also be gifted with the vampirism promotion at level 4 instead of waiting until level 6 and can be upgraded to full vampires if the requirements are met.</English>
		<French>Nourris du sang des vampires, les Moroïs sont capables d'avoir de grands accès de force. Ils peuvent également recevoir la promotion vampirisme au niveau 4 au lieu du niveau 6 et peuvent devenir de vrais vampires si les prérequis sont satisfaits.</French>
		<German>Da sie mit dem Blut der Vampire genährt wurden, sind die Moroi imstande, große Kräfte in sich zu wecken. Außerdem können sie früher die Vampirismus-Beförderung durch den "Vampirbiss" erhalten, sie müssen lediglich bis Level 4 warten. Sie können, wenn die sonstigen Anforderungen erfüllt sind, zu Vampiren aufgerüstet werden.</German>
		<Italian>Nutriti con sangue di vampiro, i Moroi sono capaci di grandi scoppi di forza. Possono inoltre ricevere la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_VAMPIRE]vampiro[\LINK] dal 4° livello invece che dal 6° e possono essere trasformati in veri vampiri se soddisfano i requisiti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Fed on the blood of vampires, the Moroi are capable of achieving great bursts of strength. They can also be gifted with the vampirism promotion at level 4 instead of waiting until level 6 and can be upgraded to full vampires if the requirements are met.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOROI_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Upgraded bloodpets have some hope of being chosen to become vampires themselves. They also have a self-only version of the dangerous spell burning blood, which gives added move and strength, but may drive them to the barbarians.</English>
		<French>Les familiers sanguins améliorés ont un espoir d'être eux-mêmes choisis pour devenir vampires. Ils peuvent lancer sur eux-mêmes une version particulière du dangereux sort [LINK=SPELL_BURNING_BLOOD]Sang Bouillonnant[\LINK], qui confère des déplacements supplémentaires et une force accrue, mais peut les conduire à devenir des barbares.</French>
		<German>Aufgerüstete Blutdiener leben in der Hoffnung darauf, dass sie auserwählt und zu Vampiren gemacht werden. Sie verfügen zudem automatisch über die Selbst-Version des gefährlichen Zaubers Brennendes Blut, der Sie extrem Stärkt und schneller macht, aber eine akute Gefahr für ihr Leben darstellt.</German>
		<Italian>I Moroi hanno qualche speranza di essere scelti per diventare loro stessi dei vampiri. Hanno inoltre l'abilità Sangue Bruciante, che gli fornisce movimento extra e un bonus alla forza e la possibilità di attaccare più volte a turno, ma con una probabilità sempre maggiore di diventare dei barbari.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Upgraded bloodpets have some hope of being chosen to become vampires themselves. They also have a self-only version of the dangerous spell burning blood, which gives added move and strength, but may drive them to the barbarians.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VAMPIRE</Tag>
		<English>Vampire</English>
		<French>Vampire</French>
		<German>Vampir</German>
		<Italian>Vampiro</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vampire</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VAMPIRE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Every Vampire on Erebus can trace their lineage to Alexis or Flauros, the first vampires born in ages past. Some of the first to receive the gift from them live on to the present, ruling clans and cities, and keeping their 'offspring' in check. Spoiled and accustomed to power, life under the rulership of a Vampire is a harsh existence, with the perpetual dread of being 'invited' to a feast. Humans ruled by Vampires in the Age of Rebirth responded one of two ways: with resigned depression, or fanatical devotion, joining the ranks of the Moroi in order to prove themselves worthy of the gift. Though relatively few have their wishes so granted, those who do frequently turn their backs on their human lives, becoming as cruel and decadent as the masters they serve. Vampires delight in darker magics and relish in combat, though only when the odds are wildly in their favor do most Vampires consider joining the melee.</English>
		<French>Chaque vampire d'Erebus peut faire remonter sa lignée jusqu'à Alexis ou Flauros, les vampires origininels, nés lors d'un âge révolu. Quelques uns des premiers à avoir reçu d'eux le don vivent encore aujourd'hui, dirigeant des clans et des villes, et gardant le contrôle de leur 'descendance'. Décadents et accrochés au pouvoir, la vie sous le joug d'un vampire est rude, avec toujours la menace latente d'être 'invité' à un de leurs festins. Les humains dirigés par les vampires à l'Âge de la Renaissance se divisent en deux catégories de réaction : une dépression résignée, ou une dévotion fanatique, rejoignant les rangs des Moroïs dans l'espoir de se montrer dignes de recevoir le don. Bien que peu d'entre eux aient vu leur v&#156;u se réaliser, ils tournent souvent le dos à leur vie humaine, deveant aussi cruels et décadents que leurs maîtres. Les vampires se délectent des magies les plus sombres et se régalent des combats, même s'ils ne se joignent à la mêlée que lorsque les chances sont clairement en leur faveur.</French>
		<German>Jeder Vampir auf Erebus kann seine Abstammungslinie auf Alexis oder Flauros, die vor langen Zeiten geborenen, ersten Vampire, zurückführen. Einige der ersten, die das Geschenk von ihnen erhielten, leben noch immer und führen Klans und Städte und halten ihren "Nachwuchs" im Zaum. Verdorben und gewohnt zu befehlen, ist das Leben unter der Herrschaft von Vampiren ein hartes, und eines in ständiger Angst vor einer Einladung zu einem "Fest". Von Vampiren beherrschte Menschen haben sich im Zeitalter der Wiedergeburt auf zwei Arten darauf eingestellt: entweder mit resignativer Depression oder sie schließen sich mit fanatischer Hingabe dem Rang der Moroi an, um sich des Geschenks als würdig zu erweisen. Obwohl nur wenigen dieser Wunsch erfüllt wird, wenden die Beschenkten ihrer menschlichen Vergangenheit normalerweise den Rücken zu und werden genauso grausam und verschwenderisch wie die Herren, denen sie dienen. Sie sind von dunkler Magie entzückt und von zünftigen Kämpfen, obwohl sie sich nur ins Kampfgetümmel stürzen, wenn die Lage schon sehr zu ihren Gunsten steht.</German>
		<Italian>Ogni vampiro su Erebus discende da Alexis o Flauros, i primi vampiri nati in tempi remoti. Alcuni dei primi a ricevere il dono in quei tempi sono ancora vivi, goverando clan e città, e tenendo sotto controllo la loro 'prole'. Viziati e abituati a comandare, la vita sotto un vampiro è dura, con il timore perenne dell'essere 'invitato' a un banchetto. Gli umani governati dai vampiri durante l'Era della Rinascita si comportano in due modi: con una rassegnata depressione o con una devozione fanatica, unendosi ai ranghi dei Moroi in modo di dimostrarsi degni del dono. Anche se sono pochi coloro che vedono il loro desiderio esaudito, quelli che lo ricevono frequentemente voltano le spalle alle loro vite umane, diventando crudeli e decadenti come i signori che servono. I Vampiri si dilettano nelle magie più oscure e traggono piacere dal combattimento, ma solo quando le situazioni sono nettamente a loro vantaggio i vampiri si buttano nella mischia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Every Vampire on Erebus can trace their lineage to Alexis or Flauros, the first vampires born in ages past. Some of the first to receive the gift from them live on to the present, ruling clans and cities, and keeping their 'offspring' in check. Spoiled and accustomed to power, life under the rulership of a Vampire is a harsh existence, with the perpetual dread of being 'invited' to a feast. Humans ruled by Vampires in the Age of Rebirth responded one of two ways: with resigned depression, or fanatical devotion, joining the ranks of the Moroi in order to prove themselves worthy of the gift. Though relatively few have their wishes so granted, those who do frequently turn their backs on their human lives, becoming as cruel and decadent as the masters they serve. Vampires delight in darker magics and in relish combat, though only when the odds are wildly in their favor do most Vampires consider joining the melee.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VAMPIRE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Capable fighters with a handful of useful spells, vampires true strength lies in their ability to grow in power from feasting on city population-and to pass this power on to worthy allies. (Units level six or higher)</English>
		<French>La vraie force des vampires, combattants compétents possédant un panel de sorts utiles, réside dans leur capacité à gagner en puissance en [LINK=SPELL_FEAST]festoyant[\LINK] aux dépens de la population d'une ville, et de transmettre ce [LINK=SPELL_GIFT_VAMPIRISM]pouvoir[\LINK] à leurs alliés qui s'en montrent dignes (niveau 6 ou plus).</French>
		<German>Fähige Kämpfer mit einer Handvoll nützlicher Zaubersprüche. Die wahre Stärke der Vampire liegt in ihrer Fähigkeit, sich der Stadtbevölkerung zu bedienen, um an Kraft zu gewinnen und diese Kraft an würdige Mitstreiter weiterzugeben.</German>
		<Italian>Dei combattenti capaci con a disposizione qualche utile magia, la vera forza dei vampiri consiste nel poter aumentare di potere mangiando la popolazione di una città, e di passare questa capacità a degli alleati degni. (Unità di 6° livello o superiore)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Capable fighters with a handful of useful spells, vampires true strength lies in their ability to grow in power from feasting on city population-and to pass this power on to worthy allies. (Units level six or higher)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VAMPIRE_LORD</Tag>
		<English>Vampire Lord</English>
		<French>Seigneur Vampire</French>
		<German>Vampirfürst</German>
		<Italian>Signore dei Vampiri</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vampire Lord</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VAMPIRE_LORD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A monster of innumerable years, a Vampire Lord has consumed so many souls, gorged himself so on the sparks of other beings, that he merely releases one into the Vaults in his place and his flesh continues on..</English>
		<French>Monstre vivant depuis une époque reculée, le Seigneur Vampire a absorbé tant d'âmes, s'est tellement gorgé des étincelles de vie des autres, que face à la mort, il lui suffit de se séparer de l'une d'entre elles afin de prolonger son existence.</French>
		<German>A monster of innumerable years, a Vampire Lord has consumed so many souls, gorged himself so on the sparks of other beings, that he merely releases one into the Vaults in his place and his flesh continues on..</German>
		<Italian>Un'essere che ha vissuto per innumerevoli anni, un Signore dei Vampiri ha consumato cosi tante anime e assorbito cosi tante scintille vitali altrui, che nel caso morisse si limiterebbe a rilasciarne una al suo posto mentre lui continua a vivere..</Italian>
		<Spanish>A monster of innumerable years, a Vampire Lord has consumed so many souls, gorged himself so on the sparks of other beings, that he merely releases one into the Vaults in his place and his flesh continues on..</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VAMPIRE_LORD_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>All vampires have unnaturally long life-spans, but the vampire lords have learned to cheat death itself. Whether through massive feasting or some more arcane ritual, the body of a vampire lord is recreated upon destruction. Some spend their stolen years further honing their martial prowess, but many, having experienced everything else in life, study forbidden knowledge, learning to cast advanced body spells without mana. A few take the final step towards immortality, and become a Lich.</English>
		<French>Tous les vampires sont dotés d'une espérance de vie anormalement longue, mais les Seigneurs Vmpires ont appris à tromper la mort elle-même. Que ce soit au travers de [LINK=SPELL_FEAST]festins[\LINK] massifs ou un rituel arcanique, le corps d'un seigneur vampire est recréé en cas de destruction. Certains consacrent ces années volées à améliorer leurs compétences martiales, mais la plupart, ayant déjà étudié tout le reste durant leur vie, se lancent dans l'étude de savoirs interdits, apprenant à lancer des sorts de la magie de corps avancés sans mana. Quelques uns franchissent le dernier pas vers l'immortalité et deviennent des Liches.</French>
		<German>Alle Vampire haben übernatürlich lange Lebenserwartungen, Vampirlords haben sogar gelernt, den Tod selbst auszutricksen. Ob wegen enormer Gelage, oder aufgrund magischer Rituale - der Körper eines Vampirlords wird bei seiner Zerstörung direkt wiederhergestellt. Einige verbringen Ihre gestohlenen Jahre damit Ihre kämpferischen Fähigkeiten zu perfektionieren. Da sie über die Jahre fast alles erlebt haben, studieren viele jedoch verbotenes Wissens und erlernen die Anwendung fortgeschrittener Zaubersprüche der Körpermagie ohne dabei Mana zu verbrauchen. Wenigen gelingt sogar der endgültige Schritt zur Unsterblichkeit und sie werden zu einem Lich.</German>
		<Italian>Tutti i vampiri hanno delle vite innaturalmente lunghe, ma i SIgnori dei Vampiri hanno imparato ad ingannare la morte stessa. Che sia per via dell'essersi nutriti in modo massiccio o di qualche rituale più arcano, il corpo di un Signore dei Vampiri viene ricreato in seguito alla sua distruzione. Alcuni spendono i loro anni migliorando ancor di più le loro abilità marziali, ma molti, avendo già provato tutto nelle loro vite, si interessano a delle conoscenze proibite, imparando a lanciare magie avanzate della magia del corpo senza necessitare del mana. Alcuni compiono anche il passo finale verso l'immortalità diventando dei Lich.</Italian>
		<Spanish>All vampires have unnaturally long life-spans, but the vampire lords have learned to cheat death itself. Whether through massive feasting or some more arcane ritual, the body of a vampire lord is recreated upon destruction. Some spend their stolen years further honing their martial prowess, but many, having experienced everything else in life, study forbidden knowledge, learning to cast advanced body spells without mana. A few take the final step towards immortality, and become a Lich.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MESSAGE_RIVER_OF_BLOOD</Tag>
		<English>A player has cast River of Blood: Your cities' population is reduced by %d1</English>
		<French>A player has cast River of Blood: Your cities' population is reduced by %d1</French>
		<German>Ein Spieler hat den Fluss aus Blut gezaubert: Die Bevölkerung in euren Städten wurde um %d1 reduziert</German>
		<Italian>Un giocatore ha lanciato la magia Fiume di Sangue: la popolazione delle tue città è stata ridotta di %d1</Italian>
		<Spanish>A player has cast River of Blood: Your cities' population is reduced by %d1</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MESSAGE_RIVER_OF_BLOOD_CALABIM</Tag>
		<English>Your raids on enemy cities brought back enough peasants to increase your city population by 2</English>
		<French>Vos raids sur les villes étrangères ont ramené suffisamment de bétail humain pour augmenter la population de votre ville de 2</French>
		<German>Your raids on enemy cities brought back enough peasants to increase your city population by 2</German>
		<Italian>Le tue incursioni nelle città avversarie hanno fruttato abbastanza popolani da incrementare la popolazione delle tue città di 2</Italian>
		<Spanish>Your raids on enemy cities brought back enough peasants to increase your city population by 2</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
