<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BARBARIAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Barbarians are generally orcs and their kin, the goblins and the ogres. These creatures were all once civilized and friends of the elves, but were twisted in body and spirit when their goddess Bhall fell from grace and crashed through Erebus. The lizardmen are frequent allies of the orcs, but their existence predates the warping of the orcs at the close of the Age of Magic. Barbarians rarely use tactics and focus on waves of foes assaulting civilized nations, though occasionally heroes will arise from their ranks. Heroes such as the Warlord King Orthus, the Ancient Acheron, or the mysterious Sailors' Dirge, which prowls the waves.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Les Barbares sont généralement des Orques et apparentés, les gobelins et les ogres. Ces créatures furent toutes civilisés et amis des Elfes, mais furent tourmentés en leurs corps et leurs esprits lorsque leur déesse Bhall tomba en disgrâce et s'écrasa à travers Erebus. Les Hommes Lézards sont de fréquents alliés des Orques, mais leur existence prédit le gauchissement des Orques à la fin de l'Age de la Magie. Les Barbares usent rarement de tactiques et se concentrent sur des vagues d'ennemis assaillant les nations civilisés, bien qu'occasionnellement des héros se dresse de leurs rangs. Héros tels que le Seigneur de Guerre Orthus, l'ancien dragon Acheron, ou le mystérieux Requiem des Marins qui rôde sur les mers.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Barbaren setzen sich im Allgemeinen aus Orks und deren Blutsverwandten, den Goblins und Trollen, zusammen. Diese Geschöpfe waren einst zivilisiert und mit den Elfen befreundet, aber sie wurden sowohl körperlich als auch geistig verändert, als ihre Göttin Bhall erst in Ungnade und dann auf Erebus fiel. Die Echsen sind häufig mit den Orks verbündetet, sie existierten aber schon vor der Veränderung der Orks am Ende des Zeitalters der Magie. Barbaren gehen selten taktisch vor und überfallen die zivilisierten Nationen in Angriffswellen, auch wenn gelegentlich Helden aus ihren Reihen hervorgehen. Solche Helden sind der Kriegsfürst Orthus, der uralte Drache Acheron oder das mysteriöse Schiff der Toten, das die Wellen durchschneidet.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Barbarians are generally orcs and their kin, the goblins and the ogres. These creatures were all once civilized and friends of the elves, but were twisted in body and spirit when their goddess Bhall fell from grace and crashed through Erebus. The lizardmen are frequent allies of the orcs, but their existence predates the warping of the orcs at the close of the Age of Magic. Barbarians rarely use tactics and focus on waves of foes assaulting civilized nations, though occasionally heroes will arise from their ranks. Heroes such as the Warlord King Orthus, the Ancient Acheron, or the mysterious Sailors' Dirge, which prowls the waves.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Los Bárbaros son generalmente Orcos y sus parientes, los trasgos y los ogros. Estas criaturas fueron una vez civilizadas y amigas de los elfos, pero fueron retorcidas en cuerpo y espíritu cuando su diosa Bhall calló del cielo y se estrelló a través de Erebus. Los Hombres Lagarto son con frecuencia aliados de los orcos, pero su existencia precede a la deformación de los Orcos al final de la Edad de la Magia. Los Bárbaros raramente usan tácticas y se concentran en oleadas de enemigos asaltando a las naciones civilizadas, aunque ocasionalmente aparecen héroes entre sus filas. Héroes como el Rey señor de la guerra Orthus, el Anciano Acheron, o la misteriosa Requiem de los Marineros, que surca los mares.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
