<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - Units -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SIDAR_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Sidar</English>
		<French>sidar:sidar:sidarae:sidarae</French>
		<German>Sidarisch</German>
		<Italian>Sidar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sidar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SIDAR_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sidar</English>
		<French>Sidaria</French>
		<German>Reich der Sidar</German>
		<Italian>Sidar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sidar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SIDAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Shades, men who have traded portions of their soul for immortality, the Grey are detached from the events of the world. Only intervening to protect themselves or striking out to destroy undead (they see undead as aberrations despite their own use of magic to extend their life), they are happy to keep to their hidden cities out of the eyes, and the wars, of the younger races.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Des ombres, des hommes qui ont vendu une part de leur âme pour l'immortalité, les Gris sont détachés des évènements du monde. N'intervenant que pour se protéger ou pour détruire les morts-vivants (qu'ils voient comme des aberrations malgré leur propre usage de la magie pour accroître leur durée de vie), ils sont heureux de rester dans leurs villes cachées, loin des regards et des guerres des races plus jeunes. </French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Grey sind Schatten, leben losgelöst von den Ereignissen in der Welt als Menschen, die Teile ihrer Seele für die Unsterblichkeit verkauft haben. Sie mischen sich nur ein, um sich selbst zu beschützen oder um Untote zu vernichten (für sie sind Untote ein Irrweg, obwohl sie selbst Magie benutzen, um ihr Leben zu verlängern). Sie sind zufrieden damit, ihre verborgenen Städte vor den Augen und den Kriegen der jüngeren Zivilisationen versteckt zu halten.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Shades, men who have traded portions of their soul for immortality, the Grey are detached from the events of the world. Only intervening to protect themselves or striking out to destroy undead (they see undead as aberrations despite their own use of magic to extend their life), they are happy to keep to their hidden cities out of the eyes, and the wars, of the younger races.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Sombras, hombres que han comerciado partes de su alma por la inmortalidad, los Grises están apartados de los sucesos del mundo. Sólo interviniendo para protegerse o para atacar y destruir a los no-muertos (ven a los no-muertos como aberraciones a pesar de usar ellos mismos la magia para alargar sus vidas), están contentos manteniendo sus ciudades ocultas fuera de los ojos y de las guerras de las razas jóvenes.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SIDAR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Strategy:

[ICON_BULLET]Any living Sidar unit that reaches level 6 can become a [LINK=UNIT_SHADE]Shade[\LINK], which lets them retire in a city as any Great Person specialist (except Great Prophet and Healer). Sidar strategy thus typically aims around to produce plenty of units, keep them alive, and gain levels on them in any way possible.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar units that continue being used past level 6 may instead take the [LINK=PROMOTION_GREATER_SHADE]Greater Shade[\LINK] promotion, which gives them a chance to avoid death. The chance is 5% times the unit's level, capped at 95%.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar Scouts are replaced with [LINK=UNIT_TRACKLESS]Trackless[\LINK], which cannot be spotted by most units and can ignore borders. These make it straightforward to map the whole world, monitor other civs, and to explore distant lairs.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar Hunters are replaced with [LINK=UNIT_DIVIDED_SOUL]Divided Souls[\LINK]. These require both Hunting and Mysticism to produce. They have the ability to teleport around explored parts of the map using their summons, and are very useful for safely attacking vulnerable targets outside of their stack. Be aware that they cannot carry hawks, and that their souls cannot move to tiles which would potentially reveal an unexplored tile.
[ICON_BULLET]The Sidar hero, [LINK=UNIT_RATHUS]Rathus Denmora[\LINK], in addition to being relatively strong, has a powerful item in the [LINK=PROMOTION_NETHER_BLADE]Netherblade[\LINK]. This blade is fatal to any living unit, win or lose.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar territory gradually fills with Mist, which blocks entry to units with less than 3 perception, which is most of them.

Author - 'Doesnt'</English>
		<French>Strategy:

[ICON_BULLET]Any living Sidar unit that reaches level 6 can become a [LINK=UNIT_SHADE]Shade[\LINK], which lets them retire in a city as any Great Person specialist (except Great Prophet and Healer). Sidar strategy thus typically aims around to produce plenty of units, keep them alive, and gain levels on them in any way possible.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar units that continue being used past level 6 may instead take the [LINK=PROMOTION_GREATER_SHADE]Greater Shade[\LINK] promotion, which gives them a chance to avoid death. The chance is 5% times the unit's level, capped at 95%.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar Scouts are replaced with [LINK=UNIT_TRACKLESS]Trackless[\LINK], which cannot be spotted by most units and can ignore borders. These make it straightforward to map the whole world, monitor other civs, and to explore distant lairs.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar Hunters are replaced with [LINK=UNIT_DIVIDED_SOUL]Divided Souls[\LINK]. These require both Hunting and Mysticism to produce. They have the ability to teleport around explored parts of the map using their summons, and are very useful for safely attacking vulnerable targets outside of their stack. Be aware that they cannot carry hawks, and that their souls cannot move to tiles which would potentially reveal an unexplored tile.
[ICON_BULLET]The Sidar hero, [LINK=UNIT_RATHUS]Rathus Denmora[\LINK], in addition to being relatively strong, has a powerful item in the [LINK=PROMOTION_NETHER_BLADE]Netherblade[\LINK]. This blade is fatal to any living unit, win or lose.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar territory gradually fills with Mist, which blocks entry to units with less than 3 perception, which is most of them.

Author - 'Doesnt'</French>
		<German>Strategy:

[ICON_BULLET]Any living Sidar unit that reaches level 6 can become a [LINK=UNIT_SHADE]Shade[\LINK], which lets them retire in a city as any Great Person specialist (except Great Prophet and Healer). Sidar strategy thus typically aims around to produce plenty of units, keep them alive, and gain levels on them in any way possible.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar units that continue being used past level 6 may instead take the [LINK=PROMOTION_GREATER_SHADE]Greater Shade[\LINK] promotion, which gives them a chance to avoid death. The chance is 5% times the unit's level, capped at 95%.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar Scouts are replaced with [LINK=UNIT_TRACKLESS]Trackless[\LINK], which cannot be spotted by most units and can ignore borders. These make it straightforward to map the whole world, monitor other civs, and to explore distant lairs.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar Hunters are replaced with [LINK=UNIT_DIVIDED_SOUL]Divided Souls[\LINK]. These require both Hunting and Mysticism to produce. They have the ability to teleport around explored parts of the map using their summons, and are very useful for safely attacking vulnerable targets outside of their stack. Be aware that they cannot carry hawks, and that their souls cannot move to tiles which would potentially reveal an unexplored tile.
[ICON_BULLET]The Sidar hero, [LINK=UNIT_RATHUS]Rathus Denmora[\LINK], in addition to being relatively strong, has a powerful item in the [LINK=PROMOTION_NETHER_BLADE]Netherblade[\LINK]. This blade is fatal to any living unit, win or lose.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar territory gradually fills with Mist, which blocks entry to units with less than 3 perception, which is most of them.

Author - 'Doesnt'</German>
		<Italian>Strategy:

[ICON_BULLET]Any living Sidar unit that reaches level 6 can become a [LINK=UNIT_SHADE]Shade[\LINK], which lets them retire in a city as any Great Person specialist (except Great Prophet and Healer). Sidar strategy thus typically aims around to produce plenty of units, keep them alive, and gain levels on them in any way possible.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar units that continue being used past level 6 may instead take the [LINK=PROMOTION_GREATER_SHADE]Greater Shade[\LINK] promotion, which gives them a chance to avoid death. The chance is 5% times the unit's level, capped at 95%.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar Scouts are replaced with [LINK=UNIT_TRACKLESS]Trackless[\LINK], which cannot be spotted by most units and can ignore borders. These make it straightforward to map the whole world, monitor other civs, and to explore distant lairs.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar Hunters are replaced with [LINK=UNIT_DIVIDED_SOUL]Divided Souls[\LINK]. These require both Hunting and Mysticism to produce. They have the ability to teleport around explored parts of the map using their summons, and are very useful for safely attacking vulnerable targets outside of their stack. Be aware that they cannot carry hawks, and that their souls cannot move to tiles which would potentially reveal an unexplored tile.
[ICON_BULLET]The Sidar hero, [LINK=UNIT_RATHUS]Rathus Denmora[\LINK], in addition to being relatively strong, has a powerful item in the [LINK=PROMOTION_NETHER_BLADE]Netherblade[\LINK]. This blade is fatal to any living unit, win or lose.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar territory gradually fills with Mist, which blocks entry to units with less than 3 perception, which is most of them.

Author - 'Doesnt'</Italian>
		<Spanish>Strategy:

[ICON_BULLET]Any living Sidar unit that reaches level 6 can become a [LINK=UNIT_SHADE]Shade[\LINK], which lets them retire in a city as any Great Person specialist (except Great Prophet and Healer). Sidar strategy thus typically aims around to produce plenty of units, keep them alive, and gain levels on them in any way possible.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar units that continue being used past level 6 may instead take the [LINK=PROMOTION_GREATER_SHADE]Greater Shade[\LINK] promotion, which gives them a chance to avoid death. The chance is 5% times the unit's level, capped at 95%.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar Scouts are replaced with [LINK=UNIT_TRACKLESS]Trackless[\LINK], which cannot be spotted by most units and can ignore borders. These make it straightforward to map the whole world, monitor other civs, and to explore distant lairs.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar Hunters are replaced with [LINK=UNIT_DIVIDED_SOUL]Divided Souls[\LINK]. These require both Hunting and Mysticism to produce. They have the ability to teleport around explored parts of the map using their summons, and are very useful for safely attacking vulnerable targets outside of their stack. Be aware that they cannot carry hawks, and that their souls cannot move to tiles which would potentially reveal an unexplored tile.
[ICON_BULLET]The Sidar hero, [LINK=UNIT_RATHUS]Rathus Denmora[\LINK], in addition to being relatively strong, has a powerful item in the [LINK=PROMOTION_NETHER_BLADE]Netherblade[\LINK]. This blade is fatal to any living unit, win or lose.
[ICON_BULLET]Sidar territory gradually fills with Mist, which blocks entry to units with less than 3 perception, which is most of them.

Author - 'Doesnt'</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SIDAR_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Sidar</English>
		<French>Sidarae</French>
		<German>Sidar</German>
		<Italian>Sidar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sidar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HIDDEN_CITY</Tag>
		<English>Hidden City</English>
		<French>Ville cachée</French>
		<German>Verborgene Stadt</German>
		<Italian>Hidden City</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hidden City</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOUSE_OF_THE_GREY</Tag>
		<English>House of the Grey</English>
		<French>Demeure du Gris</French>
		<German>Haus der Düsternis</German>
		<Italian>House of the Grey</Italian>
		<Spanish>House of the Grey</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOUSE_OF_THE_GREY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Any Sidar settlement of a notable size will contain a "House of the Grey", a building dedicated to studying the rituals and risks involved with the Sidar's manipulation of their souls.</English>
		<French>Tout campement sidar de taille respectable contiendra une "Demeure du Gris", un bâtiment dédié à l'étude des rituels et des risques liés à la manipulation de leur âme par les sidarae.</French>
		<German>Jede Sidar Siedlung einer bestimmten Größe beherbergt ein "Haus der Düsternis", ein Gebäude, das dem Studium der Rituale und Risiken zur Manipulation ihrer Seelen gewidmet ist. </German>
		<Italian>Any Sidar settlement of a notable size will contain a "House of the Grey", a building dedicated to studying the rituals and risks involved with the Sidar's manipulation of their souls.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Any Sidar settlement of a notable size will contain a "House of the Grey", a building dedicated to studying the rituals and risks involved with the Sidar's manipulation of their souls.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOUSE_OF_THE_GREY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>A House of the Grey provides Happiness and Health reliant only on Mana provided by the capital. Therefore any connected city will benefit provided you have not traded away the mana sources. It is available at Mysticism, but is also required for units of the recon line.</English>
		<French>Une "Demeure du Gris" fournit du bonheur et de la santé ne dépendant que du mana fourni par la capitale. Ainsi, toute ville reliée à la capitale en profitera, à condition que vous n'ayiez pas exporté les sources de mana. Elle est disponible une fois découvert le [LINK=TECH_MYSTICISM]Mysticisme[\LINK], et est également requis pour la construction d'unités de reconnaissance.</French>
		<German>Ein Haus der Düsternis liefert Zufriedenheit und Gesundheit und beruht dabei nur auf dem Mana, das von der Hauptstadt zur Verfügung gestellt wird. Deshalb wird jede verbundene Stadt davon profitieren, vorausgesetzt, das Mana wurde nicht zum Handeln benutzt. Es wird durch die Erforschung von "Mystik" verfügbar und wird auch zur Ausbildung von Aufklärungseinheiten benötigt.</German>
		<Italian>A House of the Grey provides Happiness and Health reliant only on Mana provided by the capital. Therefore any connected city will benefit provided you have not traded away the mana sources. It is available at Mysticism, but is also required for units of the recon line.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A House of the Grey provides Happiness and Health reliant only on Mana provided by the capital. Therefore any connected city will benefit provided you have not traded away the mana sources. It is available at Mysticism, but is also required for units of the recon line.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_SIDAR</Tag>
		<English>Sidar Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Sidar</French>
		<German>Palast der Sidar</German>
		<Italian>Sidar Palace</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Sidar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SANDALPHON</Tag>
		<English>Sandalphon</English>
		<French>Sandalphon</French>
		<German>Sandalphon</German>
		<Italian>Sandalphon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sandalphon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SANDALPHON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]It was cold and foggy, the kind of thick, solid fog that can only be sustained in the man-made canyons of a city. Everything more than an arm's length from the two walking figures started to disappear in the murk, so she had to stay fairly close in order to keep them in sight. Here and there, the soft glow of torches and lamps changed the color of the woolly vapor. She avoided them as much as she could. Casting shadows was not a good idea in her line of business.[PARAGRAPH:1]When she saw him in daylight, Sandalphon remained perfectly visible, as solid as the next man but with an unnaturally pale complexion, and dull eyes. It was as if the light never glinted off his pupils. In this foggy twilight, however, Sandalphon seemed to... blend. He seemed to glide in and out of it, or become one with it, vaguely luminescent. He did not appear to be entirely solid. At any rate, it was impossible to say exactly where the fog stopped and Sandalphon began, even though it was not hard to actually distinguish him from his vaporous surroundings. The whole man was like an optical illusion. It was a rather disturbing effect.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unexpectedly, his voice, drifting back through the mist, was strong and commanding, not at all the vaporous whisper or distant hiss you would expect from his shadowy appearance. He was discussing the merits of being a shade with his travelling companion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Immortals must necessarily become creatures of habit in the end, she reflected. It was their weakness. Years of repetition set their lives in patterns, comfortable and predictable. Sandalphon's most exploitable habit was these walks, giving those who are considering undergoing the ritual a taste of the life of a shade.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I never really missed love," Sandalphon mused, as they ambled along between the taverns and shops. "Love, hate, anger, greed and jealousy are just a few of the confusing, unnecessary emotions bound up in your soul. You soon realize that you are better off without them."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was there nothing you missed? Nothing you felt you were giving up when you abandoned your soul?" As the acolyte asked the question, they turned a corner. Cursing, she swept after them.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, of course there were things I missed. It took years before I got over the loss of pleasure over food, and smells, and music. All those things appeal to the base instincts. But in the end, they paled in comparison to the prospect of getting drunk on knowledge, of gorging yourself on all the wisdom of the world, which you have endless time to explore."[PARAGRAPH:1]They kept walking, the acolyte asking questions, Sandalphon answering with calm certainty, their route twisting in and out of the city streets, never presenting a good opportunity for her to make her move. Silently, she kept pace with them, praying that soon she would have her chance.[PARAGRAPH:1]"But surely some shades get tired of their never-ending existence? If I am to join you, am I doomed to forever walk the earth, with no escape in sight?" the acolyte asked, as they turned the corner into a short road that ended in the mouth of a long tunnel.[PARAGRAPH:1]She could not follow them in there without making too much noise. It was now or never. She pounced.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sandalphon considered the question: "Suicide is always an option," he announced at the same time as he straightened up, as if sensing a change in the texture of the fog. "It's not that we cannot die, for example, a violent death", he continued, making an elegant step to the left, and thrusting out his hand, grabbing the assassin's knife-arm. "We can." He wrenched the unfortunate assassin toward him, and for a split second he became very solid indeed, as if suddenly stepping out of the shadows and into a floodlight, as he snapped her head back and thrust her spine forward in one fluid movement that produced a sickening crack. "It's just that we are very, very hard to kill," he said, and let the assassin's limp body slide to the ground.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Il faisait froid et brumeux, le genre de brouillard à couper au couteau qui ne peut exister que dans les canyons artificiels d'une ville. Tout ce qui était à plus d'un mètre des deux silhouettes qui marchaient commencait à disparaître dans la brume, elle devait donc rester toute proche pour ne pas les perdre de vue. Ici et là, la faible lueur des torches changeait la couleur de la vapeur laiteuse. Elle les évita autant qu'elle le put. Projeter des ombres n'était jamais une bonne idée dans son métier.[PARAGRAPH:1]Lorsqu'elle le vit à la lumière du jour, Sandalphon restait parfaitement visible, aussi tangible que l'autre homme mais avec un aspect étrangement pâle et des yeux vitreux. Comme si aucune lueur n'avait jamais brillé dans ses pupilles. Dans ce crépuscule brumeux, Sandalphon semblait pourtant se fondre. Il semblait se glisser tour à tour dans et hors du brouillard, ou ne faire plus qu'un avec lui, vaguement luminescent. Il ne semblait pas être totalement solide. Il était impossible de dire exactement où le brouillard finissait et où Sandalphon commençait, même s'il n'était pas difficile de le distinguer de ses alentours vaporeux. L'homme lui-même semblait être une illusion d'optique. C'était un effet plutôt dérangeant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Étonnamment, sa voix surgissant de la brume était forte et charismatique, et non le chuchotement vaporeux ou le sifflement distant que l'on attendrait de son apparence ombreuse. Il discutait des avantages à être une Ombre avec son compagnon de voyage.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les immortels doivent être bourrés d'habitudes à la longue, se dit-elle. C'était leur faiblesse. Des années de répétition avaient fait de leur vie une rengaine , confortable et prévisible. La plus exploitable habitude de Sandalphon était ces marches durant lesquelles il donnait à ceux qui voulaient accomplir le rituel un avant-goût de la vie en tant qu'Ombre[PARAGRAPH:1]"L'amour ne m'a jamais réellement manqué," songea Sandalphon, alors qu'ils déambulaient entre les tavernes et les échoppes. "L'amour, la haine, la colère, l'avidité et la jalousie sont juste quelques-unes des émotions sans intérêt liées à  votre âme. Vous vous rendrez vite compte que vous serez mieux sans elles."[PARAGRAPH:1]"N'y a-t-il rien qui vous manque ? Rien que vous ayiez eu l'impression d'abandonner lorsque vous avez abandonné votre âme ?" Tandis que l'acolyte posait sa question, ils tournèrent au coin d'une rue. Tout en jurant, elle se glissa derrière eux.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, bien sûr qu'il y a des choses qui m'ont manqué. Ça m'a pris des années pour surpasser la perte des plaisirs de la table, des odeurs et de la musique. Toutes ces choses font appel aux bas instincts. Mais au final, elles ne sont rien face au fait de s'enivrer de savoir, de se gorger de toute la sagesse du monde, que l'on peut explorer sans fin."[PARAGRAPH:1]Il continuèrent de marcher, l'acolyte posant des questions, Sandalphon répondant avec un calme constant, leur chemin zigzaguant au gré des rues de la ville, ne lui offrant jamais une occasion d'agir. Silencieusement, elle continua de les suivre, priant pour avoir bientôt sa chance.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Mais il y a sûrement quelques Ombres qui finissent par se lasser de leur existence sans fin ? Si je vous rejoins, suis-je condamné à errer éternellement sur terre, sans possibilité de fuite ?" demanda l'acolyte, alors qu'ils s'engageaient sur une petite route qui débouchait sur un long tunnel.[PARAGRAPH:1]Elle ne pouvait les suivre dedans tout en restant assez silencieuse. C'était maintenant ou jamais. Elle s'élança.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sandalphon réfléchit à la question : "Le suicide est toujours une option," annonça-t-il, au moment où il se raidissait, comme s'il avait senti une variation de la texture du brouillard. "Ce n'est pas que nous ne pouvons pas mourir, par exemple, de mort violente" continua-t-il, faisant un élégant pas sur sa gauche, tendant brusqueement la main et attrapant le bras armé de l'assassin. "Nous pouvons." Il amena violemment l'assassin malchanceuse devant lui, et pendant un instant, il parut véritablement tangible, comme s'il était soudainement passé des ombres à la lumière d'un projecteur, tout en tirant sa tête en arriere et en arrachant sa colonne vertébrale d'un mouvement fluide qui produisit un craquement éc&#156;urant. "C'est juste que nous sommes très, très durs à tuer," dit-il, et il laissa le corps sans vie de l'assassin heurter le sol.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Es war kalt und nebelig, ein derart dicker Nebel konnte sich nur in den künstlichen Schluchten einer Stadt halten. Alles was sich weiter als eine Armeslänge von den beiden gehenden Gestalten entfernte begann im Trüben zu verschwinden, daher musste sie ziemlich nahe bleiben, um die beiden nicht aus den Augen zu verlieren. Hier und da veränderte das gedämpfte Leuchten der Fackeln und Lampen, die Farbe des wallenden Dunstes. Sie versuchte so unbemerkt wie möglich zu bleiben. Aufzufallen war nicht gut in ihrem Geschäft.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als sie ihn bei Tageslicht sah, blieb Sandalphon völlig sichtbar, genauso wie jedermann, nur unnatürlich bleichen und trüben Augen. Es war, als ob niemals Licht aus seinen Pupillen kommen würde. In diesem nebeligen Zwielicht schien Sandalphon jedoch irgendwie zu verschwimmen. Er schien hinein und heraus zu gleiten, oder eins mit dem Nebel zu werden, schwach leuchtend. Er schien nicht körperlich zu sein. Es war unmöglich festzustellen, wo der Nebel genau aufhörte und Sandalphon anfing, obwohl es nicht schwierig war, ihn von der dunstigen Umgebung zu unterscheiden. Der ganze Mann wirkte wie eine optische Täuschung, dies war verstörend.[PARAGRAPH:1]Seine Stimme jedoch, die aus dem Nebel kam, war unerwartet laut und befehlend, ganz im Gegensatz zu seinem schattenartigen Äußeren. Er besprach die Vorteile, ein Schatten zu sein, mit seinem Begleiter.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unsterbliche müssen am Ende notwendigerweise zu gewöhnlichen Wesen werden, dachte sie. Das war ihre Schwäche. Jahre der Wiederholung erzeugen in ihrem Leben Muster, gewöhnliche und vorhersehbare. Sandalphons am meisten ausnutzbare Gewohnheit waren diese Spaziergänge, wo er anderen, die das Ritual in Betracht zogen, einen Vorgeschmack auf das Leben eines Schattens gab.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich vermißte wirklich niemals die Liebe." grübelte Sandalphon, als sie zwischen den Geschäften und Wirtshäusern gingen. "Liebe, Hass, Wut, Gier und Eifersucht sind nur einige dieser verwirrenden, nicht notwendigen Gefühle in deiner Seele. Bald wirst du erkennen, dass es besser ohne sie geht."[PARAGRAPH:1] "Gab es nichts, was du vermisst hast? Nichts, was du aufzugeben glaubtest?" Als der Akolyt diese Frage stellte, gingen sie gerade um eine Ecke. Fluchend glitt sie ihnen nach.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ja natürlich gibt es Dinge, die ich vermisste. Jahrelang vermisste ich die Freude an Nahrung, Gerüche, Musik. All das scheinen Grundinstinkte zu sein. Aber schließlich und endlich verblaßten sie im Vergleich, trunken vor Wissen zu sein, in der Weisheit der Welt zu wühlen, endlos Zeit zu haben zum erforschen."[PARAGRAPH:1] Sie gingen weiter, der Akolyt stellte Fragen, Sandalphon beantwortete sie ruhig, aber bestimmt. Ihr Weg führte sie über zahlreiche Straßen in der Stadt, sie hatte nie die Gelegenheit, auf die sie wartete. Still hielt sie Schritt mit den beiden und bete, bald ihre Chance zu haben.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Aber sicherlich wurden einige Schatten ihrer niemals endenden Existenz müde? Wenn ich dir folge, werde ich verdammt, ewig auf Erden zu weilen ohne Fluchtmöglichkeit?" fragte der Akolyt. Sie kamen um eine Ecke in eine kurze Straße, die in einem langen Tunnel endete.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie würde ihnen dorthin nicht unbemerkt folgen können. Jetzt oder nie. Sie handelte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sandalphon dachte über die Frage nach: "Selbstmord ist immer eine Möglichkeit." beginnt er, richtete sich gleichzeitig auf, als ob er eine Veränderung im Nebel erahnte. "Natürlich sind auch wir sterblich, wie zum Beispiel durch einen gewaltsamen Tod." fuhr er fort. Er machte einen eleganten Schritt zur Seite und fasste den Klingenarm der Attentäterin. "Wir können sterben." Er bog die unglückliche Meuchelmörderin zu sich und für einen Sekundenbruchteil wurde er sehr körperlich, so als ob er plötzlich aus den Schatten ins helle Licht trat, wobei er ihren Kopf nach hinten riss und ihr Genick in einer fließenden Bewegung mit einem ekeligen Geräusch brach." Wir sind allerdings nur sehr, sehr schwierig zu töten. " sagte er und ließ den leblosen Körper der Attentäterin zu Boden gleiten.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]It was cold and foggy, the kind of thick, solid fog that can only be sustained in the man-made canyons of a city. Everything more than an arm's length from the two walking figures started to disappear in the murk, so she had to stay fairly close in order to keep them in sight. Here and there, the soft glow of torches and lamps changed the color of the woolly vapor. She avoided them as much as she could. Casting shadows was not a good idea in her line of business.[PARAGRAPH:1]When she saw him in daylight, Sandalphon remained perfectly visible, as solid as the next man but with an unnaturally pale complexion, and dull eyes. It was as if the light never glinted off his pupils. In this foggy twilight, however, Sandalphon seemed to... blend. He seemed to glide in and out of it, or become one with it, vaguely luminescent. He did not appear to be entirely solid. At any rate, it was impossible to say exactly where the fog stopped and Sandalphon began, even though it was not hard to actually distinguish him from his vaporous surroundings. The whole man was like an optical illusion. It was a rather disturbing effect.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unexpectedly, his voice, drifting back through the mist, was strong and commanding, not at all the vaporous whisper or distant hiss you would expect from his shadowy appearance. He was discussing the merits of being a shade with his travelling companion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Immortals must necessarily become creatures of habit in the end, she reflected. It was their weakness. Years of repetition set their lives in patterns, comfortable and predictable. Sandalphon's most exploitable habit was these walks, giving those who are considering undergoing the ritual a taste of the life of a shade.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I never really missed love," Sandalphon mused, as they ambled along between the taverns and shops. "Love, hate, anger, greed and jealousy are just a few of the confusing, unnecessary emotions bound up in your soul. You soon realize that you are better off without them."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was there nothing you missed? Nothing you felt you were giving up when you abandoned your soul?" As the acolyte asked the question, they turned a corner. Cursing, she swept after them.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, of course there were things I missed. It took years before I got over the loss of pleasure over food, and smells, and music. All those things appeal to the base instincts. But in the end, they paled in comparison to the prospect of getting drunk on knowledge, of gorging yourself on all the wisdom of the world, which you have endless time to explore."[PARAGRAPH:1]They kept walking, the acolyte asking questions, Sandalphon answering with calm certainty, their route twisting in and out of the city streets, never presenting a good opportunity for her to make her move. Silently, she kept pace with them, praying that soon she would have her chance.[PARAGRAPH:1]"But surely some shades get tired of their never-ending existence? If I am to join you, am I doomed to forever walk the earth, with no escape in sight?" the acolyte asked, as they turned the corner into a short road that ended in the mouth of a long tunnel.[PARAGRAPH:1]She could not follow them in there without making too much noise. It was now or never. She pounced.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sandalphon considered the question: "Suicide is always an option," he announced at the same time as he straightened up, as if sensing a change in the texture of the fog. "It's not that we cannot die, for example, a violent death", he continued, making an elegant step to the left, and thrusting out his hand, grabbing the assassin's knife-arm. "We can." He wrenched the unfortunate assassin toward him, and for a split second he became very solid indeed, as if suddenly stepping out of the shadows and into a floodlight, as he snapped her head back and thrust her spine forward in one fluid movement that produced a sickening crack. "It's just that we are very, very hard to kill," he said, and let the assassin's limp body slide to the ground.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]It was cold and foggy, the kind of thick, solid fog that can only be sustained in the man-made canyons of a city. Everything more than an arm's length from the two walking figures started to disappear in the murk, so she had to stay fairly close in order to keep them in sight. Here and there, the soft glow of torches and lamps changed the color of the woolly vapor. She avoided them as much as she could. Casting shadows was not a good idea in her line of business.[PARAGRAPH:1]When she saw him in daylight, Sandalphon remained perfectly visible, as solid as the next man but with an unnaturally pale complexion, and dull eyes. It was as if the light never glinted off his pupils. In this foggy twilight, however, Sandalphon seemed to... blend. He seemed to glide in and out of it, or become one with it, vaguely luminescent. He did not appear to be entirely solid. At any rate, it was impossible to say exactly where the fog stopped and Sandalphon began, even though it was not hard to actually distinguish him from his vaporous surroundings. The whole man was like an optical illusion. It was a rather disturbing effect.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unexpectedly, his voice, drifting back through the mist, was strong and commanding, not at all the vaporous whisper or distant hiss you would expect from his shadowy appearance. He was discussing the merits of being a shade with his travelling companion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Immortals must necessarily become creatures of habit in the end, she reflected. It was their weakness. Years of repetition set their lives in patterns, comfortable and predictable. Sandalphon's most exploitable habit was these walks, giving those who are considering undergoing the ritual a taste of the life of a shade.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I never really missed love," Sandalphon mused, as they ambled along between the taverns and shops. "Love, hate, anger, greed and jealousy are just a few of the confusing, unnecessary emotions bound up in your soul. You soon realize that you are better off without them."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was there nothing you missed? Nothing you felt you were giving up when you abandoned your soul?" As the acolyte asked the question, they turned a corner. Cursing, she swept after them.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, of course there were things I missed. It took years before I got over the loss of pleasure over food, and smells, and music. All those things appeal to the base instincts. But in the end, they paled in comparison to the prospect of getting drunk on knowledge, of gorging yourself on all the wisdom of the world, which you have endless time to explore."[PARAGRAPH:1]They kept walking, the acolyte asking questions, Sandalphon answering with calm certainty, their route twisting in and out of the city streets, never presenting a good opportunity for her to make her move. Silently, she kept pace with them, praying that soon she would have her chance.[PARAGRAPH:1]"But surely some shades get tired of their never-ending existence? If I am to join you, am I doomed to forever walk the earth, with no escape in sight?" the acolyte asked, as they turned the corner into a short road that ended in the mouth of a long tunnel.[PARAGRAPH:1]She could not follow them in there without making too much noise. It was now or never. She pounced.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sandalphon considered the question: "Suicide is always an option," he announced at the same time as he straightened up, as if sensing a change in the texture of the fog. "It's not that we cannot die, for example, a violent death", he continued, making an elegant step to the left, and thrusting out his hand, grabbing the assassin's knife-arm. "We can." He wrenched the unfortunate assassin toward him, and for a split second he became very solid indeed, as if suddenly stepping out of the shadows and into a floodlight, as he snapped her head back and thrust her spine forward in one fluid movement that produced a sickening crack. "It's just that we are very, very hard to kill," he said, and let the assassin's limp body slide to the ground.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SHEKINAH</Tag>
		<English>Shekinah</English>
		<French>Shekinah</French>
		<German>Shekinah</German>
		<Italian>Shekinah</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shekinah</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SHADE</Tag>
		<English>Shade</English>
		<French>Ombre</French>
		<German>Trübung</German>
		<Italian>Shade</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shade</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_GREATER_SHADE</Tag>
		<English>Greater Shade</English>
		<French>Ombre Épaisse</French>
		<German>Große Trübung</German>
		<Italian>Greater Shade</Italian>
		<Spanish>Greater Shade</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_CREATE_MIST</Tag>
		<English>Hide city in Mist</English>
		<French>Cacher la ville dans le Brouillard</French>
		<German>Im Nebel verbergen</German>
		<Italian>Hide city in Mist</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hide city in Mist</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_CREATE_MIST_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Lowers the plot radius of the city to 1[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]No Foreign Trade[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]-2 Trade Routes</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Réduit le rayon de la Ville à 1[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Pas de Commerce Extérieur[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]-2 Routes Commerciales</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Verringert den genutzten Radius der Stadt auf 1[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Kein Handel mit Ausland[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]-2 auf Handelsrouten</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Lowers the plot radius of the city to 1[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]No Foreign Trade[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]-2 Trade Routes</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Lowers the plot radius of the city to 1[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]No Foreign Trade[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]-2 Trade Routes</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_INTO_THE_MIST</Tag>
		<English>Into the Mist</English>
		<French>Dans la Brume</French>
		<German>In den Nebel</German>
		<Italian>Into the Mist</Italian>
		<Spanish>Into the Mist</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_INTO_THE_MIST_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]All of your units become invisible</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Toutes vos unités deviennent invisibles</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]All eure Einheiten werden unsichtbar</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]All of your units become invisible</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]All of your units become invisible</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_GLOBALSPELL_INTO_THE_MIST</Tag>
		<English>Grants all of the caster's units [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Hidden[\LINK]</English>
		<French>Confère à toutes les unités du lanceur la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Caché[\LINK]</French>
		<German>Alle Einheiten des Zaubernden erhalten die Bef&#246;rderung [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Verborgen[\LINK]</German>
		<Italian>Grants all of the caster's units [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Hidden[\LINK]</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grants all of the caster's units [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN]Hidden[\LINK]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_REMOVE_MIST</Tag>
		<English>Clear up the Mist</English>
		<French>Dissiper le brouillard</French>
		<German>Nebel vertreiben</German>
		<Italian>Clear up the Mist</Italian>
		<Spanish>Clear up the Mist</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_REMOVE_MIST_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Restores the plot radius of the city to 2[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City can conduct Foreign Trade again[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Trade Routes</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Rétablit le rayon de la Ville à sa valeur initiale (soit 2)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]La Ville dispose à nouveau de Commerce Extérieur[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Routes Commerciales</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Stellt den Stadtradius von 2 wieder her[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Stadt kann wieder Handel mit dem Ausland aufnehmen.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Handelsrouten</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Restores the plot radius of the city to 2[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City can conduct Foreign Trade again[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Trade Routes</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Restores the plot radius of the city to 2[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City can conduct Foreign Trade again[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Trade Routes</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DIVIDED_SOUL</Tag>
		<English>Divided Soul</English>
		<French>Âme Divisée</French>
		<German>Gespaltene Seele</German>
		<Italian>Divided Soul</Italian>
		<Spanish>Divided Soul</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DIVIDED_SOUL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Sidar understand well the nature of their souls - though they may not treasure them as do other races. Trading a portion of their souls at a time for near immortality, some Sidar become adept at separating their essence and dividing their soul. Sidar who practice this art are known as "Divided" and are said to allow their soul to travel without them, unseen and undetected by all but the most perceptive of seers.[TAB]Verdian moved slowly through the camp. The falling snow gave more notice to the alert soldiers on the perimeter than he did, but he moved slowly anyway. He could be perceived by some alert or spiritually attuned individuals if he were careless, so he stayed out of the moonlight and followed the winds. The winds were stronger than he had expected at this time, even at the foothills of Tempus Mor. The snowfall was unseasonal as well, and he used that to his advantage, getting ever closer to the center of the camp without drawing notice.[PARAGRAPH:1]The guards at the large tent were less alert, but more experienced. One man was warming himself by a large fire as Verdian passed, and his form was outlined in the smoke. The guard drew his scimitar and stepped back into the doorway of the tent, alert now though he couldn't guess for what. Verdian took a risk and pushed past him. The guardsman felt the heat of the fire give way to a chill, but the tent was sturdy and should have blocked the wind. While a false alarm may bring some menial punishment and minor humiliation upon him, ignoring an intruder here could bring his death. He called out, "Lord Commander Decius! Awaken, I fear some magic about us." Decius stirred from his rest on the floor of the tent, and other sentries rushed in.[PARAGRAPH:1]Emotion was tempered in Verdian, like his kin, and even more so when so far from his slowly beating heart. He felt neither irritation nor fear when he heard the sentry's call, but pushed himself to action. Sidar Divided Souls would usually will their somnolent bodies to reunite with their spirits slowly, and all at once. This was more for their comfort than from necessity, however. Verdian's hands appeared in the air above Decius' chest, clasped together and holding a slim stiletto. Even as the muscle and sinew of his arms and shoulders followed he forced it to begin a downward descent, despite the pain this would cause him as the rest of his body took shape.[PARAGRAPH:1]The sentries were stunned for a critical moment by this spectacle, gasping in awe but unable to reach the killer in time. Decius had been forged in far more battles than the desert warriors he now led, and had seen and slain far more frightening apparitions. He rolled out of the way, saving his heart from the blade. Verdian pierced his upper arm and hopped back, drawing another blade. His form was now complete, and though his body complained of this painful transition, his will was stronger.[PARAGRAPH:1]Decius reached for his blade, or tried to. His arm was numb, and not from pain. If the poison coating the stiletto had reached his heart, instead... He pulled the attacker's weapon out with his left hand and prepared to parry. He didn't have to, for by now his men were surrounding him. Decius finally got a chance to get a better look at Verdian, but the garb that obscured showed only that he was a human man. "You aren't the one I expected," he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]Verdian needed but a moment to concentrate, to separate. His soul would be unable to be bound by strong arms, and if he could get beyond the bounds of the camp he could pull his body back to him. Sandalphon would need to know he had failed his task. Rathus and the others would hopefully fare better against their targets. He closed his eyes, pushed away from his body... but was drawn back with a cry.[PARAGRAPH:1]Decius held a torch against the hunter's body. "I'm afraid we need to have a chat before you leave. Who are you and why did you try to kill me?"</English>
		<French>Les sidarae comprennent bien la nature de leur âme, même s'ils ne la chérissent pas autant que les autres races. Échangeant une fois une part de leur âme contre une quasi-immortalité, certains sidarae sont devenus friands de séparer leur essence et diviser leur âme. Les sidarae pratiquant cet art sont connus comme les "Divisés", et on raconte qu'ils permettent à leur âme de voyager sans eux, invisible et jamais détectée, sauf par les scruteurs les plus persipaces.[PARAGRAPH:1]Verdian se déplaçait doucement dans le campement. La neige tombante était plus visible que lui pour les soldats de faction, mais il se déplaçait quand même doucement. Il pourrait être détecté par quelqu'un d'alerte ou accoutumé au spirituel s'il était négligent. Il restait donc hors du clair de lune et suivait les vents. Les vents étaient plus puissants que ce à quoi il s'attendait pour l'heure, même pour les contreforts de Tempus Mor. La chute de neige était également hors saison, et il l'utilisait à son avantage, s'approchant toujours plus du camp sans attirer l'attention.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les gardes de la grande tente étaient moins attentifs, mais plus expérimentés. Un homme se réchauffait auprès d'un grand feu quand Verdian passa, et sa silhouette fut dessinée par la fumée. L'homme dégaina son cimeterre et recula dans l'embrasure de la tente, en alerte, bien qqu'il ne sût pas pourquoi. Verdian prit un risque et le passa. Le garde sentit que la chaleur du feu laissait sa place à un frisson, mais la tente était solide et aurait dû bloquer le vent. Une fausse alerte pouvait mener à une petite punition et une petite humiliation, mais ignorer un intrus ici pourrait lui coûter la vie. Il cria, "Seigneur Commandant Decius ! Réveillez-vous, j'ai peur qu'on soit la cible de magie." Decius s'arracha à son sommeil à même le sol de la tente, et les autres sentinelles se précipitèrent à l'intérieur.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les émotions étaient tempérées chez Verdian, comme chez tous ceux de son genre, et plus encore en étant si loin de son c&#156;ur battant lentement. Il ne ressentit ni irritation ni peur en entendant l'appel de la sentinelle, mais se mit en action. Les Âmes Divisées sidarae souhaitaient généralement que leur corps se réunissent doucement avec leurs âmes, et d'un seul coup. C'était cependant plus pour leur confort que par nécessité. Les mains de Verdian apparurent dans les airs au-dessus du torse de Decius, se joignirent en tenant un fin stylet. Même lorsque ses muscles et tendons de ses bras et épaules suivirent, il en força la descente en piqué, malgré la peine que ça lui infligerait pendant que le rest de son corps reprenait forme.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les sentinelles furent abasourdies pendant cet instant critique par ce spectacle, souffle coupé mais incapable d'atteindre le tueur à temps. Decius avait été forgé par bien plus de batailles que les guerriers du désert qu'il commandait aujourd'hui, et avait vu et vaincu de bien plus terrifiantes apparitions. Il esquiva d'une roulade, sauvant son c&#156;ur de la lame. Verdian transperça son biceps et recula, dégainant une autre lame. Sa forme était maintenant complète, et même si son corps se plaignait de cette transition douloureuse, sa volonté était plus forte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Decius saisit son arme, ou plutôt tenta de le faire. Ses bras étaient paralysés, et pas par la douleur. Si le poison du stylet avait à la place atteint son c&#156;ur... Il arracha l'arme de son assaillant avec sa main gauche et se prépara à parer. Il n'eut pas à le faire, ses hommes le cernant maintenant. Decius eut finalement la possiblité de jeter un regard plus attentif à Verdian, mais le costume le dissimulant ne révélait que sa nature humaine. "Tu n'es pas celui que j'attendais," dit-il.[PARAGRAPH:1]Verdian n'avait besoin que d'un instant pour se concentrer, se séparer. Son âme ne pourrait pas être retenue par des bras puissants, et s'il pouvait sortir des limites du camp il pourrait ramener son corps à lui. Sandalphon devait savoir qu'il avait échoué. Avec un peu de chance, Rathus et les autres s'en sortiraient mieux que lui avec leurs cibles. Il ferma les yeux, et s'extirpa de son corps... mais fut rappelé à lui avec un cri.[PARAGRAPH:1]Decius tenait une torche contre le corps du chasseur. "J'ai bien peur que vous et moi ne devions discuter avant que vous partiez. Qui êtes-vous et pourquoi avez-vous tenté de me tuer ?"</French>
		<German>Die Sidar verstehen die Natur ihrer Seelen sehr gut - obwohl sie sie nicht so hoch schätzen wie andere Rassen. Indem sie einen Teil ihrer Seele zu einem bestimmten Zeitpunkt gegen Beinahe-Unsterblichkeit eintauschen, werden manche Sidar Adepten in der Kunst, ihre Essenz von der Seele zu trennen. Sidar, die diese Kunst ausüben, werden "gespalten" genannt und man sagt, daß sie ihre Seele ohne sich herumwandern lassen können, ungesehen, unbemerkt von allen außer den besten und aufmerksamsten aller Seher.[TAB]Verdian schlich leise durch das Zeltlager. Für die wachsamen Soldaten am Rand des Lagers war selbst der fallende Schnee auffälliger als Verdian, aber er bewegte sich trotzdem langsam. Er konnte von einer aufmerksamen oder spirituell begabten Person entdeckt werden, falls er nachlässig war, so dass er dem Mondlicht fernblieb und den Winden folgten. Die Winde waren stärker als er es erwartete, selbst an den Ausläufern des Tempus Mor. Der Schneefall war ungewöhnlich für die Jahreszeit und er nutzte dies zu seinem Vorteil, um näher an das Zentrums des Lagers zu kommen ohne Aufsehen zu erregen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Wachen am großen Zelt waren weniger wachsam, aber dafür erfahrener. Ein Mann wärmte sich am großen Feuer als Verdian vorbeischlich und der Rauch zeichnete seine Umrisse nach. Der Wächter zog seinen Säbel und schritt in die Türöffnung des Zelts, nun alarmiert und auf der Hut, auch wenn er nicht wusste vor was. Verdian nahm das Risiko in Kauf und drängte sich an ihm vorbei. Der Wächter spürte, wie die Wärme des Feuers schwand und durch einen kühlen Hauch ersetzt wurde, aber das Zelt war stabil gebaut und hätte den Wind abhalten sollen. Ein falscher Alarm hätte ihm vielleicht eine geringe Strafe eingebracht und ihn vielleicht ein wenig erniedrigt, aber einen Eindringling zu übersehen konnte ihn das Leben kosten. Er brüllte: "Fürst Decius! Wacht auf, ich fürchte Magie ist am Werk!" Decius regte sich am Boden des Zelts und andere Wachen eilten herbei.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Gefühle in Verdian waren nur schwach, wie bei anderen seiner Art, und dies war noch mehr der Fall, wenn er seinem langsam schlagenden Herzen so fern war wie jetzt. Er spürter weder Ärger, noch Furcht als er den Ruf der Wache hörte, sondern zwang sich selbst zum Handeln. Getrennte Seelen der Sidar verbinden sich normal langsam mit ihren schlafenden Körpern und mit dem ganzen Körper zugleich. Das war jedoch eher eine Annehmlichkeit als eine Notwendigkeit. Verdians Hände erschienen in der Luft über Decius' Brust, einen dünnen, langen Dolch haltend. Selbst als die Muskeln und Sehnen seiner Arme und Schultern folgten, zwang er sie zu einer Abwärtsbewegung, trotz des Schmerz den er erlitt als sein restlicher Leib Gestalt annahm.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Wachen waren für einen Augenblick wie betäubt von diesem Anblick, ehrfürchtig staunend, aber nicht in der Lage den Meuchelmörder rechtzeitig zu erreichen. Decius jedoch, war hatte schon weit aus mehr Schlachten geschlagen als die Wüstenkrieger die er nun anführte und weit aus furchteinflößendere Erscheinungen gesehen und besiegt. Er rollte zur Seite und rettete so sein Herz vor der Klinge. Verdian traft seinen Oberarm und machte, eine weitere Klinge ziehend, einen Satz zurück. Seine Gestalt war nun vollständig und obwohl sein Körper durch den peinvollen Übergang schmerzte, war sein Wille stärker.[PARAGRAPH:1]Decius griff nach seiner Klinge - oder versuchte es. Sein Arm war taub und nicht durch den Schmerz. Falls das Gift auf dem Dolch sein Herz statt seinem Arm erreicht hätte... Er zog sich die Waffe des Angreifers aus dem Arm und bereitete sich darauf vor den nächsten Hieb zu parieren, doch nun waren seine Männerschon da. Decius warf nun einen Blick auf Verdian, doch das verhüllende Gewand zeigte nur einen Menschen. "Du bist nicht der, den ich erwartete!", sagte er.[PARAGRAPH:1]Verdian brauchte nur einen Moment um sich erneut zu konzentrieren, um sich erneut zu trennen. Seine Seele konnte nicht gehalten werden und außerhalb des Lagers konnte er seinen Körper wieder zu sich rufen. Sandalphon musste wissen, dass er er versagte. Rathus und die anderen hatten hoffentlich mehr Erfolg bei ihren Zielen. Er schloss seine Augen und trennte sich von seinem Leib... aber wurde mit einem Schrei zurückgezogen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Decius hielt eine Fackel gegen den Körper des Jägers. "Ich fürchte wir müssen ein wenig plaudern, bevor du uns verlässt. Wer bist du und warum hast du versucht mich zu töten?"</German>
		<Italian>The Sidar understand well the nature of their souls - though they may not treasure them as do other races. Trading a portion of their souls at a time for near immortality, some Sidar become adept at separating their essence and dividing their soul. Sidar who practice this art are known as "Divided" and are said to allow their soul to travel without them, unseen and undetected by all but the most perceptive of seers.[TAB]Verdian moved slowly through the camp. The falling snow gave more notice to the alert soldiers on the perimeter than he did, but he moved slowly anyway. He could be perceived by some alert or spiritually attuned individuals if he were careless, so he stayed out of the moonlight and followed the winds. The winds were stronger than he had expected at this time, even at the foothills of Tempus Mor. The snowfall was unseasonal as well, and he used that to his advantage, getting ever closer to the center of the camp without drawing notice.[PARAGRAPH:1]The guards at the large tent were less alert, but more experienced. One man was warming himself by a large fire as Verdian passed, and his form was outlined in the smoke. The guard drew his scimitar and stepped back into the doorway of the tent, alert now though he couldn't guess for what. Verdian took a risk and pushed past him. The guardsman felt the heat of the fire give way to a chill, but the tent was sturdy and should have blocked the wind. While a false alarm may bring some menial punishment and minor humiliation upon him, ignoring an intruder here could bring his death. He called out, "Lord Commander Decius! Awaken, I fear some magic about us." Decius stirred from his rest on the floor of the tent, and other sentries rushed in.[PARAGRAPH:1]Emotion was tempered in Verdian, like his kin, and even more so when so far from his slowly beating heart. He felt neither irritation nor fear when he heard the sentry's call, but pushed himself to action. Sidar Divided Souls would usually will their somnolent bodies to reunite with their spirits slowly, and all at once. This was more for their comfort than from necessity, however. Verdian's hands appeared in the air above Decius' chest, clasped together and holding a slim stiletto. Even as the muscle and sinew of his arms and shoulders followed he forced it to begin a downward descent, despite the pain this would cause him as the rest of his body took shape.[PARAGRAPH:1]The sentries were stunned for a critical moment by this spectacle, gasping in awe but unable to reach the killer in time. Decius had been forged in far more battles than the desert warriors he now led, and had seen and slain far more frightening apparitions. He rolled out of the way, saving his heart from the blade. Verdian pierced his upper arm and hopped back, drawing another blade. His form was now complete, and though his body complained of this painful transition, his will was stronger.[PARAGRAPH:1]Decius reached for his blade, or tried to. His arm was numb, and not from pain. If the poison coating the stiletto had reached his heart, instead... He pulled the attacker's weapon out with his left hand and prepared to parry. He didn't have to, for by now his men were surrounding him. Decius finally got a chance to get a better look at Verdian, but the garb that obscured showed only that he was a human man. "You aren't the one I expected," he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]Verdian needed but a moment to concentrate, to separate. His soul would be unable to be bound by strong arms, and if he could get beyond the bounds of the camp he could pull his body back to him. Sandalphon would need to know he had failed his task. Rathus and the others would hopefully fare better against their targets. He closed his eyes, pushed away from his body... but was drawn back with a cry.[PARAGRAPH:1]Decius held a torch against the hunter's body. "I'm afraid we need to have a chat before you leave. Who are you and why did you try to kill me?"</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Sidar understand well the nature of their souls - though they may not treasure them as do other races. Trading a portion of their souls at a time for near immortality, some Sidar become adept at separating their essence and dividing their soul. Sidar who practice this art are known as "Divided" and are said to allow their soul to travel without them, unseen and undetected by all but the most perceptive of seers.[TAB]Verdian moved slowly through the camp. The falling snow gave more notice to the alert soldiers on the perimeter than he did, but he moved slowly anyway. He could be perceived by some alert or spiritually attuned individuals if he were careless, so he stayed out of the moonlight and followed the winds. The winds were stronger than he had expected at this time, even at the foothills of Tempus Mor. The snowfall was unseasonal as well, and he used that to his advantage, getting ever closer to the center of the camp without drawing notice.[PARAGRAPH:1]The guards at the large tent were less alert, but more experienced. One man was warming himself by a large fire as Verdian passed, and his form was outlined in the smoke. The guard drew his scimitar and stepped back into the doorway of the tent, alert now though he couldn't guess for what. Verdian took a risk and pushed past him. The guardsman felt the heat of the fire give way to a chill, but the tent was sturdy and should have blocked the wind. While a false alarm may bring some menial punishment and minor humiliation upon him, ignoring an intruder here could bring his death. He called out, "Lord Commander Decius! Awaken, I fear some magic about us." Decius stirred from his rest on the floor of the tent, and other sentries rushed in.[PARAGRAPH:1]Emotion was tempered in Verdian, like his kin, and even more so when so far from his slowly beating heart. He felt neither irritation nor fear when he heard the sentry's call, but pushed himself to action. Sidar Divided Souls would usually will their somnolent bodies to reunite with their spirits slowly, and all at once. This was more for their comfort than from necessity, however. Verdian's hands appeared in the air above Decius' chest, clasped together and holding a slim stiletto. Even as the muscle and sinew of his arms and shoulders followed he forced it to begin a downward descent, despite the pain this would cause him as the rest of his body took shape.[PARAGRAPH:1]The sentries were stunned for a critical moment by this spectacle, gasping in awe but unable to reach the killer in time. Decius had been forged in far more battles than the desert warriors he now led, and had seen and slain far more frightening apparitions. He rolled out of the way, saving his heart from the blade. Verdian pierced his upper arm and hopped back, drawing another blade. His form was now complete, and though his body complained of this painful transition, his will was stronger.[PARAGRAPH:1]Decius reached for his blade, or tried to. His arm was numb, and not from pain. If the poison coating the stiletto had reached his heart, instead... He pulled the attacker's weapon out with his left hand and prepared to parry. He didn't have to, for by now his men were surrounding him. Decius finally got a chance to get a better look at Verdian, but the garb that obscured showed only that he was a human man. "You aren't the one I expected," he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]Verdian needed but a moment to concentrate, to separate. His soul would be unable to be bound by strong arms, and if he could get beyond the bounds of the camp he could pull his body back to him. Sandalphon would need to know he had failed his task. Rathus and the others would hopefully fare better against their targets. He closed his eyes, pushed away from his body... but was drawn back with a cry.[PARAGRAPH:1]Decius held a torch against the hunter's body. "I'm afraid we need to have a chat before you leave. Who are you and why did you try to kill me?"</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DIVIDED_SOUL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Divided Souls have the unique ability to create a "Severed Soul" - a portion of themselves that may travel completely unseen by other races. The Divided Soul can reconnect to the Severed Soul at any time, teleporting the unit to the location of it's wandering essence.</English>
		<French>Les Âmes Divisées ont la capacité unique de créer un [LINK=UNIT_SEVERED_SOUL]Fragment d'Âme[\LINK], une part d'eux-mêmes qui peut voyager totalement invisible des autres races. L'Âme Divisée peut se reconnecer à son Fragment d'Âme à n'importe quel moment, téléportant l'unité sur la case de son essence errante.</French>
		<German>Gespaltene Seelen haben die einzigartige Fähigkeit, eine "Getrennte Seele" zu erschaffen - einen Teil ihrer selbst, der sich frei bewegen kann, vollständig unsichtbar für andere Rassen. Die Gespaltene Seele kann sich wieder mit der Getrennten Seele verbinden, indem die Einheit zu ihrer herumwandernden Essenz teleportiert wird.</German>
		<Italian>Divided Souls have the unique ability to create a "Severed Soul" - a portion of themselves that may travel completely unseen by other races. The Divided Soul can reconnect to the Severed Soul at any time, teleporting the unit to the location of it's wandering essence.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Divided Souls have the unique ability to create a "Severed Soul" - a portion of themselves that may travel completely unseen by other races. The Divided Soul can reconnect to the Severed Soul at any time, teleporting the unit to the location of it's wandering essence.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GHOST</Tag>
		<English>Ghost</English>
		<French>Fantôme</French>
		<German>Geist</German>
		<Italian>Ghost</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ghost</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GHOST_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Ghosts have the same uses as assassins, starting with the marksman promotion which causes them to target weaker units first. Additionally, they can turn invisible at will, unless they have attacked this turn. This allows them to get to their target with ease, though surviving retribution may prove more challenging. They will keep this ability should they upgrade to Marksmen.</English>
		<French>Les Fantômes s'utilisent de la même manière que les Assassins, commençant avec la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_MARKSMAN]Tireur d'Élite[\LINK] qui leur permet d'attaquer en premier l'unité la plus faible. De plus, ils peuvent devenir invisibles à volonté, sauf s'ils ont attaqué ce tour. Ça leur permet de se rapprocher facilement de leur cible, même si survivre ensuite peut être plus compliqué. Ils garderont cette faculté, même en devenant des [LINK=UNIT_MARKSMAN]Tireurs d'Élite[\LINK].</French>
		<German>Geister werden genauso eingesetzt wie Meuchelmörder. Sie starten mit der Scharfschützen-Beförderung, welche sie befähigt, schwache Einheiten zuerst anzugreifen. Zusätzlich können sie , falls gewollt, unsichtbar gemacht werden, sofern sie nicht bereits in dieser Runde einen Gegner angegriffen haben. Das ermöglicht ihnen, ihren anvisierten Gegner leicht zu erreichen, obwohl das Überstehen des Gegenangriffes die schwierige Herausforderung ist. Sie behalten diese Fähigkeit, falls sie zu Scharfschützen aufgewertet werden sollten.</German>
		<Italian>Ghosts have the same uses as assassins, starting with the marksman promotion which causes them to target weaker units first. Additionally, they can turn invisible at will, unless they have attacked this turn. This allows them to get to their target with ease, though surviving retribution may prove more challenging. They will keep this ability should they upgrade to Marksmen.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ghosts have the same uses as assassins, starting with the marksman promotion which causes them to target weaker units first. Additionally, they can turn invisible at will, unless they have attacked this turn. This allows them to get to their target with ease, though surviving retribution may prove more challenging. They will keep this ability should they upgrade to Marksmen.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RATHUS</Tag>
		<English>Rathus Denmora</English>
		<French>Rathus Denmora</French>
		<German>Rathus Denmora</German>
		<Italian>Rathus Denmora</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rathus Denmora</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RATHUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The once-elves startled at the alarm. Even the obsidian-clad Perditioners broke their stoic watch to look toward the vortex. The ever-night was gone, light tore through the curtain that contained the veil and blinded the warriors who had never seen sunlight before.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus moved through the once-elves massed at the city's edge. He moved among them unnoticed, an easy feat for a shade who often found it more challenging to be recognized or remembered by those he knew. After decades spent like this, you become something other than mortal, the world is as much a ghost to you as you are a ghost to the world. And you pay close attention to anything that stands out from that haze. [PARAGRAPH:1]Which is why Rathus was here instead of under that light. His friends, if he hadn't slipped from their memory by now, fled the city to escape Haerlond's edict. Their fate was their own now; Rathus meant to use the distraction to check out what the elves called the Malachite Palace, a dark ziggurat with a portal at its summit. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Perditioners were more observant than most and could see even into the ethereal world, which allowed them to keep watch on anything coming through the portal. They might have seen him coming; fortunately, whatever magic was being used in the battle provided all the cover Rathus needed and he slipped up and through the portal. He felt as if he awoke, senses and memories that had long been lost to him by his state were now restored. He was reborn. [PARAGRAPH:1]A blue skinned angel stood before him, the angel was male but he appeared to be both young and old at once, as if he was a blue man in every stage of a full life, all in one unchanging form. He carried a set of chains in one hand and a key in the other, and there was a sword lying at his feet. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Any whose soul is unclaimed may enter my lord's domain, but there you will remain until creation is ended. Is that your desire?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus was confused by the memories; it was becoming harder to focus on the present as the memories become more and more vivid, harder to tell if he was in this moment or another. But he managed an answer. [PARAGRAPH:1]"No, I came to see. To pledge service to Arawn in creation if he would have use of me."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Arawn cares not for creation, his dominion is here; let the other lords bicker over the transient." [PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus focused on the Angel, he had been well trained for this task, even to the point of being able to ignore pain and he used those skills now. For better or worse, he perceived the angel in all of his memories and held this conversation with him in each of them. Each of the angel's thoughts was highlighted in different parts of his life, the bickering in the declaration of war by different religious factions, creation in the abundance of life, good and evil, and the transience in the eventual passing of everything he once considered permanent. [PARAGRAPH:1]"There are those that wield death as if they were Arawn himself."[PARAGRAPH:1]The angel smiled. "The underworld is full of their victims. Holy or unholy, the path of these men is always the same, masses killed to further their goals or the goals of those leading them; lives cut short while theirs are extended beyond the appointed time. If you seek retribution, to thin humanity of those that monopolize it, my lord will not help, but I will."[PARAGRAPH:1]The angel stepped back from the sword at his feet and motioned for Rathus to pick it up. The blade was lighter than steel and had green runes carved in its blade; the runes were unfamiliar to Rathus. It felt real to hands long separated from the sensation of touch. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Retribution?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"No," the angel answered, "Balance. This is the Nether Blade; it will strike strongest against those whom the angels have favored most. Those who no longer fear death will fear you." [PARAGRAPH:1]With that Rathus turned and left the portal. The Perditioners were set to receive him, pikes at the ready. Rathus assumed they would still be distracted by the escape; he would later discover that nearly a year had passed from the time he stepped into and out of the portal. [PARAGRAPH:1]Once outside the portal the world reverted back to the grey haze Rathus's shade nature made it. Only the portal behind him and the Nether Blade seemed truly real to his senses. The blade's green runes glowed as he raised the sword and the Perditioners shrunk back before him.</English>
		<French>Les elfes déchus sursautèrent au bruit de l'alarme. Même les Scruteurs d'Obsidienne cessèrent leur surveillance stoïque pour regarder le vortex. La nuit éternelle n'était plus, la lumière transperçait le rideau qui contenait le voile et aveuglait les guerriers qui n'avaient jusque là jamais vu la lumière du soleil.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus passa les elfes déchus massés aux frontières de la ville. Il se déplaçait parmi eux sans être remarqué, une tâche simple pour une ombre qui trouve souvent plus stimulant d'être reconnu par ceux qu'il connaissait, ou qu'ils se souviennent de lui. Après des décennies comme cela, vous devenez quelque chose d'autre qu'un mortel, le monde étant autant un fantôme pour vous que vous êtes un fantôme pour le monde. Et vous faites particulièrement attention à tout ce qui sort de cette brume.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ce qui explique pourquoi Rathus était ici plutôt que sous cette lumière. Ses amis, s'il n'était pas depuis ce temps sorti de leur mémoire, avait fui la ville pour échapper à l'édit de Haerlond. Leur destin était aujourd'hui entre leurs mains ; Rathus comptait utiliser la distraction pour examiner ce que les elfes appelaient le Palais de Malachite, une ziggourat sombre dotée d'un portail à son sommet.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les Scruteurs étaient plus observateurs que la plupart et pouvaient même voir à travers le monde éthérique, ce qui leur permet de surveiller tout ce qui pourrait traverser le portail. Ils auraient pu le voir venir ; heureusement, quelle que soit la magie utilisée dans la bataille, celle-ci lui avait fourni tout le camouflage dont Rathus avait besoin, et il s'était glissé dans le portail. Il se sentit comme s'il se réveillait, comme si les sens et les souvenirs qu'il avait perdus depuis longtemps dans son état étaient aujourd'hui restaurés. Il venait de renaître.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un ange à la peau bleue se tenait devant lui, mâle mais semblait à la fois jeune et vieux, comme s'il était un homme bleu à tous les stades d'une vie complète, dans une forme unique et statique. Il portait une paire de chaînes d'une main et une clé dans l'autre, avec une épée posée à ses pieds.[PARAGRAPH:1]"N'importe qui dont l'âme n'est pas réclamée peut entrer dans le domaine de mon seigneur, mais ici vous resterez jusqu'à la fin de Création. Est-ce celà que vous désirez ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus était confus à cause de ses souvenirs ; il était de plus en plus difficile de se concentrer sur le présent à mesure que les souvenirs devenaient de plus en plus clairs, et il était de plus en plus difficile de dire s'il vivait cet instant ou un autre. Mais il parvint à répondre.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non, je suis venu pour observer. Pour me mettre au service d'Arawn sur Création s'il en avait l'usage."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Arawn se moque de Création, son domaine est ici ; laisse les autres seigneurs se quereller pour l'éphémère."[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus se concentra sur l'ange, il avait été bien entraîné pour cette tâche, au point de pouvoir ignorer la douleur et il utilisait ses compétences à ce moment précis. Pour le meilleur ou pour le pire, il voyait l'ange dans tous ses souvenirs et tenait cette même conversation dans chacun d'eux. Chacune des pensées de l'ange était mise en valeur dans différents pans de sa vie, les querelles dans les déclarations de guerre par les différentes factions religieuses, Création dans l'abondance de la vie, le bien et le mal, et le caractère éphémère dans la fin de tout ce qu'il avait un jour cru éternel.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Voici ceux qui jouent avec la mort comme s'ils étaient Arawn lui-même."[PARAGRAPH:1]L'age sourit. "Le monde souterrain est rempli de leurs victimes. Bénis ou maudits, le chemin de ces hommes est toujours le même, un multitude de morts pour atteindre leurs buts, ou les buts de ceux qui les commandent ; des vies sont écourtées tandis que les leurs sont prolongées au-delà de leur temps imparti. Si tu veux les châtier, et débarasser l'humanité de ceux qui la monopolisent, mon seigneur ne t'aidera pas, mais je le ferai."[PARAGRAPH:1]L'ange recula de l'épée à ses pieds et commanda à Rathus de s'en saisir. L'épée était plus légère que l'acier et possédait des runes vertes gravées sur la lame ; des runes étrangères à Rathus. Elle semblait réelle dans ses mains qui n'avaient rien touché depuis longtemps.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Châtiment ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non," répondit l'ange, "Équilibre. Voici la Lame des Morts. Elle frappera le plus fort contre ceux que les anges ont favorisé le plus. Ceux qui ne craignent plus la mort te craindront."[PARAGRAPH:1]L'épée en sa possession, Rathus fit demi-tour et franchit le portail. Les Scruteurs étaient prêts à le recevoir, lances levées. Rathus pensait qu'ils seraient toujours distraits par l'évasion. Il comprendrait plus tard que pratiquement un an s'était écoulé depuis qu'il avait franchi le portail.[PARAGRAPH:1]Une fois sorti du portail, le monde revint à la brume grise créée par nature ombreuse de Rathus. Seul le portail derrière lui et la Lame des Morts lui semblaient vraiment réelle. Les runes vertes de la lame brillèrent tandis qu'il levait l'épée et les Scruteurs se débandèrent devant lui.</French>
		<German>Die ehemaligen Elfen schreckten durch den Alarm hoch. Sogar die obsidianfarben gekleideten Verdammten unterbrachen ihren stoischen Blick in den Wirbel. Die ewige Nacht war vorbei, Licht zerriss den Schleier der Finsternis und blendete die Krieger, die nie zuvor das Sonnenlicht sahen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus schritt durch die ehemaligen Elfen, die sich am Rande der Stadt angesammelt hatten. Er schritt unbemerkt durch sie hindurch, kein Problem für einen Schatten, für den es schwierig war, selbst von den eigenen Vertrauten erkannt zu werden. Nachdem Jahrzehnte so vergingen, ist man nicht mehr sterblich, die Welt erscheint einem so geisterhaft wie man selbst für die Welt. Und man wird sehr aufmerksam für Dinge, die diesen Schleier durchdringen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Deshalb war Rathus hier, statt unter dem Licht. Seine Freunde, sofern sie ihn nicht längst vergessen hatten, flohen zu der Stadt, um Haerlond's Erlass zu entkommen. Sie kümmerten sich nun um ihr eigenes Schicksal; Rathus nutzte die Ablenkung um herauszufinden, was die Elfen den Palast des Malachite nannten, einen dunklen Tempel, auf dessen Spitze sich ein Portal befindet.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Verdammten waren sensibler als die meisten anderen und konnten so sogar bis in die ätherische Welt blicken, was ihnen ermöglichte alles zu beobachten, was durch das Portal kam. Sie hätten ihn kommen sehen, glücklicherweise sorgte die ganze Zauberei beim Kampf für genügend Ablenkung, so schlüpfte er durch das Portal. Er fühlte sich, als wenn er erwacht, seine Sinne und Erinnerungen, die vor langer Zeit verloren gingen, kehrten zurück. Er wurde wiedergeboren.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ein blauhäutiger Engel stand vor ihm, er war männlich und gleichzeitig jung und alt, so als wenn er jedes Stadium seines Lebens in einer unveränderten Form erlebt hatte. Er trug ein paar Ketten in der einen Hand und einen Schlüssel in der anderen, zu seinen Füßen lag ein Schwert.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Derjenige, dessen Seele rein ist, möge in das Gebiet meines Herrschers eintreten, aber dort wirst du bis zum Ende der Zeit verbleiben. Ist das dein Wunsch?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus war durch seine Gedanken verwirrt; es wurde immer schwieriger, sich auf die Gegenwart zu konzentrieren, als seine Erinnerungen immer lebendiger wurden, er wusste nicht, ob er sich in diesem Moment befand oder in einem anderen. Doch er schaffte es, zu antworten.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Nein, ich kam um nachzusehen. Um Arawn meine Dienste bei der Erschaffung anzubieten, falls er mich benötigt."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Arawn kümmert sich nicht um Erschaffung, sein Herrschaftsgebiet ist hier; er lässt die anderen Lords untereinander streiten."[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus konzentrierte sich auf den Engel, er wurde für diese Aufgabe gut trainiert, bis zu dem Punkt, Schmerzen zu ignorieren, und er nutzte diese Fähigkeiten nun. Auf gut Glück öffnete er sich für alle Erinnerungen des Engels, und unterhielt sich mit jeder von ihnen. Jede der Erinnerungen des Engels wurden durch verschiedene Teile seines Lebens hervorgehoben, die Zankereien bei der Kriegserklärung durch verschiedene religiöse Gruppierungen, die Erschaffung und der Untergang von Leben, gut und böse, und die Vergänglichkeit alldessen, was er als immerwährend angenommen hatte.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Es gibt welche, die den Tod ebenso verbreiten, als wären sie Arawn persönlich."[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Engel lächelte. "Die Unterwelt ist voll von ihren Opfern. Heilig oder nicht, der Weg dieser Männer ist immer der gleiche: Massen werden getötet, um deren Ziele durchzusetzen oder die Ziele, die sie leiten. Die Leben der Opfer verkürzten sich, während ihre Leben sich über die vorherbestimmte Zeit verlängerten. Falls du Rache an denen suchst, die die Menschheit dezimierten, wird dir mein Herrscher nicht helfen, aber ich werde dies tun."[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Engel tat einen Schritt vom Schwert zurück und gab ihm zu verstehen, dass er es aufnehmen solle. Die Klinge war leichter als Stahl und hatte grüne Runen eingeritzt, sie kamen Rathus unbekannt vor. Es fühlte sich real an für seine Hände, die lange nichts berührt hatten.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Vergeltung?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Nein", antwortete der Engel, "Ausgleich. Dies ist die Niedere Klinge; sie wird sich als am stärksten gegen diejenigen erweisen, die von den Engeln am meisten begünstigt wurden. Diejenigen, die den Tod nicht mehr fürchten, werden dich fürchten."[PARAGRAPH:1]Damit verließ Rathus das Portal.  Die Verdammten standen mit ihren Lanzen bereit, ihn in Empfang zu nehmen. Rathus nahm an, sie wurden noch immer abgelenkt, später würde er entdecken, dass fast ein Jahr vergangen war, seit er das Portal betrat.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wieder außerhalb des Portals gewann die Welt wieder ihren grauen Schleier. Nur das Portal hinter ihm und die Niedere Klinge erschienen ihm real. Die grünen Runen der Klinge glühten, als er das Schwert erhob und sich die Verdammten vor Entsetzen abwandten.</German>
		<Italian>The once-elves startled at the alarm. Even the obsidian-clad Perditioners broke their stoic watch to look toward the vortex. The ever-night was gone, light tore through the curtain that contained the veil and blinded the warriors who had never seen sunlight before.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus moved through the once-elves massed at the city's edge. He moved among them unnoticed, an easy feat for a shade who often found it more challenging to be recognized or remembered by those he knew. After decades spent like this, you become something other than mortal, the world is as much a ghost to you as you are a ghost to the world. And you pay close attention to anything that stands out from that haze. [PARAGRAPH:1]Which is why Rathus was here instead of under that light. His friends, if he hadn't slipped from their memory by now, fled the city to escape Haerlond's edict. Their fate was their own now; Rathus meant to use the distraction to check out what the elves called the Malachite Palace, a dark ziggurat with a portal at its summit. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Perditioners were more observant than most and could see even into the ethereal world, which allowed them to keep watch on anything coming through the portal. They might have seen him coming; fortunately, whatever magic was being used in the battle provided all the cover Rathus needed and he slipped up and through the portal. He felt as if he awoke, senses and memories that had long been lost to him by his state were now restored. He was reborn. [PARAGRAPH:1]A blue skinned angel stood before him, the angel was male but he appeared to be both young and old at once, as if he was a blue man in every stage of a full life, all in one unchanging form. He carried a set of chains in one hand and a key in the other, and there was a sword lying at his feet. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Any whose soul is unclaimed may enter my lord's domain, but there you will remain until creation is ended. Is that your desire?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus was confused by the memories; it was becoming harder to focus on the present as the memories become more and more vivid, harder to tell if he was in this moment or another. But he managed an answer. [PARAGRAPH:1]"No, I came to see. To pledge service to Arawn in creation if he would have use of me."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Arawn cares not for creation, his dominion is here; let the other lords bicker over the transient." [PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus focused on the Angel, he had been well trained for this task, even to the point of being able to ignore pain and he used those skills now. For better or worse, he perceived the angel in all of his memories and held this conversation with him in each of them. Each of the angel's thoughts was highlighted in different parts of his life, the bickering in the declaration of war by different religious factions, creation in the abundance of life, good and evil, and the transience in the eventual passing of everything he once considered permanent. [PARAGRAPH:1]"There are those that wield death as if they were Arawn himself."[PARAGRAPH:1]The angel smiled. "The underworld is full of their victims. Holy or unholy, the path of these men is always the same, masses killed to further their goals or the goals of those leading them; lives cut short while theirs are extended beyond the appointed time. If you seek retribution, to thin humanity of those that monopolize it, my lord will not help, but I will."[PARAGRAPH:1]The angel stepped back from the sword at his feet and motioned for Rathus to pick it up. The blade was lighter than steel and had green runes carved in its blade; the runes were unfamiliar to Rathus. It felt real to hands long separated from the sensation of touch. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Retribution?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"No," the angel answered, "Balance. This is the Nether Blade; it will strike strongest against those whom the angels have favored most. Those who no longer fear death will fear you." [PARAGRAPH:1]With that Rathus turned and left the portal. The Perditioners were set to receive him, pikes at the ready. Rathus assumed they would still be distracted by the escape; he would later discover that nearly a year had passed from the time he stepped into and out of the portal. [PARAGRAPH:1]Once outside the portal the world reverted back to the grey haze Rathus's shade nature made it. Only the portal behind him and the Nether Blade seemed truly real to his senses. The blade's green runes glowed as he raised the sword and the Perditioners shrunk back before him.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The once-elves startled at the alarm. Even the obsidian-clad Perditioners broke their stoic watch to look toward the vortex. The ever-night was gone, light tore through the curtain that contained the veil and blinded the warriors who had never seen sunlight before.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus moved through the once-elves massed at the city's edge. He moved among them unnoticed, an easy feat for a shade who often found it more challenging to be recognized or remembered by those he knew. After decades spent like this, you become something other than mortal, the world is as much a ghost to you as you are a ghost to the world. And you pay close attention to anything that stands out from that haze. [PARAGRAPH:1]Which is why Rathus was here instead of under that light. His friends, if he hadn't slipped from their memory by now, fled the city to escape Haerlond's edict. Their fate was their own now; Rathus meant to use the distraction to check out what the elves called the Malachite Palace, a dark ziggurat with a portal at its summit. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Perditioners were more observant than most and could see even into the ethereal world, which allowed them to keep watch on anything coming through the portal. They might have seen him coming; fortunately, whatever magic was being used in the battle provided all the cover Rathus needed and he slipped up and through the portal. He felt as if he awoke, senses and memories that had long been lost to him by his state were now restored. He was reborn. [PARAGRAPH:1]A blue skinned angel stood before him, the angel was male but he appeared to be both young and old at once, as if he was a blue man in every stage of a full life, all in one unchanging form. He carried a set of chains in one hand and a key in the other, and there was a sword lying at his feet. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Any whose soul is unclaimed may enter my lord's domain, but there you will remain until creation is ended. Is that your desire?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus was confused by the memories; it was becoming harder to focus on the present as the memories become more and more vivid, harder to tell if he was in this moment or another. But he managed an answer. [PARAGRAPH:1]"No, I came to see. To pledge service to Arawn in creation if he would have use of me."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Arawn cares not for creation, his dominion is here; let the other lords bicker over the transient." [PARAGRAPH:1]Rathus focused on the Angel, he had been well trained for this task, even to the point of being able to ignore pain and he used those skills now. For better or worse, he perceived the angel in all of his memories and held this conversation with him in each of them. Each of the angel's thoughts was highlighted in different parts of his life, the bickering in the declaration of war by different religious factions, creation in the abundance of life, good and evil, and the transience in the eventual passing of everything he once considered permanent. [PARAGRAPH:1]"There are those that wield death as if they were Arawn himself."[PARAGRAPH:1]The angel smiled. "The underworld is full of their victims. Holy or unholy, the path of these men is always the same, masses killed to further their goals or the goals of those leading them; lives cut short while theirs are extended beyond the appointed time. If you seek retribution, to thin humanity of those that monopolize it, my lord will not help, but I will."[PARAGRAPH:1]The angel stepped back from the sword at his feet and motioned for Rathus to pick it up. The blade was lighter than steel and had green runes carved in its blade; the runes were unfamiliar to Rathus. It felt real to hands long separated from the sensation of touch. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Retribution?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"No," the angel answered, "Balance. This is the Nether Blade; it will strike strongest against those whom the angels have favored most. Those who no longer fear death will fear you." [PARAGRAPH:1]With that Rathus turned and left the portal. The Perditioners were set to receive him, pikes at the ready. Rathus assumed they would still be distracted by the escape; he would later discover that nearly a year had passed from the time he stepped into and out of the portal. [PARAGRAPH:1]Once outside the portal the world reverted back to the grey haze Rathus's shade nature made it. Only the portal behind him and the Nether Blade seemed truly real to his senses. The blade's green runes glowed as he raised the sword and the Perditioners shrunk back before him.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RATHUS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Rathus Denmora has the same special abilities as the Sidar Ghosts : The ability to become invisible until he attacks, and the Marksman promotion for targeting the weakest unit in a stack. He does not have a low defensive strength, though, and he starts with a unique piece of equipment, the Netherblade, which gives a large bonus against other hero units.</English>
		<French>Rathus Denmora possède les mêmes capacités spéciales que les fantômes sidars : la capacité à devenir invisible avant d'attaquer, et la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_MARKSMAN]Tireur d'Élite[\LINK] pour viser l'unité la plus faible d'une pile. Il n'est cependant pas faible en défense et commence avec un équipement unique, la [LINK=PROMOTION_NETHER_BLADE]Lame des Morts[\LINK], qui lui confère de gros bonus face aux unités héroïques.</French>
		<German>Rathus Denmora hat die gleichen Spezialfertigkeiten wie die Geister der Sidar : Die Fähigkeit unsichtbar zu sein bis er angreift und Scharfschützenbeförderung, die es ihm erlaubt die schwächste Einheit eines Verbandes anzugreifen. Er hat keinen niedrigeren Verteidigungswert und startet mit einem einzigartigen Ausrüstungsstück, der Netherklinge, die ihm einen großen Bonus gegen andere Helden verschafft.</German>
		<Italian>Rathus Denmora has the same special abilities as the Sidar Ghosts : The ability to become invisible until he attacks, and the Marksman promotion for targeting the weakest unit in a stack. He does not have a low defensive strength, though, and he starts with a unique piece of equipment, the Netherblade, which gives a large bonus against other hero units.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rathus Denmora has the same special abilities as the Sidar Ghosts : The ability to become invisible until he attacks, and the Marksman promotion for targeting the weakest unit in a stack. He does not have a low defensive strength, though, and he starts with a unique piece of equipment, the Netherblade, which gives a large bonus against other hero units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RATHUS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>Rathus Denmora has the same special abilities as the Sidar Ghosts : The ability to become invisible until he attacks, and the Marksman promotion for targeting the weakest unit in a stack. He does not have a low defensive strength, though, and he starts with a unique piece of equipment, the Netherblade, which gives a large bonus against other hero units.</English>
		<French>Rathus Denmora possède les mêmes capacités spéciales que les fantômes sidars : la capacité à devenir invisible avant d'attaquer, et la promotion Tireur d'Élite pour viser l'unité la plus faible d'une pile. Il n'est cependant pas faible en défense et commence avec un équipement unique, la Lame des Morts, qui lui confère de gros bonus face aux unités héroïques.</French>
		<German>Rathus Denmora hat die gleichen Spezialfertigkeiten wie die Geister der Sidar : Die Fähigkeit unsichtbar zu sein bis er angreift und Scharfschützenbeförderung, die es ihm erlaubt die schwächste Einheit eines Verbandes anzugreifen. Er hat keinen niedrigeren Verteidigungswert und startet mit einem einzigartigen Ausrüstungsstück, der Netherklinge, die ihm einen großen Bonus gegen andere Helden verschafft.</German>
		<Italian>Rathus Denmora has the same special abilities as the Sidar Ghosts : The ability to become invisible until he attacks, and the Marksman promotion for targeting the weakest unit in a stack. He does not have a low defensive strength, though, and he starts with a unique piece of equipment, the Netherblade, which gives a large bonus against other hero units.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rathus Denmora has the same special abilities as the Sidar Ghosts : The ability to become invisible until he attacks, and the Marksman promotion for targeting the weakest unit in a stack. He does not have a low defensive strength, though, and he starts with a unique piece of equipment, the Netherblade, which gives a large bonus against other hero units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SEVERED_SOUL</Tag>
		<English>Severed Soul</English>
		<French>Fragment d'Âme</French>
		<German>Losgelöste Seele</German>
		<Italian>Severed Soul</Italian>
		<Spanish>Severed Soul</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SEVERED_SOUL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Do you not feel it?"[NEWLINE]  "Your nerves are getting the better of you, girl"[NEWLINE]"No, there is something here. Watching..."[NEWLINE]  He snorted, then coughed, then choked on blood as it entered his lungs through the suddenly appearing puncture wound in his chest. The Sidar man stepped out from behind him, where mere seconds ago naught but air could have been seen. </English>
		<French>"Est-ce que tu le ressens ?"[NEWLINE]"Tu as les nerfs à vif ma fille"[NEWLINE]"Non, il y a quelque chose ici. Qui observe..."[NEWLINE]Il grogna, puis toussa, puis s'étouffa dans du sang tandis qu'il entrait dans ses poumons par la blessure béante apparue soudainement sur son torse. Le sidar s'écarta de son dos, là où il n'y avait rien de visible quelques secondes auparavant.</French>
		<German>"Fühlst du es nicht?"[NEWLINE]"Deine Nerven liegen blank, Mädchen."[NEWLINE]"Nein, hier ist etwas. Es beobachtet ..."[NEWLINE]Er schneufzte sich, dann hustete er und dann spuckte er Blut. Es sickerte in die Lunge, durch eine kleine Stichwunde in seiner Brust, die nach und nach sichtbar wurde. Der Sidar kam hinter ihm hervor, von dort, wo einen Sekundenbruchteil zuvor nichts als kalte Luft gewesen war.</German>
		<Italian>"Do you not feel it?"[NEWLINE]  "Your nerves are getting the better of you, girl"[NEWLINE]"No, there is something here. Watching..."[NEWLINE]  He snorted, then coughed, then choked on blood as it entered his lungs through the suddenly appearing puncture wound in his chest. The Sidar man stepped out from behind him, where mere seconds ago naught but air could have been seen. </Italian>
		<Spanish>"Do you not feel it?"[NEWLINE]  "Your nerves are getting the better of you, girl"[NEWLINE]"No, there is something here. Watching..."[NEWLINE]  He snorted, then coughed, then choked on blood as it entered his lungs through the suddenly appearing puncture wound in his chest. The Sidar man stepped out from behind him, where mere seconds ago naught but air could have been seen. </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SEVERED_SOUL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>A Severed Soul is completely invisible and may travel independantly of it's owner. The owner may be called at will to the location of the Severed Soul, allowing the Sidar to move units quickly at short notice provided the Severed Soul is well placed.</English>
		<French>Un Fragment d'Âme est totalement invisible et peut se déplacer indépendamment de son propriétaire. Le propriétaire peut être invoqué à volonté sur la place du Fragment d'Âme, permettant aux sidarae de déplacer rapidement et soudainement ses unités, pourvu que le Fragment d'Âme soit bien placé.</French>
		<German>Eine Losgelöste Seele ist völlig unsichtbar und kann sich unabhängig von ihrem Besitzer bewegen. Dieser kann bei Bedarf zu dem Standort der Losgelösten Seele gerufen werden, was es den Sidar erlaubt, Einheiten schnell und vor allem unentdeckt zu verschieben, vorausgesetzt, die Losgelöste Seele ist gut platziert.</German>
		<Italian>A Severed Soul is completely invisible and may travel independantly of it's owner. The owner may be called at will to the location of the Severed Soul, allowing the Sidar to move units quickly at short notice provided the Severed Soul is well placed.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A Severed Soul is completely invisible and may travel independantly of it's owner. The owner may be called at will to the location of the Severed Soul, allowing the Sidar to move units quickly at short notice provided the Severed Soul is well placed.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRACKLESS</Tag>
		<English>Trackless</English>
		<French>Intraçable</French>
		<German>Spurloser</German>
		<Italian>Trackless</Italian>
		<Spanish>Trackless</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SOUL_DIVIDER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Allows a Sidar recon unit to sever his soul, allowing easy and safe scouting.</English>
		<French>Allows a Sidar recon unit to sever his soul, allowing easy and safe scouting.</French>
		<German>Erlaubt es einem Sidar, sich von seiner Seele zu trenne, wodurch einfaches und sicheres Aufklären möglich wird.</German>
		<Italian>Allows a Sidar recon unit to sever his soul, allowing easy and safe scouting.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Allows a Sidar recon unit to sever his soul, allowing easy and safe scouting.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SOUL_DIVIDER</Tag>
		<English>Soul Divider</English>
		<French>Soul Divider</French>
		<German>Seelentrenner</German>
		<Italian>Soul Divider</Italian>
		<Spanish>Soul Divider</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
