<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - Units -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAZATL_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Mazatl</English>
		<French>mazatl:mazatl:mazatli:mazatli</French>
		<German>Mazatl'sch:Mazatl'schen:Mazatl'sche</German>
		<Italian>Mazatl</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mazatl</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAZATL_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Mazatl</English>
		<French>Mazatl</French>
		<German>Reich der Mazatl</German>
		<Italian>Mazatl</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mazatl</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAZATL_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Mazatl</English>
		<French>Mazatli</French>
		<German>Mazatl</German>
		<Italian>Mazatl</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mazatl</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAZATL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Mazatl are part of the lizardman race that has existed since the Age of Dragons. They spent much of the Age of Magic separated from the rest of Erebus, deep in the jungles and swampland that proved inhospitable to other races, but allowed the lizardmen to thrive in their pyramid-cities. As the Age of Ice dawned, the jungles were all but destroyed and the swampland froze. Many of the lizardmen died in a panicked exodus to try to escape the bitter cold - their reliance on warm climates meant that they were especially scarred by Mulcarn's entry into creation. The group that would later become the Mazatl took refuge in caves near an inactive volcano, where the heat from the molten earth itself kept them alive. As the Age of Ice passed, the lizards returned to the surface and rebuilt their civilization in the jungle. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Whilst the old civilization worshipped a whole pantheon of gods however, the reborn Mazatl civilization were more focused. They were eternally grateful to Kalshekk - their god of Earth - for protecting them during the Age of Ice, but the followers of Omorr - their god of foresight and learning - gained significant attention when their seers foretold that the world had not been saved from the influences of the Godswar. The icy reign of Mulcarn had been broken, but a time of Fire and Shadow lay ahead, in which the world would suffer the power of Agares himself. The Mazatl have chosen to stand against this fate and seek to avert Armageddon.</English>
		<French>Les Mazatl font partie des hommes-lézards, les sauriens qui existent depuis l'Âge des Dragons. Ils ont passé la majeure partie de l'Âge de la Magie séparés du reste d'Erebus, loin dans les jungles et les marais qui se sont révélés invivables pour les autres races, mais qui ont permis aux hommes-lézards de prospérer dans leurs villes-pyramides. Au commencement de l'Âge de Glace, les jungles furent toutes détruites et les marais gelés. Nombre d'hommes-lézards moururent dans un exode paniqué pour tenter de fuir le froid de plus en plus mordant. Leur dépendance à la chaleur fit qu'ils furent particulièrement touchés par l'arrivée de Mulcarn dans la création. Le groupe qui deviendrait plus tard les Mazatals trouva refuge dans des grottes près d'un volcan en sommeil, où la chaleur de la lave elle-même les garda en vie. À la fin de l'Âge de Glace, les lézards retournèrent à la surface et recosntruirent leur civilisation dans la jungle.[PARAGRAPH:1]Cependant, alors que l'ancienne civilisation révérait un panthéon complet de dieux, les Mazatl ressuscités étaient plus circonspects. Ils seraient éternellement reconnaissants envers Kalshekk, leur dieu de la Terre, de sa protection durant l'Âge de Glace, mais les adeptes d'Omorr, leur dieu de la prévoyance et de l'apprentissage, sont devenus bien plus écoutés depuis que leurs prophètes annoncèrent que le monde n'a pas été sauvé des influences de la Guerre des Dieux. Le règne glacé de Mulcarn a été brisé, mais un temps de Feu et d'Ombres se profile, lors duquel le monde pourrait subir le pouvoir d'Agares lui-même. Les Mazatl ont choisi de s'opposer à ce destin et cherchent à empêcher l'Armageddon.</French>
		<German>The Mazatl are part of the lizardman race that has existed since the Age of Dragons. They spent much of the Age of Magic separated from the rest of Erebus, deep in the jungles and swampland that proved inhospitable to other races, but allowed the lizardmen to thrive in their pyramid-cities. As the Age of Ice dawned, the jungles were all but destroyed and the swampland froze. Many of the lizardmen died in a panicked exodus to try to escape the bitter cold - their reliance on warm climates meant that they were especially scarred by Mulcarn's entry into creation. The group that would later become the Mazatl took refuge in caves near an inactive volcano, where the heat from the molten earth itself kept them alive. As the Age of Ice passed, the lizards returned to the surface and rebuilt their civilization in the jungle. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Whilst the old civilization worshipped a whole pantheon of gods however, the reborn Mazatl civilization were more focused. They were eternally grateful to Kalshekk - their god of Earth - for protecting them during the Age of Ice, but the followers of Omorr - their god of foresight and learning - gained significant attention when their seers foretold that the world had not been saved from the influences of the Godswar. The icy reign of Mulcarn had been broken, but a time of Fire and Shadow lay ahead, in which the world would suffer the power of Agares himself. The Mazatl have chosen to stand against this fate and seek to avert Armageddon.</German>
		<Italian>I Mazatl fanno parte di una razza lucertoloide che esiste sin dall'Era dei Draghi. Hanno passato la maggior parte dell'Era della Magia separati dal resto di Erebus all'interno di giungle e paludi che risultavano inabitabili dalle altre razze, ma che permisero ai lucertoloidi di prosperare nelle loro città piramidali. All'inizio dell'Era del Ghiaccio le loro giungle vennerò quasi distrutte completamente, e le loro paludi si ghiacciarono. Molti lucertoloidi morirono durante un esodo dettato dalla paura mentre cercavano di sfuggire al freddo, a causa della loro dipendenza dai climi caldi l'arrivo di Mulcarn nella creazione li colpì più duramente degli altri. Il gruppo che sarebbe diventato in seguito i Mazatl trovò rifugio in delle caverne vicino a un vulcano inattivo, nelle quali il calore proveniente dalla terra stessa li tenne in vita. Quando l'Era del Ghiaccio passò i lucertoloidi tornarono in superfice e ricostruirono la loro civiltà nella giungla. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mentre la vecchia civiltà venerava un intero pantheon di dei la civiltà Mazatl fu invece più focalizzata. Erano eternamente grati a Kalshekk, il loro dio della Terra, per averli protetti durante l'Era del Ghiaccio, ma i seguaci di Omorr, il loro dio della lungimiranza e apprendimento ottennerò un'attenzione significativa quando i loro veggenti preannunciarono che il mondo non era ancora stato salvato dall'influenza della Guerra degli Dei. Il dominio di ghiaccio di Mulcarn era stato spezzato, ma un periodo di Fuoco e Ombra stava arrivando, nel quale il mondo avrebbe sofferto il potere di Agares stesso. I Mazatl hanno scelto di ergersi contro questo destino, e cercano di impedire l'Armageddon.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Mazatl are part of the lizardman race that has existed since the Age of Dragons. They spent much of the Age of Magic separated from the rest of Erebus, deep in the jungles and swampland that proved inhospitable to other races, but allowed the lizardmen to thrive in their pyramid-cities. As the Age of Ice dawned, the jungles were all but destroyed and the swampland froze. Many of the lizardmen died in a panicked exodus to try to escape the bitter cold - their reliance on warm climates meant that they were especially scarred by Mulcarn's entry into creation. The group that would later become the Mazatl took refuge in caves near an inactive volcano, where the heat from the molten earth itself kept them alive. As the Age of Ice passed, the lizards returned to the surface and rebuilt their civilization in the jungle. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Whilst the old civilization worshipped a whole pantheon of gods however, the reborn Mazatl civilization were more focused. They were eternally grateful to Kalshekk - their god of Earth - for protecting them during the Age of Ice, but the followers of Omorr - their god of foresight and learning - gained significant attention when their seers foretold that the world had not been saved from the influences of the Godswar. The icy reign of Mulcarn had been broken, but a time of Fire and Shadow lay ahead, in which the world would suffer the power of Agares himself. The Mazatl have chosen to stand against this fate and seek to avert Armageddon.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HIANTHROGH</Tag>
		<English>Hianthrogh</English>
		<French>Hianthrogh</French>
		<German>Hianthrogh</German>
		<Italian>Hianthrogh</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hianthrogh</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MAZATL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Hianthrogh stood upon the highest level of the temple-palace and looked to the burning horizon. The Sheaim approached Nochtli in force. Barbaric warriors, priests of dark power and otherworldly creatures filled their ranks. Within hours they would breach the wall of jungle and be upon the Mazatl capital. Smoke filled the air, as the sense of despair filled the hearts of the Mazatl. Below him, the warriors of Nochtli prepared a desperate defence. They could not hope to stand for long, but they would stand for as long as they could.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The shards of Coatlann - one of their most important symbols - had been transported away to another city. Preparations were being made for a second stand there, but there was no time. Unless Nochtli could stand, the Sheaim would sweep through the Mazatl empire. There was little chance to defend the city however, as the Sheaim had constructed great machines of war and wielded magic that could strike down their defenders whilst they stood upon the tall walls.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]No, the enemy knew how to destroy cities well enough. Nochtli could not be defended. If defense is not possible and retreat unthinkable, the only recourse is... [PARAGRAPH]"We shall attack them as they approach" stated Hianthrogh to the temple-guards closest to him. "Carry my words to the warriors, abandon the defense preparations, set scouts upon the trails and prepare to ambush the Sheaim forces as they approach. We shall fight them in the burning jungle and they shall know of our resolve."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Few of Hianthrogh's warriors survived that day. The jungle and the city of Nochtli burned for days afterwards, but the toll exacted upon the Sheaim gave Tebryn Arbandi reason to pause. He had conquered a city stuck amongst deep swamp and charred jungle, which provided him little benefit. In exchange he had expended a large portion of his southern forces. His forces already depleted, he could expect the next assault against the lizards to be even more costly. The cost outweighed the benefit - for now, the lizards could keep their swamp. There were greater foes that were easier to topple.</English>
		<French>Hianthrogh se trouvait à l'étage le plus haut du temple-palais et regardait l'horizon flamboyant. Les Sheaims s'approchaient en force de Nochtli. Guerriers barbares, prêtres de sombres pouvoirs et créatures indescriptibles emplissaient leurs rangs. C'était une question d'heures avant qu'ils franchissent la lisière de la jungle et parviennent à la capitale Mazatl. La fumée emplissait l'air, tandis que le désespoir emplissait les c&#156;urs des Mazatls. Sous ses pieds, les guerriers de Nochtli préparaient une défense désespérée. Ils ne pouvaient pas espérer résister longtemps, mais ils le feraient aussi longtemps que possible.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les Ossements de Coatlann, un de leurs symboles les plus importants, avait été transférés dans une autre ville. Les préparatifs étaient en cours pour une deuxième ligne de défense là-bas, mais il n'était plus temps. À moins que Nochtli tienne, les Sheaims se répendraient dans tout l'empire Mazatl. Il y avait cependant peu d'espoir de défendre la ville, car les Sheaims avaient construit de formidables machines de guerre et possédaient une magie qui pourrait terrasser les défenseurs tandis qu'ils se tiendraient les hautes murailles.[PARAGRAPH:1]Non, l'ennemi savait suffisamment bien comment détruire des villes. Nochtli ne pouvait plus être défendue. Si la défense était impossible et la retraite inenvisageable, le dernier moyen envisageable était...[PARAGRAPH:1]"Nous devons les attaquer alors qu'ils approchent" ordonna Hianthrogh aux gardes du temple les plus proches de lui. "Transmettez mes ordres aux guerriers, abandonnez les préparatifs de la défense, dépêchez des éclaireurs sur les pistes et préparez des embuscades des forces Sheaim lors de leur approche. Nous devons les combattre dans la jungle en flammes et ils doivent expérimenter notre détermination."[PARAGRAPH:1]Peu de guerriers de Hianthrogh survécurent à ce jour. La jungle et la ville de Nochtli brûlèrent pendant des jours après ça, mais le prix extorqué aux Sheaims donna à Tebryn Arbandi une raison de faire une pause. Il avait conquis une ville coincée entre un marais profond et une jungle brûlée, qui ne lui apportait rien. En échange, il avait consommé une grande partie de ses forces du sud. Ses forces déjà exsangues, il se doutait que le prochain assaut contre les lézards serait encore plus coûteux. Le prix dépassa le gain. Pour aujourd'hui, les lézards pouvaient garder leur marais. Ily avait des ennemis plus degeraux qui seraient plus faciles à abattre.</French>
		<German>Hianthrogh stood upon the highest level of the temple-palace and looked to the burning horizon. The Sheaim approached Nochtli in force. Barbaric warriors, priests of dark power and otherworldly creatures filled their ranks. Within hours they would breach the wall of jungle and be upon the Mazatl capital. Smoke filled the air, as the sense of despair filled the hearts of the Mazatl. Below him, the warriors of Nochtli prepared a desperate defence. They could not hope to stand for long, but they would stand for as long as they could.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The shards of Coatlann - one of their most important symbols - had been transported away to another city. Preparations were being made for a second stand there, but there was no time. Unless Nochtli could stand, the Sheaim would sweep through the Mazatl empire. There was little chance to defend the city however, as the Sheaim had constructed great machines of war and wielded magic that could strike down their defenders whilst they stood upon the tall walls.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]No, the enemy knew how to destroy cities well enough. Nochtli could not be defended. If defense is not possible and retreat unthinkable, the only recourse is... [PARAGRAPH]"We shall attack them as they approach" stated Hianthrogh to the temple-guards closest to him. "Carry my words to the warriors, abandon the defense preparations, set scouts upon the trails and prepare to ambush the Sheaim forces as they approach. We shall fight them in the burning jungle and they shall know of our resolve."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Few of Hianthrogh's warriors survived that day. The jungle and the city of Nochtli burned for days afterwards, but the toll exacted upon the Sheaim gave Tebryn Arbandi reason to pause. He had conquered a city stuck amongst deep swamp and charred jungle, which provided him little benefit. In exchange he had expended a large portion of his southern forces. His forces already depleted, he could expect the next assault against the lizards to be even more costly. The cost outweighed the benefit - for now, the lizards could keep their swamp. There were greater foes that were easier to topple.</German>
		<Italian>Hianthrogh stava sul livello più alto del tempio-palazzo, e osservava l'orizzonte infuocato. Gli Sheaim si stavano avvicinando a Nochtli numerosi. Guerrieri barbari, sacerdoti di poteri oscuri e creature di altri mondi componevano i loro ranghi. In poche ore avrebbero superato il muro della giungla e avrebbero raggiunto la capitale Mazatl. Del fumo riempiva l'aria, mentre una sensazione di disperazione riempiva i cuori dei Mazatl. Sotto di lui i guerrieri di Nochtli preparavano una difesa disperata. Non potevano sperare di resistere a lungo, ma avrebbero resistito il più a lungo possibile.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Le schegge di Coatlann, uno dei loro simboli più importanti, erano state trasportate in un'altra città. Erano stati fatti dei preparativi per una seconda difesa li, ma non c'era tempo. A meno che Nochtli resisteva gli Sheaim avrebbero avuto via libera su tutto l'impero Mazatl. Però le probabilità di difendere la città erano scarse, visto che gli Sheaim avevano costruito grandi macchine da guerra e utilizzavano magie che potevano eliminare i difensori dalle alte mura.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]No, il nemico sapeva bene come distruggere le città. Nochtli non poteva essere difesa. Se la difesa non era possibile e la ritirata è impensabile, l'unica soluzione è... [PARAGRAPH]"Li attaccheremo mentre si avvicinano" disse Hianthrogh alle guardie del tempio più vicine a lui. "Spargete la voce tra i guerrieri, smettete di preparare le difese, mandate delle vedette sui sentieri e preparatevi a fare un'imboscata alle forze Sheaim quando si avvicinano. Li affronteremo nella giungla in fiamme e conosceranno la nostra determinazione".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Pochi furono i guerrieri di Hianthrogh che sopravvissero quel giorno. La giungla e la città di Nochtli bruciarono per giorni, ma le perdite inflitte agli Sheaim spinsero Tebryn Arbandi a fare una pausa. Aveva conquistato una città in mezzo a paludi profonde e a una giungla bruciata, il che gli dava scarso beneficio. In cambio aveva perso una larga porzione delle sue forze meridionali. Con le sue forze in tale stato, si aspettava che l'assalto successivo contro i lucertoloidi sarebbe stato ancora più costoso. Il prezzo superava i benefici, per ora i lucertoloidi potevano tenersi la loro palude. Vi erano nemici più grandi che erano più facili da far cadere.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hianthrogh stood upon the highest level of the temple-palace and looked to the burning horizon. The Sheaim approached Nochtli in force. Barbaric warriors, priests of dark power and otherworldly creatures filled their ranks. Within hours they would breach the wall of jungle and be upon the Mazatl capital. Smoke filled the air, as the sense of despair filled the hearts of the Mazatl. Below him, the warriors of Nochtli prepared a desperate defence. They could not hope to stand for long, but they would stand for as long as they could.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The shards of Coatlann - one of their most important symbols - had been transported away to another city. Preparations were being made for a second stand there, but there was no time. Unless Nochtli could stand, the Sheaim would sweep through the Mazatl empire. There was little chance to defend the city however, as the Sheaim had constructed great machines of war and wielded magic that could strike down their defenders whilst they stood upon the tall walls.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]No, the enemy knew how to destroy cities well enough. Nochtli could not be defended. If defense is not possible and retreat unthinkable, the only recourse is... [PARAGRAPH]"We shall attack them as they approach" stated Hianthrogh to the temple-guards closest to him. "Carry my words to the warriors, abandon the defense preparations, set scouts upon the trails and prepare to ambush the Sheaim forces as they approach. We shall fight them in the burning jungle and they shall know of our resolve."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Few of Hianthrogh's warriors survived that day. The jungle and the city of Nochtli burned for days afterwards, but the toll exacted upon the Sheaim gave Tebryn Arbandi reason to pause. He had conquered a city stuck amongst deep swamp and charred jungle, which provided him little benefit. In exchange he had expended a large portion of his southern forces. His forces already depleted, he could expect the next assault against the lizards to be even more costly. The cost outweighed the benefit - for now, the lizards could keep their swamp. There were greater foes that were easier to topple.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FOUND_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN</Tag>
		<English>Found Order of the Wyvern</English>
		<French>Fonder l'Ordre des Wyvernes</French>
		<German>Orden der Wyvern gründen</German>
		<Italian>Fonda Ordine della Viverna</Italian>
		<Spanish>Found Order of the Wyvern</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FOUND_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Can only be cast once all twelve Wyvern Guardians have been appointed</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Ne peut être lancé qu'après avoir créé les douze Wyvernes Gardiennes</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Zauber kann nur gewirkt werden, wenn alle 12 Wyvern Wächter ernannt worden sind.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Può essere lanciata solo dopo che tutti i 12 Guardiani della Viverna sono stati designati</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Can only be cast once all twelve Wyvern Guardians have been appointed</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FOUND_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>It was time. The twelve Wyvern Guardians strode out into the streets of Tlacotl, walking with purpose toward the newly constructed palace. [NEWLINE]"We seek audience with Lord Hianthrogh" stated the foremost warrior, "He will see us". The guard looked unsure for a second, before nodding his consent. The party was flanked by twice their number in armoured lizards as they ascended the stone stairs on the exterior of the palace, then onto the steps inlaid with gold that made up the last stretch of the climb. Finally, they reached the top and were ushered into the council chamber of Hianthrogh.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"I know why you have come and I must agree. Though I still mourn the loss of Nochtli, it is time that we put aside that which has gone before and stand once again in the path of the Sheaim and their allies." The old lizard paused for a second, peering intently at the faces before him. "Do you honestly believe that it can be done?"[NEWLINE]One of the Wyvern Guardians stepped forward and offered a scroll to Hianthrogh. "It can". Hianthrogh studied the scroll for a long moment, before nodding his reply.[NEWLINE]"Yes, I believe it can. Establish your order in every city, train those warriors you deem worthy, prepare our nation for what lies ahead."</English>
		<French>L'heure était venue. Les douze Wyvernes Gardiennes se déplaçaient à grandes enjambées dans les rues de Tlacotl, marchant à dessein vers le palais nouvellement construit.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Nous demandons audience avec le seigneur Hianthrogh" énonca le premier guerrier, "Il nous recevra". Le garde hésita une seconde, avant d'acquiescer son consentement. Le groupe était flanqué du double de guerriers sauriens en armure tandis qu'ils gravissaient les escaliers de pierre à l'extérieur du palais, puis les marches incrustées d'or qui constituaient la partie finale de l'ascension. Finalement ils atteignirent le haut et furent introduits dans la chambre du conseil de Hianthrogh.[PARAGRAPH:2]"Je sais pourquoi vous êtes venus et je ne peux qu'être d'accord. Même si je porte toujours le deuil de la perte de Nochtli, il est temps de mettre le passé de côté et se dresser à nouveau sur le chemin des Sheaims et de leurs alliés." Le vieux saurien fait une pause, posant son regard sur chacun des visages devant lui. "Pouvez-vous honnêtement croire que c'est possible ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Une des Wyvernes Gardiennes fit un pas en avant et tendit un parchemin à Hianthrogh. "C'est possible." Hianthrogh étudia le parchemin pendnat un long moment, avant de répondre d'un signe de tête.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oui, je crois que c'est possible. Implantez votre ordre dans chaque ville, entraînez les guerriers que vous estimez dignes, préparez notre nation à ce qui va suivre."</French>
		<German>It was time. The twelve Wyvern Guardians strode out into the streets of Tlacotl, walking with purpose toward the newly constructed palace. [NEWLINE]"We seek audience with Lord Hianthrogh" stated the foremost warrior, "He will see us". The guard looked unsure for a second, before nodding his consent. The party was flanked by twice their number in armoured lizards as they ascended the stone stairs on the exterior of the palace, then onto the steps inlaid with gold that made up the last stretch of the climb. Finally, they reached the top and were ushered into the council chamber of Hianthrogh.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"I know why you have come and I must agree. Though I still mourn the loss of Nochtli, it is time that we put aside that which has gone before and stand once again in the path of the Sheaim and their allies." The old lizard paused for a second, peering intently at the faces before him. "Do you honestly believe that it can be done?"[NEWLINE]One of the Wyvern Guardians stepped forward and offered a scroll to Hianthrogh. "It can". Hianthrogh studied the scroll for a long moment, before nodding his reply.[NEWLINE]"Yes, I believe it can. Establish your order in every city, train those warriors you deem worthy, prepare our nation for what lies ahead."</German>
		<Italian>Era il momento. I docici Guardiani della Viverna uscirono per le strade di Tlacotl, dirigiendosi verso il palazzo appena costruito. [NEWLINE]"Cerchiamo udienza con Lord Hianthrogh" disse l'eminente guerriero, "Lui ci accoglierà". La guardia sembrò insicura per un secondo prima di annuire. Il gruppo fu affiancato da un numero doppio del loro di lucertoloidi corazzati mentre salivano le scale esterne del palazzo, e poi sui gradini intarsiati con oro nell'ultima parte della salita. Infine raggiunsero la cima, e entrarono nella camera consiliare di Hianthrogh.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"So perché siete venuti e sono d'accordo. Anche se io piango ancora la perdita di Nochtli, è giunto il momento di mettere da parte ciò che è passato e ergersi di nuovo contro gli Sheaim e i loro alleati". Il vecchio lucertoloide fece una pausa, scrutando attentamente i volti davanti a lui. "Credete onestamente che si possa fare?"[NEWLINE]Uno dei Guardiani della Viverna fece un passo avanti e offrì una pergamena a Hianthrogh. "Può essere fatto". Hianthrogh studiò la pergamena per un pò, prima di annuire in risposta.[NEWLINE]"Si, credo che si possa fare. Stabilite il vostro ordine in ogni città, addestrate i guerrieri che ritenete degni, preparate la nostra nazione per quello che la attende".</Italian>
		<Spanish>It was time. The twelve Wyvern Guardians strode out into the streets of Tlacotl, walking with purpose toward the newly constructed palace. [NEWLINE]"We seek audience with Lord Hianthrogh" stated the foremost warrior, "He will see us". The guard looked unsure for a second, before nodding his consent. The party was flanked by twice their number in armoured lizards as they ascended the stone stairs on the exterior of the palace, then onto the steps inlaid with gold that made up the last stretch of the climb. Finally, they reached the top and were ushered into the council chamber of Hianthrogh.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]"I know why you have come and I must agree. Though I still mourn the loss of Nochtli, it is time that we put aside that which has gone before and stand once again in the path of the Sheaim and their allies." The old lizard paused for a second, peering intently at the faces before him. "Do you honestly believe that it can be done?"[NEWLINE]One of the Wyvern Guardians stepped forward and offered a scroll to Hianthrogh. "It can". Hianthrogh studied the scroll for a long moment, before nodding his reply.[NEWLINE]"Yes, I believe it can. Establish your order in every city, train those warriors you deem worthy, prepare our nation for what lies ahead."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FOUND_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Founding the Order of the Wyvern provides a free [LINK=BUILDING_DRAGON_MONASTARY]Wyvern Monastry[\LINK] in every city, as well as reducing global war-weariness as the Mazatl people prepare for the inevitable conflict ahead.</English>
		<French>Fonder l'Ordre des Wyvernes produit un Monastère des Wyvernes dans chaque ville, tout en réduisant la lassitude globale due à la guerre, puisque les Mazatls se préparent à l'inévitable conflit à venir.</French>
		<German>Die Gründung des Ordens der Wyvern gewährt ein freies Kloster der Ledernen Schwingen in jeder Stadt. Außerdem wird die Kriegsmüdigkeit reduziert, da sich das Mazatl'sche Volk auf den bevorstehenden, unabwendbaren Konflikt vorbereitet.</German>
		<Italian>Fondare l'Ordine della Viverna fornisce un [LINK=BUILDING_DRAGON_MONASTARY]Monastero della Viverna[\LINK] gratuito in ogni città, oltre a ridurre la stanchezza della guerra in ogni città in quanto il popolo Mazatl si prepara per l'inevitabile conflitto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Founding the Order of the Wyvern provides a free Wyvern Monastry in every city, as well as reducing global war-weariness as the Mazatl people prepare for the inevitable conflict ahead.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_GLOBALSPELL_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN</Tag>
		<English>Creates [LINK=BUILDING_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN]Order of the Wyvern[\LINK] in the city where cast</English>
		<French>Crée l'[LINK=BUILDING_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN]Ordre des Wyvernes[\LINK] dans la ville où est lancé le sort.</French>
		<German>Erschafft [LINK=BUILDING_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN]Ordern der Wyvern[\LINK] in der Stadt des Zauberwirkens</German>
		<Italian>Crea l'[LINK=BUILDING_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN]Ordine della Viverna[\LINK] nella città in cui viene lanciata</Italian>
		<Spanish>Creates [LINK=BUILDING_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN]Order of the Wyvern[\LINK] in the city where cast</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BARTERHOUSE</Tag>
		<English>Barterhouse</English>
		<French>Trocante</French>
		<German>Tauschhändler</German>
		<Italian>Casa del Baratto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Barterhouse</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BARTERHOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Mazatl civilization emerged from the Age of Ice in relative isolation. The swampland they inhabited proved inhospitable to other races whilst the Mazatl thrived there alone. Trading only amongst themselves, they developed an advanced barter-economy that shared work across the empire. Central to this economy were the "barterhouses" (literal translation). Deals were struck and arrangments for trade of resources made over the course of long negotiations. The talks were not solely between the representatives of the involved parties, but included representatives of other cities to ensure the deal made was best for the Mazatl civilization as a whole. As all parties must be in agreement, a relatively simply arrangement may take an inordinate length of time to agree upon, but this is accepted by the Mazatl and their economy is impressive as a result.</English>
		<French>La civilisation Mazatl est sortie de l'Âge de Glace dans un relatif isolement. Les marais qu'ils habitaient se sont révélés inhospitaliers pour les autres races tandis que les Mazatl y prospéraient. Ne commerçant qu'entre eux, ils ont développé un système évolué de troc qui répartit le travail dans tout l'empire. Point focal de cette économie, les "trocantes" (traduction littérale). Les échanges étaient figés, et les accords d'échanges de ressources étaient issus de longues négociations. Les discussions n'étaient pas uniquement faites entre les représentants des groupse concernés, mais incluaient également des représentants des autres villes pour s'assurer que l'accord passé soit le meilleur possible pour la civilisation Mazatl dans son ensemble. Puisque chaque partie doit être d'accord, un accord relativement simple peut prendre un temps inhabituel pour être passé, mais les Mazatl l'acceptent et par conséquent leur économie est florissante.</French>
		<German>The Mazatl civilization emerged from the Age of Ice in relative isolation. The swampland they inhabited proved inhospitable to other races whilst the Mazatl thrived there alone. Trading only amongst themselves, they developed an advanced barter-economy that shared work across the empire. Central to this economy were the "barterhouses" (literal translation). Deals were struck and arrangments for trade of resources made over the course of long negotiations. The talks were not solely between the representatives of the involved parties, but included representatives of other cities to ensure the deal made was best for the Mazatl civilization as a whole. As all parties must be in agreement, a relatively simply arrangement may take an inordinate length of time to agree upon, but this is accepted by the Mazatl and their economy is impressive as a result..</German>
		<Italian>La civiltà Mazatl emerse dall'Era del Ghiaccio relativamente isolata. Le paludi che abitavano erano inospitali alle altre razze al contrario dei Mazatl che invece vi prosperavano. Commerciando solo tra loro svilupparono una avanzata economia di baratto che divideva il lavoro in tutto l'impero. Al centro di questa economia vi erano le "Case del Baratto" (traduzione letterale). Gli accordi per il commercio delle risorse venivano siglati dopo lunghe trattative. I colloqui non erano esclusivamente tra i rappresentanti delle parti coinvolte, ma includevano pure i rappresentanti di altre città per fare in modo che l'accordo fosse nell'interesse della civiltà Mazatl intera. Siccome tutte le parti devono essere concordi, anche un relativamente semplice accordo può richedere un lungo periodo di tempo per raggiungere l'unanimità, ma tutto questo è accettato dai Mazatl e la loro economia è impressionante di conseguenza.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Mazatl civilization emerged from the Age of Ice in relative isolation. The swampland they inhabited proved inhospitable to other races whilst the Mazatl thrived there alone. Trading only amongst themselves, they developed an advanced barter-economy that shared work across the empire. Central to this economy were the "barterhouses" (literal translation). Deals were struck and arrangments for trade of resources made over the course of long negotiations. The talks were not solely between the representatives of the involved parties, but included representatives of other cities to ensure the deal made was best for the Mazatl civilization as a whole. As all parties must be in agreement, a relatively simply arrangement may take an inordinate length of time to agree upon, but this is accepted by the Mazatl and their economy is impressive as a result..</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DRAGON_MONASTARY</Tag>
		<English>Wyvern Monastary</English>
		<French>Monastère des Wyvernes</French>
		<German>Kloster der Ledernen Schwingen</German>
		<Italian>Monastero della Viverna</Italian>
		<Spanish>Wyvern Monastary</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DRAGON_MONASTARY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Wyvern Monastary allows the city to build the Wyvern Guardian limited unit. Each one also increases the length of Golden Ages by 5%.</English>
		<French>Le Monastère des Wyvernes permet à la ville de construire l'unité limitée Gardien des Wyvernes . Chaque Monastère augmente également la durée des Âges d'Or de 5%.</French>
		<German>Das Kloster der Ledernen Schwingen erlaubt der Stadt die Ausbildung der limitierten Wyvern Wächter. Jeder davon verlängert ein Goldenes Zeitalter um 5%.</German>
		<Italian>Il Monastero della Viverna permette alla città di creare l'unità nazionale Guardiano della Viverna. Ognuno di essi inoltre aumenta la durata delle Età dell'oro del 5%.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Wyvern Monastary allows the city to build the Wyvern Guardian limited unit. Each one also increases the length of Golden Ages by 5%.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN</Tag>
		<English>Order of the Wyvern</English>
		<French>Ordre des Wyvernes</French>
		<German>Orden der Wyvern</German>
		<Italian>Ordine della Viverna</Italian>
		<Spanish>Order of the Wyvern</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Initially the Wyvern-guardians and the monks they defended were considered to radical and outlandish. As the Order of the Wyvern grew in influence however, the Mazatl society began to be increasingly shaped by the discoveries of the Order. Some believe that if it were not for the influence of the Wyvern Guardians, Erebus would have been consumed by the flames already.</English>
		<French>Initialement, les Wyvernes Gardiennes et les moines qu'elles protégeaient étaient considérés comme radicaux et étranges. Cependant, au fur et à mesure que l'Ordre des Wyvernes gagnait en influence, la société Mazatl commença de plus en plus à être façonnée par les découvertes de l'Ordre. Certains pensent que sans l'influence des Wyvernes Gardiennes, Erebus aurait déjà été consummé par les flammes.</French>
		<German>Initially the Wyvern-guardians and the monks they defended were considered to radical and outlandish. As the Order of the Wyvern grew in influence however, the Mazatl society began to be increasingly shaped by the discoveries of the Order. Some believe that if it were not for the influence of the Wyvern Guardians, Erebus would have been consumed by the flames already.</German>
		<Italian>Inizialmente i Guardiani della Viverna e i monaci che difendono erano considerati stravaganti e radicali. Però quando l'Ordine della Viverna aumentò la sua influenza la società Mazatl iniziò ad essere sempre più plasmata dalle scoperte dell'Ordine. Alcuni ritengono che se non fosse per l'influenza dei Guardiani della Viverna, Erebus sarebbe già stato consumato dalle fiamme.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Initially the Wyvern-guardians and the monks they defended were considered to radical and outlandish. As the Order of the Wyvern grew in influence however, the Mazatl society began to be increasingly shaped by the discoveries of the Order. Some believe that if it were not for the influence of the Wyvern Guardians, Erebus would have been consumed by the flames already.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORDER_OF_THE_WYVERN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Once all twelve of the Wyvern Guardians are appointed, the Mazatl civilization may found The Order of the Wyvern in any of its cities. The Order creates Wyvern Monastaries in every Mazatl city and provides a boost to Golden Age duration and reduces global war weariness considerably.</English>
		<French>Une fois les douze Wyvernes Gardiennes construites, les Mazatls peuvent fonder l'Ordre des Wyvernes dans n'importe laquelle de leurs villes. L'Ordre crée un Monastère des Wyvernes dans chaque ville Mazatl, fournit un bonus à la durée des Âges d'Or et réduit fortement la lassitude globale due à la guerre.</French>
		<German>Sind erst alle 12 Wyvern Wächter ernannt worden, können die Mazatl den Orden der Wyver in jeder ihrer Städte gründen. Der Orden erschafft Kloster der Ledernen Schwingen in jeder Stadt der Mazatl und gewährt eine Verlängerung des Goldenen Zeitalters und eine Reduzierung der Kriegsmüdigkeit.</German>
		<Italian>Una volta che tutti i dodici Guardiani della Viverna sono designati la civiltà Mazatl può fondare l'Ordine della Viverna in qualsiasi loro città. L'Ordine crea Monasteri della Viverna in ogni città Mazatl e aumenta la durata delle Età dell'oro oltre a ridurre considerevolmente la stanchezza della guerra in tutte le città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Once all twelve of the Wyvern Guardians are appointed, the Mazatl civilization may found The Order of the Wyvern in any of its cities. The Order creates Wyvern Monastaries in every Mazatl city and provides a boost to Golden Age duration and reduces global war weariness considerably.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_MAZATL</Tag>
		<English>Mazatl Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Mazatl</French>
		<German>Palast der Mazatl</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo dei Mazatl</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mazatl Palace</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PANTHEON</Tag>
		<English>Pantheon</English>
		<French>Panthéon</French>
		<German>Pantheon</German>
		<Italian>Pantheon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pantheon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PANTHEON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A Pantheon is a temple dedicated to not just one deity, but all deities of a given mythos. Few Mazatl dedicate themselves to only a single god (and these often become priests) and most will acknowledge all of their deities - although naturally they favour some more than others.</English>
		<French>Un Panthéon est un temple dédié non pas à un unique dieu mais à toutes les divinités d'une mythologie donnée. Peu de Mazatls décident de se dévouer à un dieu unique (et ils deviennent souvent des prêtres) et la plupart reconnaissent toutes leurs divités, même s'ils favorisent naturellement l'un deux par rapport aux autres.</French>
		<German>A Pantheon is a temple dedicated to not just one deity, but all deities of a given mythos. Few Mazatl dedicate themselves to only a single god (and these often become priests) and most will acknowledge all of their deities - although naturally they favour some more than others.</German>
		<Italian>Un Pantheon è un tempio dedicato a tutte le divinità di una certa mitologia. Sono pochi i Mazatl che dedicano se stessi a solo un dio (e chi lo fa di solito diventa un sacerdote) mentre la maggior parte venera tutti i loro dei, anche se, naturalmente, favoriscono qualcuno più di altri.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A Pantheon is a temple dedicated to not just one deity, but all deities of a given mythos. Few Mazatl dedicate themselves to only a single god (and these often become priests) and most will acknowledge all of their deities - although naturally they favour some more than others.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PANTHEON_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Pantheon allows a number of different specialists to be assigned, allowing you to tailor your Great Person Production early in the game.</English>
		<French>Le Panthéon permet la création de divers spécialistes dans la ville, vous permettant d'ajuster la création de Personnage Illustres tôt dans la partie.</French>
		<German>The Pantheon allows a number of different specialists to be assigned, allowing you to tailor your Great Person Production early in the game.</German>
		<Italian>Il Pantheon permette di assegnare diversi specialisti, permettendoti di personalizzare la tua genreazione di Grandi Personaggi a inizio partita.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Pantheon allows a number of different specialists to be assigned, allowing you to tailor your Great Person Production early in the game.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLE_OF_KALSHEKK</Tag>
		<English>Sacellum of Kalshekk</English>
		<French>Sacellum de Kalshekk</French>
		<German>Sacellum von Kalshekk</German>
		<Italian>Sacellum di Kalshekk</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sacellum of Kalshekk</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLE_OF_KALSHEKK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The temples, or "Sacella" of Kalshekk resemble stone pyramids, with the public spaces open to the air. Inside the Sacellum itself, a small network of tunnels and chambers provide housing for the priests. The walls are decorated with gold and the priests practice crafting with iron and mithril alike. It is rumoured that the great Sacellum of Kalshekk in the oldest of lizard-cities - lost since before the Age of Ice - contains more precious metals and finer craftworks than the surviving dwarven kingdoms combined. Of course, the Dwarves are not prone to listen to such rumours.</English>
		<French>Les temples ou "Sacella" de Kalshekk ressemble à des pyramides de pierre, avec les espaces publics à l'air libre. À l'intérieur du Sacellum lui-même, un petit réseau de tunnels et de chambres fournit le logement pour les prêtres. Les murs sont ornés d'or et les prêtres pratiquent indistinctement l'artisanat du fer et du mithil. On raconte que le grand Sacellum de Kalshekk de la plus vieille ville saurienne, perdue depuis l'Âge de Glace, contient plus de métaux précieux et de l'artisanat plus raffiné que tous les royaumes nains restant combinés. Bien sûr, les Nains ne prêtent pas l'oreille à de telles rumeurs.</French>
		<German>The temples, or "Sacella" of Kalshekk resemble stone pyramids, with the public spaces open to the air. Inside the Sacellum itself, a small network of tunnels and chambers provide housing for the priests. The walls are decorated with gold and the priests practice crafting with iron and mithril alike. It is rumoured that the great Sacellum of Kalshekk in the oldest of lizard-cities - lost since before the Age of Ice - contains more precious metals and finer craftworks than the surviving dwarven kingdoms combined. Of course, the Dwarves are not prone to listen to such rumours.</German>
		<Italian>I templi, o "Sacella" di Kalshekk somigliano a piramidi di pietra, con gli spazi pubblici all'aria perta. All'interno del Sacellum, una piccola rete di tunnel e stanze fornisce alloggio ai sacerdoti. Le mura sono decorate con l'oro e i sacerdoti praticano la lavorazione sia del ferro che del mithril. Si dice che il grande Sacellum di Kalshekk nella città lucertoloide più vecchia, perduta sin da prima dell'Era del Ghiaccio, contiene più metalli preziosi e artefatti raffinati dei regni nanici sopravissuti combinati. Ovviamente ai nani non piace sentire queste voci.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The temples, or "Sacella" of Kalshekk resemble stone pyramids, with the public spaces open to the air. Inside the Sacellum itself, a small network of tunnels and chambers provide housing for the priests. The walls are decorated with gold and the priests practice crafting with iron and mithril alike. It is rumoured that the great Sacellum of Kalshekk in the oldest of lizard-cities - lost since before the Age of Ice - contains more precious metals and finer craftworks than the surviving dwarven kingdoms combined. Of course, the Dwarves are not prone to listen to such rumours.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLE_OF_OMORR</Tag>
		<English>Sacellum of Omorr</English>
		<French>Sacellum d'Omorr</French>
		<German>Sacellum von Omorr</German>
		<Italian>Sacellum di Omorr</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sacellum of Omorr</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLE_OF_OMORR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Sacella of Omorr look similar to those belonging to the priests of Kalshekk on the surface, but within the stone-walls they could not be more different. Whilst the priests of Kalshekk reside in small chambers and cramped tunnels, the Sacella of Omorr are practically hollow, but filled with stacks of notes, prophecies, legends and literature. It was the priests of Omorr that first divined the impending strife and the danger to the world, shaping the society of the Mazatl during the Age of Rebirth. Now they work tirelessly to discover a way to avert Armageddon.</English>
		<French>Les Sacella d'Omorr ressemblent à ceux des prêtres de Kalshekk en surface, mais ne peuvent être plus différents à l'intérieur des murs. Tandis que les prêtres de Kalshekk vivent dans des chambres et des tunnels exigüs, les Sacella d'Omorr sont pratiquement nus, mais emplis de piles de notes, prophéties, légendes et littérature. Ce sont les prêtres d'Omorr qui devinèrent les premiers la lutte à venir et le danger sur le monde, modelant la société Mazatl durant l'Âge de la Renaissance. AUjourd'hui ils travaillent sans relâche sur un moyen d'éviter l'Armageddon.</French>
		<German>The Sacella of Omorr look similar to those belonging to the priests of Kalshekk on the surface, but within the stone-walls they could not be more different. Whilst the priests of Kalshekk reside in small chambers and cramped tunnels, the Sacella of Omorr are practically hollow, but filled with stacks of notes, prophecies, legends and literature. It was the priests of Omorr that first divined the impending strife and the danger to the world, shaping the society of the Mazatl during the Age of Rebirth. Now they work tirelessly to discover a way to avert Armageddon.</German>
		<Italian>Il Sacella di Omorr è simile a quello dei sacerdoti di Kalshekk in superfice, ma dentro le mura di pietra non possono essere più diversi. Mentre i sacerdoti di Kalshekk risiedono in piccole stanze e tunnel stretti, i Sacella di Omorr sono praticamente vuoti, e riempiti di colonne di note, profezie, leggende e opere letterali. Furono i sacerdoti di Omorr a prevedere per primi il conflitto imminente e il pericolo per il mondo, plasmando la società dei Mazatl durante l'Era della Rinascita. Ora lavorano senza sosta per scoprire come impedire l'Armageddon.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Sacella of Omorr look similar to those belonging to the priests of Kalshekk on the surface, but within the stone-walls they could not be more different. Whilst the priests of Kalshekk reside in small chambers and cramped tunnels, the Sacella of Omorr are practically hollow, but filled with stacks of notes, prophecies, legends and literature. It was the priests of Omorr that first divined the impending strife and the danger to the world, shaping the society of the Mazatl during the Age of Rebirth. Now they work tirelessly to discover a way to avert Armageddon.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MARK_OF_THE_WARDEN</Tag>
		<English>Mark of the Warden</English>
		<French>Marque du Gardien</French>
		<German>Abzeichen der Wächter</German>
		<Italian>Marchio del Guardiano</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mark of the Warden</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MARK_OF_THE_WARDEN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]The Armageddon counter is lowered when this unit is created, but will rise again if the unit is slain.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Le compteur Armageddon est décrémenté lors de la création de cette unité, mais sera à nouveau incrémenté si l'unité est tuée.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Der Armageddonzähler wird bei der Erschaffung dieser Einheit verringert, steigt bei ihrer Vernichtung aber wieder an.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Il Contatore dell'Armageddon viene abbassato quando questa unità viene creata, per poi risalire quando l'unità viene uccisa.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]The Armageddon counter is lowered when this unit is created, but will rise again if the unit is slain.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SPIRITUAL_HAMMER</Tag>
		<English>Spiritual Hammer</English>
		<French>Marteau Spirituel</French>
		<German>Seelenhammer</German>
		<Italian>Martello Spirituale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Spiritual Hammer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FOUND_TEMPLE_OF_KALSHEKK</Tag>
		<English>Found Temple of Kalshekk</English>
		<French>Fonder le Sanctuaire de Kalshekk</French>
		<German>Gründe Tempel von Kalshekk</German>
		<Italian>Fonda Tempio di Kalshekk</Italian>
		<Spanish>Found Temple of Kalshekk</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FOUND_TEMPLE_OF_OMORR</Tag>
		<English>Found Temple of Omorr</English>
		<French>Fonder le Sanctuaire d'Omorr</French>
		<German>Gründe Tempel von Omorr</German>
		<Italian>Fonda Tempio di Omorr</Italian>
		<Spanish>Found Temple of Omorr</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_PURIFY</Tag>
		<English>Purify</English>
		<French>Purifier</French>
		<German>Reinigen</German>
		<Italian>Purifica</Italian>
		<Spanish>Purify</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUIDE</Tag>
		<English>Spirit Guide</English>
		<French>Guide Spirituel</French>
		<German>Seelenführer</German>
		<Italian>Spirito Guida</Italian>
		<Spanish>Spirit Guide</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_HAMMER</Tag>
		<English>Spiritual Hammer</English>
		<French>Marteau Spirituel</French>
		<German>Seelenhammer</German>
		<Italian>Martello Spirituale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Spiritual Hammer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_TRANSMUTATION</Tag>
		<English>Transmutation</English>
		<French>Transmutation</French>
		<German>Transmutation</German>
		<Italian>Trasmutazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Transmutation</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_TRANSMUTATION_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Transforms copper to gold or gold to copper</English>
		<French>Convertit le cuivre en or ou l'or en cuivre</French>
		<German>Transforms copper to gold or gold to copper</German>
		<Italian>Trasforma il rame in oro o viceversa</Italian>
		<Spanish>Transforms copper to gold or gold to copper</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COATLANN</Tag>
		<English>Coatlann</English>
		<French>Coatlann</French>
		<German>Coatlann</German>
		<Italian>Coatlann</Italian>
		<Spanish>Coatlann</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COATLANN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In the Age of Dragons, the mortal races cowered in caves as the Godswar raged across creation. The great dragons were created to serve the Angels and unleashed their terrible powers upon each other across the length and breadth of Erebus. When the compact was signed and the angels retreated from creation, the dragons too disappeared. Some say they left with the angels, others say that they sleep beneath the earth. There are even rumours that some of the dragons never left at all and still dwell amongst the mortal races.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Coatlann was a quetzal in the service of Kilmorph during the Age of Dragons. The quetzals were among the lesser beasts created in that age, but were still massively powerful and wise. A winged serpent, the quetzal was favoured for its speed and cunning where the brute force of a dragon may not suffice alone.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Coatlann constantly waged war against the forces of Aeron and Mammon during that first age - and survived. When the compact was signed, Coatlann left Erebus and resides on a plane beyond, ready to re-enter battle should the compact be broken and the Godswar restart in full.</English>
		<French>Durant l'Âge des Dragons, les races mortelles se terraient dans des grottes tandis que la Guerre des Dieux faisait rage partout dans Création. Les grands dragons furent créés pour servir les Anges et faisaient usage de leurs terribles pouvoirs les uns sur les autres en long en large et en travers d'Erebus. Quand le traité fut signé et que les Anges se retirèrent de Création, les dragons disparurent également. Certains disent qu'ils sont partis avec les Anges, d'autres qu'ils dorment dansles entrailles de la terre. Certains racontent même que certains dragons ne sont jamais partis et vivent toujours parmis les races mortelles.[PARAGRAPH:1]Coatlann était une wyverne au service de Kilmorph pendant l'Âge des Dragons. Les wyvernes faisaient partie des bêtes mineures créées lors de cet âge, mais restaient extrêmement puissantes et sages. Ressemblant énormément à un dragon, mais sans membre antérieur, la wyverne était prisée pour sa vitesse et son astuce là où la seule force brute d'un dragon pouvait ne pas suffire.[PARAGRAPH:1]Coatlann guerroya constamment contre les forces d'Aeron et Mammon durant le premier âge, et survécut. Quand le traité fut signé, Coatlann quitta Erebus et s'installa un plan en-dessous, prêt à revenir dans le combat si le traité venait à être rompu et la Guerre des Dieux venait à redémarrer totalement.</French>
		<German>In the Age of Dragons, the mortal races cowered in caves as the Godswar raged across creation. The great dragons were created to serve the Angels and unleashed their terrible powers upon each other across the length and breadth of Erebus. When the compact was signed and the angels retreated from creation, the dragons too disappeared. Some say they left with the angels, others say that they sleep beneath the earth. There are even rumours that some of the dragons never left at all and still dwell amongst the mortal races.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Coatlann was a quetzal in the service of Kilmorph during the Age of Dragons. The quetzals were among the lesser beasts created in that age, but were still massively powerful and wise. A winged serpent, the quetzal was favoured for its speed and cunning where the brute force of a dragon may not suffice alone.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Coatlann constantly waged war against the forces of Aeron and Mammon during that first age - and survived. When the compact was signed, Coatlann left Erebus and resides on a plane beyond, ready to re-enter battle should the compact be broken and the Godswar restart in full.</German>
		<Italian>Durante l'Era dei Draghi le razze mortali si rifugiavano terrorizate nelle caverne mentre la Guerra degli dei infuriava su tutta la creazione. I grandi draghi furono creati per servire gli angeli, e scatenavano i loro terribili poteri in lungo e in largo su Erebus. Quando il Patto fu siglato e gli angeli si ritirarono dalla creazione, i draghi fecero lo stesso. Alcuni dicono che se ne andarono con gli angeli, altri dicono che dormono sotto la terra. Ci sono perfino voci che dicono che alcuni draghi non se ne sono mai andati e che ancora si aggirano tra le razze mortali.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Coatlann era un quetzal al servizio di Kilmorph durante l'Era dei Draghi. I quetzal erano delle bestie minori tra quelle create in quell'era, ma comunque rimangono estremamente potenti e saggie. Essendo un serpente alato il quetzal era favorito per la sua velocità e astuzia dove la forza bruta di un drago poteva non essere sufficente.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Coatlann affrontava costantemente le forze di Aeron e Mammon durante la prima era, e sopravvisse. Quando il Patto fu siglato, Coatlann lasciò Erebus e risiede in un'altro piano, pronto a rientrare in battaglia nel caso il Patto venga infranto e la Guerra degli dei ri-iniziata.</Italian>
		<Spanish>In the Age of Dragons, the mortal races cowered in caves as the Godswar raged across creation. The great dragons were created to serve the Angels and unleashed their terrible powers upon each other across the length and breadth of Erebus. When the compact was signed and the angels retreated from creation, the dragons too disappeared. Some say they left with the angels, others say that they sleep beneath the earth. There are even rumours that some of the dragons never left at all and still dwell amongst the mortal races.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Coatlann was a quetzal in the service of Kilmorph during the Age of Dragons. The quetzals were among the lesser beasts created in that age, but were still massively powerful and wise. A winged serpent, the quetzal was favoured for its speed and cunning where the brute force of a dragon may not suffice alone.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Coatlann constantly waged war against the forces of Aeron and Mammon during that first age - and survived. When the compact was signed, Coatlann left Erebus and resides on a plane beyond, ready to re-enter battle should the compact be broken and the Godswar restart in full.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COATLANN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Whilst Coatlann is less powerful than the other dragons in Fall from Heaven, he is still of dragonkind and a mighty wyrm. Immune to magic, able to roar and breath fire, causing fear in his foes and stronger than most other units in the game - as well as boasting a greater speed and lower research cost than his more powerful kin -  Coatlann may be the answer the Mazatl seek to avert the destruction of Erebus.</English>
		<French>Bien que Coatlann soit moins puissant que les autres dragons de Ashes of Erebus, il est tout de même draconique et un puissant wyrm. Immunisé à la magie, capable de rugir et de cracher du feu, terrifiant ses adversaires et plus puissant que la plupart des unités du jeu tout en se prévalant d'une vitesse plus élevée et d'un coût de recherche réduit par rapport à ses congénères plus puissants, Coatlann pourrait bien être la solution que les Mazatls cherchent pour éviter la destruction d'Erebus.</French>
		<German>Whilst Coatlann is less powerful than the other dragons in Fall from Heaven, he is still of dragonkind and a mighty wyrm. Immune to magic, able to roar and breath fire, causing fear in his foes and stronger than most other units in the game - as well as boasting a greater speed and lower research cost than his more powerful kin -  Coatlann may be the answer the Mazatl seek to avert the destruction of Erebus.</German>
		<Italian>Sebbene Coatlann sia meno potente degli altri draghi presenti in Fall from Heaven, rimane comunque un drago. Immune alla magia, capace di ruggire e soffiare fuoco, instillare paura nei suoi nemici ed è più forte della maggior parte delle altre unità del gioco, oltre ad avere un maggiore movimento e minor costo dei draghi più forti, Coatlann può essere la risposta che i Mazatl cercano per evitare la distruzione di Erebus.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Whilst Coatlann is less powerful than the other dragons in Fall from Heaven, he is still of dragonkind and a mighty wyrm. Immune to magic, able to roar and breath fire, causing fear in his foes and stronger than most other units in the game - as well as boasting a greater speed and lower research cost than his more powerful kin -  Coatlann may be the answer the Mazatl seek to avert the destruction of Erebus.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_COATLANN_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>Coatlann was a wyvern in the service of Kilmorph during the Age of Dragons. The wyverns were among the lesser beasts created in that age, but were still massively powerful and wise. Looking much akin to a dragon - though lacking forelimbs - the wyvern was favoured for its speed and cunning where the brute force of a dragon may not suffice alone.</English>
		<French>Coatlann était une wyverne au service de Kilmorph pendant l'Âge des Dragons. Les wyvernes faisaient partie des bêtes mineures créées lors de cet âge, mais restaient extrêmement puissantes et sages. Ressemblant énormément à un dragon, mais sans membre antérieur, la wyverne était prisée pour sa vitesse et son astuce là où la seule force brute d'un dragon pouvait ne pas suffire.</French>
		<German>Coatlann war ein Wyvern im Dienste von Kilmorph w&#228;hrend des Zeitalters der Drachen. Die Wyvern geh&#246;rten in dieser Zeit zu den niederen Kreaturen, doch sie waren dennoch f&#252;r heutige Verh&#228;ltnisse &#228;u&#223;erst m&#228;chtig und weise. Sie &#228;hneln &#228;u&#223;erlich Drachen - auch wenn sie keine Vorderl&#228;ufe haben - und sind im Gegensatz zu ihnen bekannt f&#252;r ihre Geschwindigkeit und ihre Gerissenheit und machten damit die brutale Kraft der Drachen wett.</German>
		<Italian>Coatlann era una viverna al servizio di Kilmorph durante l'Era dei Draghi. Le viverne erano delle bestie minori tra quelle create in quell'era, ma comunque rimangono estremamente potenti e saggie. Sono molto simili ai draghi, sebbene prive ddegli arti anteriori, le viverne erano preferite per via della loro velocità e astuzia quando la forza bruta di un drago non era sufficente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Coatlann was a wyvern in the service of Kilmorph during the Age of Dragons. The wyverns were among the lesser beasts created in that age, but were still massively powerful and wise. Looking much akin to a dragon - though lacking forelimbs - the wyvern was favoured for its speed and cunning where the brute force of a dragon may not suffice alone.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DISCIPLE_OF_KALSHEKK</Tag>
		<English>Disciple of Kalshekk</English>
		<French>Disciple de Kalshekk</French>
		<German>Geweihter des Kalshekk</German>
		<Italian>Discepolo di Kalshekk</Italian>
		<Spanish>Disciple of Kalshekk</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DISCIPLE_OF_OMORR</Tag>
		<English>Disciple of Omorr</English>
		<French>Disciple d'Omorr</French>
		<German>Geweihter des Omorr</German>
		<Italian>Discepolo di Omorr</Italian>
		<Spanish>Disciple of Omorr</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGON_GUARDIAN</Tag>
		<English>Wyvern Guardian</English>
		<French>Gardien des wyvernes</French>
		<German>Wyvern Wächter</German>
		<Italian>Guardiano della Viverna</Italian>
		<Spanish>Wyvern Guardian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGON_GUARDIAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The priests of Omorr study tirelessly to discover a way that Armageddon may be averted, but there are those amongst them who believe that the event itself cannot be prevented. These priests have grown to believe that the only way to survive Armageddon is to fight and win in the "final battle". Once they have become so closed minded, they are no longer welcomed in Omorr's service, so they retire themselves to hidden monastries and there they prepare. They have discovered the legend of Coatlann, and believe his assistance will be essential to survive the battle. Twelve Guardians were appointed to defend the egg-relic of Coatlann, whilst others within the order work endlessly to call back the essence of the Quetzal itself.</English>
		<French>Les prêtres d'Omorr étudient sans relâche pour découvrir un moyen d'éviter l'Armageddon, mais certains d'entre eux croient que l'évènement lui-même ne pourra pas être évité. Ces prêtres sont parvenus à la conclusion que la seule manière de survivre à l'Armageddon est de se battre et gagner lors du "combat final". Une fois dans ce schéma de pensée, ils ne sont plus les bienvenus au service d'Omorr, et se retirent donc dans des monastères cachés et s'y préparent. Ils ont découvert la légende de Coatlann, et croient que son aide sera essentielle pour survivre à la bataille. Douze Gardiens furent désignés pour défendre la relique-&#156;uf de Coatlann, tandis que les autres membres de l'ordre travaillent sans relâche à rappeler l'essence de Coatlann elle-même.</French>
		<German>The priests of Omorr study tirelessly to discover a way that Armageddon may be averted, but there are those amongst them who believe that the event itself cannot be prevented. These priests have grown to believe that the only way to survive Armageddon is to fight and win in the "final battle". Once they have become so closed minded, they are no longer welcomed in Omorr's service, so they retire themselves to hidden monastries and there they prepare. They have discovered the legend of Coatlann, and believe his assistance will be essential to survive the battle. Twelve Guardians were appointed to defend the egg-relic of Coatlann, whilst others within the order work endlessly to call back the essence of the Quetzal itself.</German>
		<Italian>I sacerdoti di Omorr studiano senza sosta per scoprire un modo per impedire l'Armageddon, e tra di loro ci sono coloro che ritengono che esso non può essere evitato. Questi sacerdoti sono arrivati alla conclusione che l'unico modo per sopravvivere all'Armageddon sia quello di combattere e vincere la "battaglia finale". Una volta che diventano cosi fissati, non sono più i benvenuti al servizio di Omorr, e di conseguenza si ritirano in monasteri nascosti dove si preparano. Loro hanno scoperto la leggenda di Coatlann, e credono che la sua assistenza sarà essenziale per sopravvivere alla battaglia. Dodici Guardiani sono stati incaricati di difendere l'uovo reliquia di Coatlann, mentre gli altri membri dell'ordine lavorano senza sosta per richiamare l'essenza del Quetzal stesso.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The priests of Omorr study tirelessly to discover a way that Armageddon may be averted, but there are those amongst them who believe that the event itself cannot be prevented. These priests have grown to believe that the only way to survive Armageddon is to fight and win in the "final battle". Once they have become so closed minded, they are no longer welcomed in Omorr's service, so they retire themselves to hidden monastries and there they prepare. They have discovered the legend of Coatlann, and believe his assistance will be essential to survive the battle. Twelve Guardians were appointed to defend the egg-relic of Coatlann, whilst others within the order work endlessly to call back the essence of the Quetzal itself.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGON_GUARDIAN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Wyvern Guardians are a limited unit and only 12 may exist at a single time. They are however potent defensive units and may become further empowered if granted a Spiritual Hammer by a Priest of Kalshekk.</English>
		<French>Les Gardiens des Wyvernes sont des unités limitées et un maximum de 12 d'entre elles peuvent exister en même temps. Ce sont cependant de puissantes unités défensives et peuvent être encore renforcées par un [LINK=SPELL_SPIRITUAL_HAMMER]Marteau Spirituel[\LINK] d'un Prêtre de Kalshekk.</French>
		<German>The Wyvern Guardians are a limited unit and only 12 may exist at a single time. They are however potent defensive units and may become further empowered if granted a Spiritual Hammer by a Priest of Kalshekk.</German>
		<Italian>I Guardiani della Viverna sono un'unità nazionale e ce ne possono essere solo 12 contemporaneamente. Sono però delle potenti unità difensive e possono essere ancora potenziate se gli viene fornito un Martello Spirituale da un Sacerdote di Kalshekk.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Wyvern Guardians are a limited unit and only 12 may exist at a single time. They are however potent defensive units and may become further empowered if granted a Spiritual Hammer by a Priest of Kalshekk.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HIGH_PRIEST_OF_KALSHEKK</Tag>
		<English>High Priest of Kalshekk</English>
		<French>Grand Prêtre de Kalshekk</French>
		<German>Hohepriester des Kalshekk</German>
		<Italian>Sommo Sacerdote di Kalshekk</Italian>
		<Spanish>High Priest of Kalshekk</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HIGH_PRIEST_OF_OMORR</Tag>
		<English>High Priest of Omorr</English>
		<French>Grand Prêtre d'Omorr</French>
		<German>Hohepriester des Omorr</German>
		<Italian>Sommo Sacerdote di Omorr</Italian>
		<Spanish>High Priest of Omorr</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIZARD_BLOWPIPE</Tag>
		<English>Blowpipe</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Saurien à Sarbacane:Sauriens à Sarbacane</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Feuerschleuderer</German>
		<Italian>Lucertoloide Cerbottaniere</Italian>
		<Spanish>Blowpipe</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIZARD_BLOWPIPE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A blowgun or blowpipe is a simple weapon consisting of a small tube for firing light projectiles, or darts. The wielder blows into one end, forcing the dart out the other. Its propulsive power is its user's respiratory muscles. Sometimes, for increased effectiveness, the dart is tipped with a poison, allowing the user to attack and flee, then return later to deal with foe once the poison has done its work.</English>
		<French>Une sarbacane est une arme rudimentaire constituée d'un petit tube lançant des projectiles légers, ou des dards. L'utilisateur souffle à une extrémité, éjectant le dard à l'autre. Sa puissance de propulsion est fonction des capacités respiratoires de l'utilisateur. Parfois, pour une efficacité accrue, le dard est empoisonné, permettant à l'utilisateur d'attaquer puis fuir, pour revenir par la suite afin de s'occuper des ennemis une fois que le poison aura fait effet.</French>
		<German>A blowgun or blowpipe is a simple weapon consisting of a small tube for firing light projectiles, or darts. The wielder blows into one end, forcing the dart out the other. Its propulsive power is its user's respiratory muscles. Sometimes, for increased effectiveness, the dart is tipped with a poison, allowing the user to attack and flee, then return later to deal with foe once the poison has done its work.</German>
		<Italian>La cerbottana è un'arma semplice che consiste in un piccolo tubo con cui si lanciano piccoli proiettili o, più comunumente, dardi. Chi la utilizza soffia da una parte facendo uscire il dardo dall'altra. La sua forza propulsiva dipende dai polmoni di chi la utilizza. Qualche volta, per aumentare l'efficacia, il dardo è intinto nel veleno, per permettere al cerbottaniere di colpire e poi scappare, per poi tornare a finire il nemico una volta che il veleno ha fatto effetto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A blowgun or blowpipe is a simple weapon consisting of a small tube for firing light projectiles, or darts. The wielder blows into one end, forcing the dart out the other. Its propulsive power is its user's respiratory muscles. Sometimes, for increased effectiveness, the dart is tipped with a poison, allowing the user to attack and flee, then return later to deal with foe once the poison has done its work.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIZARD_BLOWPIPE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Blowpipe units are adept at both attack and defence. Replacing Longbowmen, they are fast enough to strike and Withdraw and they are also able to weaken and slow the healing of any unit they engage with their Poisoned Weapons.</English>
		<French>Les Sauriens à Sarbacane sont aussi efficaces en attaque qu'en défense. Remplaçant les archers à arc long, ils sont suffisamment rapides pour frapper et se replier et sont également capables d'affaiblir et ralentir les soins des unités qu'ils attaquent avec leurs Armes Empoisonnées.</French>
		<German>Blowpipe units are adept at both attack and defence. Replacing Longbowmen, they are fast enough to strike and Withdraw and they are also able to weaken and slow the healing of any unit they engage with their Poisoned Weapons.</German>
		<Italian>I Lucertoloidi Cerbottanieri sono utili sia in attacco che in difesa. Rimpiazzano gli Arcieri con Arco Lungo e sono abbastanza veloci da colpire per poi ritirarsi, inoltre indeboliscono e rallentano la guarigione delle unità che affrontano grazie alle loro Armi Avvelenate.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Blowpipe units are adept at both attack and defence. Replacing Longbowmen, they are fast enough to strike and Withdraw and they are also able to weaken and slow the healing of any unit they engage with their Poisoned Weapons.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIZARD_WORKER_MAZATL</Tag>
		<English>Lizardman Shaper</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Terrasseur Saurien:Terrasseurs Sauriens</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Geschuppte Gestalter</German>
		<Italian>Modellatore Lucertoloide</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lizardman Shaper</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIZARD_WORKER_MAZATL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Lizard workers are slow when compared to those of other races (initial work rate is 75), but their territory requires less improvements overall. Moreover, they can cast [LINK=SPELL_CREATE_SWAMP]create swamp[\LINK] and [LINK=SPELL_CLEAR_SWAMP]clear swamp[\LINK], which helps their terraforming. But beware, creating a swamp removes previous improvements![NEWLINE]They are also able to construct "Trails", hidden paths which act as roads for Swampdwelling civilizations but provide no movement benefit to others.[NEWLINE]All tiles without resources give good yield with Wetland/Jungle/Marsh+trail+swamp.</English>
		<French>Les ouvriers Sauriens sont lents comparés à ceux des autres races (leur cadence initiale de travail est de 75), mais leurs territoires nécessitent globalement moins d'aménagements. Ils sont de plus capables de lancer les sorts [LINK=SPELL_CREATE_SWAMP]Créer un Marais[\LINK] et [LINK=SPELL_CLEAR_SWAMP]Assécher le Marais[\LINK], qui les aident à terraformer leur territoire. Mais attention, créer un marais détruit tous les aménagements précédents ![NEWLINE]Ils sont également capables de construire des "Sentiers", qui sont des chemins cachés agissant comme des routes pour les civilisations adaptées aux marais mais qui ne confèrent pratiquement aucun avantage aux autres.[NEWLINE]Toutes les cases dépourvues de ressources seront productives si Tropicales/Jungle/Marécage + Sentier + Marais.</French>
		<German>NEEDS UPDATE: Lizard workers are slow when compared to those of other races but the workers of the Mazatl are able to cast Spring and Scorch. These spells allow them greater control over the spread of Wetlands and Swamps. They are also able to construct "Trails", hidden paths which act as roads for Swampdwelling civilizations but provide almost no benefit to others.</German>
		<Italian>I lavoratori lucertoloidi sono più lenti di quelli delle altre razze (il rateo di lavoro iniziale è 75), ma è anche vero che i loro territori richiedono meno miglioramenti in generale. Inoltre hanno a disposizione [LINK=SPELL_CREATE_SWAMP]Crea Palude[\LINK] e [LINK=SPELL_CLEAR_SWAMP]Rimuovi Palude[\LINK], molto utili per terraformare i loro territori. Fai attenzione però, creare una palude distrugge i miglioramenti presenti sulla casella![NEWLINE]Possono anche costruire dei "Sentieri", ovvero delle strade nascoste che solo le civiltà che abitano le paludi possono usare.[NEWLINE]Tutte le caselle senza risorse possiedono comunque una buona resa attraverso Zona umida/Giungla/Acquitrino+sentiero+palude.</Italian>
		<Spanish>NEEDS UPDATE: Lizard workers are slow when compared to those of other races but the workers of the Mazatl are able to cast Spring and Scorch. These spells allow them greater control over the spread of Wetlands and Swamps. They are also able to construct "Trails", hidden paths which act as roads for Swampdwelling civilizations but provide almost no benefit to others.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRIEST_OF_KALSHEKK</Tag>
		<English>Priest of Kalshekk</English>
		<French>Prêtre de Kalshekk</French>
		<German>Priester des Kalshekk</German>
		<Italian>Sacerdote di Kalshekk</Italian>
		<Spanish>Priest of Kalshekk</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRIEST_OF_KALSHEKK_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Priests of Kalshekk have the ability to create gold from Copper resources, and to grant the Spiritual Hammer promotion to Disciple units.</English>
		<French>Les prêtres de Kalshekk ont la possibilité de transformer le cuivre en or. Ils peuvent aussi renforcer les unités de type Disciple avec le sort [LINK=SPELL_SPIRITUAL_HAMMER]Marteau spirituel[\LINK].</French>
		<German>Priester des Kalshekk können Gold aus Kupfer-Resourcen gewinnenen und die Beförderung Geistiger Hammer an Adepten verleihen.</German>
		<Italian>I Sacerdoti di Kalshekk possono trasformare le fonti di Rame in Oro e viceversa, e possono fornire la promozione Martello Spirituale alle altre unità Discepolo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Priests of Kalshekk have the ability to create gold from Copper resources, and to grant the Spiritual Hammer promotion to Disciple units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRIEST_OF_OMORR</Tag>
		<English>Priest of Omorr</English>
		<French>Prêtre d'Omorr</French>
		<German>Priester des Omorr</German>
		<Italian>Sacerdote di Omorr</Italian>
		<Spanish>Priest of Omorr</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRIEST_OF_OMORR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Priests of Omorr are useful when facing veil civs as they have the ability to sanctify hell terrain and cure diseases. They also possess the ability to cast Spirit Guide, ensuring their experience does not go to waste. Their seer-like abilities allow them to view approaching threats by using "Floating Eye".</English>
		<French>Les Prêtres d'Omorr sont utiles pour affronter les civilisations du voile, grâce à leur capacité à sanctifier le terrain infernal et soigner les maladies. Ils ont également la possibilité de lancer le sort [LINK=SPELL_SPIRIT_GUIDE]Guide Spirituel[\LINK], s'assurant que leur expérience ne serait pas gâchée. Leurs capacités simili-prophétiques leurs permettent de détecter les menaces s'approchant en utilisant le sort [LINK=SPELL_FLOATING_EYE]Oeil Flottant[\LINK].</French>
		<German>Priests of Omorr are useful when facing veil civs as they have the ability to sanctify hell terrain and cure diseases. They also possess the ability to cast Spirit Guide, ensuring their experience does not go to waste. Their seer-like abilities allow them to view approaching threats by using "Floating Eye".</German>
		<Italian>I Sacerdoti di Omorr sono molto utili quando si affrontano civiltà che seguono il Velo Cinereo, in quanto hanno la capacità di rimuovere il terreno infernale e curare le malattie. Possono inoltre fornire la promozione Spirito Guida, permettendo cosi di non perdere l'esperienza maturata da un'unità. Le loro capacità divinatorie gli permettono inoltre di avvisatre i pericoli vicini tramite l'utilizzo di "Occhi Fluttuanti".</Italian>
		<Spanish>Priests of Omorr are useful when facing veil civs as they have the ability to sanctify hell terrain and cure diseases. They also possess the ability to cast Spirit Guide, ensuring their experience does not go to waste. Their seer-like abilities allow them to view approaching threats by using "Floating Eye".</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRIEST_MAZATL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Mazatl worship a number of different deities, but primarily Kalshekk and Omorr. Whilst none of these deities are exactly the same as those worshipped amongst the human population of Erebus, they do share aspects with some of them. Kalshekk for instance shares many similarities with Kilmorph, to the point that it is believed that both have the same origin but the current representations are derived from differing histories and mythologies. The same is true of the lizard deity Omorr and the human deity Oghma. Whether either race has the "correct" representation is a matter for philosophers and scholars to debate, but what is known is that the Priests of Kalshekk and Omorr display abilities akin to those of their counterpart religions.</English>
		<French>Les Mazalts vénèrent tout un groupe de divinités, mais surtout Kalshekk et Omorr. Bien qu'aucune d'entre elles ne soit le reflet exact de celles vénérées chez les humains d'Erebus, elles partagent quelques similitudes. Par exemple, Kalshekk partage de nombreuses ressemblances avec Kilmorph, au point qu'on croit que les deux ont la même origine mais que leurs représentations actuelles sont issues d'histoires et de mythologies différentes. C'est également le cas de la divinité saurienne Omorr et la divinité humaine Oghma. Que l'une des deux races possède la représentation "correcte" est un débat de philosophes et de professeurs, mais ce qui est sûr c'est que les Prêtres de Kalshekk et d'Omorr possèdent des compétences similaires à celles de leurs équivalents dans les autres religions.</French>
		<German>The Mazatl worship a number of different deities, but primarily Kalshekk and Omorr. Whilst none of these deities are exactly the same as those worshipped amongst the human population of Erebus, they do share aspects with some of them. Kalshekk for instance shares many similarities with Kilmorph, to the point that it is believed that both have the same origin but the current representations are derived from differing histories and mythologies. The same is true of the lizard deity Omorr and the human deity Oghma. Whether either race has the "correct" representation is a matter for philosophers and scholars to debate, but what is known is that the Priests of Kalshekk and Omorr display abilities akin to those of their counterpart religions.</German>
		<Italian>I Mazatl venerano diverse divinità, ma le principali sono Kalshekk e Omorr. Sebbene nessuna di esse sia uguale a quelle venerate dagli umani di Erebus, alcune condividono qualche aspetto. Kalshekk per esempio condivide molte somiglianze con Kilmorph, al punto che si ritiene che entrambi abbiano la stessa origine, ma le cui rappresentazioni derivano da differenti storie e mitologie. Lo stesso accade per la divinità lucertoloide Omorr e quella degli uomini Oghma. Quale delle due razze abbia la rappresentazione "corretta" è un'argomento di discussione per i filosofi e studiosi, ciò che è certo è che i Sacerdoti di Kalshekk e Omorr possiedono abilità simili a quelle delle loro controparti delle altre religioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Mazatl worship a number of different deities, but primarily Kalshekk and Omorr. Whilst none of these deities are exactly the same as those worshipped amongst the human population of Erebus, they do share aspects with some of them. Kalshekk for instance shares many similarities with Kilmorph, to the point that it is believed that both have the same origin but the current representations are derived from differing histories and mythologies. The same is true of the lizard deity Omorr and the human deity Oghma. Whether either race has the "correct" representation is a matter for philosophers and scholars to debate, but what is known is that the Priests of Kalshekk and Omorr display abilities akin to those of their counterpart religions.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WYVERN</Tag>
		<English>Wyvern</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Wyverne:Wyvernes</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Wyvern</German>
		<Italian>Viverna</Italian>
		<Spanish>Wyvern</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
