<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - Units -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GRETCHIN</Tag>
		<English>Gretchin</English>
		<French>Gretchin</French>
		<German>Gretchin</German>
		<Italian>Gretchin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gretchin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GRETCHIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Gretchin are goblin labourers (or perhaps that should be slaves), the lowest rung of Orcish society. They are drawn from the ranks of "goblins who looked at an orc funny" or "goblins who spilled an orc's drink" and other assorted heinous crimes. Forced into labour by their orcish masters, the Gretchin are motivated by little more than fear. They have makeshift tools, no training, a poor work ethic, and little oversight. The only thing that they have in their favour, is numbers. My god do they have numbers.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Goblins are among the weakest, and most numerous species in Erebus. Known for their short life cycles, copious breeding habits, and vicious backstabbing tendancies. Though pitiful when used as a military, they can make a quite effective meatshield to slow down or wound incoming armies to the Orcish territory. Gretchin are duplicated by warrens, and don't consume food to build, so you can start creating them right from turn 1[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]No matter how improbable it may seem, if you throw enough goblins at a building site, the project will eventually be finished to some reasonably functional state. And the ones who die of exhaustion in the process will be eaten by the others, so you don't even have to feed the little buggers. How's that for cheap labour?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]The hardest working goblins are rewarded with only slightly less beating and kicking than the others. And Gretchin spend most of their non-working time looking for food and avoiding angry orcs, so unlike other races' workers, they have neither the time nor incentive to improve and become better at their job. Experience would be wasted on them anyway. Gretchin are the very definition of expendable. A popular orcish campfire tale tells of how the gretchin built a mine near a griffon nest. They simply sent goblins to the building site one after another, until the beasts were exhausted from slaughtering so many victims. Then the poor griffons were swarmed and died under a thousand goblin knives.</English>
		<French>Gretchin are goblin labourers (or perhaps that should be slaves), the lowest rung of Orcish society. They are drawn from the ranks of "goblins who looked at an orc funny" or "goblins who spilled an orc's drink" and other assorted heinous crimes. Forced into labour by their orcish masters, the Gretchin are motivated by little more than fear. They have makeshift tools, no training, a poor work ethic, and little oversight. The only thing that they have in their favour, is numbers. My god do they have numbers.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Goblins are among the weakest, and most numerous species in Erebus. Known for their short life cycles, copious breeding habits, and vicious backstabbing tendancies. Though pitiful when used as a military, they can make a quite effective meatshield to slow down or wound incoming armies to the Orcish territory. Gretchin are duplicated by warrens, and don't consume food to build, so you can start creating them right from turn 1[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]No matter how improbable it may seem, if you throw enough goblins at a building site, the project will eventually be finished to some reasonably functional state. And the ones who die of exhaustion in the process will be eaten by the others, so you don't even have to feed the little buggers. How's that for cheap labour?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]The hardest working goblins are rewarded with only slightly less beating and kicking than the others. And Gretchin spend most of their non-working time looking for food and avoiding angry orcs, so unlike other races' workers, they have neither the time nor incentive to improve and become better at their job. Experience would be wasted on them anyway. Gretchin are the very definition of expendable. A popular orcish campfire tale tells of how the gretchin built a mine near a griffon nest. They simply sent goblins to the building site one after another, until the beasts were exhausted from slaughtering so many victims. Then the poor griffons were swarmed and died under a thousand goblin knives.</French>
		<German>Gretchin sind Goblinarbeiter (oder eigentlich Sklaven), der niedrigste Rang in der Gesellschaft der Orks. Sie rekrutieren sich aus "Goblins, die einen Ork schief angeschaut haben" oder "Goblins, die das Getränk eines Orks verschüttet haben" und anderen Schwerverbrechern. Von ihren orkischen Meistern zur Arbeit gezwungen, arbeiten Gretchin aus keiner anderen Motivation heraus als aus Angst. Sie nutzen selbstgebastelte Werkzeuge, haben keinerlei Ausbildung, eine schlechte Arbeitsmoral und wenig überblick. Den einzigen Vorteil, den man Gretchin zusprechen muss, ist ihre Anzahl. Mein Gott, was für eine Anzahl.
		[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Goblins gehören zu den schwächsten und zahlreichsten Spezies von Erebus. Sie sind bekannt für kurze Lebensdauer, beeindruckende Fortpflanzungsraten und hinterhältigen Machenschaften. Auch wenn sie erbärmliche Krieger darstellen, können sie doch als eine beeindruckende Fleischwand genutzt werden, die in orkisches Territorium einfallende Armeen verlangsamt oder verletzt. Gretchin werden in Gehegen verdoppelt und benötigen zum Bau keine Nahrung, also los, man kann so ab der ersten Runde haben![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Wie unangebracht die Bemerkung auch scheinen mag, wenn man nur genug Goblins auf eine Baustelle schickt, wird das Bauvorhaben tatsächlich irgendwann fertig und das auch noch in einem zufriedenstellenden Zustand. Und dejenigen, die es nicht überleben und während des Baus an Erschöpfung sterben, stellen die Nahrung der anderen dar, man muss die kleinen Racker also nicht einmal füttern. Klingt das nicht angenehm nach billiger Arbeitskraft?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Die am härtesten arbeitenden Goblins werden damit belohnt, dass sie etwas weniger Tritte und Schläge abbekommen als die anderen. Und da Gretchin ihre freie Zeit (also die Zeit, in der sie mal nicht arbeiten) damit verbringen, sich selbst etwas zu essen zu suchen und wütenden Orks aus dem Weg zu gehen, haben sie weder die Zeit noch den Willen, sich in ihrer Arbeit zu verbessern. Erfahrung wäre ohnehin bei ihnen verschwendet. Gretchin sind der Inbegriff von entbehrlich. Eine beliebte orkische Lagerfeuergeschichte handelt von Gretchin, die eine Mine in der Nähe eines Greifennests bauen wollten. Sie schickten einfach nacheinander Scharen von Goblins zur Baustelle, bis die wilden Tiere zu erschöpft vom Schlachten der unzähligen Opfer waren. Dann wurden die armen Greifen von den Horden der Goblins überwältigt und starben durch die Klingen der tausend Goblinmesser.</German>
		<Italian>Gretchin are goblin labourers (or perhaps that should be slaves), the lowest rung of Orcish society. They are drawn from the ranks of "goblins who looked at an orc funny" or "goblins who spilled an orc's drink" and other assorted heinous crimes. Forced into labour by their orcish masters, the Gretchin are motivated by little more than fear. They have makeshift tools, no training, a poor work ethic, and little oversight. The only thing that they have in their favour, is numbers. My god do they have numbers.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Goblins are among the weakest, and most numerous species in Erebus. Known for their short life cycles, copious breeding habits, and vicious backstabbing tendancies. Though pitiful when used as a military, they can make a quite effective meatshield to slow down or wound incoming armies to the Orcish territory. Gretchin are duplicated by warrens, and don't consume food to build, so you can start creating them right from turn 1[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]No matter how improbable it may seem, if you throw enough goblins at a building site, the project will eventually be finished to some reasonably functional state. And the ones who die of exhaustion in the process will be eaten by the others, so you don't even have to feed the little buggers. How's that for cheap labour?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]The hardest working goblins are rewarded with only slightly less beating and kicking than the others. And Gretchin spend most of their non-working time looking for food and avoiding angry orcs, so unlike other races' workers, they have neither the time nor incentive to improve and become better at their job. Experience would be wasted on them anyway. Gretchin are the very definition of expendable. A popular orcish campfire tale tells of how the gretchin built a mine near a griffon nest. They simply sent goblins to the building site one after another, until the beasts were exhausted from slaughtering so many victims. Then the poor griffons were swarmed and died under a thousand goblin knives.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gretchin are goblin labourers (or perhaps that should be slaves), the lowest rung of Orcish society. They are drawn from the ranks of "goblins who looked at an orc funny" or "goblins who spilled an orc's drink" and other assorted heinous crimes. Forced into labour by their orcish masters, the Gretchin are motivated by little more than fear. They have makeshift tools, no training, a poor work ethic, and little oversight. The only thing that they have in their favour, is numbers. My god do they have numbers.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]Goblins are among the weakest, and most numerous species in Erebus. Known for their short life cycles, copious breeding habits, and vicious backstabbing tendancies. Though pitiful when used as a military, they can make a quite effective meatshield to slow down or wound incoming armies to the Orcish territory.Gretchin are duplicated by warrens, and don't consume food to build, so you can start creating them right from turn 1[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]No matter how improbable it may seem, if you throw enough goblins at a building site, the project will eventually be finished to some reasonably functional state. And the ones who die of exhaustion in the process will be eaten by the others, so you don't even have to feed the little buggers. How's that for cheap labour?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH]The hardest working goblins are rewarded with only slightly less beating and kicking than the others. And Gretchin spend most of their non-working time looking for food and avoiding angry orcs, so unlike other races' workers, they have neither the time nor incentive to improve and become better at their job. Experience would be wasted on them anyway. Gretchin are the very definition of expendable. A popular orcish campfire tale tells of how the gretchin built a mine near a griffon nest. They simply sent goblins to the building site one after another, until the beasts were exhausted from slaughtering so many victims. Then the poor griffons were swarmed and died under a thousand goblin knives.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_GOBLIN</Tag>
		<English>Goblinoid</English>
		<French>Gobelinoïde</French>
		<German>Goblin</German>
		<Italian>Goblinoid</Italian>
		<Spanish>Goblinoid</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>