<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIPPUS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Hippus</English>
		<French>hippusque:hippusque:hippusques:hippusques</French>
		<German>Hippusisch</German>
		<Italian>Hippus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hippus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIPPUS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Hippus</English>
		<French>Hippus</French>
		<German>Reich der Hippus</German>
		<Italian>Hippus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hippus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIPPUS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Hippus</English>
		<French>Hippusques</French>
		<German>Hippus</German>
		<Italian>Hippus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hippus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIPPUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Hippus are the undisputed king of mounted units, gaining extra movement and withdrawal chance to all mounted units and starting with horses. Their mercenaries are swifter than those of other nations as well. [PARAGRAPH:1] The Hippus were always justly proud of their animal husbandry. Their lands, even in the Age of Magic, had fertile hills that teemed with sheep and wide plains with vast herds of horses that they tamed very shortly after the Compact, passing this trade down in their tribes since time immemorial. However in Patria magic surpassed the use of horses for most purposes. Great creatures were conjured for war, portals allowed rapid travel, and golems toiled endlessly in the fields. Then came the great upheaval of Patria, when magicians turned against each other, battling for the soul of the empire of man. Kylorin called upon the Hippus people to help him hunt down his wayward servants as the portals across Erebus were closed, and when Demons and Elementals were banished the wild Hippus raiders were still there to charge down enemy warrior mages. These exploits brought great renown to a people formerly ignored in the great empire, even as the empire crumbled. This new-found pride crippled the Hippus, breeding a fierce martial competitiveness. Their clans, even while nominally aligned, would refuse each other's help and even raid each other. They were able to hold back the advances of the frostling hordes of the Age of Ice, though many Hippus communities were wiped out by a frost golem assault rather than seek the aid of their cohorts. [PARAGRAPH:1] As the other great nations emerged into the Age of Rebirth, the Hippus turned to raid them, as well as each other, until this proud people looked to be eclipsed by peoples more united and disciplined. Rhoanna, who inherited leadership of a small Hippus tribe, made it her mission to unite her people without losing their culture. She formed the Hippus mercenary companies, and made their martial prowess and competitiveness serve them rather then consume them. Tasunke was the most famous raider amongst the Hippus; it was expected that he would challenge her for leadership, but he embraced her idea, seeing foreign gold as a better measure of a tribe's prowess than slain kinsmen. </English>
		<French>[TAB]The Hippus are the undisputed king of mounted units, gaining extra movement and withdrawal chance to all mounted units and starting with horses. Their mercenaries are swifter than those of other nations as well. [PARAGRAPH:1] The Hippus were always justly proud of their animal husbandry. Their lands, even in the Age of Magic, had fertile hills that teemed with sheep and wide plains with vast herds of horses that they tamed very shortly after the Compact, passing this trade down in their tribes since time immemorial. However in Patria magic surpassed the use of horses for most purposes. Great creatures were conjured for war, portals allowed rapid travel, and golems toiled endlessly in the fields. Then came the great upheaval of Patria, when magicians turned against each other, battling for the soul of the empire of man. Kylorin called upon the Hippus people to help him hunt down his wayward servants as the portals across Erebus were closed, and when Demons and Elementals were banished the wild Hippus raiders were still there to charge down enemy warrior mages. These exploits brought great renown to a people formerly ignored in the great empire, even as the empire crumbled. This new-found pride crippled the Hippus, breeding a fierce martial competitiveness. Their clans, even while nominally aligned, would refuse each other's help and even raid each other. They were able to hold back the advances of the frostling hordes of the Age of Ice, though many Hippus communities were wiped out by a frost golem assault rather than seek the aid of their cohorts. [PARAGRAPH:1] As the other great nations emerged into the Age of Rebirth, the Hippus turned to raid them, as well as each other, until this proud people looked to be eclipsed by peoples more united and disciplined. Rhoanna, who inherited leadership of a small Hippus tribe, made it her mission to unite her people without losing their culture. She formed the Hippus mercenary companies, and made their martial prowess and competitiveness serve them rather then consume them. Tasunke was the most famous raider amongst the Hippus; it was expected that he would challenge her for leadership, but he embraced her idea, seeing foreign gold as a better measure of a tribe's prowess than slain kinsmen. </French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Hippus sind die unangefochtenen Könige der Berittenen Einheiten, da alle ihre Berittenen Einheiten über zusätzliche Bewegungspunkte und eine erhöhte Rückzugsmöglichkeit verfügen und sie zudem mit Pferden beginnen. Ihre Söldner sind außerdem flinker als diejenigen anderer Reiche.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Hippus waren immer mit Recht stolz auf ihre Viehhaltung. Ihre Ländereien bestanden, selbst im Zeitalter der Magie, aus fruchtbaren Hügeln, die vor Schafen wimmelten, und weiten Ebenen mit gewaltigen Pferdeherden, die sie kurz nach Unterzeichnung des Paktes zähmten und dann dieses Handwerk in ihren Stämmen seit alters her weitergaben. Allerdings machte die Magie den Einsatz von Pferden für die meisten Zwecke in Patria überflüssig. Große Kreaturen wurden für Kriege beschworen, Portale erlaubten schnelles Reisen und Golems schufteten pausenlos auf den Feldern. Dann geschah der große Aufstand von Patria, als sich Zauberer gegeneinander wandten und um die Seele des Menschenimperiums kämpften. Kylorin rief das Volk der Hippus um Hilfe an, um seine unberechenbaren Diener zu jagen, als die Portale überall auf Erebus verschlossen wurden. Und als Dämonen und Elementare gebannt waren, waren die wilden Räuber der Hippus immer noch dabei, feindliche Kampfmagier niederzureiten. Diese Heldentaten brachten einem Volk großes Ansehen, das zuvor im großen Imperium immer übergangen worden war, selbst als dieses Imperium zerfiel. Dieser neu entdeckte Stolz lähmte die Hippus und gebar ein grimmiges, kriegerisches Konkurrenzdenken. Ihre Klans begannen, sich gegenseitige Hilfe zu verweigern und sich sogar gegenseitig zu überfallen, selbst wenn sie eigentlich verbündet waren. Sie waren in der Lage den Vormarsch der Frostling-Horden des Zeitalters des Eises zu bremsen, auch wenn sich viele hippusische Gemeinschaften lieber bei einem Angriff von Frostgolems aufreiben ließen, als dass sie die Hilfe ihrer Kohorte in Anspruch nahmen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Während die anderen großen Reiche ins Zeitalter der Wiedergeburt strebten, überfielen die Hippus sie auch weiterhin, ebenso wie einander, bis dieses stolze Volk erkannte, dass es von geeinteren und disziplinierteren Völkern bald in den Schatten gestellt werden würde. Rhoanna, die die Führung eines kleinen hippusischen Stammes inne hatte, machte es sich zur Aufgabe, ihr Volk zu einen, ohne ihre Kultur aufgeben zu müssen. Sie stellte die hippusischen Söldnerkompanien auf und schaffte es, ihre kriegerischen Fähigkeiten und ihr Konkurrenzdenken in Stärken umzuwandeln, die sie nicht mehr aufzehrten. Tasunke war der berühmteste Räuber der Hippus: es war erwartet worden, dass er sie zu einem Kampf um die Herrschaft herausfordern würde, aber er schloss sich breitwillig ihrem Argument an, dass ausländisches Gold ein besseres Maß für die Fähigkeiten eines Stammes sei, als getötete Blutsbrüder.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Gli Hippus sono i signori indiscussi delle unità montate, avendo movimento extra e probabilità di ritirarsi per tutte le unità montate, e iniziando con la risorsa Cavalli. Anche i loro mercenari sono più veloci di quelli delle altre civiltà. [PARAGRAPH:1] Gli Hippus sono sempre stati giustamente orgogliosi del legame con i loro animali. Le loro terre, anche nell'Era della Magia, avevano colline fertili piene di pecore e ampie pianure con grandi mandrie di cavalli che addomesticarono subito dopo la firma del Patto, questa tradizione viene tramandata nelle loro tribù da tempo immemore. Tuttavia in Patria la magia aveva surpassato l'uso del cavallo per la maggior parte dei lavori. Grandi creature venivano evocate per la guerra, dei portali permettevano viaggi rapidi e i golem lavoravano i campi senza fermarsi. Poi arrivvò la grande sommossa di Patria, in cui gli incantatori si scontrarono gli uni con gli altri, combattendo per l'anima dell'impero dell'uomo. Kylorin chiese al popolo Hippus di aiutarlo nel dare la caccia ai suoi servitori ribelli in quanto i portali su Erebus erano stati tutti sigillati, oltre al fatto che quando i Demoni e gli Elementali venivano banditi i selvaggi razziatori Hippus erano ancora presenti per attaccare i maghi guerrieri nemici. Queste imprese portarono grande fama a un popolo precedentemente ignorato dal grande impero e questa fama perdurò anche dopo che l'impero si sgretolò. Questo nuovo orgoglio però danneggiò gli Hippus, causando una feroce competizione marziale. I loro clan, anche se nominalmente alleati, rifiutavano l'aiuto da parte degli altri e si razziavano a vicenda. Sebbene riuscirono ha fermare l'avanzata delle orde di frostling dell'Era del Ghiaccio molte comunità Hippus furono distrutte dagli assalti di golem di ghiaccio piuttosto che cercare l'aiuto dei loro simili. [PARAGRAPH:1] Quando le altre grandi nazioni comparvero nell'Era della Rinascità gli Hippus iniziarono a razziarle, oltre a razziarsi a vicenda, fino a quando questo fiero popolo sembrò venir ecclissato da popoli più uniti e disciplinati. Rhoanna, che aveva ereditato la guida di una piccola tribù Hippus, si prese il compito di unire il suo popolo senza far perdergli la sua cultura. Plasmò gli Hippus in compagnie mercenarie, e fece in modo che l'abilità marziale e la competitività divennerò dei punti di forza più che di debolezza. Tasunke era il razziatore più famoso tra gli Hippus; molti si aspettavano che la avrebbe sfidata per il posto di guida, invece lui accolse le idee di lei, vedendo nella quantita di oro straniero posseduto un modo migliore per misurare l'abilità di una tribù rispetto al numero di simili uccisi. </Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Hippus are the undisputed king of mounted units, gaining extra movement and withdrawal chance to all mounted units and starting with horses. Their mercenaries are swifter than those of other nations as well. [PARAGRAPH:1] The Hippus were always justly proud of their animal husbandry. Their lands, even in the Age of Magic, had fertile hills that teemed with sheep and wide plains with vast herds of horses that they tamed very shortly after the Compact, passing this trade down in their tribes since time immemorial. However in Patria magic surpassed the use of horses for most purposes. Great creatures were conjured for war, portals allowed rapid travel, and golems toiled endlessly in the fields. Then came the great upheaval of Patria, when magicians turned against each other, battling for the soul of the empire of man. Kylorin called upon the Hippus people to help him hunt down his wayward servants as the portals across Erebus were closed, and when Demons and Elementals were banished the wild Hippus raiders were still there to charge down enemy warrior mages. These exploits brought great renown to a people formerly ignored in the great empire, even as the empire crumbled. This new-found pride crippled the Hippus, breeding a fierce martial competitiveness. Their clans, even while nominally aligned, would refuse each other's help and even raid each other. They were able to hold back the advances of the frostling hordes of the Age of Ice, though many Hippus communities were wiped out by a frost golem assault rather than seek the aid of their cohorts. [PARAGRAPH:1] As the other great nations emerged into the Age of Rebirth, the Hippus turned to raid them, as well as each other, until this proud people looked to be eclipsed by peoples more united and disciplined. Rhoanna, who inherited leadership of a small Hippus tribe, made it her mission to unite her people without losing their culture. She formed the Hippus mercenary companies, and made their martial prowess and competitiveness serve them rather then consume them. Tasunke was the most famous raider amongst the Hippus; it was expected that he would challenge her for leadership, but he embraced her idea, seeing foreign gold as a better measure of a tribe's prowess than slain kinsmen. </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HIPPUS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Strategy:
[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Hippus are masters of rush tactics, they can come screaming out of the fog of war faster then almost anyone else, and with high movement are able to keep up the pressure, allowing them to turn early military might into lands, cities, and resources.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]A key piece of the Hippus war plan is their world spell, [LINK=SPELL_WARCRY]Warcry[\LINK], giving the Hippus troops extra movement and attack. It only applies to existing units when cast, so make it count![NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]To maximize the advantage of an early rush you will want to use your free access to [LINK=BONUS_HORSE]Horses[\LINK], and beeline [LINK=TECH_HORSEBACK_RIDING]Horseback Riding[\LINK], to get your army up and running, but once you crush your nearest neighbor, what then? you will want to have [LINK=BUILDING_MARKET]Markets[\LINK], from [LINK=TECH_FESTIVALS]Festivals[\LINK], to stabilize your early economy. On later conquests you can also use [LINK=TECH_WRITING]Writing[\LINK], to bully your defeated rivals into giving you much needed tech in exchange for short lived peace.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Hippus Scouts are mounted, and able to [LINK=SPELL_DRIVE_CATTLE]Drive Cattle[\LINK], allowing them to rustle animal resources and bring them back to Hippus lands for pasture.</English>
		<French>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Stratégie : Les Hippus commencent avec la ressource Cheval et toutes leurs unités montées sont des versions améliorées par rapport à la normale leur conférant une armée extrêmement mobile. Magnadine, leur héros, convertira à la cause hippus tout barbare vaincu, et il peut louer des mercenaires - qui rejoindront les Hippus pour la moitié du coût normal.</French>
		<German>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategie: Die Hippus beginnen mit Pferden, und alle ihre berittenen Einheiten sind verbesserte Versionen der normalen, was ihnen eine erstaunlich bewegliche Armee verleiht. Magnadine, ihr Held, wird jede Art von besiegten Barbaren zu der Sache der Hippus bekehren, und er kann Söldner anwerben - welche den Hippus für die Hälfte der normalen Kosten beitreten.</German>
		<Italian>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategia: Gli Hippus iniziano con la risorsa Cavalli e tutte le loro unità montate sono una versione migliorata di quelle normali permettendogli cosi di avere un esercito incredibilmente mobile. Nel caso gli Hippus prendano contatti con la Gilda dei Nove, scopriranno che i mercenari che reclutano sono anche loro rapide unità montate. I tratti di Rhoanna sono molto adatti per scoprire tecnologie pacificamente fino a quando non decide di entrare in guerra, invece Tasunke potrebbe dover affidarsi al suo tratto Razziatore per ottenere un vantaggio economico dal saccheggiare.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Estrategia: Los Hippus empiezan con caballos y todas sus unidades montadas son versiones mejoradas de las normales, dándoles un ejército increiblemente maniobrable. Magnadine, su héroe, convertirá a cualquier unidad bárbara a la causa de los Hippus, y puede contratar mercenarios, que se unirán al Hippus por la mitad del coste normal.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_RHOANNA</Tag>
		<English>Rhoanna</English>
		<French>Rhoanna</French>
		<German>Rhoanna</German>
		<Italian>Rhoanna</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rhoanna</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_RHOANNA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Those born to the saddle become as one with their mount. In battle, this means the horse will evade incoming attacks, turn a second before you urge it to, and push itself harder than it would for anyone else. On a journey, even an urgent one such as this, it means one can let her mind wander.[PARAGRAPH:1]She was the daughter of a chieftain of a minor tribe. Her father was constantly warring with the other Hippus tribes: leading his raiders against their herds; drunkenly bragging of his valor by the campfires; scheming ways to gain some petty advantage. She wanted to scream at him, "You foolish old brute! Can't you see that our people are dying? Killing each other over honor, over imagined slights, as day by day the nations encroach on our land, their cities and armies pushing us ever closer and we turn on each other? Wake up! Think of something!" Then one raid, he didn't come back. Nor her brother. And her people turned to her.[PARAGRAPH:2]A fateful battle, almost costing their tribe it's young new leader, Rhoanna caught up in the tribe's expectations, raiding their neighbors. But they had deserved it this time, had raided her people and stolen their heartiest rams. She learned the hard way that she was not the warrior her father was. She was imposing in her family's armor, but when the time came to strike a blow at her cousins, she hesitated. Her adversary had no such delay. His swing was quick. Her parry awkward. In the dirt, confusion, hooves all about, clamor... She made it out alive to join in the retreat. The lifelong pain in her shoulder was worth the lesson-she could not continue the status quo, or she, and her people, would be trampled.[PARAGRAPH:2]The third council meeting was pivotal. Half the tribes had joined her band. The weaker half. Tasunke was the key to the rest. The esteem he was held in could sway the strongest tribes if he agreed to join her coalition.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Well, ye've come all this way, lass, have your say and be gone. The Aroul-Hippi need no one, least of all your rag-tag band." This boast earned a hearty laugh from his companions.[PARAGRAPH:1]That bravado was key, she told herself. I must make his honor drag him to us. "Rag-tag? Perhaps. Better to join together than be defeated as the Aroul."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You boast of a battle that never has been, little mare, but if you think you are man enough to take us, bring your riders-"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I speak not of a defeat at our hands, Tasunke, but one already suffered. Else why do your sheep not graze on the hills of Nimarail? Surely the grass grows as lush there as ever?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Our sheep are happier on the hills of the Conneb-Hippi." Tasunke said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, surely. It couldn't be because you fear the Amurites. Doubtless their magic blood means nothing to your brave warriors, and you merely let your sheep lead you about like lambs." She got some laughs, even some from the Aroul. "Then what about the valley of Caledor? Have the Boy-King's shepherds unmanned you?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Who is a woman to speak of manhood?" he roared. "Do you seek to see us run through by the endless armies of these empires around us? Or have you the courage to fight us yourself?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"No, Tasunke, I do not want to see the Aroul destroyed! You are the strongest-where goes the Aroul-Hippi, so goes all our people. We must put aside our pride, for the sake of our survival. Nations and empires surround us; we have this choice: cooperate or die. Let the Hippus ride as one!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Even so, we have not the strength combined to take on the least of these nations. Do you think you are the only one to realize our fate? Leave us to our games, girl."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You are right. We do not have the numbers of others. But our courage, our prowess, and our honor are legendary. The Amurites, the Kuriotates, the Elohim, huddled in their cities, what do you think they would give for these virtues? Whatever we ask."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You wish us to become merchants?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Just think of it as another kind of raiding."[PARAGRAPH:2]With this latest contract, Tasunke leading the forces, didn't know that their prey had offered more than their employer. A sea route would have gotten her from the negotiations to the staging area in time-if it weren't for that pirate. Falamar had intercepted her ship, sent her captain away, and absconded with her. For taking her on a trip she already paid for, he cost her the profits from the entire venture. He had turned the tables on the Hippus and raided her. So why couldn't she bring herself, her battle trained, horse-borne self to hate him?</English>
		<French>[TAB]Those born to the saddle become as one with their mount. In battle, this means the horse will evade incoming attacks, turn a second before you urge it to, and push itself harder than it would for anyone else. On a journey, even an urgent one such as this, it means one can let her mind wander.[PARAGRAPH:1]She was the daughter of a chieftain of a minor tribe. Her father was constantly warring with the other Hippus tribes: leading his raiders against their herds; drunkenly bragging of his valor by the campfires; scheming ways to gain some petty advantage. She wanted to scream at him, "You foolish old brute! Can't you see that our people are dying? Killing each other over honor, over imagined slights, as day by day the nations encroach on our land, their cities and armies pushing us ever closer and we turn on each other? Wake up! Think of something!" Then one raid, he didn't come back. Nor her brother. And her people turned to her.[PARAGRAPH:2]A fateful battle, almost costing their tribe it's young new leader, Rhoanna caught up in the tribe's expectations, raiding their neighbors. But they had deserved it this time, had raided her people and stolen their heartiest rams. She learned the hard way that she was not the warrior her father was. She was imposing in her family's armor, but when the time came to strike a blow at her cousins, she hesitated. Her adversary had no such delay. His swing was quick. Her parry awkward. In the dirt, confusion, hooves all about, clamor... She made it out alive to join in the retreat. The lifelong pain in her shoulder was worth the lesson-she could not continue the status quo, or she, and her people, would be trampled.[PARAGRAPH:2]The third council meeting was pivotal. Half the tribes had joined her band. The weaker half. Tasunke was the key to the rest. The esteem he was held in could sway the strongest tribes if he agreed to join her coalition.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Well, ye've come all this way, lass, have your say and be gone. The Aroul-Hippi need no one, least of all your rag-tag band." This boast earned a hearty laugh from his companions.[PARAGRAPH:1]That bravado was key, she told herself. I must make his honor drag him to us. "Rag-tag? Perhaps. Better to join together than be defeated as the Aroul."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You boast of a battle that never has been, little mare, but if you think you are man enough to take us, bring your riders-"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I speak not of a defeat at our hands, Tasunke, but one already suffered. Else why do your sheep not graze on the hills of Nimarail? Surely the grass grows as lush there as ever?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Our sheep are happier on the hills of the Conneb-Hippi." Tasunke said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, surely. It couldn't be because you fear the Amurites. Doubtless their magic blood means nothing to your brave warriors, and you merely let your sheep lead you about like lambs." She got some laughs, even some from the Aroul. "Then what about the valley of Caledor? Have the Boy-King's shepherds unmanned you?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Who is a woman to speak of manhood?" he roared. "Do you seek to see us run through by the endless armies of these empires around us? Or have you the courage to fight us yourself?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"No, Tasunke, I do not want to see the Aroul destroyed! You are the strongest-where goes the Aroul-Hippi, so goes all our people. We must put aside our pride, for the sake of our survival. Nations and empires surround us; we have this choice: cooperate or die. Let the Hippus ride as one!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Even so, we have not the strength combined to take on the least of these nations. Do you think you are the only one to realize our fate? Leave us to our games, girl."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You are right. We do not have the numbers of others. But our courage, our prowess, and our honor are legendary. The Amurites, the Kuriotates, the Elohim, huddled in their cities, what do you think they would give for these virtues? Whatever we ask."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You wish us to become merchants?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Just think of it as another kind of raiding."[PARAGRAPH:2]With this latest contract, Tasunke leading the forces, didn't know that their prey had offered more than their employer. A sea route would have gotten her from the negotiations to the staging area in time-if it weren't for that pirate. Falamar had intercepted her ship, sent her captain away, and absconded with her. For taking her on a trip she already paid for, he cost her the profits from the entire venture. He had turned the tables on the Hippus and raided her. So why couldn't she bring herself, her battle trained, horse-borne self to hate him?</French>
		<German>[TAB]Diejenigen, die schon auf einem Sattel geboren wurden, wurden eins mit dem Reittier. Im Kampf bedeutet das, dass das Pferd Angriffen ausweichen wird, schon bevor der Reiter es dazu drängt, es wird sich mehr Mühe geben als für irgendjemand anders. Auf einer Reise, auch wenn diese noch so eilig ist, kann man deshalb seine Gedanken umherwandern lassen. [PARAGRAPH:1]Sie war die Tochter des Häuptlinges eines kleineren Stammes. Ihr Vater führte ständig Krieg gegen andere Stämme der Hippus: er überfiel deren Herden; betrunken prahlte er mit seinem Mut, während sie am Lagerfeuer verweilten, ständig intrigierend, um ein paar nette Vorteile zu gewinnen. Sie wollte ihn anschreien "Du alter brutaler Narr! Bemerkst du nicht, wie deine Leute sterben? Ihr tötet euch gegenseitig der Ehre halber und wegen eingebildeten Beleidigungen, während andere Nationen von Tag zu Tag mehr von unseren Ländereien übernehmen! Ihre Städte und Armeen drängen uns immer weiter zurück, und wir bekämpfen uns gegenseitig? Wach auf! Denk darüber nach!" Eines Tages kehrte er von einem Überfall nicht mehr zurück, ebenso wenig wie ihr Bruder. Nun wandten sich ihre Leute an sie.[PARAGRAPH:2]Nach einer schicksalhaften Schlacht, die beinahe dem Stamm ihre neue Anführerin gekostet hatte, erfüllte sie die Erwartungen ihrer Leute und plünderte ihre Nachbarn. Aber diesmal hatten ihre Feinde es verdient, sie hatten ihre Leute zuvor überfallen und ihre liebsten Tiere gestohlen. Sie lernte auf die schmerzhafte Art, dass sie nicht der Krieger ist, der ihr Vater war. Sie wirkte eindrucksvoll, wenn sie die Familienrüstung trug, doch wenn es darum ging, ihren Cousins einen Schlag zu versetzen, zögerte sie. Ihr Gegner hatte nicht solche Bedenken. Er griff blitzschnell an, ihre Parade ungelenk. Sie lag verwirrt im Dreck, überall Hufe um sie herum, und Schreie. Sie entkam lebend und trat den Rückzug an. Der lebenslange Schmerz, den sie davon trug, lehrte ihr, dass es nicht so weitergehen konnte. Wenn sie und ihre Leute so weitermachen würden wie bisher, würden sie untergehen.[PARAGRAPH:2]Das dritte Ratstreffen war das alles Entscheidende. Die Hälfte der Stämme waren ihrer Truppe beigetreten. Die schwächere Hälfte. Tasunke war der Schlüssel zu den anderen. Sein Ruf könnte selbst die stärksten Stämme zum Umdenken bewegen, falls er ihrer Koalition beitreten sollte.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Nun da wir alle hier sind, mögest du uns mitteilen, was du zu sagen hast, und dann hinfort mit dir. Die Aroul-Hippi brauchen niemanden, am wenigsten eure Lumpentragende Truppe." Mit diesem Spruch erntete er herzhaftes Lachen von seinen Kameraden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Diese Prahlerei war der Schlüssel, sagte sie zu sich selbst. Ich muss ihn an seiner Ehre packen, damit er sich für uns entscheidet. "Lumpentragend? Vielleicht. Es ist besser, zusammen zu arbeiten, als besiegt zu werden wie die Aroul."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Du sprichst über einen Kampf, der niemals statt fand, kleine Stute, aber wenn du genug Mut hast uns anzugreifen, so hole deine Reiter..."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich spreche nicht von einer Niederlage, die dir von uns beigebracht wird, Tasunke, sondern von einer, die bereits stattfand. Warum sonst grasen deine Schafe nicht mehr an den Hügeln von Nimarail? Sicherlich ist das Gras dort so saftig wie immer?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Unsere Schafe sind an den Hügeln der Conneb-Hippi glücklicher" sagte Tasunke.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh sicher. Es kann natürlich nicht damit zusammenhängen, dass du die Amuriten fürchtest. Zweifellos kann ihre Blutmagie deinen mutigen Kriegern nichts anhaben, und du lässt dich von deinen Schafen leiten wie ein kleines Lamm." Einige lachten, sogar einzelne Aroul. "Und was ist mit dem Tal von Caledor? Haben die Schafherden des kindlichen Königs dir deine Männlichkeit gestohlen?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Wie kann eine Frau von Männlichkeit reden?" brüllte er. "Möchtest du dabei zusehen, wie wir von den endlosen Armeen der Imperien um uns herum überrannt werden? Oder wirst du den Mut haben, uns direkt anzugreifen?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Nein, Tasunke, ich möchte nicht mit Ansehen, wie die Aroul vernichtet werden! Ihr seid die Stärksten - wo die Aroul-Hippi hingehen, gehen alle unsere Leute hin. Um zu überleben, müssen wir unseren Stolz beiseite schieben. Nationen und Imperien umzingeln uns, deshalb haben wir nur die Wahl zusammenzuarbeiten oder zu sterben. Lasst die Hippus gemeinsam reiten!" [PARAGRAPH:1]"Selbst wenn wir das tun, reicht unsere geballte Stärke nicht aus, um auch nur die kleinste dieser Nationen zu bezwingen. Glaubst du etwa, dass du die Einzige bist, die unser Schicksal bemerkt? Lass uns in Ruhe, Mädchen."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Du hast recht, wir haben nicht die Truppenstärke der anderen. Aber unser Mut, unsere Tapferkeit und unsere Ehre sind legendär. Die Amuriten, die Kuriotaten und die Elohim, die zusammengepfercht in ihren Städten sitzen, was werden sie uns für diese Tugenden geben? Alles was wir verlangen."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Du möchtest, dass wir Händler werden?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Stell es dir nur als eine andere Form des Raubes vor."[PARAGRAPH:2]Mit dem letzten Vertrag wurde festgelegt, dass Tasunke die Truppen befehligt, nicht wissend, dass ihn mehr sein Stolz dazu brachte, als sein Verstand. Ein Schiff sollte sie vom Verhandlungsschauplatz fort bringen, doch ein Pirat kreuzte ihren Weg. Falamar fing ihr Schiff ab, entledigte sich des Kapitäns und flüchtete mit ihr. Nachdem er sie auf eine Reise mitnahm, für die sie schon gezahlt hatte, kostete er ihr die ganzen Profite ihres Unternehmens. Er nahm nun die Rolle der Hippus ein und raubte sie aus. Aber warum brachte sie ihren kampferprobten Körper dazu, ihn zu hassen?</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Coloro nati sulla sella diventano una cosa sola con la loro cavalcatura. In battaglia questo siginifica che il cavallo schiverà gli attacchi, cambierà direzione un secondo prima che li venga dato il comando, e si sforzerà in maniera maggiore di come farebbe per qualsiasi altro. In un viaggio, persino uno urgente come questo, significava poter lasciare vagare la mente.[PARAGRAPH:1]Lei era la figlia del capo di una tribù minore. Suo padre stava costantemente guerreggiando con le altre tribù Hippus: guidando i suoi razziatori contro le loro mandrie; vantandosi del suo valore da ubricao attorno al fuoco da campo; trovando modi per ottenere qualche piccolo vantaggio. Lei voleva urlargli, "Stupido vecchio bruto! Non riesci a vedere che il nostro popolo sta morendo? Uccidereci a vicenda per l'onore, per torti immagginari, mentre giorno dopo giorno le nazioni sconfinano nelle nostre terre, le loro città e i loro eserciti che ci spingono sempre più vicini e noi ci ammazziamo a vicenda? Svegliati! Pensa a qualcosa!" Poi in seguito a una razzia lui non tornò. Cosi come suo fratello. E la sua gente si rivolse a lei.[PARAGRAPH:2]In una battaglia fatidica, che quasi costò la vita alla nuova giovane condottiera della tribù, Rhoanna soddisfò le aspettative della sua tribù razziando i suoi vicini. Ma questa volta se lo meritavano, avendo razziato la sua gente e avendogli rubato le loro migliori capre. Lei imparò a sue spese che non era un guerriero come il padre. Era imponente dentro l'armatura di famiglia, ma quando arrivò il momento di colpire suo cugino lei esitò. Il suo avversario non fece altrettanto. Il suo fendente fu rapido. La sua parata goffa. In terra, confusione, zoccoli tutto intorno, clamore... Riuscì a sopravvivere per unirsi alla ritirata. Il dolore alla spalla, che sarebbe durato tutta la vita, gli era servito da lezione, non poteva far continuare lo status quo delle cose, o lei e il suo popolo sarebbero stati travolti.[PARAGRAPH:2]La terza riunione del consiglio fu fondamentale. Metà della tribù si era unità alla sua banda. La metà più debole. Tasunke era la chiave per il resto. Il rispetto di cui godeva avrebbe pututo influenzare le tribù più forti ad unirsi alla sua coalizione se lui avesse fatto altrettanto.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bene, tutti sapete come funziona, ragazza, di quello che devi dire e poi vattene. L'Aroul-Hippi non ha bisogno di nessuno, ancor meno della tua sgangherata banda." Questa spacconeria causò una vigorosa risata da parte dei suoi compagni.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quella spacconeria era la chiave, lei disse a se stessa. Devo fare in modo che il suo onore lo porti da noi. "Sgangherata? Forse. Meglio coalizzarsi che venir sconfitti come gli Aroul."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tu parli di una battaglia che non è mai avvenuta, piccola cavalla, ma se tu credi di essere abbastanza uomo da batterci porta i tuoi razziatori-"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Io non parlo di una sconfitta subita da noi, Tasunke, ma di una già avvenuta. Altrimenti perchè le vostre pecore non pascolano più sulle colline di Nimarail? Di sicuro li l'erba cresce rigogliosa come sempre?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Le nostre pecore sono più felici sulle colline dei Conneb-Hippi." Tasunke disse.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, di sicuro. Non può essere certo perche temi gli Amurite. Senza dubbio il loro sangue magico non significa niente ai tuoi impavidi guerrieri, e tu lasci che le tue pecore ti guidino come fossi un'agnello." Lei si guadagno qualche risata, persino da parte di qualche Aroul. "E che dire della valle di Caledor? I pastori del Re Ragazzo ti hanno evirato?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Come può una donna parlare di virilità?" Lui ruggi. "Vuoi vederci venir travolti dagli eserciti infiniti degli imperi che ci circondano? O hai il coraggio di affrontarci tu stessa?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"No, Tasunke, non voglio vedere gli Aroul venir distrutti! Tu sei il più forte, dove gli Aroul-Hippi vanno il nostro popolo segue. Dobbiamo mettere da parte il nostro orgoglio, per il bene della nostra sopravvivenza. Nazioni ed imperi ci circondano; dobbiamo scegliere: cooperare o morire. Lascia che gli Hippus cavalchino uniti!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Anche se fosse, non abbiamo la forza, neppure uniti, per vincere contro persino la più piccola di queste nazioni. Pensi di essere l'unica ad aver compreso il nostro destino? Lasciaci ai nostri giochi, ragazza."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hai ragione. Non abbiamo i numeri degli altri. Ma il nostro coraggio, la nostra abilità e il nostro coraggio sono leggendari. Gli Amurite, i Kuriotate, gli Elohim, si rannicchiano nelle loro città, cosa credi che darebbero per queste virtù? Qualunque cosa noi chiediamo."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ci vuoi vedere diventare mercanti?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Pensa ad esso come a un altro tipo di razzia."[PARAGRAPH:2]Con quest'ultimo contratto Tasunke, che era a capo delle forze, non sapeva che la loro preda aveva offerto più del loro datore di lavoro. Un passaggio via mare avrebbe portato in tempo lei al punto di raduno dalle negoziazioni, se non fosse stato per quel pirata. Falamar aveva intercettato la sua nave, mandato via il suo capitano, ed era scappato con lei. Per fargli fare il giro per cui lei aveva già pagato, lui gli costò tutti profitti dell'intera impresa. Aveva ribaltato il ruolo degli Hippus razziandola. Quindi perché non riusciva, con il suo spirito temprato dalla battaglia, ad odiarlo?</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Those born to the saddle become as one with their mount. In battle, this means the horse will evade incoming attacks, turn a second before you urge it to, and push itself harder than it would for anyone else. On a journey, even an urgent one such as this, it means one can let her mind wander.[PARAGRAPH:1]She was the daughter of a chieftain of a minor tribe. Her father was constantly warring with the other Hippus tribes: leading his raiders against their herds; drunkenly bragging of his valor by the campfires; scheming ways to gain some petty advantage. She wanted to scream at him, "You foolish old brute! Can't you see that our people are dying? Killing each other over honor, over imagined slights, as day by day the nations encroach on our land, their cities and armies pushing us ever closer and we turn on each other? Wake up! Think of something!" Then one raid, he didn't come back. Nor her brother. And her people turned to her.[PARAGRAPH:2]A fateful battle, almost costing their tribe it's young new leader, Rhoanna caught up in the tribe's expectations, raiding their neighbors. But they had deserved it this time, had raided her people and stolen their heartiest rams. She learned the hard way that she was not the warrior her father was. She was imposing in her family's armor, but when the time came to strike a blow at her cousins, she hesitated. Her adversary had no such delay. His swing was quick. Her parry awkward. In the dirt, confusion, hooves all about, clamor... She made it out alive to join in the retreat. The lifelong pain in her shoulder was worth the lesson-she could not continue the status quo, or she, and her people, would be trampled.[PARAGRAPH:2]The third council meeting was pivotal. Half the tribes had joined her band. The weaker half. Tasunke was the key to the rest. The esteem he was held in could sway the strongest tribes if he agreed to join her coalition.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Well, ye've come all this way, lass, have your say and be gone. The Aroul-Hippi need no one, least of all your rag-tag band." This boast earned a hearty laugh from his companions.[PARAGRAPH:1]That bravado was key, she told herself. I must make his honor drag him to us. "Rag-tag? Perhaps. Better to join together than be defeated as the Aroul."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You boast of a battle that never has been, little mare, but if you think you are man enough to take us, bring your riders-"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I speak not of a defeat at our hands, Tasunke, but one already suffered. Else why do your sheep not graze on the hills of Nimarail? Surely the grass grows as lush there as ever?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Our sheep are happier on the hills of the Conneb-Hippi." Tasunke said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh, surely. It couldn't be because you fear the Amurites. Doubtless their magic blood means nothing to your brave warriors, and you merely let your sheep lead you about like lambs." She got some laughs, even some from the Aroul. "Then what about the valley of Caledor? Have the Boy-King's shepherds unmanned you?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Who is a woman to speak of manhood?" he roared. "Do you seek to see us run through by the endless armies of these empires around us? Or have you the courage to fight us yourself?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"No, Tasunke, I do not want to see the Aroul destroyed! You are the strongest-where goes the Aroul-Hippi, so goes all our people. We must put aside our pride, for the sake of our survival. Nations and empires surround us; we have this choice: cooperate or die. Let the Hippus ride as one!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Even so, we have not the strength combined to take on the least of these nations. Do you think you are the only one to realize our fate? Leave us to our games, girl."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You are right. We do not have the numbers of others. But our courage, our prowess, and our honor are legendary. The Amurites, the Kuriotates, the Elohim, huddled in their cities, what do you think they would give for these virtues? Whatever we ask."[PARAGRAPH:1]"You wish us to become merchants?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Just think of it as another kind of raiding."[PARAGRAPH:2]With this latest contract, Tasunke leading the forces, didn't know that their prey had offered more than their employer. A sea route would have gotten her from the negotiations to the staging area in time-if it weren't for that pirate. Falamar had intercepted her ship, sent her captain away, and absconded with her. For taking her on a trip she already paid for, he cost her the profits from the entire venture. He had turned the tables on the Hippus and raided her. So why couldn't she bring herself, her battle trained, horse-borne self to hate him?</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_TASUNKE</Tag>
		<English>Tasunke</English>
		<French>Tasunke</French>
		<German>Tasunke</German>
		<Italian>Tasunke</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tasunke</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WARCRY</Tag>
		<English>Warcry</English>
		<French>Cri de Guerre</French>
		<German>Schlachtruf</German>
		<Italian>Grido di Guerra</Italian>
		<Spanish>Warcry</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WARCRY_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]All your units gain the [LINK=PROMOTION_WARCRY]Warcry[\LINK] promotion</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Toutes vos unités gagnent la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_WARCRY]Cri de Guerre[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Alle eure Einheiten erhalten die [LINK=PROMOTION_WARCRY]Schlachtruf[\LINK] Beförderung</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Tutte le tue unità ottengono la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_WARCRY]Grido di Guerra[\LINK]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]All your units gain the [LINK=PROMOTION_WARCRY]Warcry[\LINK] promotion</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_HIPPUS</Tag>
		<English>Hippus Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Hippus</French>
		<German>Palast der Hippus</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo degli Hippus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Hippus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HIPPUS_HORSELORD_FIELD</Tag>
		<English>Field of the Horselords</English>
		<French>Manège des Seigneurs équestres</French>
		<German>Land der Pferdefürsten</German>
		<Italian>Campo dei Signori dei Cavalli</Italian>
		<Spanish>Field of the Horselords</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HIPPUS_HORSELORD_FIELD_STRAT</Tag>
		<English>The Field of the Horselords gives all of your mounted units 2xp, trains them up to double the maximum on the normal Jousting Tilt, and is available earlier on the tech tree.  If you can't rule the mounted game with this, you should consider another civ and strategy.</English>
		<French>The Field of the Horselords gives all of your mounted units 2xp, trains them up to double the maximum on the normal Jousting Tilt, and is available earlier on the tech tree.  If you can't rule the mounted game with this, you should consider another civ and strategy.</French>
		<German>The Field of the Horselords gives all of your mounted units 2xp, trains them up to double the maximum on the normal Jousting Tilt, and is available earlier on the tech tree.  If you can't rule the mounted game with this, you should consider another civ and strategy.</German>
		<Italian>Il Campo dei Signori dei Cavalli da a tutte le tue unità montate 2 PE e le addestra sino ad un limite massimo doppio rispetto a quello della normale Giostra Equestre, ed è disponibile prima nell'albero tecnologico. Se non riesci a dominare la scena delle unità montate con questo dovresti cambiare civiltà e strategia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Field of the Horselords gives all of your mounted units 2xp, trains them up to double the maximum on the normal Jousting Tilt, and is available earlier on the tech tree.  If you can't rule the mounted game with this, you should consider another civ and strategy.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MAGNADINE</Tag>
		<English>Magnadine</English>
		<French>Magnadine</French>
		<German>Magnadin</German>
		<Italian>Magnadine</Italian>
		<Spanish>Magnadine</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MAGNADINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>A Superlative mounted unit, Magnadine can also recruit mercenary units to clean up behind him as he pushes deep into enemy territory or harries an assaulting force.</English>
		<French>Unité montée superlative, Magnadine peut aussi recruter des unités mercenaires pour nettoyer derrière lui lorsqu'il s'enfonce profondément en territoire ennemi ou lorsqu'il harcèle une force d'assaut.</French>
		<German>Eine super stark berittene Einheit, Magnadine kann Söldner rekrutieren, welche hinter seinem Rücken aufräumen, wenn er tief ins Feindesland vorgestoßen ist oder feindliche Angriffstruppen unter Druck setzen.</German>
		<Italian>Un'eccellente unità montata, Magnadine può inoltre reclutare unità mercenarie per ripulire la zona mentre lui continua ad avanzare dentro al territorio nemico o disturba le forze invasori.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A Superlative mounted unit, Magnadine can also recruit mercenary units to clean up behind him as he pushes deep into enemy territory or harries an assaulting force.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
