<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - Units -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARCHOS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Archosian</English>
		<French>archosien:archosienne:archosiens:archosiennes</French>
		<German>Arachonisch:Arachonischen:Arachonische</German>
		<Italian>Archosiano</Italian>
		<Spanish>Archosian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARCHOS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Archos</English>
		<French>Archos</French>
		<German>Reich der Arachonen</German>
		<Italian>Archos</Italian>
		<Spanish>Archos</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARCHOS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Archosian</English>
		<French>Archosiens</French>
		<German>Arachonen</German>
		<Italian>Archosiani</Italian>
		<Spanish>Archosian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARCHOS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>When the Age of Ice came upon Erebus, civilized men abandoned their cities and fled to the caves. In the darkness below the world, some managed to maintain their former society and heritage and waited out the Ice Age amongst friends. Others however were not so fortunate in their choice of cave. One such group were the Archos - a minor barbarian tribe during the Age of Magic. Fleeing the surface as the blizzards blasted their village, the Archosians fled into a large cave-complex. [PARAGRAPH:1]The tribe had not expected to abandon their village and had little time to prepare supplies in their hurried flight. The caves themselves offered little - save for shelter - and in desperation the tribe turned to eating the insects that dwelled in the upper caves. Scouts were sent to investigate further into the caves to find other food and when they returned days later, they carried with them a number of spider carcasses - each roughly the size of a man's head. The caves below teemed with these creatures and it seemed that - whilst unpleasant tasting - they would provide adequete food. A few tribesmen became ill at first, but over the years they developed an immunity to the poison. [PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]The immunity was not complete however. Slowly but surely the poison was building up in the bodies of the tribesmen and being passed down to the next generation. Some of the newborn showed signs of mutation or disfigurement and almost all took on an unhealthy looking pallour. Shortly before the time that the ice began to recede, a cult emerged amongst members of the tribe and centred around the worship of the spiders. The cult did not stop consuming the young spiders, but treated the meal more as a ritual than a method of survival. For each meal, they gave thanks to a greater spider, commonly called "Mother".[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]With the fall of Mulcarn and the dawning of the Age of Rebirth, the tribe emerged from the caves and resettled on the surface. Whilst the majority of the the tribesmen returned to the old ways, the Spider-Cult gained strength. They are still a minority in the village, but a significant one and they wield much power. Where the tribesmen are brutish and aggressive, the cult manipulates their strength to do Mother's bidding.</English>
		<French>Quand l'Ère Glaciaire s'installa sur Erebus, les hommes civilisés abandonnèrent leurs villes et fuirent dans les grottes. Dans les ténèbres souterraines, certains réussirent à maintenir leurs anciennes sociétés et héritages, et attendirent la fin de l'Ère Galciaire entre amis. Cependant, certains n'eurent pas cette chance dans le choix de leur grotte. Un de ces groupe étaient les Archosiens, un clan mineur de barbares durant l'Âge de Magie. Fuyant la surface tandis que les blizzards détruisaient leur village, les Archosiens se réfugièrent dans un grand réseau de grottes.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le clan n'avait pas imaginé abandonner son village et eut peu de temps pour préparer les vivres dans leur fuite précipitée. Les grottes elles-mêmes avaient peu à offrir, si ce n'est la protection de l'abri, et en désespoir de cause le clan se mit à manger les insectes qui grouillaient dans les grottes proches de la surface. Des éclaireurs furent envoyés en reconnaissance plus profondément dans les grottes afin de trouver une autres source de nourriture. Quand ils revinrent quelques jours plus tard, ils transportaient quelques carcasses d'Araignées, chacun faisant approximativement la taille d'un crâne humain. Les grottes plus en profondeur regorgaient de ces créatures, et il semblait que malgré leur goût désagréable, elles fourniraient une source de nourriture adéquate. Quelques membres du clan tombèrent malades au début, mais au fil des ans ils développèrent une immunité au poison.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Cette immunité n'était cependant pas complète. Doucement mais sûrement, le poison se répandit dans les corps des membres de la tribu et fut transmis à la génération suivante. Certains des nouveaux-nés présentaient des signes de mutations ou étaient défigurés et pratiquement tous avaient un teint malade. Peu de temps avant que la glace ne commence à reculer, une culte émergea des membres du clan, centré autour de l'Araignée. Le culte ne mit pas fin à la consommation des jeunes araignées, mais traitaient les repas plus comme un rituel que comme une méthode de survie. Pour chaque repas, ils remerciaient une araignée supérieure, communément appelée "la Mère".[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Avec la chute de Mulcarn et l'aube de l'Âge de la Renaissance, le clan émergea des grottes et recolonisa la surface. Tandis que la majorité des membres du clan revinrent à leur ancien mode de vie, le Culte de l'Araignée gagna en force. Ses membres sont toujours minoritaires dans le village, mais une minorité importante et ils possèdent beaucoup de pouvoir. Tandis que les membres deu clan sont brutaux et aggressifs, le culte les manipule et utilise leur force pour les desseins de la Mère.</French>
		<German>When the Age of Ice came upon Erebus, civilized men abandoned their cities and fled to the caves. In the darkness below the world, some managed to maintain their former society and heritage and waited out the Ice Age amongst friends. Others however were not so fortunate in their choice of cave. One such group were the Archos - a minor barbarian tribe during the Age of Magic. Fleeing the surface as the blizzards blasted their village, the Archosians fled into a large cave-complex. [PARAGRAPH:1]The tribe had not expected to abandon their village and had little time to prepare supplies in their hurried flight. The caves themselves offered little - save for shelter - and in desperation the tribe turned to eating the insects that dwelled in the upper caves. Scouts were sent to investigate further into the caves to find other food and when they returned days later, they carried with them a number of spider carcasses - each roughly the size of a man's head. The caves below teemed with these creatures and it seemed that - whilst unpleasant tasting - they would provide adequete food. A few tribesmen became ill at first, but over the years they developed an immunity to the poison. [PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]The immunity was not complete however. Slowly but surely the poison was building up in the bodies of the tribesmen and being passed down to the next generation. Some of the newborn showed signs of mutation or disfigurement and almost all took on an unhealthy looking pallour. Shortly before the time that the ice began to recede, a cult emerged amongst members of the tribe and centred around the worship of the spiders. The cult did not stop consuming the young spiders, but treated the meal more as a ritual than a method of survival. For each meal, they gave thanks to a greater spider, commonly called "Mother".[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]With the fall of Mulcarn and the dawning of the Age of Rebirth, the tribe emerged from the caves and resettled on the surface. Whilst the majority of the the tribesmen returned to the old ways, the Spider-Cult gained strength. They are still a minority in the village, but a significant one and they wield much power. Where the tribesmen are brutish and aggressive, the cult manipulates their strength to do Mother's bidding.</German>
		<Italian>Quando l'Era del Ghiaccio arrivò su Erebus, gli uomini civilizzati abbandonarono le loro città e fuggirono nelle grotte. Nell'oscurita sotto al mondo, alcuni riuscirono a mantenere la loro società intatta cosi come le loro tradizioni e attesero la fine dell'Era del Ghiaccio tra amici. Altri invece non furono cosi fortunati nella scelta delle grotte. Uno di questi gruppi erano gli Archos, una piccola tribù barbara dell'Era della Magia. Fuggendo dalla superfice in cui delle tempeste di neve hanno distrutto il loro villaggio gli Archosiani trovarono rifugio in un grande complesso di grotte. [PARAGRAPH:1]La tribù non si aspettava di dover abbandonare il loro villaggio e non ebbero il tempo per preparare dei rifornimenti nella loro frettolosa fuga. Le grotte stesse offrivano poco altro oltre al riparo, in preda alla disperazione la tribù iniziò a mangiare gli insetti che abitavano le grotte superiori. Dei ricognitori furono mandati ad esplorare le grotte più in profondità per cercare altro cibo, quando tornarono nei giorni successivi portarono con loro delle carcasse di ragni, ognuna delle dimensioni di una testa umana. Le grotte sottostanti erano piene di queste creature e sembrava che, sebbene non avessero un buon sapore, potevano fornire un'alimetazione adeguata. Qualche membro della tribù si ammalò all'inizio, ma col passare degli anni svilupparono un'immunità al veleno. [PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]L'immunità non era totale però. Lentamente il veleno si stava accumulando nei corpi della tribù venendo addirittura passato alle nuove generazioni. Alcuni dei neonati mostrarono segni di mutazione e quasi tutti avevano un pallore come fossero malati. Poco prima che il ghiaccio iniziò a sciogliersi, un culto emerse tra i membri della tribù centrato sulla venerazione dei ragni. I culto non era contro il mangiare i ragni giovani, ma ne ritualizzò l'azione. Ogni volta che li mangiavano, ringraziavano un ragno supremo, comunemente chiamato "Madre".[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Con la caduta di Mulcarn e l'iizio dell'Era della Rinascita, la tribù lasciò le grotte e si ri insediò sulla superfice. Mentre la maggior parte della tribù tornò alle vecchie usanze, il Culto dei Ragni aumentò il suo potere. Sono ancora una minoranza all'interno del villaggio, ma comunque sognificativa e dispongono di parecchio potere. Mentre i membri della tribù sono brutali e aggressivi, il culto manipola i loro punti di forza per compiere la volonta di Madre.</Italian>
		<Spanish>When the Age of Ice came upon Erebus, civilized men abandoned their cities and fled to the caves. In the darkness below the world, some managed to maintain their former society and heritage and waited out the Ice Age amongst friends. Others however were not so fortunate in their choice of cave. One such group were the Archos - a minor barbarian tribe during the Age of Magic. Fleeing the surface as the blizzards blasted their village, the Archosians fled into a large cave-complex. [PARAGRAPH:1]The tribe had not expected to abandon their village and had little time to prepare supplies in their hurried flight. The caves themselves offered little - save for shelter - and in desperation the tribe turned to eating the insects that dwelled in the upper caves. Scouts were sent to investigate further into the caves to find other food and when they returned days later, they carried with them a number of spider carcasses - each roughly the size of a man's head. The caves below teemed with these creatures and it seemed that - whilst unpleasant tasting - they would provide adequete food. A few tribesmen became ill at first, but over the years they developed an immunity to the poison. [PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]The immunity was not complete however. Slowly but surely the poison was building up in the bodies of the tribesmen and being passed down to the next generation. Some of the newborn showed signs of mutation or disfigurement and almost all took on an unhealthy looking pallour. Shortly before the time that the ice began to recede, a cult emerged amongst members of the tribe and centred around the worship of the spiders. The cult did not stop consuming the young spiders, but treated the meal more as a ritual than a method of survival. For each meal, they gave thanks to a greater spider, commonly called "Mother".[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]With the fall of Mulcarn and the dawning of the Age of Rebirth, the tribe emerged from the caves and resettled on the surface. Whilst the majority of the the tribesmen returned to the old ways, the Spider-Cult gained strength. They are still a minority in the village, but a significant one and they wield much power. Where the tribesmen are brutish and aggressive, the cult manipulates their strength to do Mother's bidding.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARCHOS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Strategy:
[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Archosians spiders and scorpions excel at denying exploration and expansion of other civs. They do this through the use of their spiders (see: [LINK=UNIT_SPIDER]Archosian Spider[\LINK] Strategy and Mechanics).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Their [LINK=UNIT_SCORPION]scorpions[\LINK] act as supplements to their troops, also spawning through [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Mother's Nest[\LINK] (the Archosian Palace), but with different properties. They do not have hidden nationality, and their attacks poison enemies, more useful for stopping healing units and wearing them down, whereas Spiders are better at zone control, picking off undefended units and ambushing from stealth. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders have hidden nationality, meaning they can enter other players territory without declaring war. However, they can't [LINK=SPELL_DECLARE_NATIONALITY]reveal their nationality[\LINK] and hence can't capture cities. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders are not built. Instead, they spawn from [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Mother's Nest[\LINK] (the Archosian Palace). Capital population changes their strength and size (4+ baby, 8+ Adult, and 12+ for Giant Spiders). [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Mother's Nest is the center of Archosian strength; the larger and more well-fed it is, the stronger the Archosians are. Early game civics like God King are more effective than normal, and whatever you can do to increase the population of the capital is best. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Additionally, you'll want to save a couple of early spiders once they reach levels 4, 5, 6 and 7 in order to increase the size of the Brood Pit; while it might feel like a waste, it'll help make all of your other spawned spiders better as the game goes on, keeping you competitive.
[NEWLINE]Author's notes: Due to spiders being able to quickly level up in early game beyond what warriors can defend against, it's generally frowned upon to use the Archosians in MP games on small maps. Played smartly, it's even possible to destroy another civ using just your starting spider and scout in the first handful of turns, so if there's a human playing as the Archosians, beware!</English>
		<French>Les Archosiens contrôlent les araignées et les scorpions, et excellent à empêcher l'exploration et l'expansion des autres civilisations au travers de leurs araignées et certaines de leurs mécaniques telles que la nationalité cachée et des promotions spécifiques (cf. Stratégie et mécanismes de l'[LINK=UNIT_SPIDER]Araignée Archosienne[\LINK]).[PARAGRAPH:1]Les [LINK=UNIT_SCORPION]scorpions[\LINK] agissent comme troupes supplémentaires, et apparaissent à la [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Tanière de la Mère[\LINK], le Palais archosien, mais ont des caractéristiques différentes. Ils n'ont pas la nationalité cachée, et leurs attaquent empoisonnent l'ennemi, plus utile pour stopper les soins des unités attaquantes et les abattre plus rapidement, quand les araignées sont meilleures dans le contrôle de zone, éliminant les cibles faibles et sans défense.[PARAGRAPH:1]La Tanière de la Mère est le c&#156;ur du pouvoir des archosiens. Plus la ville l'abritant est grande et bien nourrie, plus ils sont puissants. Dans cette optique, les doctrines de début de jeu telles que la [LINK=CIVIC_GOD_KING]Monarchie de droit divin[\LINK] sont encore plus efficaces que d'habitude, et quoi que vous puissiez faire, augmenter la population de la capitale est la meilleure chose à faire, car la force des araignées est directement liée à sa taille. De plus, vous souhaiterez sûrement conserver quelques araignées une fois qu'elles atteignent les niveaux 4, 5, 6 et 7 pour améliorer la taille de la [LINK=BUILDING_BROODCHAMBER]Chambre des Couvées[\LINK]. Bien que cela puisse sembler du gâchis de sacrifier ainsi une araignée bien expérimentée, cela vous aidera à maintenir les araignées créées en milieu et fin de partie au niveau des unités plus puissantes, vous maintenant compétitif.[PARAGRAPH:1]Note de l'auteur : Compte tenu de la capacité des araignées à progresser rapidement au-delà de ce que les guerriers peuvent affronter, il est généralement considéré comme non fair-play d'utiliser les archosiens en miultijoueur sur de petites cartes. Joués intelligemment, il est même possible de détruire une autre civilisation en n'utilisant que votre araignée et votre éclaireur de départ lors des premiers tours de jeu. Donc, méfiance si un joueur humain incarne les archosiens !</French>
		<German>[TAB]The Archosians control spiders and scorpions, and excel at denying exploration and expansion of other civs. They do this through the use of their spiders, which have a number of mechanics and specific upgrades (see: [LINK=UNIT_SPIDER]Archosian Spider[\LINK] Strategy and Mechanics).[PARAGRAPH:1]Their [LINK=UNIT_SCORPION]scorpions[\LINK] act as supplements to their troops, also spawning through [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Mother's nest[\LINK] (the Archosian Palace), but they have different properties. They do not have hidden nationality, and their attacks DO poison enemies, more useful for stopping healing of attacking units and wearing them down faster, whereas Spiders are better at zone control, picking off undefended and weak units. Archosian spiders have hidden nationality, meaning they can enter other players territory without declaring war. But, contrarily to units with [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]hidden nationality promotion[\LINK], they can't [LINK=SPELL_DECLARE_NATIONALITY]reveal their nationality[\LINK] and hence can't capture cities. [PARAGRAPH:2]Archosian spiders are not built. Instead, they spawn from [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Mother's nest[\LINK] (the Archosian Palace). Capital population changes their initial size (baby if 4+, spiders if 8+, and giant spiders if 12+). Mother's nest is the center of Archosian strength; the larger and more well-fed it is, the stronger the Archosians are. Toward this end, earlygame civics like God King are even more effective than normal, and whatever you can do to increase the population of the capital is best, as spider strength is directly related to the size. Additionally, you'll want to save a couple of early spiders once they reach levels 4, 5, 6 and 7 in order to increase the size of the Brood Pit; while it might feel a waste of a perfectly good leveled spider, it'll help make all of your other spawned spiders in mid and late game match up to the strength of stronger units, keeping you competitive.[PARAGRAPH:2]Author's notes: Due to spiders being able to quickly level up in early game beyond what warriors can defend against, it's generally frowned upon to use the Archosians in MP games on small maps. Played smartly, it's even possible to destroy another civ using just your starting spider and scout in the first handful of turns, so if there's a human playing as the Archosians, beware!</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Gli Archosiani controllano ragni e sorpioni, ed eccellono nell'impedire l'esplorazione e l'espansione alle altre civiltà. Fanno ciò attraverso i loro ragni, che hanno diverse meccaniche come la nazionalità nascosta, e miglioramenti specifici (vedere: [LINK=UNIT_SPIDER_ARCHOS]Ragno Archosiano[\LINK] Strategia e Meccaniche).[PARAGRAPH:1]I loro scoprioni fanno da complemento alle loro forze invece, generati anche dal [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Nido di Madre[\LINK] (il Palazzo Archosiano), ma hanno proprietà differenti. Non possiedono nazionalità nascosta, e i loro attacchi avvelenano i nemici, utile per fermare la guarigione delle unità attaccanti e abbatterli più in fretta, mentre i Ragni sono migliori a controllare una zona, eliminando unità indifese o deboli.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dal 3° livello, gli Scorpioni possono scegliere 1 colore tra 5 possibili (2 promozioni consecutive):[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Bianco (forza difensiva e più movimento nei terreni freddi; [LINK=PROMOTION_SCORPION_GLACIALIS]Glacialis[\LINK], poi [LINK=PROMOTION_SCORPION_GLACIALIS_GREATER]Glacialis Maggiore[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Nero (Veleno più forte; [LINK=PROMOTION_SCORPION_MORTALITAS]Mortalitas[\LINK], poi [LINK=PROMOTION_SCORPION_MORTALITAS_GREATER]Mortalitas Maggiore[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Verde (Forza nel deserto, può nascondersi e affinità al Mana del Sole; [LINK=PROMOTION_SCORPION_VIDELICET]Videlicet[\LINK], poi [LINK=PROMOTION_SCORPION_VIDELICET_GREATER]Videlicet Maggiore[\LINK])[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Blu (diversi poteri acquatici; [LINK=PROMOTION_SCORPION_AEQUOR]Aequor[\LINK], poi [LINK=PROMOTION_SCORPION_AEQUOR_GREATER]Aequor Maggiore[\LINK])[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Marrone (forza e movimento nelle colline e montagne; [LINK=PROMOTION_SCORPION_RUTILA]Rutila[\LINK], poi [LINK=PROMOTION_SCORPION_RUTILA_GREATER]Rutilia Maggiore[\LINK])[PARAGRAPH:2]Il Nido di Madre è il centro del potere Archosiano; più è ampio e ben nutrito, più son forti gli Archosiani. A questo scopo, forme di governo come Dio Re sono più efficaci del normale, e qualsiasi cosa che aumentì la popolazione della capitale è la scelta migliore, essendo la forza dei ragni legata alla grandezza della capitale. In più, è consigliabile mantenere un paio di ragni una volta che raggiungono i livelli 4, 5, 6 e 7 in modo da incrementare la dimensione della covata; potrà sembrare uno spreco di ragni ben livellati ma fare ciò permetterà agli altri ragni che vengono generati di rivaleggiare le unità più forti, mantenendoti competitivo.[PARAGRAPH:2]Nota dell'autore: Essendo i ragni facili da livellare all'inzio della partita, portandoli ad essere più forti dei guerrieri in difesa, e generalmente malvisto usare gli Archosiani in MP su mappe piccole. Se giocati intelligentemente, è persino possibile distruggere un'altra civiltà, usando soltanto i ragni iniziali e i ricognitori, nei primi turni, quindi se un umano sta usando gli Archosiani, stai in guardia!</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Archosians control spiders and scorpions, and excel at denying exploration and expansion of other civs. They do this through the use of their spiders, which have a number of mechanics and specific upgrades (see: [LINK=UNIT_SPIDER]Archosian Spider[\LINK] Strategy and Mechanics).[PARAGRAPH:1]Their [LINK=UNIT_SCORPION]scorpions[\LINK] act as supplements to their troops, also spawning through [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Mother's nest[\LINK] (the Archosian Palace), but they have different properties. They do not have hidden nationality, and their attacks DO poison enemies, more useful for stopping healing of attacking units and wearing them down faster, whereas Spiders are better at zone control, picking off undefended and weak units. Archosian spiders have hidden nationality, meaning they can enter other players territory without declaring war. But, contrarily to units with [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]hidden nationality promotion[\LINK], they can't [LINK=SPELL_DECLARE_NATIONALITY]reveal their nationality[\LINK] and hence can't capture cities. [PARAGRAPH:2]Archosian spiders are not built. Instead, they spawn from [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Mother's nest[\LINK] (the Archosian Palace). Capital population changes their initial size (baby if 4+, spiders if 8+, and giant spiders if 12+). Mother's nest is the center of Archosian strength; the larger and more well-fed it is, the stronger the Archosians are. Toward this end, earlygame civics like God King are even more effective than normal, and whatever you can do to increase the population of the capital is best, as spider strength is directly related to the size. Additionally, you'll want to save a couple of early spiders once they reach levels 4, 5, 6 and 7 in order to increase the size of the Brood Pit; while it might feel a waste of a perfectly good leveled spider, it'll help make all of your other spawned spiders in mid and late game match up to the strength of stronger units, keeping you competitive.[PARAGRAPH:2]Author's notes: Due to spiders being able to quickly level up in early game beyond what warriors can defend against, it's generally frowned upon to use the Archosians in MP games on small maps. Played smartly, it's even possible to destroy another civ using just your starting spider and scout in the first handful of turns, so if there's a human playing as the Archosians, beware!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CORANE</Tag>
		<English>Corane</English>
		<French>Corane</French>
		<German>Corane</German>
		<Italian>Corane</Italian>
		<Spanish>Corane</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CORANE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Corane's birth was no different from the others. No physical mutations, nothing irregular with the boy. Most children learned to respect and revere the spiders that routinely wandered through the streets, catching what small animals they could and bringing them to Mother or the village market. Corane was different. When he saw one of this spiders he would kill it. Crush it with whatever was nearby then pick it up carefully, so as not to damage the body. The Elders were appalled and his parents scolded and beat him mercilessly, but he continued to collect these dead spiders, keeping them in a small box. He would carefully pull off their legs and make designs with them. Several contained all eight legs, some did not. He separated the fangs and poison sacks from their bodies and kept them in a special jar as he studied what remained of the carcasses.[PARAGRAPH:1]One day Barbarian Orcs attacked his village, intent on pillaging and plundering whatever they could find. They had burst into Corane's house, expecting easy prey and much loot to be taken. However, in the center of the room stood Corane, holding what seemed to be a simple piece of metal, ornately decorated with small spikes and baubles dotting the surface. Unrecognized by the orcs, Corane's creation didn't stop them from attacking, but the poison sacks and still-venomous spider fangs caringly affixed to his club did stop their lives. The Orcs assaulted him, but one-by-one fell to his new weapon. The Orcs were eventually driven off and the villagers accepted Corane as a hero in the battle.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the years passed, he became a general in the army of the Archos. He commanded his troops be immunized to the poison of the spiders through experiments that would be considered illegal under most governments. When he was finished, he stood before a massive army, ready to give their lives to protect the Archos and to do the bidding of Mother. Following Daracaat's orders, he led this men to a small valley, the Valley of Spiders, and began build his own empire, keen on the destruction of all other civilizations around him. [PARAGRAPH:2]Corane paced back and forth in front of the prisoner. He looked the man over, and was once again disgusted. The man's hair was dirty and knotted, he wore clothes that looked like patchwork, and his skin seemed dirty enough to make even slaves cringe. The man was caught sneaking through the fortress walls with bundles of military papers. He was beaten and promptly brought to Corane for questioning. [PARAGRAPH:1]"You've come all this way. Traveled the great mountains. Gone through the haunted forest. All to try to spy on us. Tell me. What is it that you have come for?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner merely looked down, staunchly remaining quiet.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Very well, then. Agnir, show him what happens when prisoners do not comply."[PARAGRAPH:1]A rather gruff looking Archosian nodded and grabbed one of the prisoner's hands. Holding the hand to the ground, he slowly drew a wicked looking knife, chuckling. Down came the knife, off came the fingers, and out came the screams. The prisoner fell to the ground, clutching his now fingerless hand, sobbing and crying to Junil.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Now. Will you tell me why you have come all this way?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner merely spat on Corane's shoes and cursed Mother.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You dare insult Mother, you ingrate!?" Corane smacked the prisoner across the face. "Nobody, and I repeat, nobody insults Mother. Cut off his other fingers!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner screamed and protested as the guards held his other hand to the ground, his voice reaching a new intensity with a corresponding loss of digits. Corane reached out and grabbed the sobbing prisoner by the hair and held him up to look him in the eye.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Now tell me!" he bellowed, voice echoing off the stone walls. "Who are you!? Where did you come from!? Why are you here?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner sobbed slightly and held his now mangled hands close to his chest. "I...I was sent to spy on you. Learn your tactics, but that's all I know."[PARAGRAPH:1]Dropping the prisoner, Corane nodded silently, then whirled about and kicked the prisoner in the stomach. "Tell me all of it! All the truth!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner began to wail openly and cry hysterically. "I was to learn your military formations and your resources! I was to learn your plans and report them to my master! I was to find weaknesses in your defenses! I swear that's all I know!" As he finished yelling he curled up on the stone floor, which was slowly becoming stained with his blood.[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane held his hands behind his back and bent over to speak to the prisoner. "And who, might I ask, is your master? Or must we sever. other things?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner screamed at this and yelled "Capria! Capria! It was Capria, I swear!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane stood up looking satisfied, and turned to Agnir. "Have our scribes recorded this session?" Agnir nodded and grabbed a chart from a nearby Archosian.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The whole thing. The questioning, commission of guilt, everything." Agnir looked up at Corane. "What shall we put as his sentence, milord?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane looked at the whimpering man before him. "Throw him to the spiders. I am sure Mother is hungry and wishes for a more... exotic meal." With that, Corane strode into his throne room and closed the doors behind him. Agnir and some fellow soldiers lifted the sobbing wreck and threw him into a dark hole. Amongst the screams of agony, the hissing of creatures and the sound of their many legs converging on their screaming meal played a soothing tune to Corane's ear.</English>
		<French>La naissance de Corane n'était pas différente de celle des autres. Pas de mutations physiques, rien de particulier avec ce garçon. La plupart des enfants apprennent à respecter et révérer les araignées qui se déplacent dans les rues, attrapant tous les petits animaux qu'elles peuvent pour les les apporter à la Mère ou au marché du village. Corane était différent. Chaque fois qu'il voyait une de ces araignées il la tuait. L'écrasait avec n'importe quoi à portée, puis la ramassait précautionneusement pour ne pas abîmer le corps. Les anciens en étaient consternés et ses parents le grondaient et le frappaient sans pitié, mais il continuait de collecter ces araignées mortes, les gardant dans une petite boîte. Il détachait les pattes et faisait des sculptures avec. Certaines avaient leurs huit pattes, d'autres non. Il séparait les crocs et les sacs de venin de leurs corps et les conservait dans une jarre spéciale tandis qu'il étudiait ce qu'il restait des carcasses.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un jour, des Orcs barbares attaquèrent le village, avec l'intention de tout piller et ravir. Ils firent irruption dans la maison de Corane, s'attendant à y trouver une proie facile et un beau butin. Cependant au centre de la pièce se tenait Corane, tenant ce qui semblait être un simple morceau de métal orné de fioritures telles que des petites pointes et des babioles parsemant la surface. Incapables d'identifier la création de Corane, les Orcs n'en tinrent pas compte et attaquèrent, mais les sacs de poison et les crocs d'araignées encore venimeux fixés avec soin sur sa massue mirent fin à leurs vies. Les Orcs l'attaquèrent, mais un par un succombèrent devant sa nouvelle arme. Les Orcs finirent par être repoussés et les villageois considérèrent Corane comme un héros de la bataille.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les années passant, il devint un général de l'armée archosienne. Il fit en sorte d'immuniser ses troupes au poison des araignées au travers d'expériences qui seraient considérées comme illégales dans la plupart des gouvernements. Quand il eut fini, il se tenait devant une armée massive, prêt à donner sa vie pour protégerles Archosiens et suivre la volonté de la Mère. Suivant les ordres de Daracaat, il mena son armée dans une petite vallée, la Vallée des Araignées, et commença à construire son propre empire, avec pour but la destruction de toutes les autres civilisations autour de lui.[PARAGRAPH:2]Corane faisait les cent pas devant le prisonnier. Il examina l'homme, et fut à nouveau dégoûté. Ses cheveux étaient sales et noués, il portait des vêtements qui ressemblaient à un patchwork et sa peau semblait suffisamment sale pour faire reculer les esclaves. L'homme avait été capturé tandis qu'il se faufilait par-dessus les murs de la forteresse avec des rouleaux de papiers militaires. Il avait été battu et immédiatement amené à Corane pour être interrogé.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Vous avez fait tout ce chemin. Franchi les grandes montagnes. Traversé la forêt hantée. Tout ça pour tenter de nous espionner. Dites moi. Pour quelle raison êtes-vous venu ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Le prisonnier baissa simplement les yeux, se murant dans un mutisme absolu.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Très bien. Agnir, montre-lui ce qui arrive aux prisonniers qui ne coopèrent pas."[PARAGRAPH:1]Un archosien à l'air revêche acquiesca et saisit une main du prisonnier. Maintenant la main au sol, il tira doucement un couteau menaçant de son fourreau, en gloussant. La lame se baissa, les doigts se détachèrent, et les cris sortirent. Le prisonnier tomba au sol, serrant sa main sans doigts, pleurant et larmoyant à l'adresse de Junil.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Et maintenant, me diras-tu pourquoi tu as fait tout ce chemin ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Le prisonnier se contenta de cracher sur les chaussures de Corane et de maudire la Mère.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tu oses insulter la Mère, espèce d'ingrat ?!?" Corane gifla le visage du prisonnier. "Personne, et je le répète, personne n'insulte la Mère. Coupe-lui les autres doigts."[PARAGRAPH:1]Le prisonnier hurla et se débattit tandis que les gardes plaquaient son autre main au sol, sa voix gagnant en intensité au fur et à mesure de la perte des phalanges. Corane se rapprocha et attrapa le prsionnier larmoyant par les cheveux et le souleva pour le regarder dans les yeux.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Maintenant dis-moi !" beugla-t-il, sa voix faisant écho sur les murs de pierre. "Qui es-tu !? D'où viens-tu ?! Pourquoi es-tu là ?!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Le prisonnier sanglota légèrement et rapprocha ses mains mutilées de son torse. "Je... j'ai été envoyé pour vous espionner. Étudier vos tactiques, mais c'est tout ce que je sais."[PARAGRAPH:1]Lâchant le prisonnier, Corane acquiesca silencieusement, puis se tourna sur lui-même et frappa le prisonnier à l'estomac. "Dis-moi tout ! Toute la vérité !"[PARAGRAPH:1]Le prisonnier commença ouvertement à gémir et pleurer comme un hystérique. "Je devais étudier vos formations militaires et vos ressources ! Je devais étudier vos plans et les rapporter à mon maître ! Je devais trouver les faiblesses dans vos défenses ! C'est tout ce que je sais, je le jure !" Tout en finissant de crier il se recroquevillait sur le sol de pierre, qui commençait à se gorger de son sang.[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane mit ses mains dans son dos et se pencha pour parler au prisonnier. " Et qui, si je peux me permettre, est-ton maître ? Ou nous devrons trancher... autre chose ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Le prisonnier se mit à crier "Capria ! Capria ! C'était Capria, je le jure !"[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane se leva d'un air satisfait, et se tourna vers Agnir. "Nos scribes ont-ils tout enregistré ?" Agnir acquiesca et attrapa le rouleau d'un archosien proche.[PARAGRAPH:1]"L'ensemble. L'interrogatoire, l'aveu de culpabilité, tout." Agnir regarda Corane. "Que devons-nous marquer comme sentence, monseigneur ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane regarda le pleurnichard devant lui. "Jetez-le aux araignées. Je suis sûr que la Mère a faim et désire un... plat plus exotique." Sur ces mots, Corane marcha à grandes enjambées dans sa chambre du trône et ferma les portes derrière lui. Agnir et quelques soldats soulevèrent le débris larmoyant et le lancèrent dans un trou noir. Accompagnant les hurlements d'agonie, les sifflements des créatures et le son de leurs multiples pattes convergeant vers leur repas hurlant étaient une mélodie douce aux oreilles de Corane.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Corane's birth was no different from the others. No physical mutations, nothing irregular with the boy. Most children learned to respect and revere the spiders that routinely wandered through the streets, catching what small animals they could and bringing them to Mother or the village market. Corane was different. When he saw one of this spiders he would kill it. Crush it with whatever was nearby then pick it up carefully, so as not to damage the body. The Elders were appalled and his parents scolded and beat him mercilessly, but he continued to collect these dead spiders, keeping them in a small box. He would carefully pull off their legs and make designs with them. Several contained all eight legs, some did not. He separated the fangs and poison sacks from their bodies and kept them in a special jar as he studied what remained of the carcasses.[PARAGRAPH:1]One day Barbarian Orcs attacked his village, intent on pillaging and plundering whatever they could find. They had burst into Corane's house, expecting easy prey and much loot to be taken. However, in the center of the room stood Corane, holding what seemed to be a simple piece of metal, ornately decorated with small spikes and baubles dotting the surface. Unrecognized by the orcs, Corane's creation didn't stop them from attacking, but the poison sacks and still-venomous spider fangs caringly affixed to his club did stop their lives. The Orcs assaulted him, but one-by-one fell to his new weapon. The Orcs were eventually driven off and the villagers accepted Corane as a hero in the battle.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the years passed, he became a general in the army of the Archos. He commanded his troops be immunized to the poison of the spiders through experiments that would be considered illegal under most governments. When he was finished, he stood before a massive army, ready to give their lives to protect the Archos and to do the bidding of Mother. Following Daracaat's orders, he led this men to a small valley, the Valley of Spiders, and began build his own empire, keen on the destruction of all other civilizations around him. [PARAGRAPH:2]Corane paced back and forth in front of the prisoner. He looked the man over, and was once again disgusted. The man's hair was dirty and knotted, he wore clothes that looked like patchwork, and his skin seemed dirty enough to make even slaves cringe. The man was caught sneaking through the fortress walls with bundles of military papers. He was beaten and promptly brought to Corane for questioning. [PARAGRAPH:1]"You've come all this way. Traveled the great mountains. Gone through the haunted forest. All to try to spy on us. Tell me. What is it that you have come for?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner merely looked down, staunchly remaining quiet.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Very well, then. Agnir, show him what happens when prisoners do not comply."[PARAGRAPH:1]A rather gruff looking Archosian nodded and grabbed one of the prisoner's hands. Holding the hand to the ground, he slowly drew a wicked looking knife, chuckling. Down came the knife, off came the fingers, and out came the screams. The prisoner fell to the ground, clutching his now fingerless hand, sobbing and crying to Junil.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Now. Will you tell me why you have come all this way?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner merely spat on Corane's shoes and cursed Mother.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You dare insult Mother, you ingrate!?" Corane smacked the prisoner across the face. "Nobody, and I repeat, nobody insults Mother. Cut off his other fingers!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner screamed and protested as the guards held his other hand to the ground, his voice reaching a new intensity with a corresponding loss of digits. Corane reached out and grabbed the sobbing prisoner by the hair and held him up to look him in the eye.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Now tell me!" he bellowed, voice echoing off the stone walls. "Who are you!? Where did you come from!? Why are you here?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner sobbed slightly and held his now mangled hands close to his chest. "I...I was sent to spy on you. Learn your tactics, but that's all I know."[PARAGRAPH:1]Dropping the prisoner, Corane nodded silently, then whirled about and kicked the prisoner in the stomach. "Tell me all of it! All the truth!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner began to wail openly and cry hysterically. "I was to learn your military formations and your resources! I was to learn your plans and report them to my master! I was to find weaknesses in your defenses! I swear that's all I know!" As he finished yelling he curled up on the stone floor, which was slowly becoming stained with his blood.[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane held his hands behind his back and bent over to speak to the prisoner. "And who, might I ask, is your master? Or must we sever. other things?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner screamed at this and yelled "Capria! Capria! It was Capria, I swear!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane stood up looking satisfied, and turned to Agnir. "Have our scribes recorded this session?" Agnir nodded and grabbed a chart from a nearby Archosian.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The whole thing. The questioning, commission of guilt, everything." Agnir looked up at Corane. "What shall we put as his sentence, milord?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane looked at the whimpering man before him. "Throw him to the spiders. I am sure Mother is hungry and wishes for a more... exotic meal." With that, Corane strode into his throne room and closed the doors behind him. Agnir and some fellow soldiers lifted the sobbing wreck and threw him into a dark hole. Amongst the screams of agony, the hissing of creatures and the sound of their many legs converging on their screaming meal played a soothing tune to Corane's ear.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La nascita di Corane non fu diversa da quella degli altri. Nessuna mutazione fisica, nulla di irregolare nel bambino. La maggior parte dei bambini imparava a rispettare e riverire i ragni che regolarmente giravano per le strade, catturando i piccoli animali che potevano e portandoli a Madre o al mercato del villaggio. Corane era diverso. Quando vedeva uno di questi ragni lo uccideva. Schiacciandolo con qualsiasi cosa aveva a portata di mano per poi prendere il corpo cautamente cosi da non danneggiarlo. Gli Anziani erano inorriditi da ciò e i suoi parenti lo sgridavano e picchiavano a causa di questo suo comportamento, ma lui continuò a collezionare i ragni morti, tenendoli in una cassetta. Gli avrebbe rimosso attentamente le gambe e portato avanti dei progetti con loro. Alcuni avevano tutte e otto le gambe, altri no. Asportava le zanne e le sacche di veleno dai corpi tenendole in un barattolo speciale mentre continuava a studiare il resto della carcassas.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un giorno degli Orchi barbari attaccarono il suo villaggio con l'intento di saccheggiare qualsiasi cosa trovavano. Fecere irruzzione nella casa di Corane aspettandosi delle facili prede, con parecchio bottino da prendre. Ma al centro della stanza c'era Corane, impugnando quello che sembrava essere un semplice pezzo di metallo, finemente decorato con piccole punte e cindoli. La creazione di Corane non impedì agli orchi di attaccarlo, ma le sacche di veleno e le zanne di ragno accuratamente fissate al suo randello stroncarono le loro vite. Uno ad uno gli orchi caddero sotto i colpi della sua nuova arma. Gli orchi furono respinti e gli abitanti del villaggio acclamarono Corane come un eroe.[PARAGRAPH:1]Col passare degli anni, diventò un generale dell'esercito Archos. Ordinò che le sue truppe fossero rese immuni dal veleno dei ragni attraverso esperimenti che sarebbero stati ritenuti illegali dalla maggior parte dei governi. Quando finì, aveva davanti a se un imponente armata, pronta a dare la vita per protegger gli Archos e a eseguire gli ordini di Madre. Seguendo gli ordini di Daracaat, guidò quegli uomini in una piccola vallata, la Valle dei Ragni, e iniziò a costruire il suo impero, con l'intenzione di distruggere tutte le altre civiltà che lo circondavano. [PARAGRAPH:2]Corane camminava avanti e indietro davanti al prigioniero. Guardò l'uomo e ne fu di nuovo disgustato. I suoi capelli erano sporchi e annodati, i suoi vestiti sembravano essere stati rattoppati un numero elevato di volte, e la sua pelle era cosi sporca che avrebbe fatto rabbrividire perfino gli schiavi. Quell'uomo fu catturato mentre si muoveva furtivamente attraverso le mura della fortezza con delle cartelle di documenti militari. Fu picchiato e portato subito da Corane per essere interrogato. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Sei venuto fin qui. Scalando le grandi montagne. Attraversando le foreste infestate. Tutto questo per cercare di spiarci. Dimmi. Per che cos'è che sei venuto?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Il prigioniero si limitò a guardare in basso, restando in silenzio.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Molto bene allora. Agnir, mostragli cosa succede quando i prigionieri non collaborano."[PARAGRAPH:1]Il burbero Archosiano annuì e afferrò una mano del prigioniero. Tenendo la mano attaccata al terreno, sguaino letamente un coltello dall'aspetto minaccioso, ridacchiando. Il coltello calò, le dita furono tagliate, e le urla iniziarono. Il prigioniero cadde a terra, stringendo la sua mano ormai senza dita, piangendo e invocando Junil.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ora. Mi dirai per che cosa sei venuto qui?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Il prigioniero si limitò a sputare sulle scarpe di Corane e maleddì Madre.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tu osi insultare Madre, ingrato!?" Corane colpì il prigioniero in faccia. "Nessuno, ripeto, nessuno insulta Madre. Tagliateli le altre dita!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Il prigioniero urlò e protestò mentre le guardie tenevano l'altra sua mano attaccata al terreno, la sua voce raggiunse una nuova intensità ad ogni dito tagliato. Corane prese per i capelli il singhiozzante prigioniero sollevandolo per guardarlo negli occhi.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Dimmelo ora!" urlò, con la sua voce che rieccheggiava sulle pareti di pietra. "Chi sei!? Da dove vieni!? Perché sei qui?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Il prigioniero singhiozzo leggermente tenendo le mani, quello che ne rimaneva, vicino al petto. "I...Io sono stato mandato a spiarvi. Scoprire le vostre tattiche questo è tutto quello che so."[PARAGRAPH:1]Lasciando il prigioniero, Corane annuì silenziosamente, poi girò su se stesso e calciò il prigioniero nello stomaco. "Dimmi tutto! Tutta la verità!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Il prigioniero inizò a piangere in modo isterico. "Dovevo scoprire le vostre formazioni militari e le risorse a vostra disposizione! Dovevo scoprire i vostri piani e comunicarli al mio signore! Dovevo cercare debolezze nelle vostre difese! Questo è tutto ciò che so lo giuro!" Mentre finiva di urlare si raggomitolò sul pavimento di pietra, che si stava lentamente macchiando del suo sangue.[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane poggiò una mano sulla schiena del prigioniero e si chinò per parlargli. "E chi, se posso chiedere, è il tuo signore? O dobbiamo tagliare. altre cose?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Il prigioniero urlò e disse "Capria! Capria! È Capria, lo giuro!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane si rialzò soddisfatto e si voltò verso Agnir. "I nostri scribi hanno registrato questa sessione?" Agnir annuì e prese un pezzo di carta da un Archosiano vicino.[PARAGRAPH:1]"L'intera cosa. L'interrogatorio, l'ammissione di colpa, tutto." Agnir guardò a Corane. "Qual'è la sua sentenza, mio signore?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane guardò all'uomo di fronte a lui. "buttaelo ai ragni. Sono certo che Madre è affamata e desidererebbe un pasto... più esotico." Infine, Corane entrò nella sua sala del trono e chiuse le porte dietro di lui. Agnir e altri soldati sollevarono il prigioniero e lo buttarono dentro un buco. Gli urli di dolore, il sibilio delle creature e il suone delle loro zampe che convergevano verso la loro rumorosa preda erano come una melodia rilassante alle orecchie di Corane.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Corane's birth was no different from the others. No physical mutations, nothing irregular with the boy. Most children learned to respect and revere the spiders that routinely wandered through the streets, catching what small animals they could and bringing them to Mother or the village market. Corane was different. When he saw one of this spiders he would kill it. Crush it with whatever was nearby then pick it up carefully, so as not to damage the body. The Elders were appalled and his parents scolded and beat him mercilessly, but he continued to collect these dead spiders, keeping them in a small box. He would carefully pull off their legs and make designs with them. Several contained all eight legs, some did not. He separated the fangs and poison sacks from their bodies and kept them in a special jar as he studied what remained of the carcasses.[PARAGRAPH:1]One day Barbarian Orcs attacked his village, intent on pillaging and plundering whatever they could find. They had burst into Corane's house, expecting easy prey and much loot to be taken. However, in the center of the room stood Corane, holding what seemed to be a simple piece of metal, ornately decorated with small spikes and baubles dotting the surface. Unrecognized by the orcs, Corane's creation didn't stop them from attacking, but the poison sacks and still-venomous spider fangs caringly affixed to his club did stop their lives. The Orcs assaulted him, but one-by-one fell to his new weapon. The Orcs were eventually driven off and the villagers accepted Corane as a hero in the battle.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the years passed, he became a general in the army of the Archos. He commanded his troops be immunized to the poison of the spiders through experiments that would be considered illegal under most governments. When he was finished, he stood before a massive army, ready to give their lives to protect the Archos and to do the bidding of Mother. Following Daracaat's orders, he led this men to a small valley, the Valley of Spiders, and began build his own empire, keen on the destruction of all other civilizations around him. [PARAGRAPH:2]Corane paced back and forth in front of the prisoner. He looked the man over, and was once again disgusted. The man's hair was dirty and knotted, he wore clothes that looked like patchwork, and his skin seemed dirty enough to make even slaves cringe. The man was caught sneaking through the fortress walls with bundles of military papers. He was beaten and promptly brought to Corane for questioning. [PARAGRAPH:1]"You've come all this way. Traveled the great mountains. Gone through the haunted forest. All to try to spy on us. Tell me. What is it that you have come for?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner merely looked down, staunchly remaining quiet.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Very well, then. Agnir, show him what happens when prisoners do not comply."[PARAGRAPH:1]A rather gruff looking Archosian nodded and grabbed one of the prisoner's hands. Holding the hand to the ground, he slowly drew a wicked looking knife, chuckling. Down came the knife, off came the fingers, and out came the screams. The prisoner fell to the ground, clutching his now fingerless hand, sobbing and crying to Junil.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Now. Will you tell me why you have come all this way?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner merely spat on Corane's shoes and cursed Mother.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You dare insult Mother, you ingrate!?" Corane smacked the prisoner across the face. "Nobody, and I repeat, nobody insults Mother. Cut off his other fingers!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner screamed and protested as the guards held his other hand to the ground, his voice reaching a new intensity with a corresponding loss of digits. Corane reached out and grabbed the sobbing prisoner by the hair and held him up to look him in the eye.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Now tell me!" he bellowed, voice echoing off the stone walls. "Who are you!? Where did you come from!? Why are you here?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner sobbed slightly and held his now mangled hands close to his chest. "I...I was sent to spy on you. Learn your tactics, but that's all I know."[PARAGRAPH:1]Dropping the prisoner, Corane nodded silently, then whirled about and kicked the prisoner in the stomach. "Tell me all of it! All the truth!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner began to wail openly and cry hysterically. "I was to learn your military formations and your resources! I was to learn your plans and report them to my master! I was to find weaknesses in your defenses! I swear that's all I know!" As he finished yelling he curled up on the stone floor, which was slowly becoming stained with his blood.[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane held his hands behind his back and bent over to speak to the prisoner. "And who, might I ask, is your master? Or must we sever. other things?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The prisoner screamed at this and yelled "Capria! Capria! It was Capria, I swear!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane stood up looking satisfied, and turned to Agnir. "Have our scribes recorded this session?" Agnir nodded and grabbed a chart from a nearby Archosian.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The whole thing. The questioning, commission of guilt, everything." Agnir looked up at Corane. "What shall we put as his sentence, milord?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Corane looked at the whimpering man before him. "Throw him to the spiders. I am sure Mother is hungry and wishes for a more... exotic meal." With that, Corane strode into his throne room and closed the doors behind him. Agnir and some fellow soldiers lifted the sobbing wreck and threw him into a dark hole. Amongst the screams of agony, the hissing of creatures and the sound of their many legs converging on their screaming meal played a soothing tune to Corane's ear.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_DARACAAT</Tag>
		<English>Daracaat</English>
		<French>Daracaat</French>
		<German>Daracaat</German>
		<Italian>Daracaat</Italian>
		<Spanish>Daracaat</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_DARACAAT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Haruspex turned toward him, spider's legs partly hidden by the black robe. "Daracaat. You are of Mother's chosen. You are the fiercest of your kind. You will lead the others when the ice passes". Daracaat looked up in surprise as the words were spoken and a cruel grin played across his features. [NEWLINE]"If that is Mother's will", he said. Something in his voice caught the attention of the Haruspex. A slight inflection, an insincere murmur, a trace of doubt.[NEWLINE]"Her will is not your's to divine, brute!" growled the Haruspex, two of its legs knocking Daracaat clean from his feet as they sprang forth from the cloak. He did not attempt to regain his feet straightaway, but lay stunned for a moment as the Haruspex spoke. "You do not need to concern yourself with what she wants, know only that I will be the one to tell you what is required of you. Her plan is beyond your knowing."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Daracaat regained his senses and smiled as he offered his reply. "I have a greater knowing of things than you may think, priest. I am aware that she does not speak to you, nor any of our tribe. What is she really? A Goddess? A Beast? It doesn't matter - she is Power. Your words direct us in her name and we follow. You wish me to lead the others - I will. I will take the power I am given and build the tribe strong, stronger than it ever was. We shall rule the surface whilst you remain here in your cave. My place will be unchallenged so long as you appoint me as Her champion. That shall be the way of it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Daracaat left the chamber and headed back up the tunnel, closer to the surface with the rest of the tribesmen. The Haruspex remained. Thoughtful for a moment, he contemplated the best way to dispose of the oaf and who would replace him. [NEWLINE]"No, actually he will suffice for now", he decided. It was true that Daracaat was a fool, a simple and bloodthirsty barbarian, but that did not reduce his usefulness as a tool. "He will have enemies plenty enough to satisfy his hunger when we return above, and his victims will in turn feed Her."</English>
		<French>Le Haruspex se tourna vers lui, ses jambes d'araignée partiellement cachées par la robe noire. "Daracaat, vous êtes l'élu de la Mère. Vous êtes le plus féroce de votre race. Vous guiderez les autres après l'ère glaciaire". Daracaat paraissait surpris tandis qu'il parlait, et un sourire cruel se dessinait.[NEWLINE]"Si telle est la volonté de la Mère", dit-il. Quelque chose dans sa voix attira l'attantion du Haruspex. Une petite intonation, un murmure non sincère, une pointe de doute.[NEWLINE]"Ce n'est pas à vous d'interpréter Sa volonté, brute!", gronda le Haruspex, deux de ses pattes surgissant de sous son manteau pour renverser Daracaat. Il ne chercha pas à se reveler de suite, mais resta gisant tandis que le Haruspex parlait: "Vous n'avez pas à vous soucier de ce qu'Elle veut, mais seulement que je serai celui qui vous dira ce qui sera attendu de vous. Son plan est au-delà de voter compréhension."[PARAGRAPH:2]Daraccat reprit conscience et sourit tandis qu'il répondait: "J'ai connaissance de bien plus que vous ne pourriez le penser, prêtre. Je suis conscient qu'Elle ne s'adresse pas à vous, pas plus qu'à n'importe qui de votre clan. Qu'est-Elle en réalité? Une déesse? Une bête? Aucune importance, elle est le Pouvoir. Vos paroles nous dirigent en son nom et nous obéissons. Vous souhaites que je dirige les autres, je le ferai.Je prendrai le pouvoir et renforcerai le clan, afin de le rendre plus fort qu'il ne l'a jamais été. Nous gouvernerons la surface tandis que vous resterez ici dans votre grotte. Mon autorité sera incontestée tant que vous me désignerez comme Son champion. cela doit se passer comme ça."[PARAGRAPH:2]Daracaat quitta la chambre et remonta le tunnel, se rapprochant de la surface avec le reste du clan. Le Haruspex resta sur place. Pensif, il envisagea la meilleure façon de se débarasser de cet imbécile et qui pourrait le remplacer.[NEWLINE]"Non, il fera l'affaire pour l'instant", décida-t-il. Il était vrai que c'était un idiot, un simple barbare sanguinaire, mais cela ne le rendait pas moins utile en tant qu'outil. "Il aura suffisamment d'ennemi pour le satisafaire quand nous rejoindrons la surface, et en retour ses victimes La nourriront."</French>
		<German>Der Haruspex wandte sich ihm zu, die Spinnenbeine nur zum Teil bedeckt von der schwarzen Robe. "Daracaat. Ihr seid einer von Mutters Auserwählten. Ihr seid der Wildeste unserer Art. Ihr werdet die anderen anfÿhren, wenn das Eis schmilzt".</German>
		<Italian>L'Haruspex si voltò verso di lui, le zampe di ragno parzialmente nascoste dalla veste nera. "Daracaat. Tu sei stato scelto da Madre. Sei il più feroce di tutti. Tu guiderai gli altri quando il ghiaccio sparirà". Daracaat guardò su sorpreso mentre le parole venivano pronunciate e un sorriso crudela appariva sul suo viso. [NEWLINE]"Se questa è la volontà di Madre", disse. Qualcosa nella sua voce attirò l'attenzione dell'Haruspex. Una leggera inflessione, un finto mormorio, una traccia di dubbio.[NEWLINE]"La sua volotà non è tua da indovinare, bruto!" ringhiò l'Haruspex, sbilanciando Daracaat con due delle sue zampe che uscivano da sotto il mantello. Non tentò di rialzarsi subito, ma rimase stordito un momento mentre l'Haruspex parlava. "Non c'è bisogno che ti preoccupi di cosa lei voglia, sappi soltanto che sarò io a dirti cosa ti è richiesto. Il suo piano è oltre la tua comprensione."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Daracaat riacquistò i sensi e sorrise mentre rispondeva. "La mia conoscenza è più grande di quanto tu possa pensare, prete. Io so che lei non ti parla, ne parla a chiunque della nostra tribù. Cosa è lei veramente? Una Dea? Una Bestia? Non ha importanza, lei è Potere. Le tue parole ci guidano in suo nome e noi seguiamo. Tu vuoi che io guidi gli altri, lo farò. Prenderò il potere che mi viene dato e renderò la tribù forte, più di quanto sia mai stata. Noi domineremo la superfice mentre tu te ne stai nella tua grotta. La mia posizione sarà incontrastata sino a quando tu mi nimini Suo campione. È cosi che si dovrà fare."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Daracaat lasciò la stanza e si diresse verso il tunnel, più vicino alla superfice con il resto dei membri della tribù. L'Haruspex rimase. Pensando per un momento, contemplò il modo migliore per disfarsi dell'idiota e di chi lo avrebbe rimpiazzato. [NEWLINE]"No, andrà bene per ora", decise. Era vero che Daracaat era un'idiota, un barbaro semplice e sanguinario, ma questo non riduceva la sua utilità come strumento. "Avrà abbastanza nemici con cui saziare la sua sete di sangue quanto torneremo in superfice, e le sue vittime nutriranno Lei".</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Haruspex turned toward him, spider's legs partly hidden by the black robe. "Daracaat. You are of Mother's chosen. You are the fiercest of your kind. You will lead the others when the ice passes". Daracaat looked up in surprise as the words were spoken and a cruel grin played across his features. [NEWLINE]"If that is Mother's will", he said. Something in his voice caught the attention of the Haruspex. A slight inflection, an insincere murmur, a trace of doubt.[NEWLINE]"Her will is not your's to divine, brute!" growled the Haruspex, two of its legs knocking Daracaat clean from his feet as they sprang forth from the cloak. He did not attempt to regain his feet straightaway, but lay stunned for a moment as the Haruspex spoke. "You do not need to concern yourself with what she wants, know only that I will be the one to tell you what is required of you. Her plan is beyond your knowing."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Daracaat regained his senses and smiled as he offered his reply. "I have a greater knowing of things than you may think, priest. I am aware that she does not speak to you, nor any of our tribe. What is she really? A Goddess? A Beast? It doesn't matter - she is Power. Your words direct us in her name and we follow. You wish me to lead the others - I will. I will take the power I am given and build the tribe strong, stronger than it ever was. We shall rule the surface whilst you remain here in your cave. My place will be unchallenged so long as you appoint me as Her champion. That shall be the way of it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Daracaat left the chamber and headed back up the tunnel, closer to the surface with the rest of the tribesmen. The Haruspex remained. Thoughtful for a moment, he contemplated the best way to dispose of the oaf and who would replace him. [NEWLINE]"No, actually he will suffice for now", he decided. It was true that Daracaat was a fool, a simple and bloodthirsty barbarian, but that did not reduce his usefulness as a tool. "He will have enemies plenty enough to satisfy his hunger when we return above, and his victims will in turn feed Her."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_VERAATO</Tag>
		<English>Veraato</English>
		<French>Veraato</French>
		<German>Veraato</German>
		<Italian>Veraato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Veraato</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROODCHAMBER</Tag>
		<English>Brood Chamber</English>
		<French>Chambre des Couvées</French>
		<German>Brutkammer</German>
		<Italian>Camera della Covata</Italian>
		<Spanish>Brood Chamber</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROODCHAMBER1_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Spider units gain 1 free promotion[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Nest Population of 8[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Giant Spider of Level 5 or more</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Les Araignées gagnent une promotion gratuite.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]L'amélioration nécessite une population de la Cité-Tanière de 8[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]L'amélioration nécessite une Araignée Géante de niveau 5 ou plus.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Spinneneinheiten erhalten eine freie Beförderung[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Aufwertung benötigt eine Nestgröße von 8[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Aufwertung benötigt eine Riesenspinne auf Level 5 oder höher</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Le unità di ragni ottengono 1 promozione gratuita[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Per migliorarla la popolazione del Nido deve essere 8[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Per migliorarla bisogna avere un Ragno gigante di Livello 5 o più</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Spider units gain 1 free promotion[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Nest Population of 8[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Giant Spider of Level 5 or more</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROODCHAMBER2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Spider units gain 2 free promotions[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Nest Population of 12[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Giant Spider of Level 6 or more</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Les Araignées gagnent 2 promotions gratuites.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]L'amélioration nécessite une population de la Cité-Tanière de 12[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]L'amélioration nécessite une Araignée Géante de niveau 6 ou plus.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Spinneneinheiten erhalten zwei freie Beförderungen[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Aufwertung benötigt eine Nestgröße von 12[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Aufwertung benötigt eine Riesenspinne auf Level 6 oder höher</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Le unità di ragni ottengono 2 promozioni gratuite[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Per migliorarla la popolazione del Nido deve essere 12[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Per migliorarla bisogna avere un Ragno gigante di Livello 6 o più</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Spider units gain 2 free promotions[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Nest Population of 12[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Giant Spider of Level 6 or more</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROODCHAMBER3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Spider units gain 3 free promotions[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Nest Population of 16[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Giant Spider of Level 7 or more</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Les Araignées gagnent 3 promotions gratuites.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]L'amélioration nécessite une population de la Cité-Tanière de 16[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]L'amélioration nécessite une Araignée Géante de niveau 7 ou plus.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Spinneneinheiten erhalten drei freie Beförderungen[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Aufwertung benötigt eine Nestgröße von 16[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Aufwertung benötigt eine Riesenspinne auf Level 7 oder höher</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Le unità di ragni ottengono 3 promozioni gratuite[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Per migliorarla la popolazione del Nido deve essere 16[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Per migliorarla bisogna avere un Ragno gigante di Livello 7 o più</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Spider units gain 3 free promotions[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Nest Population of 16[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upgrade requires Giant Spider of Level 7 or more</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROODCHAMBER4_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Spider units gain 4 free promotions[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brood Chamber is fully upgraded.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Les Araignées gagnent 4 promotions gratuites.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]La Chambre des Couvées est améliorée au maximum.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Spinneneinheiten erhalten vier freie Beförderungen[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brutkammer ist voll ausgenutzt.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Le unità di ragni ottengono 4 promozioni gratuite[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]La Camera della Covata è comletamente sviluppata.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Spider units gain 4 free promotions[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brood Chamber is fully upgraded.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DARK_WEALD</Tag>
		<English>Dark Weald</English>
		<French>Sombre Bois</French>
		<German>Dunkle Lande</German>
		<Italian>Bosco Oscuro</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dark Weald</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DARK_WEALD_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Each Dark Weald increases the chance of a spider being spawned by the nest.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Chaque Bois Sombre augmente les chances d'apparition d'une Araignée à la Tanière.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Jedes Dunkle Land erhöht die Entstehungschance einer Spinne in dem Nest.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Ogni Bosco Oscuro aumenta le probabilità di generare un ragno dal nido.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Each Dark Weald increases the chance of a spider being spawned by the nest.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DARK_WEALD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A wild corner of the world, the Dark Weald is the perfect place for the children of Mother. Ignorant wanderers and unwelcome visitors who enter it are unlikely to ever see daylight again.</English>
		<French>Un lieu sauvage, le Sombre Bois est l'endroit rêvé pour les enfants de la Mère. Les vagabonds ignorants et les visiteurs inopportuns qui y pénètrent ont peu de chances de jamais revoir la lueur du jour.</French>
		<German>Als wilde Ecke der Welt sind Dunkle Lande ein perfekter Platz für die Kinder der Mutter. Leichsinnige Reisende und unwillkommene Gäste, die sie betreten, werden das Tageslicht schwerlich wiedersehen.</German>
		<Italian>Il Bosco Oscuro è un angolo selvaggio del mondo e un posto perfetto per i figli di Madre. I viaggiatori ignoranti e i visitatori indesiderati che vi entrano difficilmente vedono la luce del sole di nuovo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A wild corner of the world, the Dark Weald is the perfect place for the children of Mother. Ignorant wanderers and unwelcome visitors who enter it are unlikely to ever see daylight again.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DARK_WEALD_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Replacing the Grove and allowing access to the powerful Spiderkin and Haruspex units, a Dark Weald also increases the spawn rate of Mother's Nest.</English>
		<French>Remplaçant le Bosquet et donnant accès aux puissants Tisseuses et Haruspex, le Sombre Bois augmente également la fréquence d'apparition de renforts à la Tanière de la Mère.</French>
		<German>Ersetzt den Hain und erlaubt Zugang zu den mächtigen Spinnen und Haruspex-Einheiten, Dunkle Lande erhöhen zusätzlich die Brutrate des Nests der Mutter.</German>
		<Italian>Rimpiazza il Boschetto e fornisce accesso alle potenti unità Aracnomorfo e Haruspex, il Bosco Oscuro aumenta inoltre le probabilità di generazione del Nido di Madre.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Replacing the Grove and allowing access to the powerful Spiderkin and Haruspex units, a Dark Weald also increases the spawn rate of Mother's Nest.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS</Tag>
		<English>Mother's Nest</English>
		<French>Tanière de la Mère</French>
		<German>Nest der Mutter</German>
		<Italian>Nido di Madre</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mother's Nest</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Has a chance of spawning a spider each turn. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Chance of spawning increased with larger Nest-city population and more  total number of cities controlled. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Chance of spawning reduced for each spider already controlled.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]A une chance de faire apparaître une Araignée à chaque tour.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Les chances d'apparition augmentent avec une population de Cité-Tanière plus importante et plus de villes contrôlées.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Les chances d'apparition diminuent pour chaque Araignée déjà contrôlée.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Möglichkeit, jede Runde eine Spinne zu gebären. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Die Wahrscheinlichkeit erhöht sich durch eine größere Nestbevölkerung und die Zahl der kontrollierten Städte. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Die Wahrscheinlichkeit schrumpft mit jeder bereits kontrollierten Spinne.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Ha una probabilità di generare un ragno ogni turno. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]La probabilità di generare ragni aumenta quanto è più grande la popolazione della città e da quante città si controllano. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Le probabilità di generare un ragno diminuiscono per ogni ragno che già si controlla.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Has a chance of spawning a spider each turn. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Chance of spawning increased with larger Nest-city population and more  total number of cities controlled. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Chance of spawning reduced for each spider already controlled.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Viewed from the surface, the village of Anta seems much like any barbarian settlement, with its warriors, farmers and elders. Below the ground however, in caves only accessible to those chosen to enter, the true leader of the village lies dormant - a queen spider of titanic proportions. Known to the villagers as "Mother" and worshipped by a spider-cult drawn from the population, the spider waits.</English>
		<French>Observé depuis la surface, le village d'Anta ressemble énormément à n'importe quel campement de barbares, avec ses guerriers, ses fermiers et ses anciens. Cependant, sous la surface, dans des grottes uniquement accessibles à ceux autorisés à entrer, le vrai dirigeant du village reste endormi: une reine araignée aux proportions titanesques. Connue par les villageois sous le nom de "Mère", et adoré par un culte populaire autour de l'araignée, l'Araignée attend.</French>
		<German>Von oben betrachtet gleicht das Dorf Anta einem gewöhnlichen Barbarendorf, mit seinen Kriegern, Farmern und Weisen. Unter der Oberfläche jedoch, in Höhlen, die nur Auserkorenen zugänglich sind, ruht der wahrer Anführer des Dorfes - eine Spinnenkönigin von gigantischen Ausmaßen. Den Dorfbewohnern bekannt als "Mutter" und verehrt von einem Spinnenkult, der sich aus der Bevölkerung zusammensetzt, wartet die Spinne.</German>
		<Italian>Visto da fuori, il villaggio di Anta è simili a qualsiasi altro insediamento barbaro, con i suoi guerrieri, contadini e anziani. Sotto di esso invece, in grotte accessibili solamente a chi è stato scelto, il vero capo del villaggio giace dormiente, unaa regina ragno di proporzioni titaniche. Conosciuta dagli abitanti del villaggio come "Madre" e venerata da un culto che venera i ragni nato dalla popolazione, il ragno attende.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Viewed from the surface, the village of Anta seems much like any barbarian settlement, with its warriors, farmers and elders. Below the ground however, in caves only accessible to those chosen to enter, the true leader of the village lies dormant - a queen spider of titanic proportions. Known to the villagers as "Mother" and worshipped by a spider-cult drawn from the population, the spider waits.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Mother's Nest is at the heart of the Archos civilization. The prime concern of the tribe is to keep Mother happy and increase the size of her nest. This is reflected by increasing bonuses as the city containing Mother's Nest increases in size. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City Size 4: May spawn Baby Spiders. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City Size 8: May spawn Spiders. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City Size 12: May spawn Giant Spiders.  [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City Size 16: Worldspell available (also requires Feral Bond)[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]The chance of spawning increases as the city grows and other cities are founded, though is reduced for each spider already controlled. The maximum number of spiders you may have is related to the population of the Nest city and the total number of cities you have currently. A "Dark Weald" building (replaces Grove) built in any city will also increase the chances of spawning in the nest.[PARAGRAPH:1]If you bring an experienced spider to your Nest, it may be deemed worthy to mate with (and subsequently be devoured by) Mother. This allows the brood to increase in strength by granting free promotions to all newly born spiders. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brood Strength 1: Requires City Size 4 and a Level 4 Giant Spider[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brood Strength 2: Requires City Size 8 and a Level 5 Giant Spider[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brood Strength 3: Requires City Size 12 and a Level 6 Giant Spider[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brood Strength 4: Requires City Size 16 and a Level 7 Giant Spider</English>
		<French>La Tanière de la Mère est au c&#156;ur de la civilisation Archosienne. Le but premier du clan est de garder la Mère heureuse et augmenter la taille de sa tanière. Ceci est reflété par l'augmentation de bonus tandis que la cité contenant la Tanière de la Mère croît.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Taille de la ville 4 : Peut permettre l'apparition de Bébé Araignées.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Taille de la ville 8 : Peut permettre l'apparition d'Araignées.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Taille de la ville 12 : Peut permettre l'apparition d'Araignées Géantes.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Taille de la ville 16 : Permet le lancement du sort mondial (avec Lien Sauvage).[PARAGRAPH:2]Les chances d'apparition d'Araignées augmentent de pair avec la taille de la ville, de même qu'avec la fondation de nouvelles villes, et diminue pour chaque Araignée déjà contrôlée. Le nombre maximal d'Araignées que vous pouvez contrôler est lié à la population de la Cité-Tanière et au nombre total de villes actuellement possédées. La construction d'un "Sombre Bois" (qui remplace le Bosquet) dans n'importe quelle ville augmentera également les chances d'apparition d'Araignée dans la Tanière.[PARAGRAPH:1]Si vous ramenez une Araignée expérimentée à votre Tanière, elle peut être considérée comme digne de s'accoupler (et par conséquent être dévorée) à la Mère. Cela permet à la couvée de se renforcer en fournissant des promotions gratuites à toutes vos Araignées à naître.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Force de la Couvée 1 : Requiert la Cité-Tanière de taille 4 et une Araignée Géante de niveau 4.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Force de la Couvée 2 : Requiert la Cité-Tanière de taille 8 et une Araignée Géante de niveau 5.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Force de la Couvée 3 : Requiert la Cité-Tanière de taille 12 et une Araignée Géante de niveau 6.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Force de la Couvée 4 : Requiert la Cité-Tanière de taille 16 et une Araignée Géante de niveau 7.</French>
		<German>PROBABLY OBSOLETE[NEWLINE]Das Nest der Mutter ist das Herz der Arachonischen Zivilisation. Das Hauptanliegen des Stammes ist das Wohlbefinden der Mutter und die Vergrößerung ihres Nestes. Dies spiegelt sich durch steigende Boni wieder sobald die Stadt das Nest der Mutter erweitert. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Bevölkerung 5: Babyspinnen können enstehen. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Bevölkerung 10: Riesenspinnen können entstehen. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Bevölkerung 15: Weltenzauber verfügbar (benötigt Ungezähmte Bindung)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Bevölkerung 20: Starke Riesenspinnen können entstehen[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Die Chance einer Enstehung erhöht sich, wenn die Stadt wächst und andere Städte gegründet werden, verringert sich jedoch durch jede bereits kontrollierte Spinne. Andere Städte innerhalb der Zivilisation entsprechen nur dem äquivalent von 1 Bevölkerung im Nest, unabhängig von ihrer tatsächlichen Einwohnerzahl. Ein "Dunkle Lande"-Gebäude (ersetzt Hain), das in einer beliebigen Stadt gebaut wurde, erhöht ebenfalls die Chance einer Ausbrütung.</German>
		<Italian>Il Nido di Madre è il cuore della civiltà Archos. La preoccupazione principale della popolazione della tribù è di mantenere Madre felice e di aumentare le dimensioni del suo nido. Ciò si riflette in bonus che aumentano con l'aumentare della grandezza della città in cui è presente il Nido di Madre. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grandezza della Città 4: Può generare Ragnetti. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gradezza della Città 8: Puo generare Ragni. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grandezza della Città 12: Può generare Ragni Giganti. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grandezza della Città 16: Magia Mondiale disponibile (richiede anche Legame Bestiale)[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]La probabilità di generare unità aumenta con l'aumentare della popolazione della città e con il numero di città che si possiedono, ma viene ridotta dal numero di ragni che già si controlla. Il numero massimo di ragni che si possono controllare e dettato dalla popolazione della città in cui vi è il Nido di Madre e dal numero di città che si controlla. L'edificio "Bosco Oscuro" (rimpiazza il Boschetto) costruito in ogni città aumenterà le probabilità di generare unità del nido.[PARAGRAPH:1]Se porti un ragno con molta esperienza al Nido potrebbe essere ritenuto degno di accoppiarsi con (e successivamente essere divorato da) Madre. Questo permette alla covata di aumentare la sua forza fornendo promozioni gratuite a tutti i nuovi ragni. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Potenza dela Covata 1: Richiede Grandezza della città 4 e un Ragno Gigante di Livello 4[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Potenza della Covata 2: Richiede Grandezza della Città 8 e un Ragno Gigante di Livello 5[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Potenza della Covata 3: Richiede Grandezza della Città 12 e un Ragno Gigante di Livello 6[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Potenza della Covata 4: Richiede Grandezza della CIttà 16 e un Ragno Gigante di Livello 7</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mother's Nest is at the heart of the Archos civilization. The prime concern of the tribe is to keep Mother happy and increase the size of her nest. This is reflected by increasing bonuses as the city containing Mother's Nest increases in size. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City Size 4: May spawn Baby Spiders. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City Size 8: May spawn spiders. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City Size 12: May spawn Giant Spiders.  [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]City Size 16: Worldspell available (also requires Feral Bond)[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]The chance of spawning increases as the city grows and other cities are founded, though is reduced for each spider already controlled. The maximum number of spiders you may have is related to the population of the Nest city and the total number of cities you have currently. A "Dark Weald" building (replaces Grove) built in any city will also increase the chances of spawning in the nest.[PARAGRAPH:1]If you bring an experienced spider to your Nest, it may be deemed worthy to mate with (and subsequently be devoured by) Mother. This allows the brood to increase in strength by granting free promotions to all newly born spiders. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brood Strength 1: Requires City Size 4 and a Level 4 Giant Spider[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brood Strength 2: Requires City Size 8 and a Level 5 Giant Spider[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brood Strength 3: Requires City Size 12 and a Level 6 Giant Spider[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Brood Strength 4: Requires City Size 16 and a Level 7 Giant Spider</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MESSAGE_SCORPION_BORN_IN_NEST</Tag>
		<English>A scorpion has been born in the nest.</English>
		<French>Un Scorpion est né à la Tanière.</French>
		<German>Ein Skorpion ist dem Nest entschlüpft.</German>
		<Italian>Uno Scoprione è nato nel Nido.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A scorpion has been born in the nest.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MESSAGE_SPIDER_BORN_IN_NEST</Tag>
		<English>A spider has been born in the nest.</English>
		<French>Une Araignée est née à la Tanière.</French>
		<German>Eine Spinne ist dem Nest entschlüpft.</German>
		<Italian>Un Ragno è nato nel Nido.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A spider has been born in the nest.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_CALL_SPIDERS</Tag>
		<English>Call Spiders</English>
		<French>Invoquer des Araignées</French>
		<German>Spinnen beschwören</German>
		<Italian>Chiama i Ragni</Italian>
		<Spanish>Call Spiders</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_CALL_SPIDERS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Haruspex is able to call spiders into battle.</English>
		<French>Le Haruspex est capable d'invoquer des Araignées au combat.</French>
		<German>Der Haruspex kann Spinnen in den Kampf rufen.</German>
		<Italian>L'Haruspex è capace di chiamare dei ragni in battaglia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Haruspex is able to call spiders into battle.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_DEVOUR_MATE</Tag>
		<English>Devour Mate</English>
		<French>Dévorer le partenaire</French>
		<German>Gefressen werden</German>
		<Italian>Divora il Compagno</Italian>
		<Spanish>Devour Mate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_DEVOUR_MATE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>This spell allows an experienced spider to return to the nest to ensure future generations of the brood are strong. After the first time it is used, the Nest will gain a "Brood Chamber". Further uses require increasingly experienced spiders to upgrade the Broodchamber (the current level required for upgrade is displayed on the Broodchamber help text in the city).</English>
		<French>Ce sort permet à une Araignée vétéran de retourner à la Tanière afin de s'assurer que la future génération de la couvée sera forte. Après sa première utilisation, la Tanière aura construit une "Chambre des Couvées". Les utilisations ultérieures nécessitent des Araignées de plus en plus expérimentées afin d'améliorer la Chambre des Couvées (le niveau requis pour l'amélioration est affiché dans la bulle d'aide de la Chambre des Couvées dans la ville).</French>
		<German>Dieser 'Zauber' opfert eine erfahrene Spinne im Nest. Dadurch wird die nachkommende Brut nur noch stärker. Das erste Wirken des 'Zaubers' erschafft eine Brutkammer. Weiteres Wirken benötigt erfahrenere Spinnen und werter die Brutkammer immer weiter auf (das benötigt Level der Spinne und der Stadt wird im Brutkammer-Hilfe-Menü der Stadt angezeigt).</German>
		<Italian>Questa magia permette a un ragno esperto di tornare al nido per aumentare la forza delle future covate. Dopo la prima volta che viene usata, il Nido otterrà una "Camera della Covata". Ulteriori usi richiedono ragni sempre più esperti per migliorare la Camera della Covata (l'attuale livello necessario per migliorarla e mostrato nel testo della Camera della Covata nella città).</Italian>
		<Spanish>This spell allows an experienced spider to return to the nest to ensure future generations of the brood are strong. After the first time it is used, the Nest will gain a "Brood Chamber". Further uses require increasingly experienced spiders to upgrade the Broodchamber (the current level required for upgrade is displayed on the Broodchamber help text in the city).</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FERAL_RAGE</Tag>
		<English>Feral Rage</English>
		<French>Rage Sauvage</French>
		<German>Wilde Raserei</German>
		<Italian>Rabbia Bestiale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Feral Rage</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FERAL_RAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Whilst the druid uses its affinity with nature to protect, the Haruspex uses it to drive animals into a furious rage.</English>
		<French>Tandis que le druide utilise ses affinités avec la nature pour protéger, le Haruspex l'utilise pour faire entrer les animaux dans une rage furieuse.</French>
		<German>Während der Druide seine Verbundenheit mit der Natur dafür benutzt, um zu beschützen, versetzt der Haruspex damit Tiere in eine fürchterliche Raserei.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre il druido usa la sua affinità alla natura per proteggerla, l'Haruspex la usa per spingere gli animali in una rabbia furibonda.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Whilst the druid uses its affinity with nature to protect, the Haruspex uses it to drive animals into a furious rage.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MINOR_BROOD</Tag>
		<English>Minor Brood</English>
		<French>Pondre Couvée Mineure</French>
		<German>Mindere Brut</German>
		<Italian>Covata minore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Minor Brood</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MINOR_BROOD_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Consumes the "meat" resource, creates a half dozen or more Baby Spiders.  Experienced Giant Spiders create more powerful Baby Spiders.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Détruit la "nourriture" et crée une demi-douzaine ou plus de Bébé Araignées. Les Araignées Géantes de plus haut niveau créent des Bébé Araignées plus puissantes.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Verbraucht die "Fleisch"-Quelle, und produziert daraus 6 oder mehr Babyspinnen. Erfahrene Riesenspinnen erschaffen stärkere als unerfahrene.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Consuma la risorsa "carne" per creare sei o più Ragnetti. I Ragni Giganti esperti creano Ragnetti più forti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Consumes the "meat" resource, creates a half dozen or more Baby Spiders.  Experienced Giant Spiders create more powerful Baby Spiders.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MINOR_BROOD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Glutted with sufficient blood Giant Spiders are able to reproduce at terrifying rate.</English>
		<French>Rassasiées avec suffisamment de sang, les Araignées Géantes sont capables de se reproduire à une vitesse terrifiante.</French>
		<German>Glutted with sufficient blood Giant Spiders are able to reproduce at terrifying rate.</German>
		<Italian>Riforniti con sufficente sangue i Ragni Giganti si possono riprodurre a una velocità terrifficante.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Glutted with sufficient blood Giant Spiders are able to reproduce at terrifying rate.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MINOR_BROOD_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Requires - and completely consumes - a Cow, Pig, Sheep, Horse, Deer or Artic Deer resource.[NEWLINE]For every level after the second the resulting Baby Spiders gain an Empower level. (Max Empower V.)</English>
		<French>Requiert (et détruit complètement) des vaches, des cochons, des moutons, des chevaux, des cerfs ou des cerfs arctiques (ressources).[NEWLINE]Pour chaque niveau après le second, les nouvelles Bébé Araignées gagnent un niveau d'infusion de puissance (Infusion de Puissance V maximum).</French>
		<German>Requires - and completely consumes - a Cow, Pig, Sheep, Horse, Deer or Artic Deer resource.[NEWLINE]For every level after the second the resulting Baby Spiders gain an Empower level. (Max Empower V.)</German>
		<Italian>Richede, e consuma completamente, una risorsa di Bovini, Maiali, Pecora, Cavallo, Cervo o Renna.[NEWLINE]Per ogni livello dopo il secondo i Ragnetti risultanti ottengono un livello di Potere. (Max Potere V.)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Requires - and completely consumes - a Cow, Pig, Sheep, Horse, Deer or Artic Deer resource.[NEWLINE]For every level after the second the resulting Baby Spiders gain an Empower level. (Max Empower V.)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WAKE_MOTHER</Tag>
		<English>Awaken Mother</English>
		<French>Réveil de la Mère</French>
		<German>Mutter erwecken</German>
		<Italian>Svegliare Madre</Italian>
		<Spanish>Awaken Mother</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WAKE_MOTHER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Requires a population of 16 in the nest-city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Releases the Mother Spider from the nest to wreak havoc upon your foes.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Requiert une population de 16 dans la Cité-Tanière.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Invoque la Mère des Araignées à la tanière pour ravager les rangs de vos ennemis.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Benötigt eine Bevölkerung von 16 in der Nest-Stadt.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Entsendet die Spinnenmutter aus dem Nest, um Verwüstung unter Euren Feinden anzurichten.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Richiede una popolazione di 16 nella città del nido.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Libera il Ragno Madre dal nido per devastare i tuoi nemici.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Requires a population of 16 in the nest-city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Releases the Mother Spider from the nest to wreak havoc upon your foes.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WAKE_MOTHER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>This Archos Worldspell unleashes a potent hero-unit, but being able to do so in a timely fashion requires a strategic decision early in the game. The spell requires the "Feral Bond" technology, which lies along the recon-line of technologies. Fortunately, this a strong line for the Archos anyway, but the scientific expense required to reach Feral Bond is significant and may hamper your development in other areas.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Also be aware that you need to build your capital to size 15 before the world spell is available. The Nest building helps with happiness (provided you can find meat-resources) but you will need to carefully consider how to develop the Nest-city from the start. Everything your tribe does should ultimately be to improve the nest and please Mother.</English>
		<French>Ce sort mondial Archosien relâche une unité héroïque puissante, mais être capable de le lancer tôt implique de prendre un décision stratégique très tôt dans le jeu. Ce sort nécessitant la technologie "Lien Sauvage", qui se trouve dans l'arbre de technologie lié au renseignement. Heureusement, c'est de toutes les façons un arbre utile pour Archos, mais l'investissement en recherche nécessaire à la recherche de Lien Sauvage est important et peut handicaper votre développement dans d'autres domaines.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Par ailleurs, gardez bien à l'esprit que votre capitale doit avoir au moins 15 de population pour que le sort mondial soit disponible. La construction de la Tanière aide à éviter les citoyens mécontents (à conditions que vous trouviez des ressources de type nourriture), mais vous devrez réfléchir attentivement à la façon de dévolopper votre Cité-Tanière dès le départ. Tout ce que fait votre clan devrait idéalement servir à développer la Tanière et plaire à la Mère.</French>
		<German>This Archos Worldspell unleashes a potent hero-unit, but being able to do so in a timely fashion requires a strategic decision early in the game. The spell requires the "Feral Bond" technology, which lies along the recon-line of technologies. Fortunately, this a strong line for the Archos anyway, but the scientific expense required to reach Feral Bond is significant and may hamper your development in other areas.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Also be aware that you need to build your capital to size 15 before the world spell is available. The Nest building helps with happiness (provided you can find meat-resources) but you will need to carefully consider how to develop the Nest-city from the start. Everything your tribe does should ultimately be to improve the nest and please Mother.</German>
		<Italian>La Magia Mondiale Archos scatena una potente unità eroe, ma per poterlo fare al momento giusto e necessario prendere decisioni strategiche all'inzio della partita. La magia richede la tecnologia "Legame Bestiale", che fa parte della linea di tecnologie per la ricognizione. Fortunatamente, è una linea molto utile agli Archos, ma lo sforzo scientifico richesto per raggiungere Legame Bestiale è significativo e può rallentare il tuo sviluppo in altre aree.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Ricorda inoltre che devi far crescere la tua capitale sino a grandezza 15 prima che la magia diventi disponibile. L'edificio Nido aiuta la felicità (se riesci a trovare risorse di carne) ma dovrai decidere attentamente come sviluppare la città del Nido dall'inizio. Tutto ciò che la tua tribù fa dovrebbe portare al miglioramento del Nido e al compiacere Madre.</Italian>
		<Spanish>This Archos Worldspell unleashes a potent hero-unit, but being able to do so in a timely fashion requires a strategic decision early in the game. The spell requires the "Feral Bond" technology, which lies along the recon-line of technologies. Fortunately, this a strong line for the Archos anyway, but the scientific expense required to reach Feral Bond is significant and may hamper your development in other areas.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Also be aware that you need to build your capital to size 15 before the world spell is available. The Nest building helps with happiness (provided you can find meat-resources) but you will need to carefully consider how to develop the Nest-city from the start. Everything your tribe does should ultimately be to improve the nest and please Mother.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WAKE_MOTHER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Invokes Mother, the Archosian hero.</English>
		<French>Invoque la Mère, l'unité héroïque des Archosiens.[NEWLINE]Voir le background pour plus d'informations</French>
		<German>Invokes Mother, the Archosian hero.</German>
		<Italian>Richiama Madre, l'eroe Archosiano.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Invokes Mother, the Archosian hero.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BRUTE</Tag>
		<English>Brute</English>
		<French>Brute</French>
		<German>Arachna</German>
		<Italian>Bruto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Brute</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BRUTE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Brutes are simply the fiercest and most aggressive of their tribe. Wielding a heavy stone or bronze axe, lashing out at times with teeth or clawed hand - these warriors show the first physical signs of Mother's toxic influence.</English>
		<French>Les Brutes sont tout simplement les plus cruels et les plus agressifs de leur clan. Utilsant une lourde hache de pierre ou de bronze, ruant parfois de coups de leurs mains griffues ou mordant, ces guerriers montrent les premiers signes physiques de l'influence toxique de la Mère.</French>
		<German>Brutes are simply the fiercest and most aggressive of their tribe. Wielding a heavy stone or bronze axe, lashing out at times with teeth or clawed hand - these warriors show the first physical signs of Mother's toxic influence.</German>
		<Italian>I bruti sono semplicemente i più feroci e aggressivi della loro tribù. Usando una pietra pesante o un'ascia di bronzo, usando a volte i denti o una mano artigliata, questi guerrieri mostrano i primi segni fisici dell'influenza tossica di Madre.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Brutes are simply the fiercest and most aggressive of their tribe. Wielding a heavy stone or bronze axe, lashing out at times with teeth or clawed hand - these warriors show the first physical signs of Mother's toxic influence.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BRUTE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Boasting an increased strength due to +1 Poison combat, Brutes will often not feel the effects of lacking Iron Weapons. Even without weapon upgrades, these units are a solid choice.</English>
		<French>Profitant d'une force accrue grâce au +1 Poison (puissance de combat), les Brutes ne ressentiront généralement pas les effets du manque d'armes de Fer. Même sans les améliorations d'armes, ces unités sont un choix solide.</French>
		<German>Boasting and increased strength due to +1 Poison combat, Brutes will often not feel the effects of lacking Iron Weapons. Even without weapon upgrades, these units are a solid choice.</German>
		<Italian>Avendo una maggiore forza grazie al +1 da veleno, i Bruti spesso non sentono l'effetto del non avere Armi in Ferro. Persino senza armi migliori queste unità rimangono una valida scelta.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Boasting and increased strength due to +1 Poison combat, Brutes will often not feel the effects of lacking Iron Weapons. Even without weapon upgrades, these units are a solid choice.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CHOSEN</Tag>
		<English>Chosen</English>
		<French>Élu</French>
		<German>Auserwählter</German>
		<Italian>Prescelto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chosen</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CHOSEN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The "Chosen" are those Archosians who display some physical mutation as a result of the time spent living in the spider's nest during the Age of Ice. In the most extreme cases, these mutations take the form of additional limbs or eyes. The Chosen are allowed entry to Mother's Nest itself and defend the cult from outsiders.</English>
		<French>Les "Élus" sont les Archosiens qui présentent des mutations physiques issues du temps passé dans la Tanière durant l'Ère Glaciaire. Dans les cas les plus extrêmes, ces mutations se manifestent sous la forme de membres ou yeux supplémentaires. Les Élus sont autorisés à pénétrer la Tanière de la Mère elle-même et défendent le culte des étrangers.</French>
		<German>The "Chosen" are those Archosians who display some physical mutation as a result of the time spent living in the spider's nest during the Age of Ice. In the most extreme cases, these mutations take the form of additional limbs or eyes. The Chosen are allowed entry to Mother's Nest itself and defend the cult from outsiders.</German>
		<Italian>I "Prescelti" sono gli Archosiani che possiedono qualche mutazione fisica dovuta al periodo di tempo passato vivendo nel nido dei ragni durante l'Era del Ghiaccio. Nei casi più estremi queste mutazioni si presentano sotto forza di arti o occhi addizionali. Ai Prescelti è permesso entrare nel Nido di Madre stessa e difendono il culto dagli estranei.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The "Chosen" are those Archosians who display some physical mutation as a result of the time spent living in the spider's nest during the Age of Ice. In the most extreme cases, these mutations take the form of additional limbs or eyes. The Chosen are allowed entry to Mother's Nest itself and defend the cult from outsiders.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CHOSEN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Chosen are the first Archos unit able to make use of Iron Weapons. Whilst they lack the late-game benefit of Mithril Weapons, they enjoy an innate bonus of +1 Poison Combat.</English>
		<French>Les Élus sont les premières unités archosiennes capables d'utiliser des armes de fer. Bien qu'ils ne puissent pas utiliser l'avantage des armes en mithril de fin de jeu, ils profitent d'un bonus inné de +1 Poison (Puissance de combat).</French>
		<German>Chosen are the first Archos unit able to make use of Iron Weapons. Whilst they lack the late-game benefit of Mithril Weapons, they enjoy an innate bonus of +1 Poison Combat.</German>
		<Italian>I Prescelti sono la prima unità Archos capace di usare Armi in Ferro. Nonostante non abbiano la possibilità di usare Armi in Mithril, possiedono un bonus innato di +1 da veleno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chosen are the first Archos unit able to make use of Iron Weapons. Whilst they lack the late-game benefit of Mithril Weapons, they enjoy an innate bonus of +1 Poison Combat.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ETERNAL</Tag>
		<English>Eternal</English>
		<French>Éternel</French>
		<German>Ewiger</German>
		<Italian>Eterno</Italian>
		<Spanish>Eternal</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HARUSPEX</Tag>
		<English>Haruspex</English>
		<French>Haruspex</French>
		<German>Haruspex</German>
		<Italian>Haruspex</Italian>
		<Spanish>Haruspex</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HARUSPEX_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Haruspex are the priests of the Archosian spider-cult, fiercely dedicated to Mother. They share some of the same abilities as Druids, but whilst a Druid serves to preserve the balance of nature, a Haruspex utilises a darker and more unforgiving aspect of the wild.</English>
		<French>Les Haruspex sont les prêtres du culte de l'Araignée archosien, cruellement dédié à la Mère. Ils partagent certaines compétences avec les druides, mais tandis que le druide est dévoué à la préservation de l'équilibre de la nature, le haruspex utilise un aspect plus sombre et impitoyable des contrées sauvages.</French>
		<German>Haruspex sind die Priester des Arachonischen Spinnenkultes, Mutter geweiht und ihr Leben ihr gewidmet. Sie teilen einige Fähigkeiten mit den Druiden, aber während ein Druide versucht, das Gleichgewicht der Natur zu bewahren, benutzt ein Haruspex einen dunkleren und unverzeihlicheren Aspekt der Wildnis.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Haruspex sono i preti del culto dei ragni Archosiano, ferocemente devoti a Madre. Condividono alcune abilità con i Druidi, ma dove un Druido cerca di preservare l'equilibrio della natura, un Haruspex utilizza un'aspetto più oscuro e spietato di quest'ultima.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Haruspex are the priests of the Archosian spider-cult, fiercely dedicated to Mother. They share some of the same abilities as Druids, but whilst a Druid serves to preserve the balance of nature, a Haruspex utilises a darker and more unforgiving aspect of the wild.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HARUSPEX_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Haruspex gains access to the Chaos sphere of magic, enabling a range of more aggressive spells. He lacks the potent summons of a normal druid however and must rely on his own strength and affinities to survive.</English>
		<French>Le Haruspex a obtenu l'accès à la sphère magique du Chaos, procurant une variété de sorts plus agressifs. Il lui manque cependant le puissantes invocations d'un Druide classique et ne peut compter que sur sa force propre et ses compétences pour survivre.</French>
		<German>Der Haruspex erhält Zugang zu der magischen Sphäre des Chaos, die eine Reihe offensiverer Zauber beinhaltet. Es mangelt ihm jedoch im Vergleich mit einem normalen Druiden an mächtigen Beschwörungen, und so ist er auf seine eigen Stärke und Verbundenheiten angewiesen, um zu überleben.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Haruspex ottengono accesso alla sfera della magia del Caos, permettendo un uso di magie più aggressive. Ma gli mancano le potenti evocazioni dei normali Druidi e può fare affidamento solo sulla sua forza e affinità per sopravvivere.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Haruspex gains access to the Chaos sphere of magic, enabling a range of more aggressive spells. He lacks the potent summons of a normal druid however and must rely on his own strength and affinities to survive.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HUNTSMAN</Tag>
		<English>Huntsman</English>
		<French>Veneur</French>
		<German>Waidmann</German>
		<Italian>Cacciatore Archosiano</Italian>
		<Spanish>Huntsman</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HUNTSMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Archosian Huntsmen spend weeks in the wilds of Erebus, stalking prey with a spider companion. When it is time to strike, the spider attacks and paralyses the target with venom before the Huntsman deals the deathblow. The tribe have been living with spiders for so long that the venom in the carcass is no longer deadly to them - though it does take it's toll.</English>
		<French>Les Veneurs Archosiens passent des semaines dans les contrées sauvages d'Erebus, pistant ses proies avec son compagnon Araignée. Lorsqu'il faut frapper, l'Araignée attaque et paralyse sa cible avec son venin avant que le Veneur fasse le tir mortel. Le clan a vécu avec les Araignées depuis si longtemps que le venin présent dans la carcasse n'est plus mortel pour eux (même s'il continue de prendre son dû).</French>
		<German>Archosian Huntsmen spend weeks in the wilds of Erebus, stalking prey with a spider companion. When it is time to strike, the spider attacks and paralyses the target with venom before the Huntsman deals the deathblow. The tribe have been living with spiders for so long that the venom in the carcass is no longer deadly to them - though it does take it's toll.</German>
		<Italian>I cacciatori Archosiani passano settimane nelle terre selvaggie di Erebus, cacciando furtivamente le prede insieme a un ragno. Quando è il momento di colpire il ragno paralizza il bersaglio con il veleno per poi far dare il colpo di grazia dal cacciatore. La tribù ha vissuto con i ragni per cosi tanto tempo che il veleno presente nella carcassa della preda non è più mortale per loro, sebbene continui ad avere degli effetti spiacevoli.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Archosian Huntsmen spend weeks in the wilds of Erebus, stalking prey with a spider companion. When it is time to strike, the spider attacks and paralyses the target with venom before the Huntsman deals the deathblow. The tribe have been living with spiders for so long that the venom in the carcass is no longer deadly to them - though it does take it's toll.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HUNTSMAN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Using +1 Poison combat to make up what he lacks offensively, the Archosian Huntsman is a good choice for defending your lands against early invasion (especially from the barbarians, if your "alliance" proves to be "unstable").</English>
		<French>Utilisant le bonus de combat de +1 Poison pour compenser ses manques offensifs, le Veneur Archosien est un bon choix pour défendre votre territoire contre des invasions précoces (particulièrement des Barbares, si votre "Alliance" s'avère "instable").</French>
		<German>Using +1 Poison combat to make up what he lacks offensively, the Archosian Huntsman is a good choice for defending your lands against early invasion (especially from the barbarians, if your "alliance" proves to be "unstable").</German>
		<Italian>Usando il bonus +1 da veleno per compensare ciò che gli manca in attacco il cacciatore Archosiano è una buona scelta per difendere i tuoi territori contro le prime invasioni (specialmente quelle dei barbari, se la tua "alleanza" si dimostra "instabile").</Italian>
		<Spanish>Using +1 Poison combat to make up what he lacks offensively, the Archosian Huntsman is a good choice for defending your lands against early invasion (especially from the barbarians, if your "alliance" proves to be "unstable").</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOTHER_SPIDER</Tag>
		<English>Mother</English>
		<French>Mère</French>
		<German>Mutter</German>
		<Italian>Madre</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mother</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOTHER_SPIDER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Light. Bright. Prey outside. Hunt. Kill. Feed.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The massive form of the spider burst from the cave on legs like chitinous birch trees. The dwarves stood for a moment in shock as the beast speared the first of them. Panic swept the ranks of the Soldiers of Kilmorph and some began to run. Never before had they seen such a beast, and by Kandros' gold - it looked angry.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Kill. Feed. Kill. Feed. Kill. Protect the nest.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Haruspex emerged from the cave next, leading a host of giant spiders. Beneath them, the floor moved as a carpet of Mother's young raced ahead. As the first spells were cast, the dwarves were in full flight. Huntsmen were already in pursuit, few of their warriors would make it back to their mountain homes. The Haruspex attended Mother, expecting her to return to the nest. She did not. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Hunt. Kill. Feed. Hunt...</English>
		<French>Lumière. Brillance. Proie dehors. Chasser. Tuer.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]La forme massive de l'Araignée surgit de la grotte sur des pattes comme des bouleaux chitineux. Les nains restèrent figés de stupeur tandis que la bête harponnait le premier d'entre eux. La panique s'empara des rangs des Soldats de Kilmorph et certains se mirent à courir. Jamais ils n'avaient vu une telle bête, et par tout l'or de Kandros, elle semblait vraiment furieuse![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Tuer. Nourrir. Tuer. Nourrir. Tuer. Protéger la Tanière.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Les Haruspex émergèrent par la suite de la grotte, menant une horde d'Araignées Géantes. A leurs pieds, le sol se mouvait comme un tapis tandis que les rejetons de la Mère se précipitaient dehors. Tandis que les premiers sorts étaient lancés, les nains étaient en pleine fuite. Les veneurs étaient déjà à leur poursuite, peu d'entre eux reverraient jamais leur montagne natale. Les Haruspex attendirent la Mère, espérant qu'elle reviendrait à la Tanière. Elle ne revint pas.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Chasser. Tuer. Nourrir. Chasser...</French>
		<German>Licht. Helligkeit. Bete draußen. Jage. Töte. Friß.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Die massige Gestalt der Spinne schoss aus der Höhle, auf Beinen wie chitingewordene Baumstämme. Die Zwerge erstarrten einen Moment vor Schreck, als das Biest die ersten von ihnen durchbohrte.  Panik erfasste die Reihen der Soldaten von Kilmorph, und einige flohen bereits. Niemals zuvor hatten sie so eine Bestie erblickt, und bei Kandros Gold - sie sah verärgert aus.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Töte. Friß. Töte. Friß. Töte. Beschütze das Nest.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Der Haruspex stürmte als nächstes aus der Höhle, gefolgt von einem Heer Riesenspinnen. Unter ihnen bewegte sich der Boden, als ein Teppich aus Mutters Jüngsten losraste. Als die ersten Zauber gewirkt wurden, befanden sich die Zwerge bereits in heilloser Flucht. Waidmänner nahmen bereits die Verfolgung auf, nur wenige ihrer Krieger würden es heim zu ihren Bergen schaffen. Der Haruspex begleitete Mutter, in der Erwartung, sie würde ins Nest zurückkehren. Was sie nicht tat. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Jage. Töte. Friß. Jage...</German>
		<Italian>Luce. Brillante. Prede fuori. Cacciare. Uccidere. Nutrirsi.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]La forma imponente del ragno usci dalla grotta su zampe chitinose che sembravano alberi di betualla. I nani rimasero un momento in stato di shock quando la bestia infilzò il primo di loro. Il panico si diffuse tra i Soldati di Kilmorph e qualcuno iniziò a scappare. Mai prima d'ora avevano visto una bestia come quella, e per l'oro di Kandros, sembrava arrabbiata.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Uccidere. Nutrirsi. Uccidere. Nutrirsi. Uccidere. Proteggere il nido.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Gli Haruspex arrivarono dalla grotta successiva, guidando un gruppo di Ragni Giganti. Sotto di loro, il pavimento era coperto da un tappeto di giovani figli di Madre che correvano davanti. Mentre le prime magie venivano lanciate i nani erano già in piena rotta. I cacciatori Archosiani erano gia all'inseguimento, sarebbero stati pochi i guerrieri nanici che sarebbero riusciti a tornare alle loro case nelle montagne. Gli Haruspex assisterono Madre, aspettandosi che sarebbe tornata al nido. Lei non lo fece. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Cacciare. Uccidere. Nutrirsi. Cacciare...</Italian>
		<Spanish>Light. Bright. Prey outside. Hunt. Kill. Feed.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The massive form of the spider burst from the cave on legs like chitinous birch trees. The dwarves stood for a moment in shock as the beast speared the first of them. Panic swept the ranks of the Soldiers of Kilmorph and some began to run. Never before had they seen such a beast, and by Kandros' gold - it looked angry.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Kill. Feed. Kill. Feed. Kill. Protect the nest.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Haruspex emerged from the cave next, leading a host of giant spiders. Beneath them, the floor moved as a carpet of Mother's young raced ahead. As the first spells were cast, the dwarves were in full flight. Huntsmen were already in pursuit, few of their warriors would make it back to their mountain homes. The Haruspex attended Mother, expecting her to return to the nest. She did not. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Hunt. Kill. Feed. Hunt...</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOTHER_SPIDER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Releasing Mother upon the world is one of the highlights of playing the Archos, but be careful not to let enthusiasm get the better of her. Whilst she is a competent unit in combat, she is far from invincible - and let's face it, when you're *that* big, you're going to draw some unwanted attention from your enemies... [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She can in-fact be released twice (using the Birthright Regained ritual),the tales of her first death were obviously greatly exaggerated (she was just pining for the Fjords). Only one instance of Mother can exist at a time however.</English>
		<French>Lâcher la Mère à la surface du monde est un de vos objectifs lorsque vous jouez Archosien, mais attention de ne pas vous laisser entrainer par votre enthousiasme. Bien que ce soit une bonne unité de combat, elle est loin d'être invincible, et disons le clairement, quand vous êtes SI grosse, vous attirez malgré vous l'attention de vos ennemis...[ ][NEWLINE]En réalité elle peut être relâchée deux fois (en utilisant le rituel de Regain Inaliénable). Les récits de sa première mort étaient visiblement fortement exagérés (elle désirait juste s'accaparer les Fjords). Une seule Mère peut cependant être présente à la fois.</French>
		<German>Releasing Mother upon the world is one of the highlights of playing the Archos, but be careful not to let enthusiasm get the better of her. Whilst she is a competent unit in combat, she is far from invincible - and let's face it, when you're *that* big, you're going to draw some unwanted attention from your enemies... [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She can in-fact be released twice (using the Birthright Regained ritual), the tales of her first death were obviously greatly exaggerated (she was just pining for the Fjords). Only one instance of Mother can exist at a time however.</German>
		<Italian>Liberare Madre sul mondo è una dei punti salienti del giocare gli Archos, ma stai attento a non farti prendere troppo dall'entusiamo. Sebbene sia competente in combattimento non è invincibile, e ammettiamolo, quando sei *cosi* grande, finirai per attirare qualche attenzione indesiderata... [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In effetti Lei può essere liberata due volte (usando il rituale Riottenere Diritto di Nascità), le storie della sua prima morte erano ovviamente gonfiate (si stava solo struggendo per i Fjords). Comunque solo un'unità di Madre può esistere alla volta.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Releasing Mother upon the world is one of the highlights of playing the Archos, but be careful not to let enthusiasm get the better of her. Whilst she is a competent unit in combat, she is far from invincible - and let's face it, when you're *that* big, you're going to draw some unwanted attention from your enemies... [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She can in-fact be released twice (using the Birthright Regained ritual), the tales of her first death were obviously greatly exaggerated (she was just pining for the Fjords). Only one instance of Mother can exist at a time however.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NESTING_SPIDER</Tag>
		<English>Nesting Spider</English>
		<French>Araignée de Fortin</French>
		<German>Nistende Spinne</German>
		<Italian>Ragno del Forte</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nesting Spider</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NESTING_SPIDER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Archosian Fort Commander UU has roughly the same effectiveness compared to a normal Fort Commander. It has higher initial strength and combat ability (except against recon units), but takes a longer time to unlock its full abilities, and does not have access to the full set of promotions that the Fort Commander does.[NEWLINE]Abilities:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]After combat they have a 25% chance of creating a temporary baby spider.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Nesting spiders can [LINK=SPELL_SPAWN_BABY_SPIDER]summon a baby spider[\LINK] (temporary) after reaching level 3, and gain a ranged attack at level 5.</English>
		<French>Le Commandant de Fort unique archosien a globalement la même efficacité qu'un Commandant de Fort classique. Il possède une force de départ plus élevée de même que des capacités de combat améliorées (sauf contre les éclaireurs), mais demande plus de temps pour libérer tout son potentiel, et n'a pas accès à l'ensemble des promotions d'un Commandant de Fort.[NEWLINE]Capacités :[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Après un combat, il a 25% de chances de créer temporairement une Araignée junvénile.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Les Araignées de Fortin peuvent [LINK=SPELL_SPAWN_BABY_SPIDER]créer une araignée juvénile[\LINK] (temporaire) une fois le niveau 3 atteint.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]À partir du niveau 5, les Araignées de Fortin obtiennent une attaque à distance.</French>
		<German>The Archosian Fort Commander UU has roughly the same effectiveness compared to a normal Fort Commander. It has higher initial strength and combat ability (except against recon units), but takes a longer time to unlock its full abilities, and does not have access to the full set of promotions that the Fort Commander does.[NEWLINE]Abilities:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]After combat they have a 25% chance of creating a temporary baby spider.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Nesting spiders can [LINK=SPELL_SPAWN_BABY_SPIDER]summon a baby spider[\LINK] (temporary) after reaching level 3, and gain a ranged attack at level 5.</German>
		<Italian>Il Comandante del Forte Archosiano UU ha circa la stessa utilità di un normale Comandante del Forte. Ha una forza e abilità combattiva iniziale maggiore (tranne contro unità da ricognizione), ma impiega più tempo a sbloccare tutte le sue abilità, e non ha accesso alla lista completa di promozioni che il Comandante del Forte ha.[NEWLINE]Abilità:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Dopo il combattimento ha il 25% di probabilità di creare un ragnetto temporaneo.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]I Ragno del Forte possono [LINK=SPELL_SPAWN_BABY_SPIDER]Evocare un Ragnetto[\LINK] (temporaneo) dopo aver raggiunto il livello 3, e ottengono un'attacco dalla distanza al livello 5.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Archosian Fort Commander UU has roughly the same effectiveness compared to a normal Fort Commander. It has higher initial strength and combat ability (except against recon units), but takes a longer time to unlock its full abilities, and does not have access to the full set of promotions that the Fort Commander does.[NEWLINE]Abilities:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]After combat they have a 25% chance of creating a temporary baby spider.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Nesting spiders can [LINK=SPELL_SPAWN_BABY_SPIDER]summon a baby spider[\LINK] (temporary) after reaching level 3, and gain a ranged attack at level 5.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPIDER_ARCHOS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[H2]Archosian Spiders - Appearance and growth[\H2][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders are not built. Instead, they spawn from [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Mother's nest[\LINK] (the Archosian Palace). Capital population changes their initial size (baby if 4+, spiders if 8+, and giant spiders if 12+)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Baby spiders automatically grow to spiders after a random time (hidden mechanism: [LINK=PROMOTION_GROWTH_SPURTS]Growth spurts[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Spiders can become giant spiders if the Nest's population has attained 12 by using the spell [LINK=SPELL_SPIDER_ARCHOS]Spider Upgrade[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Additionally, with Animal Handling, spiders can build the [LINK=BUILDING_SPIDER_WEB]spider web[\LINK] building, which provides a source of Silk (+1[ICON_HAPPY]).[NEWLINE][H2]Combat Features[\H2][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders (in fact all spiders) are invisible to all but recon units. They have the [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_BLOOD]spider blood promotion[\LINK], giving them +1 poison combat, but they do not give the poisoned promotion to units in combat (contrarily to scorpions).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders have hidden nationality, meaning they can enter other players territory without declaring war. But, contrarily to units with [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]hidden nationality promotion[\LINK], they can't [LINK=SPELL_DECLARE_NATIONALITY]reveal their nationality[\LINK] and hence can't capture cities.[PARAGRAPH:2]From level 3, Spiders can choose 1 color among 5 possibilities (2 consecutive promotions):[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Red (speed and blitz; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_RHAGODESSA]Rhagodessa[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_RHAGODESSA_GREATER]Greater Rhagodessa[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Yellow (can cast Web spells; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_TEXTUS]Textus[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_TEXTUS_GREATER]Greater Textus[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grey (strength and anti recon; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_MUCRO]Mucro[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_MUCRO_GREATER]Greater Mucro[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Blue (various aquatic powers; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_ARGYRONETA]Argyroneta[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_ARGYRONETA_GREATER]Greater Argyroneta[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Green (strength and ranged attack; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_VENENUM]Venenum[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_VENENUM_GREATER]Greater Venenum[\LINK]).</English>
		<French>[H2]Araignées archosiennes - Apparence et croissance[\H2][PARAGRAPH:1]Les araignées archosiennes ne sont pas construites. Au lieu de cela, elles apparaissent à la [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Tanière de la Mère[\LINK] (le Palais Archosien). La population de la capitale change leur taille initiale :[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]juvénile pour une population de 4+,[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] adulte pour une population de 8+,[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] et géantes pour une population de 12+.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les araignées juvéniles deviennent automatiquement adultes après une durée aléatoire (mécanisme caché : [LINK=PROMOTION_GROWTH_SPURTS]Poussée de Croissance[\LINK]).[PARAGRAPH:1]Une fois que la Tanière a atteint 12 de population, les Araignées peuvent devenir des Araignées Géantes en utilisant le sort [LINK=SPELL_SPIDER_ARCHOS]Évolution de l'Araignée[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:1]En outre, après la découverte du [LINK=TECH_ANIMAL_HANDLING]Dressage[\LINK] les Araignées deviennent capables de construire des "bâtiments"[LINK=BUILDING_SPIDER_WEB]toile d'araignée[\LINK], qui fournissent de la Soie (+1[ICON_HAPPY]).[NEWLINE][H2]Capacités de Combat[\H2][PARAGRAPH:1]Les araignées archosiennes (et en fait toutes les araignées) sont invisibles sauf des éclaireurs. Elles ont la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_BLOOD]Sang Arachnéen[\LINK], qui leur confère un bonus de +1 au combat empoisonné, mais ne donne pas la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_POISONED]Empoisonné[\LINK] au unités qu'elles affrontent (contrairement aux scorpions).[PARAGRAPH:1]Les Araignées Archosiennes ont la nationalité cachée, leur permettant de pénétrer sur un territoire ennemi (d'un autre joueur) sans avoir à lui déclarer la guerre. Mais, contrairement aux unités possédant la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]Nationalité Cachée[\LINK], elles ne peuvent pas [LINK=SPELL_DECLARE_NATIONALITY]révéler leur nationalité[\LINK] ni capturer les villes.[PARAGRAPH:2]À partir du niveau 3, les Araignées peuvent choisir une couleur parmi 5 possibilités (2 promotions consécutives) :[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Rouge (Vitesse et blitz; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_RHAGODESSA]Rhagodessa[\LINK], puis [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_RHAGODESSA_GREATER]Rhagodessa (Ancienne)[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Jaune (Peut lancer le sort [LINK=SPELL_WEB]Toile[\LINK]; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_TEXTUS]Textus[\LINK], puis [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_TEXTUS_GREATER]Textus (Ancienne)[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grise (Force et Anti-Éclaireur; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_MUCRO]Mucro[\LINK], puis [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_MUCRO_GREATER]Mucro (Ancienne)[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Bleue (Pouvoirs aquatiques variés; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_ARGYRONETA]Argyroneta[\LINK], puis [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_ARGYRONETA_GREATER]Argyroneta (Ancienne)[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Verte (Force et attaque à distance; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_VENENUM]Vénéneuse[\LINK], puis [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_VENENUM_GREATER]Vénéneuse (Ancienne)[\LINK]).</French>
		<German>[H2]Archosian Spiders - Appearance and growth[\H2][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders are not built. Instead, they spawn from [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Mother's nest[\LINK] (the Archosian Palace). Capital population changes their initial size (baby if 4+, spiders if 8+, and giant spiders if 12+)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Baby spiders automatically grow to spiders after a random time (hidden mechanism: [LINK=PROMOTION_GROWTH_SPURTS]Growth spurts[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Spiders can become giant spiders if the Nest's population has attained 12 by using the spell [LINK=SPELL_SPIDER_ARCHOS]Spider Upgrade[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Additionally, with Animal Handling, spiders can build the [LINK=BUILDING_SPIDER_WEB]spider web[\LINK] building, which provides a source of Silk (+1[ICON_HAPPY]).[NEWLINE][H2]Combat Features[\H2][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders (in fact all spiders) are invisible to all but recon units. They have the [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_BLOOD]spider blood promotion[\LINK], giving them +1 poison combat, but they do not give the poisoned promotion to units in combat (contrarily to scorpions).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders have hidden nationality, meaning they can enter other players territory without declaring war. But, contrarily to units with [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]hidden nationality promotion[\LINK], they can't [LINK=SPELL_DECLARE_NATIONALITY]reveal their nationality[\LINK] and hence can't capture cities.[PARAGRAPH:2]From level 3, Spiders can choose 1 color among 5 possibilities (2 consecutive promotions):[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Red (speed and blitz; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_RHAGODESSA]Rhagodessa[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_RHAGODESSA_GREATER]Greater Rhagodessa[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Yellow (can cast Web spells; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_TEXTUS]Textus[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_TEXTUS_GREATER]Greater Textus[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grey (strength and anti recon; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_MUCRO]Mucro[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_MUCRO_GREATER]Greater Mucro[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Blue (various aquatic powers; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_ARGYRONETA]Argyroneta[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_ARGYRONETA_GREATER]Greater Argyroneta[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Green (strength and ranged attack; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_VENENUM]Venenum[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_VENENUM_GREATER]Greater Venenum[\LINK]).</German>
		<Italian>[H2]Ragni Archosiani - Aspetto e crescità[\H2][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]I ragni Archosiani non sono prodotti. Bensì, vengono generati dal [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Nido di Madre[\LINK] (il Palazzo Archosiano). A seconda della popolazione della Capitale cambia la loro dimensione iniziale (ragnetto se 4+, ragno se 8+, e ragno gigante se 12+)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]I Ragnetti crescono automaticamente in ragni dopo un periodo di tempo casuale (meccanica nascosta: [LINK=PROMOTION_GROWTH_SPURTS]Growth spurts[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]I ragni possono diventare ragni giganti se la popolazione del Nido ha raggiunto grandezza 12 utilizzando la magia [LINK=SPELL_SPIDER_ARCHOS]Migliorare Ragno[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]In più, con Gestione degli Animali, i ragni possono costruire l'edificio [LINK=BUILDING_SPIDER_WEB]Ragnatela del ragno[\LINK], che fornisce la risorsa Seta (+1[ICON_HAPPY]).[NEWLINE][H2]Caratteristiche di combattimento[\H2][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]I ragni Archosiani (nei fatti tutti i ragni) sono invisibili a tutti tranne che alle unità da ricognizione. Hanno la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_BLOOD]Sangue di ragno[\LINK], che gli da un +1 da veleno, ma non avvelenano le unità in combattimento (al contrario degli scorpioni).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]I ragni Archosiani hanno la nazionalità nascosta, il che significa che possono entrare nei territori degli altri giocatori senza avere il diritto di passaggio e essere in guerra. Ma, contrariamente alle altre unità con la [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]nazionalità nascosta[\LINK], loro non possono [LINK=SPELL_DECLARE_NATIONALITY]rivelare la nazionalità[\LINK] e quindi non possono catturare le città.[PARAGRAPH:2]Dal livello 3, i Ragni possono scegliere 1 colore tra 5 possibili (2 promozioni consecutive):[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Rosso (Velocità e Incursione; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_RHAGODESSA]Rhagodessa[\LINK], poi [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_RHAGODESSA_GREATER]Rhagodessa Maggiore[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Giallo (Puo lanciare la magia Ragnatela; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_TEXTUS]Textus[\LINK], poi [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_TEXTUS_GREATER]Textus Maggiore[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grigio (Forza e bonus contro Unità da Ricognizione; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_MUCRO]Mucro[\LINK], poi [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_MUCRO_GREATER]Mucro Maggiore[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Blu (Diversi poteri acquatici; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_ARGYRONETA]Argyroneta[\LINK], poi [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_ARGYRONETA_GREATER]Argyroneta Maggiore[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Verde (Forza e attacco dalla distanza; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_VENENUM]Venenum[\LINK], poi [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_VENENUM_GREATER]Venenum Maggiore[\LINK]).</Italian>
		<Spanish>[H2]Archosian Spiders - Appearance and growth[\H2][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders are not built. Instead, they spawn from [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE_ARCHOS]Mother's nest[\LINK] (the Archosian Palace). Capital population changes their initial size (baby if 4+, spiders if 8+, and giant spiders if 12+)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Baby spiders automatically grow to spiders after a random time (hidden mechanism: [LINK=PROMOTION_GROWTH_SPURTS]Growth spurts[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Spiders can become giant spiders if the Nest's population has attained 12 by using the spell [LINK=SPELL_SPIDER_ARCHOS]Spider Upgrade[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Additionally, with Animal Handling, spiders can build the [LINK=BUILDING_SPIDER_WEB]spider web[\LINK] building, which provides a source of Silk (+1[ICON_HAPPY]).[NEWLINE][H2]Combat Features[\H2][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders (in fact all spiders) are invisible to all but recon units. They have the [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_BLOOD]spider blood promotion[\LINK], giving them +1 poison combat, but they do not give the poisoned promotion to units in combat (contrarily to scorpions).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Archosian spiders have hidden nationality, meaning they can enter other players territory without declaring war. But, contrarily to units with [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]hidden nationality promotion[\LINK], they can't [LINK=SPELL_DECLARE_NATIONALITY]reveal their nationality[\LINK] and hence can't capture cities.[PARAGRAPH:2]From level 3, Spiders can choose 1 color among 5 possibilities (2 consecutive promotions):[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Red (speed and blitz; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_RHAGODESSA]Rhagodessa[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_RHAGODESSA_GREATER]Greater Rhagodessa[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Yellow (can cast Web spells; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_TEXTUS]Textus[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_TEXTUS_GREATER]Greater Textus[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grey (strength and anti recon; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_MUCRO]Mucro[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_MUCRO_GREATER]Greater Mucro[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Blue (various aquatic powers; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_ARGYRONETA]Argyroneta[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_ARGYRONETA_GREATER]Greater Argyroneta[\LINK]).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Green (strength and ranged attack; [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_VENENUM]Venenum[\LINK], then [LINK=PROMOTION_SPIDER_VENENUM_GREATER]Greater Venenum[\LINK]).</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRIBESMAN</Tag>
		<English>Tribesman</English>
		<French>Tribal</French>
		<German>Stammeskrieger</German>
		<Italian>Membro della Tribù</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tribesman</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRIBESMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>All Archosian Tribesmen are able to fight in defence of the nest, but the tribe has had little interest in weapon development relying instead on those tribesmen "better suited" by nature to fight.</English>
		<French>Tous les Tribaux Archosiens sont capables de se battre pour défendre la Tanière, mais le clan ne porte que peu d'intérêt au développement des armes, s'appuyant à la place sur ces Tribaux naturellement "taillés" pour le combat.</French>
		<German>All Archosian Tribesmen are able to fight in defence of the nest, but the tribe has had little interest in weapon development relying instead on those tribesmen "better suited" by nature to fight.</German>
		<Italian>Tutti i membri della tribù Archosiana sono capaci di combattere per difendere il nido, ma la tribù ha poco interesse nello sviluppo di armi affidandosi invece a quei membri naturalmente "più adatti" a combattere.</Italian>
		<Spanish>All Archosian Tribesmen are able to fight in defence of the nest, but the tribe has had little interest in weapon development relying instead on those tribesmen "better suited" by nature to fight.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRIBESMAN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Archosian Tribesmen are limited to using only Bronze weapons. They do however enjoy a slight increase to City Defence and will defend their homes with great zeal. They also upgrade into the Brute unit, which can be powerful in the early game.</English>
		<French>Le Tribal Archosien ne peut utiliser que des armes de Bronze. Il bénéficie cependant d'une défense de ville améliorée et défendra son foyer avec zêle. Il s'améliore également en Brute, qui peut se révéler puissante en début de jeu.</French>
		<German>Arachonische Stammeskrieger sind beschränkt auf den Gebrauch von Bronzewaffen. Wie auch immer erfreuen sie sich eines leichten Bonusses bei der Stadtverteidigung und sie beschützen ihre Heime mit großer Emsigkeit. Sie können auch zur Arachna befördert werden, die eine mächtige Einheit in der Frühphase des Spiels ist.</German>
		<Italian>I membri della tribù Archosiana si limitano all'utilizzo delle armi in Bronzo. Hanno però un bonus nella difesa della città e difenderanno le loro case con grande zelo. Si possono anche migliorare in Bruti, che possono essere molto potenti all'inizio della partita.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Archosian Tribesmen are limited to using only Bronze weapons. They do however enjoy a slight increase to City Defence and will defend their homes with great zeal. They also upgrade into the Brute unit, which can be powerful in the early game.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RECLUSE</Tag>
		<English>Recluse</English>
		<French>Reclus</French>
		<German>Einsiedler</German>
		<Italian>Eremita</Italian>
		<Spanish>Recluse</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RECLUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>When a hunting team survives the wilds long enough to become noteworthy, they may be sent further afield to hunt more dangerous prey. The spider becomes more deadly as it grows and the Recluse relies on it to a greater degree.</English>
		<French>Quand un binôme de chasse survit suffisamment longtemps pour être remarqué, ils peuvent être envoyés encore plus loin pour chasser des proies encore plus dangereuses. L'Araignée devient plus dangereuse à mesure qu'elle grandit et le Reclus compte encore plus sur elle.</French>
		<German>When a hunting team survives the wilds long enough to become noteworthy, they may be sent further afield to hunt more dangerous prey. The spider becomes more deadly as it grows and the Recluse relies on it to a greater degree.</German>
		<Italian>Quando una squadra di caccia sopravvive alle terre selvaggie abbastanza a lungo da diventare degna di nota, può venir mandata più lontano per cacciare prede più pericolose. Il ragno diventa sempre più letale man mano che cresce e l'Eremita si affida a lui in misura maggiore.</Italian>
		<Spanish>When a hunting team survives the wilds long enough to become noteworthy, they may be sent further afield to hunt more dangerous prey. The spider becomes more deadly as it grows and the Recluse relies on it to a greater degree.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RECLUSE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>A strong unit in the wilds, but relatively weak when attacking cities - the Recluse is best suited to intercepting enemies as they approach or hunting down wounded units.</English>
		<French>Une unité puissante dans les contrées sauvages, mais relativement faibles pour l'attaque de ville. Le Reclus est plus efficace pour intercepter les ennemis qui approchent ou achever les unités blessées.</French>
		<German>A strong unit in the wilds, but relatively weak when attacking cities - the Recluse is best suited to intercepting enemies as they approach or hunting down wounded units.</German>
		<Italian>Una forte unità nelle terre selvagge, ma relativamente debole quando si attaccano le città, l'Eremita è più adatto a intercettare i nemici quando si avvicinano o a eliminare unità ferite.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A strong unit in the wilds, but relatively weak when attacking cities - the Recluse is best suited to intercepting enemies as they approach or hunting down wounded units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPIDERKIN</Tag>
		<English>Spiderkin</English>
		<French>Arachnomorphe</French>
		<German>Spinnentier</German>
		<Italian>Aracnomorfo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Spiderkin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPIDERKIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The most successful hunters may find that they develop mutations as they continue to eat the poisoned meat of their kills. This is seen as a "gift" from Mother and a sign that the hunter is favoured. In anycase, many of these mutations prove beneficial in combat and the Spiderkin is practically immune to further poisoning.</English>
		<French>Les chasseurs les plus efficaces peuvent découvrir qu'ils développent des mutations tandis qu'ils continuent de manger la viande empoisonnée de leurs victimes. Elles sont vues comme des "présents" de la Mère et un signe que le chasseur est favorisé. N'importe comment, la plupart de ces mutations se révèlent bénéfiques en combat et l'Arachnomorphe est pratiquement immunisé à tout empoisonnement ultérieur.</French>
		<German>Die erfolgreichsten Jäger mögen Mutationen an sich bemerken, wenn sie nur kontinuierlich das vergiftete Fleisch ihrer Beute verzehren. Dies wird als ein "Geschenk" von Mutter und als Zeichen ihrer Gunst angesehen. In jedem Fall entpuppen sich viele dieser Mutationen als nützlich im Kampf, so sind die Sipplinge der Spinnentiere z.B. praktisch immun gegen weitere Vergiftungen.</German>
		<Italian>I cacciatori di maggior sucesso possono sviluppare delle mutazioni in seguito al continuo consumo della carne avvelenata delle loro prede. Questo viene visto come un "dono" da Madre e un simbolo del suo favore. In ogni caso, molte di queste mutazioni si dimostrano utili in combattimento e l'Aracnomorfo è praticamente immune ad un ulteriore avvelenamento.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The most successful hunters may find that they develop mutations as they continue to eat the poisoned meat of their kills. This is seen as a "gift" from Mother and a sign that the hunter is favoured. In anycase, many of these mutations prove beneficial in combat and the Spiderkin is practically immune to further poisoning.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPIDERKIN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Trading raw combat-prowess for deadly poison, the Spiderkin is a match for the Beastmasters of other races. In fact, his multiple additional limbs grant 1-3 first strikes, allowing him to more easily withstand attacks by groups of weaker opponents.</English>
		<French>Délaissant les prouesses au combat au profit des poisons mortels, l'Arachnomorphe est l'équivalent des Maîtres des Bêtes pour les autres races. Dans les faits, ses membres multiples lui confèrent 1 à 3 premières attaques, lui permettant de mieux résister aux attaques de groupes d'ennemis plus faibles.</French>
		<German>Den seltenen Heldenmut im Kampf ersetzt durch tödliches Gift - so ist der Sippling eine Herausforderung für die Bestienmeister anderer Rassen. Tatsächlich ermöglichen die zusätzlichen Gliedmaßen 1-3 Erstschläge, was ihn dazu befähigt, auch dem Angriff von Gruppen schwächerer Feinde zu trotzen.</German>
		<Italian>Scambiando della potenza in combattimento grezza per del letale veleno, l'Aracnomorfo è più che capace di confrontarsi con i Signore delle Bestie delle altre razze. Infatti, i suoi diversi arti in più gli forniscono 1-3 attacchi improvvisi, permettendogli di resistere più facilmente agli attacchi da gruppi di unità più deboli.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Trading raw combat-prowess for deadly poison, the Spiderkin is a match for the Beastmasters of other races. In fact, his multiple additional limbs grant 1-3 first strikes, allowing him to more easily withstand attacks by groups of weaker opponents.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNITNAME_SWORD_SPIDER</Tag>
		<English>Sword Spider</English>
		<French>Araignée Lame</French>
		<German>Schwertspinne</German>
		<Italian>Rago Lama</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sword Spider</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNITNAME_WEAVER_SPIDER</Tag>
		<English>Weaver Spider</English>
		<French>Araignée de Tisserand</French>
		<German>Netzspinne</German>
		<Italian>Ragno Tessitore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Weaver Spider</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_FORTSPIDER1</Tag>
		<English>Fort Spider I</English>
		<French>Araignée de Fortin I</French>
		<German>Festungssppinne I</German>
		<Italian>Ragno del Forte I</Italian>
		<Spanish>Fort Spider I</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_FORTSPIDER2</Tag>
		<English>Fort Spider II</English>
		<French>Araignée de Fortin II</French>
		<German>Festungsspinne II</German>
		<Italian>Ragno del Forte II</Italian>
		<Spanish>Fort Spider II</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SPAWN_BABY_SPIDER</Tag>
		<English>Spawn Baby Spider</English>
		<French>Créer une araignée juvénile</French>
		<German>Erschaffe Babyspinne</German>
		<Italian>Crea Ragnetto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Spawn Baby Spider</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
