<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CLAN_OF_EMBERS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Clan</English>
		<French>clanique:clanique:claniques:claniques</French>
		<German>Orkisch</German>
		<Italian>Clan</Italian>
		<Spanish>Clan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CLAN_OF_EMBERS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Clan of Embers</English>
		<French>Clan des Braises</French>
		<German>Reich des Aschenklans</German>
		<Italian>Clan delle Braci</Italian>
		<Spanish>Clan de las Ascuas</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CLAN_OF_EMBERS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Clan of Embers</English>
		<French>Claniques</French>
		<German>Klan der Asche</German>
		<Italian>Clan delle Braci</Italian>
		<Spanish>Clan de las Ascuas</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CLAN_OF_EMBERS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Clan has access to the cheapest, but not always the most powerful, units in the game. Starting at peace with the barbarians and with access to Fire mana allows them a strong early and mid-game start which may wane if they haven't established themselves well by the time other civilizations start making the more-advanced units and heroes.[PARAGRAPH:1]Fire was the tool Kylorin used to cleanse the rot from Patria, for Bhall had given her righteous followers gifts to rival those sorcerous powers gained first from Ceridwen. The passionate fire goddess was a force for good. Those who loved justice and mercy could use her power to counter the wicked mages Kylorin had trained. But she fell to the wily whispers of Agares, God of Despair, raining fire on the just and unjust alike in a terrible day heralding the end of the Age of Magic. Once devout men of many nations, the orcs were transformed, cursed and enraged when Bhall fell. The holy city of Braduk had the goddess pass through as she fell from the Heavens, taking many of those who loved goodness and trapping them in Hell. Half the city was rendered a flaming pit, but those people who remained, in touch with the fiery spirit of Bhall, were twisted into the orcs. Mulcarn, Bhall's former nemesis, took this chance to claim dominion over Erebus, and the orcs, along with the rest of the world, were ushered into the Age of Ice. [PARAGRAPH:1]They survived, huddled around the fires of Braduk the Burning, and developed barbarous rituals and a savage warrior culture, raiding struggling human settlements. The holy scepter of the High Priest of Bhall was affixed with a brutal axe head by the Orc warlord Orthus, and many nascent tribes fell to its power. One people stood up to the orcs, though. Those who had been taken to Hell with Bhall were freed by Sabathiel, the Archangel of Junil late in the Age of Ice, as Mulcarn's contest with Kylorin drew near. These battle-hardened warriors were a true test for the savage orcs, but the orcs were too numerous for the Bannor to defeat, living in the relative luxury amidst the fires of Braduk. Jonas was a fierce warlord of great renown among the orcs, who resented being subordinate to the matriarchal priesthood of Bhall. He staged a coup against the high priestess, but Bhall took notice of her people again, and humbled Jonas, making him her priest. Captured as a babe, the orc Sheelba was raised among the Bannor as a human girl but was spurned and taken in by the orc clans, united under Jonas's Ember Banner. Her insights into civilization have the potential to allow these clans to rise above the petty barbarous orc tribes led by the likes of Orthus, even as their sheer strength and Jonas's cunning allows them to tear down the human civilizations.</English>
		<French>Le feu était l'outil utilisé par Kylorin pour éradiquer la pourriture de Patria, que Bhall avait donné à ses fidèles servants pour rivaliser avec les pouvoirs de sorciers initialement obtenus de Ceridwen. La déesse passionnée du feu était une force du bien. Ceux qui aimaient la justice et la pitié pouvaient utiliser ses pouvoirs pour contrer les mages corrompus entrainés autrefois par Kylorin. Mais elle succomba aux rusés chuchotements d'Agares, Dieu du Désespoir, faisant pleuvoir le feu indistincetement sur les justes et les injustes dans un terrible jour marqaunt la fin de l'Âge de la Magie. Autrefois, hommes dévoués de nombreuses nations, les orcs furent transformés, maudits et enragés quand Bhall chuta. La cité sacrée de Braduk vit la déesse la traverser tandis qu'elle chutait des Cieux, emportant nombre de ceux qui prônaient la bonté et les emprisonnant en Enfer. La moitié de la cité était transformée en un gigantesque brasier, mais ceux qui restaient, en contact avec l'esprit fougueux de Bhall, furent transformés en Orcs. Mulcarn, l'ancien ennemi juré de Bhall, saisit sa chance de s'emparer de domaines d'Erebus, et les Orcs, comme le reste du monde, furent projetés dans l'Âge de Glace.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ils survécurent, agglutinés autour des feux de Braduk l'Enflammée, et développèrent des rituels barbares et une culture guerrière sauvage, raidant les fragiles colonies humaines. Au sceptre sacré du Grand Prêtre de Bhall fut fixée une rude lame de hache par le chef de guerre Orc nommé Orthus, et nombre de jeunes tribus succombèrent à son pouvoir. Pourtant un peuple s'éleva contre les Orcs. Ceux qui avaient été emportés en Enfer avec Bhall furent libérés vers les fin de l'Âge de Glace par Sabathiel, l'archange de Junil, tandis que l'affrontement entre Mulcarn et Kylorin se rapprochait. Ces soldats endurcis furent un vrai test pour les sauvages Orcs, mais ces derniers étaient trop nombreux pour permettre aux Bannors de les vaincre, car vivant dans le confort relatif des feux de Braduk.[NEWLINE]Jonas était un féroce chef de guerre de grand renom parmis les Orcs, qui refusait d'être sous la coupe du clergé matriarcal de Bhall. Il fomenta un coup d'état contre la hautre prêtresse, mais Bhall prit à nouveau conscience de son peuple et humilia Jonas en en faisant sa prêtresse.[NEWLINE]Encore enfant quand elle fut capturée, l'Orc Sheelba fut élevée parmis les Bannor comme une fillette humaine, mais en fut rejettée puis emportée par les clans orcs unis sous la Bannière de Braises de Jonas. Ses connaissances internes de la civilisation lui permettent d'amener ces clans à s'élever au-dessus des ridicules tribus barbares orcs menées par Orthus et ses pairs, y compris en force brute, et l'astuce de Jonas d'abattre les civilisations humaines.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Der Klan kann die günstigsten, wenn auch nicht immer die stärksten, Einheiten des Spiels aufstellen. Die Orks des Klan leben zunächst in Frieden mit den Barbaren und haben Zugang zum Mana des Feuers. Dies ermöglicht ihnen, einen starke Position in der frühen oder mittleren Phase einer Partie einzunehmen, die aber auch schnell dahinschwinden kann, wenn sie sich keine gute Ausgangslage verschafft haben, um es spätestens dann mit den stärkeren Einheiten und Helden anderer Zivilisationen aufnehmen zu können.[PARAGRAPH:1]Feuer war das Werkzeug, das Kylorin einsetzte, um Patria von der Fäulnis zu säubern, denn Bhall hatte ihren rechtschaffenen Anhängern ebenfalls Gaben verliehen, um es mit den Zauberkräften, die zuvor durch Ceridwen erlangt wurden, aufnehmen zu können. Die leidenschaftliche Feuergöttin war eine Macht des Guten. Jene, die der Gerechtigkeit und der Barmherzigkeit verschrieben waren, konnten ihre Kräfte nutzen, um den boshaften Magier, die Kylorin ausgebildet hatte, entgegentreten zu können. Aber sie verfiel den verschlagenen Einflüsterungen von Agares, dem Gott der Verzweiflung, ließ an einem furchtbaren Tag, der das Ende des Zeitalters der Magie einläutete, Feuer auf die Gerechten und die Ungerechten gleichermaßen niederregnen. Die Orks, die sich einst aus frommen Menschen vieler Reiche zusammensetzten, wurden verwandelt, verflucht und erzürnt, als Bhall fiel. Die Göttin durchschlug die heilige Stadt Braduk, als sie vom Himmel stürzte und nahm viele, die das Gute liebten, mit sich in die Hölle. Die Hälfte der Stadt bestand nur noch aus einer brennenden Grube, während das Erscheinungsbild der Überlebenden, die noch mit der feurigen Essenz von Bhall verbunden waren, zu jenem der Orks verdreht wurde. Mulcarn, Bhalls einstiger Erzfeind, ergriff diese Gelegenheit, um die Vorherrschaft über Erebus zu beanspruchen, so dass die Orks, zusammen mit dem Rest der Welt, in das Zeitalter des Eises gezwungen wurden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie überlebten, dicht gedrängt um die Feuer von Braduk the Burning, und entwickelten barbarische Rituale und eine wilde Kriegerkultur, während sie ums Überleben kämpfende menschliche Siedlungen überfielen. Das heilige Zepter des Hohepriesters von Bhall wurde vom orkischen Kriegsherren Orthus an einem groben Axtkopf befestigt und viele im Entstehen begriffene Stämme fielen seiner Macht zum Opfer. Ein Volk bot den Orks jedoch die Stirn. Jene, die mit Bhall zur Hölle gefahren waren, wurden von Sabathiel, dem Erzengel von Junil, spät im Zeitalter des Eises befreit, als Mulcarns Kampf mit Kylorin immer näher rückte. Diese kampferfahrenen Krieger waren ein echte Herausforderung für die wilden Orks, aber die Orks waren zu zahlreich, als dass die Bannor sie besiegen konnten, da sie in der verhältnismäßigen Behaglichkeit der Feuern von Braduk gelebt hatten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Jonas war ein grimmiger Kriegsherr von großem Ansehen unter den Orks, dem es nicht gefiel, dass er sich der matriarchalischen Priesterschaft von Bhall unterordnen musste. So inszenierte er einen Staatsstreich gegen die Hohepriesterin, aber Bhall wurde wieder auf ihr Volk aufmerksam und demütigte Jonas, indem sie ihn zu ihrem Priester machte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als Kleinkind entführt, wurde die Orkin Sheelba zunächst von den Bannor als Menschenmädchen aufgezogen, aber schon bald verstoßen und von den orkischen Klans aufgenommen, die unter Jonas' Aschenbanner vereint worden waren. Ihre Einblicke in die Zivilisation haben das Potential, diesen Klans zu ermöglichen, über die kleinen barbarischen Ork-Klans hinauszuwachsen, die von Orthus und seinesgleichen angeführt werden. Gerade weil ihre bloße Stärke und Jonas' Durchtriebenheit ihnen sowieso ermöglicht, die menschlichen Zivilisationen niederzureißen.</German>
		<Italian>Il Clan ha accesso alle unità più economiche, anche se non sempre le più forti, di tutti. L'iniziare in pace con i barbari e l'accesso al mana del fuoco gli permette di avere un buon vanatggio a inizio e a metà partita ma che svanisce se non riesce ad consolidarsi bene per quando le altre civiltà inizieranno a creare unità ed eroi più avanzati.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il fuoco fu lo strumento usato da Kylorin per rimuovere la corruzione da Patria, in quanto Bhall aveva dato ai suoi seguaci doni sufficenti a rivaleggiare i poteri magici prima ottenuti da Ceridwen. L'appassionata dea del fuoco era una forza del bene. Coloro che amavano la giustizia e la pietà potevano usare il suo nome per contrastare i malvagi maghi che Kylorin aveva istruito. Ma soccombette agli astuti sussurri di Agares, Dio della Disperazione, facendo piovere fuoco sugli onesti e i disonesti in equal misura durante una terribile giornata che preannunciava la fine dell'Era della Magia. Un tempo uomini devoti di varie nazioni, gli orchi furono trasformati, maledetti e irati quando Bhall cadde. La città santa di Braduk fu attraversata dalla dea mentre cadeva dai Paradisi, portando con se molti di quelli che amavano la bontà e intrappolandoli all'Inferno. Metà della città divenne una fossa ardente, mentre le persone che vi rimasero, toccate dallo spirito infuocato di Bhall, furono trasformate negli orchi. Mulcarn, la vecchia nemesi di Bhall, colse l'occasione per rivendicare il suo dominio su Erebus, e gli orchi, insieme al resto del mondo, entrarono nell'Era del Ghiaccio. [PARAGRAPH:1]Essi sopravvissero, accalcandosi attorno ai fuochi di Braduk l'Ardente, e svilupparono barbarici rituali e una societa guerriera selvaggia, razziando gli insediamenti umani in difficolta. Lo scettro santo del Sommo Sacerdote di Bhall fu unito alla testa di un'ascia dal signore della guerra orchesco Orthus, e molte tribù nascenti caddero sotto il suo potere. Un popolo si erse contro gli orchi però. Coloro che erano stati portati all'Inferno da Bhall furono liberati da Sabathiel, l'Arcangelo di Junil, verso la fine dell'Era del Ghiaccio, quando lo scontro tra Mulcarn con Kylorin si avvicinava. Questi veterani temprati dalla battaglia furono una vera sfida per i selvaggi orchi, tuttavia gli orchi erano troppo numerosi per essere sconfitti dai Bannor, vivendo in una sorta di lusso in mezzo ai fuochi di Braduk. Jonas era un feroce signore della guerra di grande fama tra gli orchi, che provava del risentimento all'essere sottomesso al clero matriarcale di Bhall. Cosi progetto un golpe contro la somma sacerdotessa, ma Bhall notò di nuovo la sua gente, e umiliò Jonas, rendendolo un suo prete. Catturata da bambina, l'orco Sheelba crebbe tra i Bannor come una bambina umana ma non fu mai accettata da loro, per poi venir accettata dai clan degli orchi, riunitisi sotto lo Stendardo della Brace di Jonas. Le sue conoscenze della civiltà hanno il potenziale di permettere a questi clan di elevarsi al di sopra delle piccole tribù orchesche guidate da orchi come Orthus, comunque, anche solo la loro forza bruta e l'astuzia di Jonas gli permette di distruggere le civiltà umane.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Clan has access to the cheapest, but not always the most powerful, units in the game. Starting at peace with the barbarians and with access to Fire mana allows them a strong early and mid-game start which may wane if they haven't established themselves well by the time other civilizations start making the more-advanced units and heroes.[PARAGRAPH:1]Fire was the tool Kylorin used to cleanse the rot from Patria, for Bhall had given her righteous followers gifts to rival those sorcerous powers gained first from Ceridwen. The passionate fire goddess was a force for good. Those who loved justice and mercy could use her power to counter the wicked mages Kylorin had trained. But she fell to the wily whispers of Agares, God of Despair, raining fire on the just and unjust alike in a terrible day heralding the end of the Age of Magic. Once devout men of many nations, the orcs were transformed, cursed and enraged when Bhall fell. The holy city of Braduk had the goddess pass through as she fell from the Heavens, taking many of those who loved goodness and trapping them in Hell. Half the city was rendered a flaming pit, but those people who remained, in touch with the fiery spirit of Bhall, were twisted into the orcs. Mulcarn, Bhall's former nemesis, took this chance to claim dominion over Erebus, and the orcs, along with the rest of the world, were ushered into the Age of Ice. [PARAGRAPH:1]They survived, huddled around the fires of Braduk the Burning, and developed barbarous rituals and a savage warrior culture, raiding struggling human settlements. The holy scepter of the High Priest of Bhall was affixed with a brutal axe head by the Orc warlord Orthus, and many nascent tribes fell to its power. One people stood up to the orcs, though. Those who had been taken to Hell with Bhall were freed by Sabathiel, the Archangel of Junil late in the Age of Ice, as Mulcarn's contest with Kylorin drew near. These battle-hardened warriors were a true test for the savage orcs, but the orcs were too numerous for the Bannor to defeat, living in the relative luxury amidst the fires of Braduk. Jonas was a fierce warlord of great renown among the orcs, who resented being subordinate to the matriarchal priesthood of Bhall. He staged a coup against the high priestess, but Bhall took notice of her people again, and humbled Jonas, making him her priest. Captured as a babe, the orc Sheelba was raised among the Bannor as a human girl but was spurned and taken in by the orc clans, united under Jonas's Ember Banner. Her insights into civilization have the potential to allow these clans to rise above the petty barbarous orc tribes led by the likes of Orthus, even as their sheer strength and Jonas's cunning allows them to tear down the human civilizations.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CLAN_OF_EMBERS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategy: The Clan isn't likely to outbuild the other civs. They don't have access to special buildings and suffer a -10% to their tech rate. But this is offset by the fact that they start at peace with the barbarians so they can explore without fear and they usually don't have to worry about protecting their cities in the early game. Although they are able to attack animals, most animals will leave the clan alone, even the fearsome hill giants consider the clan their brothers and usually ignore them. With the masonry technology gained, they can significantly increase their unit production with the warrens building, and their "For the Horde!" World Spell has chance of converting any non-hero barbarian orc. A strategy of early and aggressive warfare may thus be for the best.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Beware, if The Clan breaks the peace with the Barbarians, they will lose the ability to recruit barbarians, whether through "For the Horde" or other means. </English>
		<French>Le Clan a accès aux unités les moins chères du jeu, bien qu'elles ne soient pas les plus puissantes. Commençant en paix avec les barbares et avec l'accès à un Mana de Feu, ils ont les atouts nécessaires dominer au début et même en milieu de partie, mais qui peuvent se résorber s'ils ne se sont pas puissamment établis lorsque les autres civilisations commencent à créer les unités avancées et les héros.[NEWLINE]Le Clan ne peut surpasser les autres civilisations en termes de développement de villes. Ils n'ont pas de bâtiments speciaux et souffrent d'un malus de 10% à leur taux de recherche. Mais cela est compensé par le fait qu'ils commencent en paix avec les barbares et peuvent donc explorer sans peur, et ils n'ont en général pas à proteger leurs villes au début de la partie. Bien qu'ils puissent attaquer les animaux, la plupart de ceux-ci laisseront le clan tranquille. Même les terrifiants géants des collines considèrent le clan comme des frères et les ignorent généralement. Après avoir découvert la [LINK=TECH_MASONRY]Maçonnerie[\LINK], ils peuvent doubler leur production d'unités en construisant un [LINK=BUILDING_WARRENS]Creuset du Carnage[\LINK], et leur sort mondial [LINK=SPELL_FOR_THE_HORDE]Pour la Horde ![\LINK] a une chance de convertir n'importe quel orc barbare non héros. Une stratégie guerrière et agressive très tôt dans la partie est probablement le meilleur choix.</French>
		<German>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategie: Dem Clan wird es kaum gelingen, andere Zivilisationen mit Stadterweiterungen zu übertrumpfen. Sie haben keinen Zugang zu Spezialgebäuden, und erleiden -10% an ihrer Forschungsrate. Aber das wird dadurch ausgeglichen, dass sie im Frieden mit den Barbaren beginnen, und so ohne Sorgen entdecken können, und sich normalerweise keine Gedanken über die Bewachung ihrer Städte am Anfang des Spieles machen müssen. Obwohl es ihnen Möglich ist, Tiere anzugreifen, werden die meisten Tiere den Clan in Ruhe lassen, und sogar die beängstigenden Hügelriesen betrachten den Clan als ihre Brüder, und ignorieren ihn normalerweise. Die blutdurstige Natur des Klans zeigt sich darin, dass er unfähig ist, eroberte Städte zu behalten, anstatt sie sofort zu zerstören. Eine Strategie des frühen und aggressiven Kriegführens wird darum wohl das Beste sein.</German>
		<Italian>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategia: Il Clan non è in grado di superare le altre civiltà nello sviluppo. Non hanno molti edifici unici e hanno un malus del -10% al loro tasso di ricerca. Tutto ciò è conpensato però dal fatto di iniziare in pace con i barbari, permettendogli di esplorare senza timori e senza doversi preoccupare di proteggere le loro città a inizio partita. Possono comunque attaccare gli animali però, anche se la maggior parte degli animali lascia il clan in pace, persino i temibili giganti delle colline considerano il clan come fratelli e di solito li ignorano. Con la tecnologia Muratura possono costruire l'edificio Agoge, che fornisce un grande bonus alla produzione per le unità militari, la loro magia globale "Per l'Orda!" ha la possibilità di convertire qualsiasi orco barbaro (esclusi gli eroi). Una strategia per una guerra aggressiva e iniziale potrebbe essere la cosa migliore.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Fai attenzione, se il Clan rompe la tregua con i barbari non potrà più reclutarli, sia attraverso "Per l'Orda!" che con altri metodi. </Italian>
		<Spanish>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Estrategia: El Clan no destaca en las construcciones como otras civilizaciones.  No tienen acceso a edificios especiales y sufren un -10% en su tasa de investigación.  Pero esto está compensado porque empiezan en paz con los Bárbaros, de forma que pueden explorar sin temor y generalmente no tienen que preocuparse de proteger sus ciudades al principio.  Aunque pueden atacar a animales, la mayoría de los animales dejarán al clan tranquilo, incluso los gigantes de las colinas consideran al clan como sus hermanos y normalmente los ignoran. Su naturaleza sangrienta los hace incapaces de mantener ciudades capturadas, arrasándolas en su lugar. Una estrategia de guerra agresiva y temprana podría ser lo mejor.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HAFGAN</Tag>
		<English>Hafgan the Purger</English>
		<French>Hafgan le Répurgateur</French>
		<German>Hafgan der Säuberer</German>
		<Italian>Hafgan l'Epuratore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hafgan the Purger</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HAFGAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_1]Part 1: Bellowing Embers[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_2]Part 2: Bellowing Embers[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_3]Part 3: Bellowing Embers[\LINK][H2]Part 4 Bellowing Embers[\H2]The Clan of Embers may have the biggest army ever seen, more warriors than any warboss has ever dreamt to gather, yet they are weak. Their will is weak, their faith is weak. And they are foolish. They had thought him a fool, yet they hadn't even noticed his departure of Braduk with all his tribe. Only two drunken guards had barred his way; one now had a spear planted in his belly, and Hafgan had chopped the other one's head himself.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]All the others were still feasting and celebrating the marriage of Jonas Endain and his new slut-queen. Stupid fools. Soon enough, he would teach them Bhall's true way. It would surely mean slaying Jonas. Too bad. Hafgan had been rather fond of him before he met the Bannor girl. He might have forgiven this marriage, even though a weak human-like child like her was worth nothing. He might even have tolerated the girl's ridiculous attempts to teach them human tactics and discipline. Pathetic; as if they needed to fight like the feeble humans. However, he would never forget that the so-called Priest-King allowed her to discuss peace terms with the Bannor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Peace! The word alone was treason, heresy, the exact opposite of Bhall's teachings. Any true orc knew that their kind can only thrive through endless war and by spilling their enemies' blood for their Goddess. The worst part had been the s**t's speech. She had called it a strategic move, to better fight the Chislev and other enemies. Strategy! Another weakling's concept, good only for cowards who are too weak or too frightened for a good fight.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She was wrong, he knew it. They were all wrong, and he would show it to them all. He, Hafgan the Purger, chieftain of the Burning Spears. For he was Bhall's true chosen champion. He, not Jonas, not this other fool Rantine. He might lack the strength to fight Jonas and the entire Clan for the moment, but that would change. He would crush humans, again and again - for that was the only way to 'negotiate' with them. And the glory of his victories would rally the true orcs behind him. He would lead them all to greatness, and leave only ashes behind him. For fire is the only way.</English>
		<French>[LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_1]Les Braises Hurlantes, Chapitre 1[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_2]Les Braises Hurlantes, Chapitre 2[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_3]Les Braises Hurlantes, Chapitre 3[\LINK][H2]Les Braises Hurlantes, Chapitre 4[\H2]The Clan of Embers may have the biggest army ever seen, more warriors than any warboss has ever dreamt to gather, yet they are weak. Their will is weak, their faith is weak. And they are foolish. They had thought him a fool, yet they hadn't even noticed his departure of Braduk with all his tribe. Only two drunken guards had barred his way; one now had a spear planted in his belly, and Hafgan had chopped the other one's head himself.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]All the others were still feasting and celebrating the marriage of Jonas Endain and his new slut-queen. Stupid fools. Soon enough, he would teach them Bhall's true way. It would surely mean slaying Jonas. Too bad. Hafgan had been rather fond of him before he met the Bannor girl. He might have forgiven this marriage, even though a weak human-like child like her was worth nothing. He might even have tolerated the girl's ridiculous attempts to teach them human tactics and discipline. Pathetic; as if they needed to fight like the feeble humans. However, he would never forget that the so-called Priest-King allowed her to discuss peace terms with the Bannor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Peace! The word alone was treason, heresy, the exact opposite of Bhall's teachings. Any true orc knew that their kind can only thrive through endless war and by spilling their enemies' blood for their Goddess. The worst part had been the s**t's speech. She had called it a strategic move, to better fight the Chislev and other enemies. Strategy! Another weakling's concept, good only for cowards who are too weak or too frightened for a good fight.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She was wrong, he knew it. They were all wrong, and he would show it to them all. He, Hafgan the Purger, chieftain of the Burning Spears. For he was Bhall's true chosen champion. He, not Jonas, not this other fool Rantine. He might lack the strength to fight Jonas and the entire Clan for the moment, but that would change. He would crush humans, again and again - for that was the only way to 'negotiate' with them. And the glory of his victories would rally the true orcs behind him. He would lead them all to greatness, and leave only ashes behind him. For fire is the only way.</French>
		<German>[LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_1]Part 1: Bellowing Embers[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_2]Part 2: Bellowing Embers[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_3]Part 3: Bellowing Embers[\LINK][H2]Part 4 Bellowing Embers[\H2]The Clan of Embers may have the biggest army ever seen, more warriors than any warboss has ever dreamt to gather, yet they are weak. Their will is weak, their faith is weak. And they are foolish. They had thought him a fool, yet they hadn't even noticed his departure of Braduk with all his tribe. Only two drunken guards had barred his way; one now had a spear planted in his belly, and Hafgan had chopped the other one's head himself.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]All the others were still feasting and celebrating the marriage of Jonas Endain and his new slut-queen. Stupid fools. Soon enough, he would teach them Bhall's true way. It would surely mean slaying Jonas. Too bad. Hafgan had been rather fond of him before he met the Bannor girl. He might have forgiven this marriage, even though a weak human-like child like her was worth nothing. He might even have tolerated the girl's ridiculous attempts to teach them human tactics and discipline. Pathetic; as if they needed to fight like the feeble humans. However, he would never forget that the so-called Priest-King allowed her to discuss peace terms with the Bannor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Peace! The word alone was treason, heresy, the exact opposite of Bhall's teachings. Any true orc knew that their kind can only thrive through endless war and by spilling their enemies' blood for their Goddess. The worst part had been the s**t's speech. She had called it a strategic move, to better fight the Chislev and other enemies. Strategy! Another weakling's concept, good only for cowards who are too weak or too frightened for a good fight.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She was wrong, he knew it. They were all wrong, and he would show it to them all. He, Hafgan the Purger, chieftain of the Burning Spears. For he was Bhall's true chosen champion. He, not Jonas, not this other fool Rantine. He might lack the strength to fight Jonas and the entire Clan for the moment, but that would change. He would crush humans, again and again - for that was the only way to 'negotiate' with them. And the glory of his victories would rally the true orcs behind him. He would lead them all to greatness, and leave only ashes behind him. For fire is the only way.</German>
		<Italian>[LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_1]Le Braci Urlanti, 1° Parte[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_2]Le Braci Urlanti, 2° Parte[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_3]Le Braci Urlanti, 3° Parte[\LINK][H2]Le Braci Urlanti, 4° Parte[\H2]The Clan of Embers may have the biggest army ever seen, more warriors than any warboss has ever dreamt to gather, yet they are weak. Their will is weak, their faith is weak. And they are foolish. They had thought him a fool, yet they hadn't even noticed his departure of Braduk with all his tribe. Only two drunken guards had barred his way; one now had a spear planted in his belly, and Hafgan had chopped the other one's head himself.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]All the others were still feasting and celebrating the marriage of Jonas Endain and his new slut-queen. Stupid fools. Soon enough, he would teach them Bhall's true way. It would surely mean slaying Jonas. Too bad. Hafgan had been rather fond of him before he met the Bannor girl. He might have forgiven this marriage, even though a weak human-like child like her was worth nothing. He might even have tolerated the girl's ridiculous attempts to teach them human tactics and discipline. Pathetic; as if they needed to fight like the feeble humans. However, he would never forget that the so-called Priest-King allowed her to discuss peace terms with the Bannor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Peace! The word alone was treason, heresy, the exact opposite of Bhall's teachings. Any true orc knew that their kind can only thrive through endless war and by spilling their enemies' blood for their Goddess. The worst part had been the s**t's speech. She had called it a strategic move, to better fight the Chislev and other enemies. Strategy! Another weakling's concept, good only for cowards who are too weak or too frightened for a good fight.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She was wrong, he knew it. They were all wrong, and he would show it to them all. He, Hafgan the Purger, chieftain of the Burning Spears. For he was Bhall's true chosen champion. He, not Jonas, not this other fool Rantine. He might lack the strength to fight Jonas and the entire Clan for the moment, but that would change. He would crush humans, again and again - for that was the only way to 'negotiate' with them. And the glory of his victories would rally the true orcs behind him. He would lead them all to greatness, and leave only ashes behind him. For fire is the only way.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_1]Part 1: Bellowing Embers[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_2]Part 2: Bellowing Embers[\LINK][NEWLINE][LINK=LORE_BELLOWING_EMBERS_3]Part 3: Bellowing Embers[\LINK][H2]Part 4 Bellowing Embers[\H2]The Clan of Embers may have the biggest army ever seen, more warriors than any warboss has ever dreamt to gather, yet they are weak. Their will is weak, their faith is weak. And they are foolish. They had thought him a fool, yet they hadn't even noticed his departure of Braduk with all his tribe. Only two drunken guards had barred his way; one now had a spear planted in his belly, and Hafgan had chopped the other one's head himself.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]All the others were still feasting and celebrating the marriage of Jonas Endain and his new slut-queen. Stupid fools. Soon enough, he would teach them Bhall's true way. It would surely mean slaying Jonas. Too bad. Hafgan had been rather fond of him before he met the Bannor girl. He might have forgiven this marriage, even though a weak human-like child like her was worth nothing. He might even have tolerated the girl's ridiculous attempts to teach them human tactics and discipline. Pathetic; as if they needed to fight like the feeble humans. However, he would never forget that the so-called Priest-King allowed her to discuss peace terms with the Bannor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Peace! The word alone was treason, heresy, the exact opposite of Bhall's teachings. Any true orc knew that their kind can only thrive through endless war and by spilling their enemies' blood for their Goddess. The worst part had been the s**t's speech. She had called it a strategic move, to better fight the Chislev and other enemies. Strategy! Another weakling's concept, good only for cowards who are too weak or too frightened for a good fight.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She was wrong, he knew it. They were all wrong, and he would show it to them all. He, Hafgan the Purger, chieftain of the Burning Spears. For he was Bhall's true chosen champion. He, not Jonas, not this other fool Rantine. He might lack the strength to fight Jonas and the entire Clan for the moment, but that would change. He would crush humans, again and again - for that was the only way to 'negotiate' with them. And the glory of his victories would rally the true orcs behind him. He would lead them all to greatness, and leave only ashes behind him. For fire is the only way.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_JONAS</Tag>
		<English>Jonas Endain</English>
		<French>Jonas Endain</French>
		<German>Jonas Endain</German>
		<Italian>Jonas Endain</Italian>
		<Spanish>Jonas Endain</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SHEELBA</Tag>
		<English>Sheelba</English>
		<French>Sheelba</French>
		<German>Sheelba</German>
		<Italian>Sheelba</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sheelba</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_CLAN_OF_EMBERS</Tag>
		<English>Clan of Embers Palace</English>
		<French>Palais du Clan des Braises</French>
		<German>Palast des Klan der Asche</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo del Clan delle Braci</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio del Clan Ascua</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WARRENS</Tag>
		<English>Agoge</English>
		<French>Creuset du Carnage</French>
		<German>Agoge</German>
		<Italian>Agoge</Italian>
		<Spanish>Agoge</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WARRENS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Doubles the amount of units trained in the city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Doesn't affect heroes, national, siege or naval units.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Double le nombre d'unités produites dans la ville.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]N'affecte pas les héros, les unités nationales, navales et de siège.</French>
		<German>Verdoppelt die Menge der aufgestellten Einheiten in der Stadt.[NEWLINE]Gilt nicht für Helden, National- Belagerungs- und See-Einheiten.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Doubles the amount of units trained in the city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Doesn't affect heroes, national, siege or naval units.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Dobla la cantidad de unidades entrenadas en la ciudad.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]No afecta a unidades héroes, nacionales, de asedio o navales.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WARRENS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>When we finally conquered their city, we were not prepared to face what was hidden in these strange, ruined buildings. I was chosen to be part of an exploration team sent inside what we thought to be a shabby warehouse, but once inside the stench of rotting flesh almost stunned me. In the dim light of our lantern we saw thousands of little shiny eyes, belonging to countless baby orcs fighting one another or feasting on rats and other vermin. Here and there my eyes caught the shapes of pregnant orc females, their swelled wombs forcing them to sit helplessly in the dirt. We all knew war too well and knew what had to be done, but in my heart I felt like the monsters I sworn to fight, as killing children was horrible for me, regardless of their race. Our commander ordered to set fire to these warrens, and I think I will never forget their screams... that day I paid with my own humanity the price of joining the crusade...[PARAGRAPH:1]-Jarn, Bannor soldier</English>
		<French>Quand nous avons finalement pris la ville, nous n'étions pas préparés à faire face à ce qui se cachait dans ces étranges bâtiments ruinés. J'avais été choisi pour faire partie de l'équipe d'exploration de ce que nous pensiosn être un entrepôt misérable, mais une fois à l'intérieur la puanteur de la chair pourrissante m'a presque assomé. Dans la chiche lumière de nos lanternes, nous avons vu des milliers de petits yeux brillants, appartenant à d'innombrables bébés orcs se battant entre eux ou festoyant de rats ou autres vermines. Alors j'aperçus la forme de femmelles orcs enceintes, leurs ventres gonflés les obligeant à rester assises dans la terre. Nous connaissions tous trop bien la guerre et savions ce qui devait être fait, mais au fond de moi-même je me sentais comme les monstres que nous avions juré de combattre, car tuer des enfants m'était insupportable, qu'importe leur race. Notre chef nous ordonna de mettre le feu à ce clapier, et je crois que je n'oublierai jamais leurs cris... ce jour là j'ai payé de mon humanité le prix pour m'être joint à la croisade...[PARAGRAPH:1]- Jarn, Soldat Bannor</French>
		<German>Als wir schließlich ihre Stadt erobert hatten, waren wir nicht auf das vorbereitet, was uns in diesen seltsamen, ruinierten Gebäuden erwarten würde. Ich war ausgewählt worden bei ein Erkundungsteam mitzugehen, dass ein Gebäude untersuchen sollte, das wor für ein schäbiges Warenlager hielten. Aber als wir einmal darin waren hätte mich der Gestank von verottendem Fleisch beinahe ohnmächtig werden lassen. Im schwachen Licht unserer Laternen sahen wir tausende kleine, leuchtende AUgen, die zu zahllosen Orkbabys gehörten, welche sich gegenseitig bekämpften oder von Ratten und anderen Nagetieren ernährten. Hier und dort konnte ich die Umrisse schwangerer Orkfrauen erkennen, ihre dicken Bäuche zwangen sie, hilflos im Dreck zu sitzen. Wir alle kannten den Krieg nur zu gut und wussten was getan werden musste, aber tief in meinem Herzen fühlte ich mich wie eines der Monster, die ich geschworen hatte zu bekämpfen, denn die Ermordung von Kinder ist in meinen Augen abscheulich, egal welcher Rasse sie angehören. Unser Kommandant befahl Feuer an diese "Zuchtgehege" zu legen und ich denke ich werden niemals ihre Schreie vergessen können... an diesem Tag bezahlte ich mit meiner eigenen Menschlichkeit den Preis für den Beitritt zum Kreuzzug...[PARAGRAPH:1]- Jarn, Soldat der Bannor</German>
		<Italian>Quando riuscimmo finalmente a conquistare la loro città non eravamo minimamente preparati per cosa trovammo in quegli strani edifici in rovina. Fui scelto per far parte di una squadra esplorativa che sarebbe entrata in quello che si pensava fosse un vecchio magazzino, una volta entrato la puzza di carne marcescente mi stordì. Con la fioca luce delle nostra lanterna vedemmo migliaia di piccoli occhi luccicanti che appartenevano ad innumerevoli bambini orchi che combattevano tra di loro e che si cibavano di ratti. Ogni tanto i miei occhi scorgevano la figura di un orchessa gravida, il cui ventre enorme la obbligava a sedersi sulla terra impotente. Tutti noi conoscevamo bene la guerra e ciò che doveva esser fatto, ma nel mio cuore mi sentii come i mostri che avevo giurato di combattere, in quanto uccidere dei bambini era una cosa orribile per me, indifferentemente dalla razza a cui appartenevano. Il nostro comandante ordinò di appiccare il fuoco a quegli edifici, non penso che dimenticheò mai le loro urla... quel giorno pagai con la mia umanità l'essermi unito alla crociata...[PARAGRAPH:1]- Jarn, soldato Bannor</Italian>
		<Spanish>When we finally conquered their city, we were not prepared to face what was hidden in these strange, ruined buildings. I was chosen to be part of an exploration team sent inside what we thought to be a shabby warehouse, but once inside the stench of rotting flesh almost stunned me. In the dim light of our lantern we saw thousand of little shiny eyes, belonging to countless baby orcs fighting one another or feasting on rats and other vermin. Here and there my eyes caught the shapes of pregnant orc females, their swelled wombs forcing them to sit helplessly in the dirt. We all knew war too well and knew what had to be done, but in my heart I felt like the monsters I sworn to fight, as killing children was horrible for me, regardless of their race. Our commander ordered to set fire to these warrens, and I think I will never forget their screams... that day I paid with my own humanity the price of joining the crusade ...[PARAGRAPH:1]- Jarn, Bannor soldier</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MULTI_FOR_THE_HORDE</Tag>
		<English>For the Horde</English>
		<French>Pour la Horde !</French>
		<German>Für die Horde!</German>
		<Italian>Per l'Orda!</Italian>
		<Spanish>For the Horde</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FOR_THE_HORDE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Grants the player control of every Orc Savage in the game.  Units cost no upkeep but will return to being Savages unless hired as a permanent member of the Civ. Not available if the player is at war with Savages.</English>
		<French>Donne au joueur le contrôle de tous les Orques sauvages en jeu. Les unités ne coûtent pas d'entretien, mais redeviendrotn sauvages à moins d'être recrutées comme lelbre permanent de la civilisation.</French>
		<German>Der Zaubernde &#252;bernimmt die Kontrolle &#252;ber jeden Ork der Wilden Truppen im Spiel. Die erhaltenen Einheiten kosten keinen Unterhalt, werden aber wieder zu Wilden Truppen werden, wenn sie nicht als permanente Mitglieder der Zivilisation angeheuert werden.</German>
		<Italian>Mette sotto il controllo del giocatore ogni orco barbaro in gioco. Queste unità non costano mantenimento ma torneranno ad essere barbare se non vengono arruolate e rese membri permanenti della civiltà. Non disponibile se in guerra con i Barbari.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grants the player control of every Orc Savage in the game.  Units cost no upkeep but will return to being Savages unless hired as a permanent member of the Civ. Not available if the player is at war with Savages.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_FOR_THE_HORDE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]All Barbarian units are converted to your civilization, teleported to the caster, and granted the [LINK=PROMOTION_FOR_THE_HORDE]For The Horde[\LINK] promotion.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Toutes les unités barbares rejoignent votre civilisation, sont téléportées sur le lanceur et reçoivent la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_FOR_THE_HORDE]Pour la Horde ![\LINK] .</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]All Barbarian units are converted to your civilization, teleported to the caster, and granted the [LINK=PROMOTION_FOR_THE_HORDE]For The Horde[\LINK] promotion.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Tutte le unità barbare vengono convertite alla tua civiltà, teletrasportate dove è stata lanciata la magia e gli viene data la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_FOR_THE_HORDE]Per l'Orda[\LINK].</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]All Barbarian units are converted to your civilization, teleported to the caster, and granted the [LINK=PROMOTION_FOR_THE_HORDE]For The Horde[\LINK] promotion.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BIG_BOSS</Tag>
		<English>Big Boss</English>
		<French>Grand Chef</French>
		<German>Gro&#223;er Herr</German>
		<Italian>Grande Capo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Big Boss</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOSS</Tag>
		<English>Boss</English>
		<French>Chef</French>
		<German>Herr</German>
		<Italian>Capo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Boss</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OGRE</Tag>
		<English>Ogre</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Ogre:Ogres</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Troll</German>
		<Italian>Ogre</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ogre</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OGRE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Ogres have long been the rulers of places civilization would rather not tread. Now that the realms of civilization have been cut back, the ogres aim to make sure man stays in his place, claiming the hills and bogs as their own and thriving despite the cold.</English>
		<French>Ogres have long been the rulers of places civilization would rather not tread. Now that the realms of civilization have been cut back, the ogres aim to make sure man stays in his place, claiming the hills and bogs as their own and thriving despite the cold.</French>
		<German>Ogres have long been the rulers of places civilization would rather not tread. Now that the realms of civilization have been cut back, the ogres aim to make sure man stays in his place, claiming the hills and bogs as their own and thriving despite the cold.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Ogre sono stati per molto tempo i signori dei posti che le civiltà evitavano. Ora che la supremazia della civilizzazione è stata ridotta gli ogre mirano a far rimanere l'uomo dove sta, rivendicando le colline e le paludi come loro prosperando nonostante il freddo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ogres have long been the rulers of places civilization would rather not tread. Now that the realms of civilization have been cut back, the ogres aim to make sure man stays in his place, claiming the hills and bogs as their own and thriving despite the cold.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OGRE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Horsemen can cover ground very swiftly, taking the fight to enemies across the realm. Few orcs have the patience or aptitude for animal training however, and the Clan of Embers fields no mounted regiments past the early wolf riders and goblin chariots. The Ogres, huge brutes with giant strides, fill the heavy cavalry niche quite effectively, slamming into enemy formations with more mass, if less speed. </English>
		<French>Horsemen can cover ground very swiftly, taking the fight to enemies across the realm. Few orcs have the patience or aptitude for animal training however, and the Clan of Embers fields no mounted regiments past the early wolf riders and goblin chariots. The Ogres, huge brutes with giant strides, fill the heavy cavalry niche quite effectively, slamming into enemy formations with more mass, if less speed. </French>
		<German>Pikienere sind disziplinierte Truppen, die darin geschult sind massive Stangen zu führen, die sie auf den Boden aufstützen um Kavallerieangriffe zu kontern. Der Klan der Asche hat keinen bedarf für solche Formationen, sie haben Trolle. Große Scheusale, die mit Baumstämmen umher- schwingen, sie können mit einem einzelnen Schlag, Kavallerie durch die Luft fliegen lassen. Unintelligent, sogar verglichen mit Orks und Goblins, aber man braucht kein Genie zu sein  um zu erkennen, das wenn ein Trupp Kavallerie dich angreift, du besser hart und schnell zuschlägst.</German>
		<Italian>I cavalieri possono coprire grandi distanze molto rapidamente, affrontando i nemici in tutto il territorio. Però pochi sono gli orchi con la pazienza, o l'attitudine, per addestrare gli animali e a causa di ciò il Clan delle Braci non ha truppe montate oltre i cavalcatori di lupi e i carri dei goblin. Gli Ogre, enormi bruti con passi da gigante, ricoprono il ruolo della cavalleria pesante abbastanza efficacemente, schiantandosi contro la formazione nemica con maggiore massa anche se minore velocità. </Italian>
		<Spanish>Horsemen can cover ground very swiftly, taking the fight to enemies across the realm. Few orcs have the patience or aptitude for animal training however, and the Clan of Embers fields no mounted regiments past the early wolf riders and goblin chariots. The Ogres, huge brutes with giant strides, fill the heavy cavalry niche quite effectively, slamming into enemy formations with more mass, if less speed. </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OGRE_WARCHIEF</Tag>
		<English>Ogre Warchief</English>
		<French>Chef de Guerre Ogre</French>
		<German>Oger Kriegshäuptling</German>
		<Italian>Ogre Capoguerra</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ogre Warchief</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OGRE_WARCHIEF_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In human societies 'chief' often denotes a wise and revered leader. Ogres, however, respect only strength. Leadership of their cities can change in a single brawl. Actually, when these brutes begin to march on human cities, they can change leadership with a single brawl as well. One look at what the War chief does to the first defender will often induce all the back up to flee in terror. An incredible fighter when he needs to be, the Ogre Warchiefs learn the hard way that honor means nothing on the field of battle. The brutish ogres they lead would double cross them at the first opportunity. Warchiefs are therefore not above sacrificing minions as a distraction, and will always ensure one way or another, that they live to fight another day.</English>
		<French>In human societies 'chief' often denotes a wise and revered leader. Ogres, however, respect only strength. Leadership of their cities can change in a single brawl. Actually, when these brutes begin to march on human cities, they can change leadership with a single brawl as well. One look at what the War chief does to the first defender will often induce all the back up to flee in terror. An incredible fighter when he needs to be, the Ogre Warchiefs learn the hard way that honor means nothing on the field of battle. The brutish ogres they lead would double cross them at the first opportunity. Warchiefs are therefore not above sacrificing minions as a distraction, and will always ensure one way or another, that they live to fight another day.</French>
		<German>In menschlichen Gesellschaften, kennzeichnet der Titel "Oberhaupt" oft einen weisen und verehrten Anführer. Wie auch immer, Oger respektieren nur Stärke. Die Führung in ihren Städten kann sich durch einen einzelnen Streit ändern. Auch, wenn sie gegen menschliche Städte marschieren, kann sich die Führung genauso schnell ändern, durch einen einzigen Streit. Wenn jemand sieht, was der Ogerhäuptling mit dem ersten Verteidiger macht, wird dies die hinteren Verteidiger oft veranlassen, in Angst und Schrecken zu fliehen. Ein unglaublicher Kämpfer, wenn es sein muss. Oger Kriegshäuptlinge lernen auf die harte Tour, dass Ruhm auf dem Schlachtfeld keine Bedeutung hat. Die brutalen Oger, die sie anführen, fackeln nicht lange und überwältigen sie bei der ersten sich bietenden Gelegenheit. Daher sind Oger Kriegshäuptlinge nicht zimperlich damit, Untergebene für Ablenkungsmanöver zu opfern, sie werden immer auf die eine oder die andere Art sicherstellen, dass sie überleben, um am nächsten Tag kämpfen zu können.</German>
		<Italian>Nelle società umane il titolo 'capo' spesso indica una guida saggia e riverita. Gli Ogre, invece, rispettano solo la forza. La guida delle città può cambiare a seguito di una sola rissa. Persino quando questi bruti iniziano a marciare verso le città umane possono cambiare guida con una sola rissa. Spesso basta vedere cosa fa il capoguerra ai primi difensori per far scappare terrorizzati gli eventuali rinforzi. Degli incredibili combattenti quando devono esserlo, i Capoguerra Ogre hanno imparato nella maniera più dura che l'onore non ha valore sul campo di battaglia. I brutali ogre che guidano li tradirebbero alla prima opportunità. I Capoguerra, di conseguenza, non si fanno scrupoli a sacrificare i loro servitori per creare diversivi, assicurandosi, in un modo o in un'altro, di vivere per combattere un'altro giorno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>In human societies 'chief' often denotes a wise and revered leader. Ogres, however, respect only strength. Leadership of their cities can change in a single brawl. Actually, when these brutes begin to march on human cities, they can change leadership with a single brawl as well. One look at what the War chief does to the first defender will often induce all the back up to flee in terror. An incredible fighter when he needs to be, the Ogre Warchiefs learn the hard way that honor means nothing on the field of battle. The brutish ogres they lead would double cross them at the first opportunity. Warchiefs are therefore not above sacrificing minions as a distraction, and will always ensure one way or another, that they live to fight another day.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OGRE_WARCHIEF_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Say what you will about the lumbering Ogre Warchief, but they are to crafty to be trapped in battle. They will reappear in your capital if they are defeated.</English>
		<French>Say what you will about the lumbering Ogre Warchief, but they are to crafty to be trapped in battle. They will reappear in your capital if they are defeated.</French>
		<German>Say what you will about the lumbering Ogre Warchief, but they are to crafty to be trapped in battle. They will reappear in your capital if they are defeated.</German>
		<Italian>Si può dire quello che si vuole dei goffi Capoguerra Ogre, ma sono difficili da intrappolare in battaglia. Riappariranno nella tua capitale se vengono sconfitti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Say what you will about the lumbering Ogre Warchief, but they are to crafty to be trapped in battle. They will reappear in your capital if they are defeated.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_STONESKIN_OGRE</Tag>
		<English>Stoneskin Ogre</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Ogre Lithoderme:Ogres Lithodermes</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Felsentroll</German>
		<Italian>Ogre Pelle di pietra</Italian>
		<Spanish>Stoneskin Ogre</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_STONESKIN_OGRE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Ogres have tremendous regenerative ability and a very high tolerance for pain. Long lived ogres will typically be covered in scars, but these old wounds give them a thick layer of calluses, further reducing their susceptibility to pain. Their reflexes tend to be dulled somewhat, but killing a Stone-skin ogre is a tremendously difficult task. Even wounding one is rare, and is not recommended without a great withdrawal rate.</English>
		<French>Ogres have tremendous regenerative ability and a very high tolerance for pain. Long lived ogres will typically be covered in scars, but these old wounds give them a thick layer of calluses, further reducing their susceptibility to pain. Their reflexes tend to be dulled somewhat, but killing a Stone-skin ogre is a tremendously difficult task. Even wounding one is rare, and is not recommended without a great withdrawal rate.</French>
		<German>Felsentrolle haben überragende regenerative Fähigkeiten und eine hohe Schmerztoleranz. Ältere Trolle sind typischerweise mit Narben bedeckt, doch diese alten Wunden geben ihnen eine dicke Hornhaut, die ihre Schmerzempfänglichkeit weiter reduziert. Ihre Reflexe sind nicht besonders ausgeprägt -  trotzdem ist es extrem schwer, einen Felsentroll zu töten. Sogar einen zu verwunden ist sehr schwer und nicht ohne Rückzugsmöglichkeiten zu empfehlen.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Ogre hanno delle incredibili capacità rigenerative e un'elevata tolleranza al dolore. Gli Ogre più anziani sono regolarmente coperti da cicatrici, e queste vecchie ferite rendono la loro spessa pelle ancora più callosa, riducendo la loro sensibilità al dolore. Per quanto i loro riflessi siano scarsi uccidere un'Ogre Pelle di pietra è un'impresa incredibilmente ardua. Persino ferirli è raro, e non è consigliabile farlo senza una grande probabilità di ritirarsi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ogres have tremendous regenerative ability and a very high tolerance for pain. Long lived ogres will typically be covered in scars, but these old wounds give them a thick layer of calluses, further reducing their susceptibility to pain. Their reflexes tend to be dulled somewhat, but killing a Stone-skin ogre is a tremendously difficult task. Even wounding one is rare, and is not recommended without a great withdrawal rate.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OVERLORD</Tag>
		<English>Overlord</English>
		<French>Overlord</French>
		<German>Oberherr</German>
		<Italian>Overlord</Italian>
		<Spanish>Overlord</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRIEST_OF_BHALL</Tag>
		<English>Orcish Druid</English>
		<French>Druide Orque</French>
		<German>Orcish Druid</German>
		<Italian>Orcish Druid</Italian>
		<Spanish>Orcish Druid</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RANTINE</Tag>
		<English>Rantine</English>
		<French>Rantine</French>
		<German>Rantin</German>
		<Italian>Rantine</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rantine</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_RANTINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Rantine is a powerful early weapon against any enemies of the Clan of Embers, and a great tool against their allies, with his ability to convert barbarian cities if he is the strongest unit in it.</English>
		<French>Rantine est une puissante et précoce arme contre les ennemis du Clan des Braises, et un excellent outil contre leurs alliés, grâce à sa capacité de convertir les villes barbares s'il est l'unité présente la plus puissante.</French>
		<German>Rantin ist ein mächtiger Krieger des Klans der Asche im frühen Spiel. Auch gegen Barbaren kann er helfen, da sich jede Barbarische Stadt, in der keine mächtigere Kreatur als dieser grausame Schlächter befindet, dem Klan anschließen wird.</German>
		<Italian>Rantine è una potente arma contro ogni nemico del Clan nelle prime fasi della partita, avendo l'abilità di convertire le città barbare se lui è l'unità più forte in essa.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rantine is a powerful early weapon against any enemies of the Clan of Embers, and a great tool against their allies, with his ability to convert barbarian cities if he is the strongest unit in it.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WAR_BOSS</Tag>
		<English>War Boss</English>
		<French>Chef de Guerre</French>
		<German>Kriegsherr</German>
		<Italian>Capoguerra</Italian>
		<Spanish>War Boss</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LOOTER</Tag>
		<English>Looter</English>
		<French>Brigand</French>
		<German>Looter</German>
		<Italian>Looter</Italian>
		<Spanish>Looter</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PLUNDERER</Tag>
		<English>Plunderer</English>
		<French>Pillard</French>
		<German>Plunderer</German>
		<Italian>Plunderer</Italian>
		<Spanish>Plunderer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MARAUDER</Tag>
		<English>Marauder</English>
		<French>Maraudeur</French>
		<German>Marauder</German>
		<Italian>Marauder</Italian>
		<Spanish>Marauder</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
