<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BANNOR_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Bannor</English>
		<French>bannorien:bannorienne:bannoriens:bannoriennes</French>
		<German>Bannorisch</German>
		<Italian>Bannor</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bannor</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BANNOR_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Bannor</English>
		<French>Bannor</French>
		<German>Reich der Bannor</German>
		<Italian>Bannor</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bannor</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BANNOR_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Bannor</English>
		<French>Bannoriens</French>
		<German>Bannor</German>
		<Italian>Bannor</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bannor</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BANNOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Bannor are a good all-around civ who shine once embarking upon a total war. Their Crusade civic will give them troops on the field and decreased war weariness.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Bannor started with a handful of people, trapped in hell during the fall of Braduk but rescued by Sabathiel, an angel in Junil's service. In exchange for their salvation, the spirits bound themselves and their descendants to ceaselessly battle the forces of chaos and disorder. As Sabathiel led the honorable spirits forth into the light, they formed the vanguard in a devastating war against the Clan of Embers, even more powerful then than they are today. Throughout the entire Age of Rebirth the Bannor waged brutal and merciless war not only on the Clan, but on all who would not submit to law and order.[PARAGRAPH:1]Throughout this war of liberation and extermination, these heroes of an ancient age forged conquered, allied, and submitting tribes, cities, and nations into a human empire which, with the aid and guidance of Sabathiel, may stand firm even against the looming apocalypse, when unequaled evil is loosed upon Erebus. [PARAGRAPH:1]This continuing Holy War permeates every part of their society, leaving it almost totally militarized. For the Bannor, there is no clear line between religion, family, and politics. They apply a frightening religious fervor to the art of war, and their obsession with order makes even the peasant regiments among the best drilled of all the empires. All men are trained from childhood in the arts of war-hand-to-hand combat, archery, self defense, strength, and agility. Unlike most other societies, there are plenty of possibilities for rising through the ranks through bravery and skill, a fact which inspires as much if not more fighting fervor than the religious element.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because they need to be defended and ready at all times, outlying villages are more like forts, every farm is a small castle, the cities are huge garrison towns but also centers of trade, religion, and diplomacy. Few men are without scars from battle and the women are strong-willed and hardened. They know that the children they raise may one day be lost in battle, and they also know that one day the war may come to them. It is a rare woman among the Bannor that cannot handle a sword. [PARAGRAPH:1]A central part of understanding the fabric of Bannor society is understanding the split between estates and "free land." The estates are enormous tracts of land, almost sub-kingdoms, under the rule of an Order, a Family or one of those peculiarities of the Bannor: a Hereditary Order-a religious order with members exclusively from one clan. Centered on a stronghold or small fortified city, the main function of the estates is to provide the necessary resources to field one Order or Family division, the powerful and highly dedicated fighting forces that make up the feared backbone of the Bannor armies.[PARAGRAPH:1]The lion's share of the land in the Bannor empire is the "free land." The villages and cities that occupy and make a living off this land must, in addition to paying taxes and organizing their own defenses, provide a number of soldiers, fully trained and equipped, according to the wealth of the settlement. Although the Orders and Families are the spearhead and armored fist of Bannor armies, "free land" conscripts provide the bulk forces that are needed to carry a battle.[PARAGRAPH:1]By far the most numerous of the estate-holders, the non-hereditary Orders will take fighters from all across the world, all nations and races. Those deemed worthy in prowess and intelligence are taught in the ways and language of the Bannor and then join the fighting forces on the same footing as native Bannor.[PARAGRAPH:1]The hereditary Orders are in reality families that have founded or taken over control of an Order. All the major positions are held by and passed down from father to son, uncle to nephew, like any usual aristocratic title. It is one of the few options a rich non-noble family has of gaining an estate and the power and responsibility that comes with it.[PARAGRAPH:1]The noble Families all trace their lineage back to one of the spirits that Sabathiel set free. They use this holy heritage to legitimize their enormous power, and it is the reason the priesthood tolerates their existence and their meddling in the running of things. There are very few Families, but every one of them wields as much power and wealth as an Order. However, the priesthood keeps these secular powerhouses under careful and strict control, lest they attempt to change the fabric of Bannor society.[PARAGRAPH:1]The highly-trained and well-equipped men who fight in the professional divisions of the Orders and Families come from a variety of backgrounds and fight for any number of reasons: Some do it for money or status, some few do it for glory or personal revenge, but most do it because they truly believe they are on the front line of the war against Evil.[PARAGRAPH:1]As any Bannor priest could tell you, the war fought by the Bannor is far more complicated than a simple Good-Evil battle. The priesthood, under the guidance of Sabathiel (or so they claim) decide who is an enemy. Although they have yet to fight a civilization that conforms to some kind of law and sense of justice and compassion, few who can avoid it dare cross the Bannor, lest they be "damned" and added to the list of civilizations that must be taught to repent.[PARAGRAPH:1]The focal point of the entire Bannor Empire is their capital, centered around the Bannor Palace, The Halls of Sabathiel. Although still recognizably a garrison city, it is also a sprawling, international metropolis matched by few other cities in Erebus. This is where the Orders have their headquarters, this is where the Families meet to discuss affairs of state, and this is where people come to consult with the priesthood. People of all races flock to the city to swell the ranks of the Orders, the Halls of Sabathiel have a constant stream of visitors coming to pay tribute or ask favors of his priests, and the bazaars and markets attract traders from far and wide, catering to the needs of a multiracial, multinational and multicultural army and administration.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel, the mythical ruler of the Bannor, unwilling to set foot upon Erebus and break the letter or the spirit of the Compact, is said to reside deep within the recesses of his Halls, watching, guiding, teaching, and warding over the Bannor, urging them on but unable to physically manifest. He is a shadow king, never seen by his subjects but always a haunting figure, ever present in their consciousness. Their battlefield commanders are much more present figures to most Bannormen, Capria being the best example, who as a young girl led her people as they stepped from hell, and soon grew in honor and authority through the end of the Age of Ice and dawn of the Age of Rebirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]In this day, there are those even among the Bannor, and even more so among their enemies, who whisper that both Sabathiel and his original spirits are naught but legends invented by a militant priesthood looking for ways to legitimize their rule. Whatever the truth of the matter, the fact is that in the Age of Rebirth, the Bannor must rely on human flesh and cold steel, not angels and spirits, to bring Law to the dark corners of the world.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The Bannor are a good all-around civ who shine once embarking upon a total war. Their Crusade civic will give them troops on the field and decreased war weariness.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Bannor started with a handful of people, trapped in hell during the fall of Braduk but rescued by Sabathiel, an angel in Junil's service. In exchange for their salvation, the spirits bound themselves and their descendants to ceaselessly battle the forces of chaos and disorder. As Sabathiel led the honorable spirits forth into the light, they formed the vanguard in a devastating war against the Clan of Embers, even more powerful then than they are today. Throughout the entire Age of Rebirth the Bannor waged brutal and merciless war not only on the Clan, but on all who would not submit to law and order.[PARAGRAPH:1]Throughout this war of liberation and extermination, these heroes of an ancient age forged conquered, allied, and submitting tribes, cities, and nations into a human empire which, with the aid and guidance of Sabathiel, may stand firm even against the looming apocalypse, when unequaled evil is loosed upon Erebus. [PARAGRAPH:1]This continuing Holy War permeates every part of their society, leaving it almost totally militarized. For the Bannor, there is no clear line between religion, family, and politics. They apply a frightening religious fervor to the art of war, and their obsession with order makes even the peasant regiments among the best drilled of all the empires. All men are trained from childhood in the arts of war-hand-to-hand combat, archery, self defense, strength, and agility. Unlike most other societies, there are plenty of possibilities for rising through the ranks through bravery and skill, a fact which inspires as much if not more fighting fervor than the religious element.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because they need to be defended and ready at all times, outlying villages are more like forts, every farm is a small castle, the cities are huge garrison towns but also centers of trade, religion, and diplomacy. Few men are without scars from battle and the women are strong-willed and hardened. They know that the children they raise may one day be lost in battle, and they also know that one day the war may come to them. It is a rare woman among the Bannor that cannot handle a sword. [PARAGRAPH:1]A central part of understanding the fabric of Bannor society is understanding the split between estates and "free land." The estates are enormous tracts of land, almost sub-kingdoms, under the rule of an Order, a Family or one of those peculiarities of the Bannor: a Hereditary Order-a religious order with members exclusively from one clan. Centered on a stronghold or small fortified city, the main function of the estates is to provide the necessary resources to field one Order or Family division, the powerful and highly dedicated fighting forces that make up the feared backbone of the Bannor armies.[PARAGRAPH:1]The lion's share of the land in the Bannor empire is the "free land." The villages and cities that occupy and make a living off this land must, in addition to paying taxes and organizing their own defenses, provide a number of soldiers, fully trained and equipped, according to the wealth of the settlement. Although the Orders and Families are the spearhead and armored fist of Bannor armies, "free land" conscripts provide the bulk forces that are needed to carry a battle.[PARAGRAPH:1]By far the most numerous of the estate-holders, the non-hereditary Orders will take fighters from all across the world, all nations and races. Those deemed worthy in prowess and intelligence are taught in the ways and language of the Bannor and then join the fighting forces on the same footing as native Bannor.[PARAGRAPH:1]The hereditary Orders are in reality families that have founded or taken over control of an Order. All the major positions are held by and passed down from father to son, uncle to nephew, like any usual aristocratic title. It is one of the few options a rich non-noble family has of gaining an estate and the power and responsibility that comes with it.[PARAGRAPH:1]The noble Families all trace their lineage back to one of the spirits that Sabathiel set free. They use this holy heritage to legitimize their enormous power, and it is the reason the priesthood tolerates their existence and their meddling in the running of things. There are very few Families, but every one of them wields as much power and wealth as an Order. However, the priesthood keeps these secular powerhouses under careful and strict control, lest they attempt to change the fabric of Bannor society.[PARAGRAPH:1]The highly-trained and well-equipped men who fight in the professional divisions of the Orders and Families come from a variety of backgrounds and fight for any number of reasons: Some do it for money or status, some few do it for glory or personal revenge, but most do it because they truly believe they are on the front line of the war against Evil.[PARAGRAPH:1]As any Bannor priest could tell you, the war fought by the Bannor is far more complicated than a simple Good-Evil battle. The priesthood, under the guidance of Sabathiel (or so they claim) decide who is an enemy. Although they have yet to fight a civilization that conforms to some kind of law and sense of justice and compassion, few who can avoid it dare cross the Bannor, lest they be "damned" and added to the list of civilizations that must be taught to repent.[PARAGRAPH:1]The focal point of the entire Bannor Empire is their capital, centered around the Bannor Palace, The Halls of Sabathiel. Although still recognizably a garrison city, it is also a sprawling, international metropolis matched by few other cities in Erebus. This is where the Orders have their headquarters, this is where the Families meet to discuss affairs of state, and this is where people come to consult with the priesthood. People of all races flock to the city to swell the ranks of the Orders, the Halls of Sabathiel have a constant stream of visitors coming to pay tribute or ask favors of his priests, and the bazaars and markets attract traders from far and wide, catering to the needs of a multiracial, multinational and multicultural army and administration.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel, the mythical ruler of the Bannor, unwilling to set foot upon Erebus and break the letter or the spirit of the Compact, is said to reside deep within the recesses of his Halls, watching, guiding, teaching, and warding over the Bannor, urging them on but unable to physically manifest. He is a shadow king, never seen by his subjects but always a haunting figure, ever present in their consciousness. Their battlefield commanders are much more present figures to most Bannormen, Capria being the best example, who as a young girl led her people as they stepped from hell, and soon grew in honor and authority through the end of the Age of Ice and dawn of the Age of Rebirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]In this day, there are those even among the Bannor, and even more so among their enemies, who whisper that both Sabathiel and his original spirits are naught but legends invented by a militant priesthood looking for ways to legitimize their rule. Whatever the truth of the matter, the fact is that in the Age of Rebirth, the Bannor must rely on human flesh and cold steel, not angels and spirits, to bring Law to the dark corners of the world.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Bannor sind eine vielseitige Zivilisation, die glänzen kann, wenn ein totaler Krieg beginnt. Ihre Gesellschaftsform "Kreuzzug" verschafft ihnen zusätzliche Truppen und eine verminderte Kriegsunzufriedenheit.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Bannor entstanden aus einer Handvoll Menschen, die während Braduks Fall in der Hölle gefangen waren, aber von Sabathiel gerettet wurden, einem Engel in den Diensten von Junil. Als Gegenleistung für ihre Errettung schworen sie, ihre Seelen und jene ihrer Nachkommen dem unablässigen Kampf gegen die Kräfte des Chaos und der Verderbnis zu widmen. Als Sabathiel diese Seelen zurück in das Licht führte, bildeten sie die Vorhut in einem verheerenden Krieg gegen den Klan der Asche, der damals sogar noch mächtiger war als heute. Während des gesamten Zeitalters der Magie führten die Bannor nicht nur einen brutalen und mitleidslosen Krieg gegen den Klan, sondern auch gegen jene, die sich Recht und Ordnung nicht beugen wollten.[PARAGRAPH:1]In diesem Befreiungs- und Vernichtungskrieg schmiedeten diese Helden eines vergangenen Zeitalters aus eroberten, verbündeten und unterworfenen Stämmen, Städten und Nationen ein Menschen-Reich, das, mit Sabathiels Hilfe und Führung, sogar der heraufziehenden Apokalypse trotzen könnte, wenn  das beispiellos Böse auf Erebus losgelassen würde.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dieser stetige Heilige Krieg durchdringt alle Bereiche ihrer Gesellschaft, die in Folge dessen nahezu vollständig militarisiert ist. Für die Bannor gibt es keine klare Trennung von Religion, Familie und Politik. Sie betreiben das Kriegshandwerk mit einem erschreckend religiösen Eifer und ihre Besessenheit von Befehlen macht sogar die Bauernregimenter zu den bestausgebildeten aller Reiche. Alle Männer werden von Kindesbeinen an in der Kriegskunst unterrichtet - Nahkampf, Bogenschießen, Selbstverteidigung, Kraft und Schnelligkeit. Im Gegensatz zu den meisten anderen Gesellschaften gibt es viele Möglichkeiten, durch Mut und Geschick in der Hierarchie aufzusteigen, eine Tatsache, die zu ebensoviel erschreckendem Eifer anspornt wie das religiöse Element, wenn nicht mehr.[PARAGRAPH:1]Weil sie zu jeder Zeit verteidigungsbereit sein müssen, gleichen abgelegene Dörfer kleinen Festungen, jeder Baurnhof ist eine kleine Burg und die Städte sind eigentlich Garnisonsstädte, obwohl sie auch Zentren des Handels, der Religion und der Diplomatie beherbergen. Nur wenige Männer haben keine Kampfnarben und die Frauen sind entschlossen und abgehärtet. Sie wissen, dass die Kinder, die sie großziehen, eines Tages in der Schlacht fallen könnten und sie wissen auch, dass der Krieg eines Tages ihre Heimat erreichen könnte. Deshalb ist selten eine Frau zu finden, die kein Schwert führen kann.[PARAGRAPH:1]Um die Struktur der bannorischen Gesellschaft vollständig verstehen zu können, muss man den Unterschied zwischen Lehen und "freiem Land" verstehen. Die Lehen sind riesige Landstriche, fast schon kleine Königreiche, unter der Herrschaft eines Ordens, einer Familie oder, einer der Eigenheiten der Bannor, eines Hausordens: ein religiöser Orden, dessen Mitglieder ausschließlich aus einem Klan stammen. Mit einer Festung oder einer kleinen befestigten Stadt als Mittelpunkt ist die Hauptaufgabe der Lehen, die notwendigen Mittel aufzubringen, um eine Ordens- oder Familien-Division aufstellen zu können. Diese starken und hochmotivierten Kampfverbände bilden das gefürchtete Rückgrat der bannorischen Armeen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Löwenanteil des Landes im Reich der Bannor ist "freies Land". Die Dörfer und Städte, die diese Gebiete in Anspruch nehmen und von ihnen leben, müssen, neben der Zahlung von Steuern und der Planung ihrer eigenen Verteidigung, entsprechend ihres Reichtums eine Anzahl voll ausgebildeter und ausgerüsteter Soldaten zur Verfügung stellen. Obwohl die Orden und die Familien die Speerspitze und die gepanzerte Faust der bannorischen Armeen bilden, besteht der Hauptteil der Soldaten, die für die Austragung einer Schlacht benötigt werden, aus Wehrpflichtigen aus dem "freien Land".[PARAGRAPH:1]Die bei weitem zahlreichsten Lehnsherren, die offenen Orden, nehmen Krieger aus der ganzen Welt auf, von allen Nationen und Rassen. Jene, die sich durch Tapferkeit und Intelligenz auszeichnen, werden in den Gebräuchen und der Sprache der Bannor unterwiesen und kämpfen in den Armeen gleichberechtigt mit gebürtigen Bannor.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Hausorden sind eigentlich Familienklans, die einen Orden gegründet oder übernommen haben. Alle Schlüsselpositionen werden von Familienmitgliedern besetzt und von Vater zu Sohn und Onkel zu Neffe vererbt, wie jeder normale Adelstitel. Dies ist eine der wenigen Möglichkeiten für eine reiche, nicht-adelige Familie, ein Lehen und die damit verbundene Macht und Verantwortung zu erhalten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die adeligen Familien führen ihre Abstammung auf eine der Seelen zurück, die Sabathiel befreite. Sie benutzen dieses heilige Vermächtnis, um ihre enorme Machtfülle zu rechtfertigen und es ist der Grund, aus dem die Priesterschaft ihr Fortbestehen und ihre Einmischung in die Staatsgeschäfte dulden. Es gibt sehr wenige Adelsfamilien, aber jede von ihnen verfügt über ebensoviel Macht und Reichtum wie ein Orden. Die Priesterschaft wacht über diese weltlichen Machtzentren allerdings mit Sorgfalt und Strenge, damit sie nicht versuchen, die Struktur der bannorischen Gesellschaft zu verändern.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die gut ausgebildeten und ausgerüsteten Männer, die in den Divisionen der Orden und Familien Dienst tun, verfügen über vielfältige Herkünfte und kämpfen aus einer Vielzahl von Gründen: Einige tun es für Geld oder Ansehen, einige wenige kämpfen für die Ehre oder aus persönlichen Rachemotiven, aber die meisten ziehen in den Kampf, weil sie wirklich daran glauben, dass sie im Krieg gegen das Böse an vorderster Front stehen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wie jeder bannorische Priester zu berichten weiß, ist der Krieg, in dem die Bannor kämpfen, deutlich komplizierter als ein simpler Konflikt zwischen Gut und Böse. Die Priesterschaft, unter der Führung von Sabathiel (wie sie selbst behaupten) entscheidet, wer ein Feind ist. Obwohl die Bannor bisher noch nie ihre Waffen gegen eine Zivilisation erhoben haben, die irgendeiner Art von Gesetz und einem Sinn für Gerechtigkeit und Mitgefühl folgt, wagt niemand, der es vermeiden kann, die Bannor zu verärgern, da man sonst "verdammt" und der Liste der Zivilisationen hinzugefügt würde, denen man Demut beibringen müsse.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Brennpunkt des gesamten Reichs der Bannor ist ihre Haupstadt, die sich rund um den Palast der Bannor, die Hallen von Sabathiel, erhebt. Obwohl auch sie das Antlitz einer Garnisonsstadt trägt, präsentiert sie sich auch als eine ausufernde, internationale Metropole, mit der sich nur wenige andere Städte auf Erebus messen können. Hier haben die Orden ihre Hauptsitze, hier treffen sich die Familien, um Staatsangelegenheiten zu diskutieren, und hierher kommen die Menschen, um die Priesterschaft um Rat zu fragen. Menschen aller Rassen strömen in die Stadt, um die Ränge der Orden anschwellen zu lasen, ein steter Strom von Besuchern füllt die Hallen von Sabathiel, die kommen, um Tribut zu zollen oder die Gunst eines Priesters zu erbitten, und die Basare und Märkte ziehen Händler von nah und fern an, die sich um die Bedürfnisse einer multi-ethnischen, multinationalen und multikulturellen Armee und Verwaltung kümmern.[PARAGRAPH:1]Da er nicht gewillt ist, einen Fuß auf Erebus zu setzen und die Vereinbarungen oder den Geist des Paktes zu brechen, heißt es, dass Sabathiel, der legendäre Herrscher der Bannor, tief in den Nischen seiner Hallen haust, beobachtend, lenkend, lehrend und über die Bannor wachend, während er sie weiter voran treibt, aber nicht in der Lage ist, sich körperlich zu manifestieren. Er ist ein Schattenkönig, immer als Schreckgespenst in ihren Gedanken präsent, aber seine Untertanen bekommen ihn nie zu Gesicht. Ihre Truppenkommandeure sind für die meisten Bannor sehr viel gegenwärtigere Gestalten, Capria ist dafür das beste Beispiel, da sie als junges Mädchen ihr Volk anführte, als dieses aus der Hölle hinaustrat, und früh während des Endes des Zeitalters des Eises und des Anbruchs des Zeitalters der Wiedergeburt an Ehre und Autorität gewann.[PARAGRAPH:1]Heutzutage gibt es viele, sogar unter den Bannor, aber vor allem unter ihren Feinden, die raunen, dass sowohl Sabathiel als auch die ursprünglichen Seelen nichts als Legenden seien, erfunden von einer aggressiven Priesterschaft, die nach Wegen suchte, um ihre Vorherrschaft zu legitimieren. Wie auch immer die Wahrheit aussehen mag, Tatsache ist, dass sich die Bannor im Zeitalter der Wiedergeburt müssen auf menschliches Fleisch und kalten Stahl verlassen müssen und nicht auf Engel und Seelen, um Recht und Gesetz bis in die dunkelsten Ecken der Welt zu tragen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]I Bannor sono una buona civiltà versatile che da il meglio di se una volta entrati in una guerra totale. La loro forma di governo Crociata gli fornisce truppe direttamente sul campo e diminuisce la stanchezza della guerra.[PARAGRAPH:1]I Bannor erano in origine una manciata di persone, intrappolati all'inferno durante la caduta di Braduk ma salvati da Sabathiel, un'angelo al servizio di Junil. In cambio della loro salvezza, quelle persone vincolarono loro e i loro discendenti al combattere senza sosta le forze del caos e del disordine. Mentre Sabathiel guidava queste persone onorevoli verso la luce, esse formarono l'avanguardia nella devastante guerra contro il Clan delle Braci, che era anche più forte di quanto sia attualmente. Durante tutta l'Era della Rinascita i Bannor intrapresero una guerra brutale e spietata non solo contro il Clan, ma anche contro chiunque non si sottometteva alla legge e all'ordine.[PARAGRAPH:1]Attraverso questa guerra di liberazione e di sterminio, questi eroi di un era antica crearono, conquistarono, si allearono e sottomesserò tribù, città e nazioni in un unico impero umano che, con l'aiuto e la guida di Sabathiel, potrebbe perfino resistere contro l'incombente apocalisse, quando il male senza limite sarà liberato su Erebus. [PARAGRAPH:1]Questa perenne Guerra Santa permea ogni parte della società, lasciandola quasi completamente militarizzata. Per i Bannor, non c'è una chiara linea di demarcazione tra religione, famiglia e politica. Applicano un temibile fervore religioso all'arte della guerra, e la loro ossessione per l'ordine rende persino i loro reggimenti di popolani tra le unità meglio addestrate di tutti gli imperi. Tutti gli uomini vengono addestrati dall'infanzia nelle arti della guerra: combattimento corpo a corpo, tiro con l'arco, auto difesa, forza e agilità. Diversamente dalla maggior parte delle altre società, ci sono molti modi per scalare i ranghi attraverso il coraggio e l'abilità, un fatto che inspira un fervore combattivo tanto quanto, se non addirittura maggiore, rispetto alla compenente religiosa.[PARAGRAPH:1]Siccome devono essere sempre difesi e pronti, i villagi periferici sono molto simili a dei forti, ogni fattoria un piccolo castello, le città sono delle enormi caserme, ma anche centri per il commercio, per la religione e la diplomazia. Pochi uomini sono senza cicatrici da battaglia e le donne sono determinate e temprate. Sanno che i figli che accudiscono potrebbero un giorno morire in battaglia, e sanno anche che un giorno la guerra potrebbe arrivare da loro. È rara la donna tra i Bannor che non sa maneggiare la spada. [PARAGRAPH:1]Il punto centrale da capire per comprendere la struttura della societa Bannor è la differenza tra le tenute e le "terre libere". Le tenute sono enormi pezzi di terra, quasi sotto regni, che sono governate da un Ordine, da una Famiglia o da un Ordine Ereditario, che è una particolarità dei Bannor, che consiste in un'Ordine religioso che recluta i suoi membri solo da uno specifico gruppo di persone, di solito un gruppo di famiglie. Con al centro una fortezza o una piccola città fortificata, la funzione principale delle tenute è di fornire le risorse necessarie per dispiegare una divisione dell'Ordine o della Famiglia, che sono unità di combattenti molto forti e altamente dedicate che formano inoltre la spina dorsale dei tanto temuti eserciti Bannor.[PARAGRAPH:1]La maggior parte delle terre nell'impero Bannor sono le "terre libere". I villaggi e le città che le occupano devono, in aggiuntà al pagare le tasse e organizzare le loro difese, fornire un numero di soldati, completamente addestrati ed equipaggiati, a seconda della loro ricchezza. Sebbene gli Ordini e le Famiglie sono la punta della lancia e il pugno corazzato degli eserciti Bannor, sono i coscritti delle "terre libere" a formare la maggior parte delle forze necessarie a portare avanti una battaglia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Gli Ordini non ereditari, di gran lunga coloro che hanno più tenute, prendono i loro guerrieri da tutto il mondo, da tutte le nazioni e da tutte le razze. Coloro giudicati degni per abilità e intelligenza vengono istruiti nelle tradizioni e nella lingua Bannor per poi venir inseriti in una unità di combattenti allo stesso modo dei Bannor nativi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Gli Ordini Ereditari sono in realtà delle famiglie che hanno fondato o preso il controllo di un Ordine. Tutte le cariche principali sono passate da padre in figlio, da zio a nipote, come i normali titoli nobiliari. È una delle poche opzioni che una famiglia ricca, ma non nobile, ha per ottenere una tenuta, con i poteri e le responsabilità che ciò comporta.[PARAGRAPH:1]Tutte le Famiglie nobili tracciano la loro discendenza da una delle persone salvate da Sabathiel. Usano questa discendenza sacra per legittimizzare il loro enorme potere, ed è inoltre questa la ragione per cui il clero tollera la loro esistenza e la loro intromissione nella gestione delle cose. Sono molto poche le Famiglie, ma ognuna di loro possiede un potere e una ricchezza pari a quella di un'Ordine. Ciononostante, il clero mantiene queste potenze secolari sotto uno attento e stretto controllo, nel timore che possano provare a cambiare la struttura della società Bannor.[PARAGRAPH:1]Gli uomini altamente addestrati e ben equipaggiati che compongono le divisioni degli Ordini e delle Famiglie possono avere origini e storie diverse cosi come possono essere diversi i motivi per cui combattono: alcuni lo fanno per i soldi o lo status, pochi altri lo fanno per la gloria o per vendetta personale, ma la maggior parte lo fa perche credono veramente di essere in prima linea nella guerra contro il Male.[PARAGRAPH:1]Come ti può dire qualsiasi prete Bannor, la guerra combattuta dai Bannor è più complicata di una semplice battaglia tra Bene e Male. Il clero, guidato da Sabathiel (o cosi loro dicono) decide chi è un nemico. Sebbene debbano ancora combattere contro una civiltà che segue una qualche forma di legge e un senso di giustizia e compassione, sono pochi coloro che potendo osano far arrabbiare i Bannor, in modo da evitare di essere "dannati" e venir aggiunti alla lista di civiltà a cui bisogna insegnare a pentirsi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il punto focale dell'intero impero Bannor è la loro capitale, al cui centro vi è il palazzo dei Bannor, le Sale di Sabathiel. Nonostante sia anch'essa una città-caserma è anche un importante metropoli cosmopolita, sono poche le altre città su Erebus che possono rivaleggiarla. Qui è dove gli Ordini hanno i loro Quartier Generale, dove le Famiglie si riuniscono per discutere degli affari di stato ed è sempre qui che la gente viene a chiedere consiglio al clero. Appartenenti di tutte le razze arrivano in città per unirsi ai ranghi degli Ordini, le Sale di Sabathiel hanno sempre un costante flusso di visitatori che passano a rendere omaggio o chiedere favori ai preti, mentre i bazar e i mercati attraggono mercanti da tutto il mondo, intenti a soddisfare i bisogni di una amministrazione e di un'esercito multiculturale, multinazionale e multirazziale.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel, il mitico sovrano dei Bannor che non vuole mettere piede su Erebus per non infrangere il Patto, si dice che risieda nella parte più interna delle sue Sale, osservando, guidando, insegnando e proteggendo i Bannor, spronandoli a continuare ma incapace di manifestarsi fisicamente. È un re invisibile, mai visto dai suoi sudditi ma sempre presente tra loro. Invece i loro comandanti sono figure molto più presenti per molti Bannor, Capria ne è il miglior esempio, colei che da ragazza guidò il suo popolo mentre uscivano dall'inferno, e che presto crebbè in onore e autorità durante la fine dell'Era del Ghiaccio e l'inizio dell'Era della Rinascita.[PARAGRAPH:1]In questi giorni ci sono coloro, persino tra i Bannor, e in particola modo tra i loro nemici, che sussurrano che sia Sabathiel chee la storia delle persone salvate dall'inferno non siano altro che delle leggende inventate da un clero militante che cercava un modo per legitimizzare il loro comandare. Qualunque sia la verità della faccenda, il fatto oggettivo è che nell'Era della Rinascita, i Bannor devono fare affidamento sugli uomini e sul freddo acciaio, non sugli angeli e spiriti, per portare la Legge negli angoli bui del mondo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Bannor are a good all-around civ who shine once embarking upon a total war. Their Crusade civic will give them troops on the field and decreased war weariness.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Bannor started with a handful of people, trapped in hell during the fall of Braduk but rescued by Sabathiel, an angel in Junil's service. In exchange for their salvation, the spirits bound themselves and their descendants to ceaselessly battle the forces of chaos and disorder. As Sabathiel led the honorable spirits forth into the light, they formed the vanguard in a devastating war against the Clan of Embers, even more powerful then than they are today. Throughout the entire Age of Rebirth the Bannor waged brutal and merciless war not only on the Clan, but on all who would not submit to law and order.[PARAGRAPH:1]Throughout this war of liberation and extermination, these heroes of an ancient age forged conquered, allied, and submitting tribes, cities, and nations into a human empire which, with the aid and guidance of Sabathiel, may stand firm even against the looming apocalypse, when unequaled evil is loosed upon Erebus. [PARAGRAPH:1]This continuing Holy War permeates every part of their society, leaving it almost totally militarized. For the Bannor, there is no clear line between religion, family, and politics. They apply a frightening religious fervor to the art of war, and their obsession with order makes even the peasant regiments among the best drilled of all the empires. All men are trained from childhood in the arts of war-hand-to-hand combat, archery, self defense, strength, and agility. Unlike most other societies, there are plenty of possibilities for rising through the ranks through bravery and skill, a fact which inspires as much if not more fighting fervor than the religious element.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because they need to be defended and ready at all times, outlying villages are more like forts, every farm is a small castle, the cities are huge garrison towns but also centers of trade, religion, and diplomacy. Few men are without scars from battle and the women are strong-willed and hardened. They know that the children they raise may one day be lost in battle, and they also know that one day the war may come to them. It is a rare woman among the Bannor that cannot handle a sword. [PARAGRAPH:1]A central part of understanding the fabric of Bannor society is understanding the split between estates and "free land." The estates are enormous tracts of land, almost sub-kingdoms, under the rule of an Order, a Family or one of those peculiarities of the Bannor: a Hereditary Order-a religious order with members exclusively from one clan. Centered on a stronghold or small fortified city, the main function of the estates is to provide the necessary resources to field one Order or Family division, the powerful and highly dedicated fighting forces that make up the feared backbone of the Bannor armies.[PARAGRAPH:1]The lion's share of the land in the Bannor empire is the "free land." The villages and cities that occupy and make a living off this land must, in addition to paying taxes and organizing their own defenses, provide a number of soldiers, fully trained and equipped, according to the wealth of the settlement. Although the Orders and Families are the spearhead and armored fist of Bannor armies, "free land" conscripts provide the bulk forces that are needed to carry a battle.[PARAGRAPH:1]By far the most numerous of the estate-holders, the non-hereditary Orders will take fighters from all across the world, all nations and races. Those deemed worthy in prowess and intelligence are taught in the ways and language of the Bannor and then join the fighting forces on the same footing as native Bannor.[PARAGRAPH:1]The hereditary Orders are in reality families that have founded or taken over control of an Order. All the major positions are held by and passed down from father to son, uncle to nephew, like any usual aristocratic title. It is one of the few options a rich non-noble family has of gaining an estate and the power and responsibility that comes with it.[PARAGRAPH:1]The noble Families all trace their lineage back to one of the spirits that Sabathiel set free. They use this holy heritage to legitimize their enormous power, and it is the reason the priesthood tolerates their existence and their meddling in the running of things. There are very few Families, but every one of them wields as much power and wealth as an Order. However, the priesthood keeps these secular powerhouses under careful and strict control, lest they attempt to change the fabric of Bannor society.[PARAGRAPH:1]The highly-trained and well-equipped men who fight in the professional divisions of the Orders and Families come from a variety of backgrounds and fight for any number of reasons: Some do it for money or status, some few do it for glory or personal revenge, but most do it because they truly believe they are on the front line of the war against Evil.[PARAGRAPH:1]As any Bannor priest could tell you, the war fought by the Bannor is far more complicated than a simple Good-Evil battle. The priesthood, under the guidance of Sabathiel (or so they claim) decide who is an enemy. Although they have yet to fight a civilization that conforms to some kind of law and sense of justice and compassion, few who can avoid it dare cross the Bannor, lest they be "damned" and added to the list of civilizations that must be taught to repent.[PARAGRAPH:1]The focal point of the entire Bannor Empire is their capital, centered around the Bannor Palace, The Halls of Sabathiel. Although still recognizably a garrison city, it is also a sprawling, international metropolis matched by few other cities in Erebus. This is where the Orders have their headquarters, this is where the Families meet to discuss affairs of state, and this is where people come to consult with the priesthood. People of all races flock to the city to swell the ranks of the Orders, the Halls of Sabathiel have a constant stream of visitors coming to pay tribute or ask favors of his priests, and the bazaars and markets attract traders from far and wide, catering to the needs of a multiracial, multinational and multicultural army and administration.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel, the mythical ruler of the Bannor, unwilling to set foot upon Erebus and break the letter or the spirit of the Compact, is said to reside deep within the recesses of his Halls, watching, guiding, teaching, and warding over the Bannor, urging them on but unable to physically manifest. He is a shadow king, never seen by his subjects but always a haunting figure, ever present in their consciousness. Their battlefield commanders are much more present figures to most Bannormen, Capria being the best example, who as a young girl led her people as they stepped from hell, and soon grew in honor and authority through the end of the Age of Ice and dawn of the Age of Rebirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]In this day, there are those even among the Bannor, and even more so among their enemies, who whisper that both Sabathiel and his original spirits are naught but legends invented by a militant priesthood looking for ways to legitimize their rule. Whatever the truth of the matter, the fact is that in the Age of Rebirth, the Bannor must rely on human flesh and cold steel, not angels and spirits, to bring Law to the dark corners of the world.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BANNOR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategy: The Bannor are a pretty generalist, law-oriented civilization. When led by Sabathiel (Organized/Spiritual), they are well-suited for warfare, while Capria (Industrial/Imperialist) lends well for a more peaceful playing style. Of the two extremes, however, they're a bit more suited towards warfare-guardsmen promotion on melee units helps keep support units alive, and their unique Crusade civic brings frequent recruits from towns and allows unique flagbearer support units. Think twice before turning a standard war into a crusade, however, for once begun the Bannor player cannot initiate diplomacy with any of their foes. Their hero makes them especially well suited towards warring with demon- or undead-using civilizations.[NEWLINE] Most Bannor troops also take part in the Chain of Command. They can gain military ranks, which allow them to command units from lower ranks. Animals and Rogue units are not part of the regular army, and thus, not in the Chain of Command.</English>
		<French>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Stratégie : Les Bannors sont plutôt une civilisation généraliste et orientée vers la loi. Lorsqu'ils sont menés par Sabathiel (Organisé/Résistant à la Magie), ils sont bien équipés pour la guerre, tandis que Capria (Industriel/Spirituel) convient bien pour une style de jeu plus pacifique. Entre ces deux extrêmes, ils sont plutôt adaptés pour la guerre, les Porte-Ecu aidant à conserver en vie les piles d'invasion, et leur doctrine unique Croisade rend amusant, et bien, la croisade. Leur héro les rend spécialement adapté à lutter contre les civilisations usant de démons et de morts-vivants.</French>
		<German>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategie: Die Bannor sind eine ziemlich ausgewogene, gesetzsorientierte Zivilisation. Wenn sie von Sabathiel geführt werden (Organisiert/Magieresistent), sind sie gut ausgerüstet für Kriege, während sich Capria (Industriell/Spirituell) mehr für einen friedlicheren Spielstil eignet. Von beiden Extremen tendieren sie jedoch eher zur Kriegsführung - Schildknappen helfen ihnen, Einheitenstapel am Leben zu halten, und ihre einzigartige Kreuzzug-Gesellschaftsform, macht es lustiger, nun, Kreuzzüge zu führen. Ihr Held macht sie besonders tauglich für Kriege gegen Zivilisationen, die besonders Dämonen oder Untote benützen.</German>
		<Italian>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategia: I Bannor sono una civiltà abbastanza generalista, ma con una predisposizione verso la legalità. Quando sono guidati da Sabathiel (Organizzato/Carismatico), sono molto adatti alla guerra, mentre con Capria (Industrioso/Spirituale) tendono verso uno stile di gioco più pacifico. Tra i due estremi però, quello che più gli si addice è quello della guerra, la promozione Guardia sulle unità da combattimento ravvicinato aiuta a tenere in vita le unità da supporto, e Crociata, la loro forma di governo unica, attirerà nuove reclute dai paesi e permette di creare un'unità da supporto unica, il Portabandiera. Però pensaci bene prima di trasformare una normale guerra in una crociata, perché una volta iniziata il giocatore Bannor non potrà accedere alla diplomazia con i suoi nemici. Il loro eroe li rende anche particolarmente adatti ad affrontare civilità che fanno uso di demoni o non-morti.[NEWLINE] Most Bannor troops also take part in the Chain of Command. They can gain military ranks, which allow them to command units from lower ranks. Animals and Rogue units are not part of the regular army, and thus, not in the Chain of Command.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Estrategia: Bannor es una civilización bastante generalista y orientada a la ley. Cuando es dirigida por Sabathiel (Organizado/Resistente a la Magia), están muy bien preparados para la guerra, mientras que Capria (Industrial/Espiritual) los dirige más para un estilo pacífico de juego. A pesar de los extremos, están preparados más bien para la guerra - los portaescudos ayudan a manenter viva las pilas de unidades, y su doctrina única, Cruzada, los hace más adecuados para, bueno, cruzadas. Su héroe los hace especialmente útiles para la luchar contra civilizaciones de demonios o no-muertos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ANGAAD</Tag>
		<English>Angaad</English>
		<French>Angaad</French>
		<German>Angaad</German>
		<Italian>Angaad</Italian>
		<Spanish>Angaad</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ANGAAD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Angaad stood stock-still while her attendants fussed with pins in her headdress. Her hands were clenched into fists at her sides, and her brow was smashed into a grimace.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Is something wrong, my lady?" asked Brennen innocently. She glowered at him, and his blank faced cracked. He grinned, then suddenly looked serious again. "Consider, my lady - we need the full support of Tethira and her allies in supplying troops for the spring campaign. You know it's worth your time, or you wouldn't be here for the ceremony."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad sighed and unclasped her hands. "Yes, my love. You are right, as always. I just feel like such a fool in . . . this." She waved a hand at her reflection mirror in front of her; she was wearing the ceremonial 'armor' crafted for her at great expense by artisans of the Order. It was impressive, but it left rather more of her flesh exposed than she liked. Brennen grinned again. "You look rather fetching. It's certainly more flattering than your usual attire: mud, sweat, blood, and steel."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Matriarch of the Bannor cocked a rebuking eyebrow at her consort. "Are you suggesting that I tart my way into Tethira's good graces?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Not hers, but perhaps her brother's," replied Brennen with a smirk.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Raise your arms, my lady," murmured one of her attendants. Angaad did so, looking thoughtfully into the distance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Therein lies the problem, Brennen," she mused, as the ladies-in-waiting fastened a silver chain around her midsection. "I want to wear mud, blood, sweat, and steel. I only endure these ridiculous frills so that I can go back through that Gate and lead our people to victory at Galveholme."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No-one would deny that the Galveholme campaign is your rightful place, my lady, as was the Dark Pass campaign two years ago. All know that you were born to lead us in these wars, and that the wars are just," said Brennen.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad smiled, despite herself. Brennen's love for her was exceeded only by his faith in her skills as a leader. "And what will happen when Galveholme falls? What will happen when the threat of Sheaim is finally expunged?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Then we will have peace, my lady. Peace to work the fields and live in quiet, as we were intended to. Peace to raise children - our children - without the horror of death always hanging over them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad looked down at her hands. Scars crisscrossed her knuckles. A long, ragged brown mark ran almost the length of her left forearm - a memento given her by a Sheaim assassin who had nearly succeeded in his attempt. Her hands and arms were hard and well-defined, and her left bicep, strengthened through years of wielding a shield, flexed and strained against her decorative armlet. She let out a long, slow breath. "And in peace, Brennen, what becomes of the one who was born for war?"</English>
		<French>Angaad resta figée tandis que sa camérière lui glissait des épingles dans la coiffure. Ses poings étaient serrés, et son front était plissé.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Quelque chose ne va pas, ma Dame?" demanda innocemment Brennen. Elle lui lança un regard noir, et son expression vide s'effaça. Il sourit, puis repris soudain son sérieux. "Réfléchissez ma Dame - nous avons besoin de l'appui inconditionnel de Tethira et de ses aliiés pour le ravitaillement des troupes pour la campagne de printemps. Vous savez que cela  vaut le coup, sinon vous n seriez pas là  pour la cérémonie."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad soupira et desserra les poings. "Oui mon Amour, vous avez raison, comme toujours. J'ai juste l'impression d'être une idiote dans .... tout ça." Elle porta la main au miroir devant elle; elle portait l'"armure" cérémonielle forgée pour elle à  grands frais par les artisans de l'Ordre. Elle était impressionnante, mais il restait toujours trop de chair exposée à  son goût. Brennen sourit à  nouveau. "Vous êtes ravissante. C'est bien plus flatteur que votre accoutrement habituel: boue, sueur, sang et acier."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]La Matriarche des Bannor dressa un sourcil de reproche à  son conjoint. "Suggérez-vous que je perds mon temps à  gagner les bonnes gràces de Tethira?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Pas les siennes mais peut-être celles de son frère", répondit Brennen avec un petit sourire satisfait.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Levez les bras, ma Dame", murmura une de ses camérières. Ce qui fit Angaad, regardant pensivement dans le lointain.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Là  réside le problème, Brennen", songea-t-elle, alors que les dames d'honneur attachaient une chaine d'argent autour de son abdomen. "Je veux porter la boue, le sang, la sueur et l'acier. Je ne supporte ces fioritures ridicules que pour pouvoir repasser cette Porte et conduire notre peuple à  la victoire à  Galveholme."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Personne ne met en doute le fait que la campagne de Galveholme est votre juste place, ma Dame, de même que la campagne du Passage Sombre deux ans plus tôt. Tous savent que vous êtes née pour nous commander dans ces guerres, et que ces guerres sont justes", dit Brennen.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad sourit malgré elle. L'amour de Brennen pour elle n'était surpassé que par sa confiance dans ses compétences de dirigeant. "Et que se passera-t-il quand Galveholm tombera? Que se passera-t-il quand la menace de Sheaim sera finalement éradiquée?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Alors nous serons en paix, ma Dame. La paix permettant de travailler les champs et vivre en sécurité, comme nous le souhaitions. La paix permettant d'élever des enfants - nos enfants - sans les horreurs de la mort rà´dant continuellement tout autour d'eux."Angaad baissa les yeux vers ses mains. Les cicatrices s'entrecroisaient sur ses poings. Une longue marque irrégulière et marron courait sur presque tout son avant bras gauche - un souvenir de l'assassin Sheaim que avait presque réussi sa mission. Ses mains et bras étaient forts et bien dessinés, et son biceps gauche renforcé pour toutes ces années à  porter un bouclier, bien fixé sur son brassard décoratif. Elle laissa échapper une longue et lente expiration. "Et en temps de paix, que devient celle qui était née pour la guerre?"</French>
		<German>Angaad stand unter Schock und einfach nur da, während ihre Gehilfen mit Nadeln an ihrer Kopfbedeckung herumfingerten. Ihre Hände an ihren verkrampft am Körper klebenden Armen waren zu Fäusten geballt. Ihre Stirn war zu einer angewiderten Grimasse verzogen. "Stimmt etwas nicht, Herrin?", fragte Brennen unschuldig. Sie warf ihm einen finsteren Blick zu. Der leere Ausdruck von seinem Blick verschwand. Er grinste und setzte schnell wieder einen ernsten Gesichtsausdruck auf. "Bedenkt, meine Herrin Â wir benötigen die Tethiras volle Unterstützung und die ihrer Verbündeten, um unsere Truppen für das Vorhaben im Frühling vorzubereiten. Ihr wisst, dass es Eure Zeit wert ist, sonst wäret Ihr gar nicht erst zu dieser Zeremonie erschienen." Angaad seufzte und lockerte ihre Hände. "Ja, mein Lieber. Ihr habt ja recht, wie üblich. Ich fühle mich nur wie eine Närrin in Â diesem Zeug hier." Sie deutete mit einer Hand auf ihr Ebenbild im Spiegel vor ihr; sie trug die Prunkrüstung, die für viel Geld von den "Kunsthandwerkern der Ordnung" gefertigt worden war. Brennen lächelte erneut. "Ihr seht bezaubernd aus. Auf jeden Fall ist es wesentlich schmeichelhafter als Euer üblicher Schmuck: Schlamm, Schweiß, Blut und Stahl." Die Matriarchin der Bannor hob eine Augenbraue, um ihren Begleiter zu tadeln. "Schlagt Ihr etwa vor, dass ich Tethiras Wohlwollen mit weiblichen Reizen gewinne?" "Vielleicht nicht ihres, aber möglicherweise das ihres Bruders.", feixte Brennen. "Hebt bitte die Arme, Herrin", murmelte einer ihrer Gehilfen. Angaad folgte der Aufforderung und blickte gedankenverloren in die Ferne.[NEWLINE]"Darin liegt das Problem, Brennen." sinnierte sie, während ihr die Zofen eine silberne Kette um die Taille legten. "Ich mag es, Schlamm, Blut, Schweiß und Stahl zu tragen. Ich ertrage diese lächerlichen Rüschen hier nur, damit ich zurück an das Tor gehen kann und unsere Leute zum Sieg bei Galveholme führen kann."[NEWLINE]"Niemand streitet ab, dass die Galveholme der richtige Platz für Euch ist, meine Herrin, ebenso wie der Feldzug am Schwarzpass vor zwei Jahren. All wissen, dass Ihr geboren wurdet, um uns in diesen Kriegen zu führen, und dass diese Kriege gerechtfertigt sind.", sagte Brennen. Angaad lächelte gegen ihren Willen. Brennens Zuneigung zu ihr wurde nur von seinen Fähigkeiten der Menschenführung übertroffen. "Und was wird passieren, wenn Galveholme fallen wird? Was wird werden, wenn die Bedrohung durch die Sheaim endgültig und für immer beseitigt sein wird?"[NEWLINE]"Dann werden wir Frieden haben, meine Herring. Frieden, um auf den Feldern zu arbeiten und uns der Ruhe zu erfreuen, wie wir es eigentlich tun sollten. Frieden, um Kinder Â unsere Kinder Â aufziehen zu können, ohne den Schrecken des Todes über uns."[NEWLINE]Angaad blickte auf ihre Hände hinab. Narben überzogen ihre Fingerknöchel. Eine, lange verblichene braune Narbe zog nahezu über die gesamte ihres Unterarms Â eine Erinnerung an den Meuchelmörder der Sheaim, der sein Vorhaben beinahe zu einem erfolgreichen Abschluss gebracht hätte. Ihre Hände und Arme waren hart und gut gefiniert, und ihr linker Bizeps, durch jahrelanges Tragen eines Schildes gestählt, spannte sich unter ihrem dekorativen Armschützer an. Sie atmete langsam und bedächtig aus. "Und im Frieden, Brennen, was wird wohl aus jemandem werden, der für den Krieg geboren wurde?"</German>
		<Italian>Angaad rimase immobile mentre le sue servitrici armeggiavano con il suo corpicapo. Aveva le mani strette a pugno sui fianchi, e la fronte corrugata.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Qualcosa non va, mia signora?" chiese Brennen in maniera innocente. Lei lo guardò torvo. Lui sorrise leggermente, per poi tornare subito serio. "Ricordate, mia signora - abbiamo bisogno del pieno supporto di Tethira e dei suoi alleati per poter rifornire le truppe per la campagna primaverile. Sapete che ciò vale il vostro tempo, altrimenti non sareste qui per la cerimonia".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad sospirò e rilassò le mani. "Si, amore mio. Hai ragione, come sempre. E solo che mi sembra di essere una stupida dentro . . . questo". Disse indicando con la mano il suo riflesso nello specchio che aveva davanti; stava indossando l'armatura cerimoniale, dal costo elevato, forgiata apposta per lei dagli artigiani dell'Ordine. Era stupefacente, ma lasciava più pelle scoperta di quanto gli piacesse. Brennen sorrise di nuovo. "Sei parecchio attraente. Di sicuro più di quando indossi il tuo abbigliamento abituale: fango, sudore, sangue e acciaio".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]La Matriarca dei Bannor alzò un sopraciglio come a rimproverare il suo consorte. "Stai suggerendo che io mi faccia strada dentro le grazie di Tethira?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Non le sue, ma magari quelle di suo fratello" rispose Brennen con un ghigno.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Alzate le braccia, mia signora" mormoro una delle sue servitrici. Angaad lo fece, con lo sguardo perso nel vuoto mentre rifletteva.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Qui sta il problema, Brennen" riflettè, mentre le dame di compagnia fissavano una catena d'argento attorno alla sua vita. "Io voglio indossare fango, sangue, sudore e acciaio. Sopporto questi ridicoli fronzoli solamente perché cosi posso tornare a quel Cancello e guidare la nostra gente alla vittoria a Galveholm".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Nessuno nega che la campagna per Galveholm sia il posto più adatto a te, mia signora, come lo era la campagna per il Passo Oscuro due anni fa. Tutti sanno che voi siete nata per guidarci in queste guerre, e che queste guerre sono giuste" disse Brennen.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad sorrise, suo malgrado. L'amore di Brennen per lei era superato solo dalla sua fede nelle sue capacità da leader. "E cosa succederà quando Galveholm cadrà? Cosa accadrà quando la minaccia degli Sheaim sarà finalmente eliminata?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Avremo la pace, mia signora. La pace per lavorare i campi e vivere tranquilli, come tutti vorremmo. La pace per far crescere i bambini - i nostri bambini - senza l'orrore della morte che aleggia sempre su di loro".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad guardò le sue mani. Delle cicatrici si incrociavano sulle sue nocche. Una era lunga quasi quanto il suo avambraccio sinistro - un ricordo lasciatogli da un'assassino Sheaim che era quasi riuscito nel suo intento. Le sue mani, cosi come le sue braccia, erano ben definite, e il suo bicipite sinistro, sviluppato attraverso anni di uso di uno scudo, riempiva completamente il bracciale decorativo. Espirò lentamente e a lungo. "E con la pace, Brennen, cosa succederà a coloro che sono nati per la guerra?"</Italian>
		<Spanish>Angaad stood stock-still while her attendants fussed with pins in her headdress. Her hands were clenched into fists at her sides, and her brow was smashed into a grimace.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Is something wrong, my lady?" asked Brennen innocently. She glowered at him, and his blank faced cracked. He grinned, then suddenly looked serious again. "Consider, my lady - we need the full support of Tethira and her allies in supplying troops for the spring campaign. You know it's worth your time, or you wouldn't be here for the ceremony."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad sighed and unclasped her hands. "Yes, my love. You are right, as always. I just feel like such a fool in . . . this." She waved a hand at her reflection mirror in front of her; she was wearing the ceremonial 'armor' crafted for her at great expense by artisans of the Order. It was impressive, but it left rather more of her flesh exposed than she liked. Brennen grinned again. "You look rather fetching. It's certainly more flattering than your usual attire: mud, sweat, blood, and steel."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Matriarch of the Bannor cocked a rebuking eyebrow at her consort. "Are you suggesting that I tart my way into Tethira's good graces?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Not hers, but perhaps her brother's," replied Brennen with a smirk.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Raise your arms, my lady," murmured one of her attendants. Angaad did so, looking thoughtfully into the distance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Therein lies the problem, Brennen," she mused, as the ladies-in-waiting fastened a silver chain around her midsection. "I want to wear mud, blood, sweat, and steel. I only endure these ridiculous frills so that I can go back through that Gate and lead our people to victory at Galveholme."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No-one would deny that the Galveholme campaign is your rightful place, my lady, as was the Dark Pass campaign two years ago. All know that you were born to lead us in these wars, and that the wars are just," said Brennen.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad smiled, despite herself. Brennen's love for her was exceeded only by his faith in her skills as a leader. "And what will happen when Galveholme falls? What will happen when the threat of Sheaim is finally expunged?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Then we will have peace, my lady. Peace to work the fields and live in quiet, as we were intended to. Peace to raise children - our children - without the horror of death always hanging over them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angaad looked down at her hands. Scars crisscrossed her knuckles. A long, ragged brown mark ran almost the length of her left forearm - a memento given her by a Sheaim assassin who had nearly succeeded in his attempt. Her hands and arms were hard and well-defined, and her left bicep, strengthened through years of wielding a shield, flexed and strained against her decorative armlet. She let out a long, slow breath. "And in peace, Brennen, what becomes of the one who was born for war?"</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CAPRIA</Tag>
		<English>Capria</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Capria</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Capria</German>
		<Italian>Capria</Italian>
		<Spanish>Capria</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CAPRIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Capria held Sabra close as they waited near the portal. Her sister was quivering, whether from fear or excitement she didn't know. Either way, her father had told her to keep her calm. So she did.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kneeling down to eye level, she said, "Remember what we talked about, Sabra? We're going home, so today you need to be extra brave. What's home going to be like?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabra smiled. "No monsters!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"That's right! What else?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"The fire is just in the sky, and not all around. I can go play in the grass and run and not fall in the pits or the lava or be eaten by the shadows!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"That's right, little one," Capria said, hoping the stories that they told the young ones were true. She herself took the elders at their word what the outside world was like. But even memories of home were exaggerated, it could not be worse than living here.[PARAGRAPH:1]The booming voice of Sabathiel rang out as if to prove it to her. "Soldiers to arms! We are being followed!" The men rushed to the rear of their company, leaving their wives and children to await entry to the new world. Capria picked up her sister, bouncing her in her arms. "People of Braduk! Prepare to return!" Sabathiel cried out, then unfurled his wings. Capria shielded her eyes as the brilliant light flashed out from the angel, then subsided. Sabathiel stood facing them, a gateway of light behind him turning the back of the canyon into their route home. "Hurry! Your men cannot hold out forever!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The families approached the gateway, but hesitated before entering. Capria gritted her teeth, and pushed to the front. "Come, brothers, sisters! This is what we have been living for!" Without another look back, she stepped into the light...[PARAGRAPH:2]...and out of the fire. The heat at her back was the first thing she noticed, nearly searing her skin through the heavy leather armor she wore as a Secondline-woman. The darkness alarmed her; instead of a perpetual red haze, there was blackness above her, pierced by countless points of light. She turned to see more of her people emerging from the flames, and reacting as she had, hurrying ahead in surprise. Then she turned back and noticed the screams.[PARAGRAPH:1]"They're free! Ahhhhhhhhhhh!" An old woman, green skinned and heavily marked was writhing on the ground a few yards in front her. Other green skinned people watched the strangers coming out of their Sacred Fire with shock.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What have they done to our city?" asked an elderly woman emerging from the flames.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Well, what gifts have been given to us by dear ol' Bhall tonight?" The deep voice came from an orc man who pushed past the crowd of orc children eating and playing by the flames near the humans. Unlike the smooth skinned younger orcs, long bone spikes protruded from his back, shoulders, and arms. "Metal blades on young girls? Take your spears, my clan." The burly orc hefted a massive axe and grinned at Capria. Others came forth, wielding long wooden spears.[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria bent down to set her sister on the ground, then in a blink had an orc child in her arms and a dagger at its throat. "We don't know who you are monster, but we mean you no harm. Let us walk out of here and your child lives."[PARAGRAPH:1]"A trade, girl? One life of ours for all of yours?" Orthus pulled a sharpened bone knife from his belt. "That doesn't sound like a good trade." Orthus' arm swung out, and the knife came flying towards Capria. She blinked, and before her eyes opened she could feel warm blood splash on her face. But not hers. The orc child went limp in her arms before it could scream.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You value life, human. Death is the currency I trade in." Orthus hefted his axe and started towards the humans.[PARAGRAPH:2]Blood splattered on Donal's face, and by the burning, he knew it belonged to the demon. He gritted his teeth and ducked under a leaping Hellhound, thrusting upward with his short sword. Its snarl turned to a yelp, but it still managed to kick his helmet off as it tumbled gracelessly to the ground. Donal raised his shield to fend off a fireball hurled by a towering fire elemental, shouting over his shoulder, "Are we about done here, my lord? I do think they are sorry to see us leaving."[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel grunted. "Another... another few minutes, my friends, and the elders shall have left this accursed place. I trust you can hold out?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"We will do what we must!" said Alessi. Donal's burly comrade swung his halberd in a wide arc, knocking a Gaersteed to its knees and unseating its rider. The Death Knight continued his charge, however, and pierced Alessi's left shoulder with a long ebon blade. The warrior dropped his pole-arm and staggered, perfectly exposed for the coup d'grace. Donal spun towards them, slicing down on the Demon Knight's arm and turning a lethal blow into merely an ugly gut wound.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Demon snarled, and knocked him to the ground with a quick shield bash. It advanced on Donal until an arrow flew into its chest. Then another hit, and a third, and fourth, until finally he fell.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Pull back and regroup!" said the marksman, before being set upon by a swarm of harpies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal sheathed his sword and helped his friend to his feet. "You're not dying before you see daylight, Alessi, I swear it." The pair stumbled back towards the portal, as their peers closed ranks behind them.[PARAGRAPH:2]Capria stumbled as she tried to back away from the advancing orcs. Her hand found a long spear, blackened with bits of burnt swine clinging to it. She lunged and thrust it into the throat of an advancing orc, who fell with a whimper, snapping her weapon in two as he fell. "C'mon, friends, we've all faced worse than this before!" She unsheathed her short sword. "Ring formation, boys and women to arms. Children and elderly in the center! We'll work our way towards the gate. Slay the beasts if they come, but hold your position!" An orc charged her, spear first. She prepared to dodge, but he dropped to the ground before he reached her, felled by a slung stone.[PARAGRAPH:1]The group began to move towards the gate of the palisade, past hovels. Behind them a wounded man staggered out of the flames, clutching his chest. A pair of goblins leapt upon him, stabbing repeatedly. He managed to grasp a handful of grass before breathing his last.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You will never escape me, humans," Orthus cried. Swinging viciously, he bowled into their formation, breaking the ranks and cleaving a young girl just below the ribs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria barely noticed the death of her best friend. She did see her sister dangling from the Orc King's hand. She dropped and rolled under the spikes, coming up directly in front of Orthus, too close for him to wield his Axe. Behind her the humans closed ranks.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Be glad I'm sick of death," Capria growled, plunging her sword into Orthus' gut up to the hilt. She didn't stay to finish him, but slung her sister over her shoulder and turned away. The worst of the orcs had been stopped already, and the freedom was in sight.[PARAGRAPH:2]"You're the last, Donal," said Sabathiel. The other soldiers had charged through the portal during the last lull in the melee. The ones who had survived the onslaught, at least.[PARAGRAPH:1]"And then you'll follow, my lord?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Someone must remain on this pedestal to keep the portal open. I will stay behind."[PARAGRAPH:1]"No you won't. My people need you, you must go through!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I cannot lead them in the next world as I did in this Infernal hell, Donal."[PARAGRAPH:1]"It's not a leader they need, there's wisdom and strength in even the young girls, like brave Capria. They need a symbol, to stay united in the real world, my lord. You must go through. I will hold open the doorway for you."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I cannot leave anyone behind, Donal!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal Lugh stood beside the angel, feeling an enormous weight descend upon him. "There's got to be another way out of here, Sabathiel. I'll find it, somewhere, and I'll make it back, if I have to kill every demon in Hell to do it." A moaning sound drew their attention to the corpses of their friends, beginning to rise as an imp on the cliff above them giggled and danced in a circle. Sabathiel and Donal exchanged one last glance, then the angel embraced the man, and turned and flew through the portal. The instant Donal stepped towards it in vain hope that the angel was wrong, but it vanished, and he sighed. Then he turned back towards the shambling corpses.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Alrighty, my friends, who's first?"</English>
		<French>[TAB]Capria held Sabra close as they waited near the portal. Her sister was quivering, whether from fear or excitement she didn't know. Either way, her father had told her to keep her calm. So she did.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kneeling down to eye level, she said, "Remember what we talked about, Sabra? We're going home, so today you need to be extra brave. What's home going to be like?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabra smiled. "No monsters!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"That's right! What else?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"The fire is just in the sky, and not all around. I can go play in the grass and run and not fall in the pits or the lava or be eaten by the shadows!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"That's right, little one," Capria said, hoping the stories that they told the young ones were true. She herself took the elders at their word what the outside world was like. But even memories of home were exaggerated, it could not be worse than living here.[PARAGRAPH:1]The booming voice of Sabathiel rang out as if to prove it to her. "Soldiers to arms! We are being followed!" The men rushed to the rear of their company, leaving their wives and children to await entry to the new world. Capria picked up her sister, bouncing her in her arms. "People of Braduk! Prepare to return!" Sabathiel cried out, then unfurled his wings. Capria shielded her eyes as the brilliant light flashed out from the angel, then subsided. Sabathiel stood facing them, a gateway of light behind him turning the back of the canyon into their route home. "Hurry! Your men cannot hold out forever!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The families approached the gateway, but hesitated before entering. Capria gritted her teeth, and pushed to the front. "Come, brothers, sisters! This is what we have been living for!" Without another look back, she stepped into the light...[PARAGRAPH:2]...and out of the fire. The heat at her back was the first thing she noticed, nearly searing her skin through the heavy leather armor she wore as a Secondline-woman. The darkness alarmed her; instead of a perpetual red haze, there was blackness above her, pierced by countless points of light. She turned to see more of her people emerging from the flames, and reacting as she had, hurrying ahead in surprise. Then she turned back and noticed the screams.[PARAGRAPH:1]"They're free! Ahhhhhhhhhhh!" An old woman, green skinned and heavily marked was writhing on the ground a few yards in front her. Other green skinned people watched the strangers coming out of their Sacred Fire with shock.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What have they done to our city?" asked an elderly woman emerging from the flames.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Well, what gifts have been given to us by dear ol' Bhall tonight?" The deep voice came from an orc man who pushed past the crowd of orc children eating and playing by the flames near the humans. Unlike the smooth skinned younger orcs, long bone spikes protruded from his back, shoulders, and arms. "Metal blades on young girls? Take your spears, my clan." The burly orc hefted a massive axe and grinned at Capria. Others came forth, wielding long wooden spears.[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria bent down to set her sister on the ground, then in a blink had an orc child in her arms and a dagger at its throat. "We don't know who you are monster, but we mean you no harm. Let us walk out of here and your child lives."[PARAGRAPH:1]"A trade, girl? One life of ours for all of yours?" Orthus pulled a sharpened bone knife from his belt. "That doesn't sound like a good trade." Orthus' arm swung out, and the knife came flying towards Capria. She blinked, and before her eyes opened she could feel warm blood splash on her face. But not hers. The orc child went limp in her arms before it could scream.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You value life, human. Death is the currency I trade in." Orthus hefted his axe and started towards the humans.[PARAGRAPH:2]Blood splattered on Donal's face, and by the burning, he knew it belonged to the demon. He gritted his teeth and ducked under a leaping Hellhound, thrusting upward with his short sword. Its snarl turned to a yelp, but it still managed to kick his helmet off as it tumbled gracelessly to the ground. Donal raised his shield to fend off a fireball hurled by a towering fire elemental, shouting over his shoulder, "Are we about done here, my lord? I do think they are sorry to see us leaving."[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel grunted. "Another... another few minutes, my friends, and the elders shall have left this accursed place. I trust you can hold out?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"We will do what we must!" said Alessi. Donal's burly comrade swung his halberd in a wide arc, knocking a Gaersteed to its knees and unseating its rider. The Death Knight continued his charge, however, and pierced Alessi's left shoulder with a long ebon blade. The warrior dropped his pole-arm and staggered, perfectly exposed for the coup d'grace. Donal spun towards them, slicing down on the Demon Knight's arm and turning a lethal blow into merely an ugly gut wound.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Demon snarled, and knocked him to the ground with a quick shield bash. It advanced on Donal until an arrow flew into its chest. Then another hit, and a third, and fourth, until finally he fell.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Pull back and regroup!" said the marksman, before being set upon by a swarm of harpies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal sheathed his sword and helped his friend to his feet. "You're not dying before you see daylight, Alessi, I swear it." The pair stumbled back towards the portal, as their peers closed ranks behind them.[PARAGRAPH:2]Capria stumbled as she tried to back away from the advancing orcs. Her hand found a long spear, blackened with bits of burnt swine clinging to it. She lunged and thrust it into the throat of an advancing orc, who fell with a whimper, snapping her weapon in two as he fell. "C'mon, friends, we've all faced worse than this before!" She unsheathed her short sword. "Ring formation, boys and women to arms. Children and elderly in the center! We'll work our way towards the gate. Slay the beasts if they come, but hold your position!" An orc charged her, spear first. She prepared to dodge, but he dropped to the ground before he reached her, felled by a slung stone.[PARAGRAPH:1]The group began to move towards the gate of the palisade, past hovels. Behind them a wounded man staggered out of the flames, clutching his chest. A pair of goblins leapt upon him, stabbing repeatedly. He managed to grasp a handful of grass before breathing his last.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You will never escape me, humans," Orthus cried. Swinging viciously, he bowled into their formation, breaking the ranks and cleaving a young girl just below the ribs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria barely noticed the death of her best friend. She did see her sister dangling from the Orc King's hand. She dropped and rolled under the spikes, coming up directly in front of Orthus, too close for him to wield his Axe. Behind her the humans closed ranks.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Be glad I'm sick of death," Capria growled, plunging her sword into Orthus' gut up to the hilt. She didn't stay to finish him, but slung her sister over her shoulder and turned away. The worst of the orcs had been stopped already, and the freedom was in sight.[PARAGRAPH:2]"You're the last, Donal," said Sabathiel. The other soldiers had charged through the portal during the last lull in the melee. The ones who had survived the onslaught, at least.[PARAGRAPH:1]"And then you'll follow, my lord?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Someone must remain on this pedestal to keep the portal open. I will stay behind."[PARAGRAPH:1]"No you won't. My people need you, you must go through!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I cannot lead them in the next world as I did in this Infernal hell, Donal."[PARAGRAPH:1]"It's not a leader they need, there's wisdom and strength in even the young girls, like brave Capria. They need a symbol, to stay united in the real world, my lord. You must go through. I will hold open the doorway for you."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I cannot leave anyone behind, Donal!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal Lugh stood beside the angel, feeling an enormous weight descend upon him. "There's got to be another way out of here, Sabathiel. I'll find it, somewhere, and I'll make it back, if I have to kill every demon in Hell to do it." A moaning sound drew their attention to the corpses of their friends, beginning to rise as an imp on the cliff above them giggled and danced in a circle. Sabathiel and Donal exchanged one last glance, then the angel embraced the man, and turned and flew through the portal. The instant Donal stepped towards it in vain hope that the angel was wrong, but it vanished, and he sighed. Then he turned back towards the shambling corpses.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Alrighty, my friends, who's first?"</French>
		<German>[TAB]Capria hielt Sabra umschlungen, als sie vor dem Portal warteten. Ihre Schwester zitterte, ob vor Angst oder vor Aufregung, wusste sie nicht. Weshalb auch immer, ihr Vater hatte ihnen gesagt, dass sie ruhig sein müssten. Also blieb sie ruhig.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie kniete sich herunter, um auf Augenhöhe zu kommen, und sprach: "Weißt du noch, worüber wir geredet haben, Sabra? Wir gehen nach Hause, also musst du jetzt besonders tapfer sein. Was wird es zu Hause geben?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabra lächelte. "Keine Monster!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Genau! Wie wird es noch sein?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Feuer gibt's nur im Himmel, und nicht überall. Ich kann im Gras spielen und laufen, und fall' dann nicht in Lavagruben oder werde von den Schatten gefressen!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Genau, Kleines", sagte Capria, und hoffte, dass die Geschichten die sie der Kleinen erzählt hatten, wahr waren. Sie selbst nahm die Älteren beim Wort, wenn diese über die Äußere Welt sprachen. Aber es konnte nicht schlimmer sein, als hier zu leben.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die laute Stimme von Sabathiel erschallte, wie um ihre Gedanken zu bestätigen: "Soldaten, zu den Waffen! Wir werden verfolgt!" Die Männer liefen zu den Reihen ihrer Kompanien, und ließen die Frauen und Kinder zurück, den Eintritt in die neue Welt zu erwarten. Capria hob ihre Schwester auf, und wog sie in ihren Armen. "Volk der Braduk! Bereitet euch vor, zurück zu kehren!", rief Sabathiel, und entfaltete seine Flügel. Capria bedeckte ihre Augen, als ein helles Licht von dem Engel ausstrahlte, dann senkte sie ihre Hand. Sabathiel stand ihnen zugewandt, und hinter ihm war ein Tunnel aus Licht, der das Ende des Canyons zu ihrem Weg nach Hause machte. "Beeilt euch! Eure Männer können nicht für immer aushalten!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Familien näherten sich dem Tunnel, aber zögerten dann. Capria biss die Zähne zusammen, und drängte sich nach vorne. "Nun kommt, Brüder und Schwestern! Das ist es, wofür wir gelebt haben!" Ohne einen weiteren Blick zurück trat sie in das Licht...[PARAGRAPH:1]...und aus dem Feuer. Die Hitze in ihrem Rücken war das erste, was sie bemerkte, die fast ihre Haut versengte, durch die schwere Lederrüstung, die sie als Zweitlinien-Frau trug. Die Dunkelheit beunruhigte sie, statt einem ewigen roten Glühen, war nun Schwärze über ihr, durchbrochen von unzähligen Lichtpunkten. Sie drehte sich um, um mehr von ihrem Volk zu sehen, das aus den Flammen hervorkam, und sich genauso verhielt, wie sie sich verhalten hatte, also überrascht vorwärts eilte. Dann drehte sie sich wieder um, und bemerkte die Schreie.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sie sind frei! Ahhhhhhhhhhh!" Eine alte Frau, mit grüner Haut und auffällig vielen Zeichen darauf, wand sich auf dem Boden, ein paar Meter vor ihr. Weitere grüne Wesen sahen schockiert zu, wie die Fremden aus ihrem heiligen Feuer kamen.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was haben sie mit unserer Stadt gemacht?", fragte eine ältere Frau, die aus den Flammen trat.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Schön, was für Geschenke hat uns denn der gute alte Bhall heute Nacht gebracht?" Die tiefe Stimme gehörte einem Ork-Mann, der sich durch die Menge von spielenden und essenden Ork-Kindern am Feuer drängte. Im Gegensatz zu den glatthäutigen jüngeren Orks, ragten lange Knochenspitzen aus seinem Rücken, seinen Schultern, und seinen Armen. "Metallklingen an jungen Mädchen? Zu euren Speeren, mein Clan." Der stämmige Ork hob eine massive Axt, und grinste Capria an. Andere kamen hinzu, die lange Holzspeere bereithielten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria beugte sich, um ihre Schwester abzusetzen, und hatte ohne zu blinzeln sofort ein Ork-Kind in ihren Armen, und einen Dolch an dessen Kehle. "Wir wissen nicht, wer ihr seid, Monster, aber wir wollen nichts Böses. Lasst uns von hier gehen, und euer Kind bleibt am Leben!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ein Handel, Mädchen? Eines unserer Leben für alle eure Leben?" Orthus zog ein scharfes Knochenmesser aus seinem Gürtel. "Das klingt nicht nach einem guten Geschäft." Orthus' Arm schnellte vor, und das Messer flog auf Capria zu. Sie blinzelte, und noch bevor sie ihre Augen öffnete, fühlte sie warmes Blut, das in ihr Gesicht spritzte. Aber nicht ihres. Das Ork-Kind erschlaffte in ihren Armen, noch bevor es schreien konnte.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Du liebst das Leben, Mensch, ich liebe den Tod." Orthus nahm seine Axt und ging auf die Menschen zu.[PARAGRAPH:2]Blut spritzte auf Donals Gesicht, und an dem Brennen erkannte er, dass es einem Dämonen gehört hatte. Er biss die Zähne zusammen, duckte sich unter einem springenden Höllenhund, und stieß mit seinem Kurzschwert nach oben. Das Knurren wurde zu einem Winseln, aber der Hund konnte immer noch Donals Helm vom Kopf treten, als er würdelos zu Boden fiel. Donal hob seinen Schild, um einen Feuerball abzuwehren, den ein auftürmendes Feuerelementar geschleudert hatte, und rief über seine Schulter: "Sind wir bald fertig hier, mein Herr? Ich glaube, sie sind enttäuscht, dass wir sie verlassen."[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel schnaufte. "Noch... ein paar Minuten, mein Freund, dann haben die Älteren diesen verfluchten Ort verlassen. Ich könnt doch solange aushalten?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Wir werden tun, was wir müssen!" sagte Alessi. Donals stämmiger Kamerad schwang seine Hellebarde in weitem Bogen, und schlug ein Gaer-Tier zu boden, was dessen Reiter aus dem Sattel warf. Der Todesritter griff dennoch weiter an, und durchbohrte Alessis linke Schulter mit einer langen, nachtschwarzen Klinge. Der Krieger ließ seinen Waffenarm hängen und stolperte, genau richtig ungeschützt für einen Gnadenstoß. Donal rannte zu ihnen, schlitzte den Arm des Todesritters auf, und ließ den tödlichen Schlag so in einer nur hässlichen Bauchwunde enden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Dämon knurrte, und schlug ihn mit einem schnellen Schildschlag zu Boden. Er näherte sich Donal immer mehr, bis sich ein Pfeil in seine Brust bohrte. Dann ein zweiter, ein dritter, und ein vierter, bis er endlich fiel.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Zieht euch zurück und gruppiert euch neu!" rief der Schütze, bevor er von einem Schwarm Harpyen angegriffen wurde.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal steckte sein Schwert in die Scheide, und half seinem Freund auf die Füße. "Du wirst nicht sterben, bevor du nicht Tageslicht gesehen hast, Alessi, das schwöre ich!" Das Paar stolperte zurück, dem Portal entgegen, während ihre Gefährten die Reihen hinter ihnen schlossen.[PARAGRAPH:2]Capria hatte Mühe, nicht zu fallen, als sie versuchte, vor den herannahenden Orks zurück zu weichen. Ihre Hand fand einen langen Speer, der mit Stücken von verbranntem Schwein geschwärzt war, die daran hingen. Sie hohlte Luft, und stieß ihn in die Kehle eines herannahenden Orks. Dieser fiel mit einem Wimmern, und zerbrach dabei ihre Waffe. "Verzagt nicht, Freunde, wir alle haben schon schlimmeres als dies erlebt!" Sie zog ihr Kurzschwert. "Ringformation, Buben und Frauen zu den Waffen, Kinder und Alte in die Mitte! Wir werden uns Richtung Tor durcharbeiten. Erschlagt die Bestien wenn sie herankommen, aber haltet euer Position!" Ein Ork ging auf sie los, mit dem Speer voran. Sie bereitete sich vor, sich zu ducken, aber er fiel zu Boden bevor er sie erreichen konnte, gefällt von einem geschleuderten Stein.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Gruppe begann sich zu bewegen, in Richtung der Tore in den Palisaden, an den Hütten vorbei. Hinter ihnen stolperte ein verwundeter Mann aus den Flammen, der seine Brust umfasst hielt. Ein paar Goblins gingen auf ihn los, und stießen mehrmals auf ihn ein. Er konnte noch eine Handvoll Gras ergreifen, bevor er seinen letzten Atemzug machte.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ihr werdet mir nie entkommen, Menschen!", rief Orthus. Mit gewaltigen Schlägen drang er in ihre Formation, durchbrach ihre Reihen, und schnappte ein junges Mädchen am Nacken.[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria nahm den Tod ihres besten Freundes kaum wahr, sie sah nur, dass ihre Schwester von der Hand des Ork-Königs baumelte. Sie ließ sich fallen, rollte unter die Spitzen, und erhob sich genau vor Orthus, zu nahe, als dass er sie mit seiner Axt erreichen konnte. Hinter ihr schlossen die Menschen ihre Reihen wieder.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sei froh, dass ich vom Tod nichts mehr sehen kann," grollte Capria, und stieß ihr Schwert bis ans Heft in Orthus' Eingeweide. Sie warf sich ihre Schwester über die Schulter, und trat Orthus aus dem Weg. Die meisten der Orks waren nun schon geschlagen, und Freiheit war in Sicht.[PARAGRAPH:2]"Du bist der letzte, Donal", sagte Sabathiel. Die übrigen Soldaten waren in der letzten Kampfpause durch das Portal gestürmt. Die jenige die das Gemetzel überlebt hatten, jedenfalls.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Und dann werdet Ihr Folgen, mein Herr?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Jemand muss auf dieser Seite bleiben, um das Tor offen zu halten. Ich werde zurück bleiben."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Das könnt Ihr nicht! Mein Volk braucht Euch, Ihr müsst durch das Portal gehen!"[PARAGRAPH:1] Ich kann sie nicht in der nächsten Welt führen, wie ich sie in dieser infernalischen Hölle geführt habe, Donal."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was sie brauchen ist kein Anführer, es gibt Weisheit und Stärke sogar in den jungen Mädchen, wie der tapferen Capria. Sie brauchen ein Symbol, um in der wahren Welt vereint zu bleiben. Du musst hindurch gehen, ich werde den Durchgang für dich offen halten."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich kann niemanden zurücklassen, Donal!"[PARAGRAPH:1] Donal Lugh stand an der Seite des Engels, und fühlte, wie sich ein enormes Gewicht auf seine Schultern legte. "Es muss einen anderen Weg hier hinaus geben, Sabathiel. Ich werde ihn finden, irgendwie, und ich werde zurückkommen, selbst wenn ich jeden Dämon der Hölle dafür töten muss!" Ein stöhnendes Geräusch lenkte ihre Aufmerksamkeit auf die Leichen ihrer Freunde, die begannen, sich zu erheben, während ein Imp auf der Klippe über ihnen im Kreis tanzte und kicherte. Sabathiel und Donal sahen einander ein letztes Mal an, dann umarmte der Engel den Mann, drehte sich um, und flog durch durch das Portal. In dem Moment, als Donal auf es zutrat, verschwand es, und er seufzte. Dann drehte er sich um, zu den sich schüttelnden Leichen.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Also gut, meine Freunde, wer möchte als erstes?"</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Capria teneva Sabra vicino mentre aspettavano vicino al portale. Sua sorella stava tremando, se era per paura o per l'eccitazione lei non lo sapeva. In ogni caso, suo padre gli aveva detto di farla rimanere calma. E cosi lei fece.[PARAGRAPH:1]Inginocchiandosi fino al livello degli occhi, disse, "Ricordi di cosa abbiamo parlato, Sabra? Stiamo tornando a casa, quindi oggi devi essere molto coraggiosa. Come sarà casa?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabra sorrise. "Niente mostri!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Esatto! Cos'altro?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Il fuoco è solo in cielo e non tutto attorno. Potrò andare a giocare nell'erba e correre senza cadere nelle fosse o nella lava o essere mangiata dalle ombre!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Esatto, piccolina" Capria disse, sperando che le storie che dicevano ai bambini fossero vere. Lei stessa si affidava alle parole degli anziani per come era il mondo esterno. Ma anche se i ricordi di casa erano esaggerati non sarebbe potuto essere peggio che vivere qui.[PARAGRAPH:1]La voce rimbombante di Sabathiel riecheggiò come a dimostrazione del suo pensiero. "Soldati alle armi! Stiamo venendo seguiti!". Gli uomini corserò verso la retroguardia della compagnia, lasciando le loro mogli e figli ad aspettare di poter entrare nel nuovo mondo. Capria prese in braccio sua sorella. "Popolo di Braduk! Preparatevi a tornare!" Sabathiel urlò per poi estendere le sue ali. Capria si schermò gli occhi quando una luce brillante fu emanata dall'angelo, per poi affievolirsi. Sabathiel rimase a guardarli, un portale di luce dietro di lui trasformava il canyon in una via per casa. "Presto! I vostri uomini non possono resistere per sempre!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Le famiglie si avvicinavano al portale, ma esitavano prima di entrarci. Capria strinse i denti e si fece largo sino al portale. "Andiamo fratelli e sorelle! Questo è ciò per cui siamo sopravvissuti!". Senza guardarsi più indietro entrò nella luce...[PARAGRAPH:2]...e uscì dalle fiamme. Il calore dietro di lei fu la prima cosa che notò, quasi gli bruciava la pelle nonostante la sua armatura di cuoio che indossava in quanto una donna da rinforzo. L'oscurità la allarmò; al posto di una perenne foschia rossa c'era buio sopra di lei, perforata da innumerevoli puntini luminosi. Quando si voltò vide altri del suo popolo emergere dalle fiamme, e che reagivano come aveva reagito lei, avanzando sorpresi. Poi si girò di nuovo e notò le urla.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sono liberi! Ahhhhhhhhhhh!". Una vecchia donna, dalla pelle verde e pesantemente marchiata si stava contorcendo per terra a qualche metro di fronte a lei. Altre persone dalla pelle verde osservavano, sotto shock, gli stranieri emergere dal loro Fuoco Sacro.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Che cosa hanno fatto alla nostra città?" chiese una donna anziana appena emersa dalle fiamme.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bene, quali doni ci vengono dati dalla cara vecchia Bhall stanotte?". Questa voce profonda proveniva da un orco che si faceva largo tra la folla di bambini che stavano mangiando e giocando con le fiamme vicino agli umani. Diversamente dagli orchi più giovani, che avevano la pelle liscia, quest'orco aveva dei lunghi spuntoni ossei che spuntavano dalla schiena, dalle spalle e dalle braccia. "Lame di metallo su delle giovani ragazze? Prendete le vostre lance, mio clan". Poi l'orco, che era bello robusto, sollevò un'enorme ascia e sorrise a Capria. Arrivarono altri orchi che impugnavano delle lunghe lancie di legno.[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria si abbassò per poggiare sua sorella a terra, poi in un un battito di ciglia prese un bambino orco e gli puntò un pugnale alla gola. "Non sappiamo chi tu sia mostro, ma non vogliamo farvi del male. Lasciateci andare via e il bambino vivrà."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Uno scambio, ragazza? Una vita delle nostre per tutte le vostre?" Orthus estrasse un coltello d'osso affilato dalla sua cintura. "Non sembra essere un buono scambio". Orthus lanciò il coltello verso Capria. Lei sbatté le palpebre, e prima che riaprisse gli occhi sentì uno spruzzo di sagnue caldo sulla faccia. Ma non era il suo. Il bambino orco morì ancora prima di poter urlare.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tu dai un valore alla vita, umano. Ma la valuta che uso io negli scambi è la morte". Orthus sollevò la sua ascia e si diresse verso gli umani.[PARAGRAPH:2]Del sangue finì sulla faccia di Donal, e da come bruciava, lui sapeva che apparteneva al demone. Strinse i denti e si abbassò mentre un Segugio Infernale saltava verso di lui, per poi affondare verso l'alto la sua spada corta. Il rignhio della bestia si trasformò in un guaito, ma riuscì comunque a fargli perdere l'elmo mentre cascava a terra sgraziatamente. Donal sollevò lo scudo per proteggersi da una palla di fuoco lanciatagli contro da un imponente elementale del fuoco, mentre urlava da sopra la sua spalla, "Abbiamo finito qui, mio signore? Credo siano dispiaciuti del nostro partire".[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel borbottò. "Ancora... ancora qualche minuto, amici miei, e gli anziani avrannò abbandonato questo posto maledetto. Posso confidare in voi per resistere?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Faremo ciò che dobbiamo!" disse Alessi. Il robusto compagno di Donal agitò la sua alabarda in un ampio arco, colpendo un cavallo Gaer sulle ginocchia e disarcionando il suo cavaliere. Il Cavaliere della Morte continuò però la sua carica, e perforò la spalla sinistra di Alessi con una lunga lama nera. Il guerriero fece cadere la sua arma e barcollò, rimanendo perfettamente esposto a un colpo di grazia. Donal si voltò verso di loro, tagliando il braccio del Cavaliere Demoniaco trasfromando un colpo letale in una semplice, per quanto brutta, ferita all'addome.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il Demone ringhiò, e fece cadere a terra Donal con un rapido colpo di scudo. Poi avanzò verso di lui sino a quando una freccia non si conficco nel suo petto. E poi un'altra, e una terza, e una quarta, fino a quando finalmente cadde a terra.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Indietreggiate e riorganizzatevi!" disse il tiratore esperto prima di essere aggredito da uno stormo di arpie.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal rinfoderò la spada e aiutò il suo amico a mettersi in piedi. "Tu non morirai prima di aver visto la luce del sole, Alessi, lo giuro". Il duo arrancò verso il portale, mentre i loro compagni serravano i ranghi dietro di loro.[PARAGRAPH:2]Capria inciampò mentre cercava di indietreggare davanti agli orchi che avanzavano. La sua mano trovò una lunga lancia annerita, con attaccati dei pezzi di maiale bruciati. Poi fece un passo avanti perforando la gola di un'orco, che cadde con un mugolio, spezzando la lancia in due nel mentre. "Avanti amici, abbiamo affrontato cose ben peggiori di questo prima d'ora!". Lei estrasse la spada corta. "Formazione a cerchio, ragazzi e donne alle armi. Bambini e anziani al centro! Ci apriremo la strada sino al cancello. Uccidete le bestie se si avvicinano, ma mantenete le vostre posizioni!". Un'orco caricò verso di lei con una lancia. Capria si preparò a schivare, ma l'orco cadde a terra prima di raggiungerla essendo stato ucciso da una pietra lanciata da una fionda.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il gruppò iniziò a muoversi verso il cancello della palizzata. Dietro di loro un'uomo ferito uscì dalle fiamme arrancando mentre si stringeva il petto. Un paio di goblin gli saltarono addosso pugnalandolo ripetutamente. L'uomo riuscì ad afferrare dell'erba prima di esalare l'utlimo respiro.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non mi sfuggirete mai umani" Orthus urlò, per poi fiondarsi contro la formazione degli umani agitando selvaggiamente l'ascia, rompendo la linea difensiva mentre tagliava in due una ragazzina poco al di sotto delle costole.[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria notò a malapena la morte della sua migliore amica. Ciò su cui era concentrata era sua sorella che penzolava dalla mano del Re orco. Così si buttò a terra e rotolò sotto le lance, arrivando esattamente davanti a Orthus, cosi vicino che lui non avrebbe potuto usare la sua Ascia. Dietro di lei gli umani serrarono di nuovo i ranghi.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sii grato che ho visto abbastanza morte" Capria gli ringhiò contro, mentre infilava la sua spada fino all'elsa dentro il ventre di Orthus. Non rimase a finire il lavoro però, e una volta presa la sorella e messa in spalla si allontanò. L'orco più pericoloso era già stato sistemato e la libertà era vicina.[PARAGRAPH:2]"Tu sei l'ultimo, Donal" disse Sabathiel. Gli altri soldati avevano attraversato di corsa il portale durante l'ultima breve pausa del combattimento. Perlomeno quelli che erano sopravvissuti all'assalto dei demoni.[PARAGRAPH:1]"E poi ci seguirete, mio signore?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Qualcuno deve rimanere su questo piedistallo per mantenere aperto il portale. Rimarrò io".[PARAGRAPH:1]"No, non potete rimanere. La mia gente ha bisogno di voi!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"In quel mondo non posso guidarli come ho fatto in questo inferno, Donal."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non è di un leader che hanno bisogno, c'è forza e saggezza anche nei giovani, ne è un esempio la coraggiosa Capria. Ciò di cui hanno bisogno è un simbolo che li tenga uniti nel mondo reale, mio signore. Voi dovete attraversare il portale. Lo terrò aperto io per voi".[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non posso lasciare nessuno dietro, Donal!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal Lugh si affiancò all'angelo, sentendo un peso enorme scendere su di lui. "Ci deve essere un'altra via per uscire da qui, Sabathiel. La troverò, ovunque sia, e vi raggiungerò, anche se se dovrò uccidere ogni demone dell'Inferno per farlo". Dei gemiti spostarono la loro attenzione sui cadaveri dei loro amici, che stavano venedo rianimati da un imp che stava danzando in cerchio su una rupe. Sabathiel e Donal si scambiarono un'ultimo sguardo, poi l'angelo abbracciò l'uomo, prima di voltarsi e attraversare il portale. Nell'istante in cui Donal scese dal piedistallo verso il portale, sperando inutilmente che l'angelo si sbagliasse, il portale svanì, e lui sospirò. Poi tornò dai cadaveri dei suoi amici.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Molto bene amici, chi è il primo?"</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Capria held Sabra close as they waited near the portal. Her sister was quivering, whether from fear or excitement she didn't know. Either way, her father had told her to keep her calm. So she did.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kneeling down to eye level, she said, "Remember what we talked about, Sabra? We're going home, so today you need to be extra brave. What's home going to be like?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabra smiled. "No monsters!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"That's right! What else?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"The fire is just in the sky, and not all around. I can go play in the grass and run and not fall in the pits or the lava or be eaten by the shadows!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"That's right, little one," Capria said, hoping the stories that they told the young ones were true. She herself took the elders at their word what the outside world was like. But even memories of home were exaggerated, it could not be worse than living here.[PARAGRAPH:1]The booming voice of Sabathiel rang out as if to prove it to her. "Soldiers to arms! We are being followed!" The men rushed to the rear of their company, leaving their wives and children to await entry to the new world. Capria picked up her sister, bouncing her in her arms. "People of Braduk! Prepare to return!" Sabathiel cried out, then unfurled his wings. Capria shielded her eyes as the brilliant light flashed out from the angel, then subsided. Sabathiel stood facing them, a gateway of light behind him turning the back of the canyon into their route home. "Hurry! Your men cannot hold out forever!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The families approached the gateway, but hesitated before entering. Capria gritted her teeth, and pushed to the front. "Come, brothers, sisters! This is what we have been living for!" Without another look back, she stepped into the light...[PARAGRAPH:2]...and out of the fire. The heat at her back was the first thing she noticed, nearly searing her skin through the heavy leather armor she wore as a Secondline-woman. The darkness alarmed her; instead of a perpetual red haze, there was blackness above her, pierced by countless points of light. She turned to see more of her people emerging from the flames, and reacting as she had, hurrying ahead in surprise. Then she turned back and noticed the screams.[PARAGRAPH:1]"They're free! Ahhhhhhhhhhh!" An old woman, green skinned and heavily marked was writhing on the ground a few yards in front her. Other green skinned people watched the strangers coming out of their Sacred Fire with shock.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What have they done to our city?" asked an elderly woman emerging from the flames.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Well, what gifts have been given to us by dear ol' Bhall tonight?" The deep voice came from an orc man who pushed past the crowd of orc children eating and playing by the flames near the humans. Unlike the smooth skinned younger orcs, long bone spikes protruded from his back, shoulders, and arms. "Metal blades on young girls? Take your spears, my clan." The burly orc hefted a massive axe and grinned at Capria. Others came forth, wielding long wooden spears.[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria bent down to set her sister on the ground, then in a blink had an orc child in her arms and a dagger at its throat. "We don't know who you are monster, but we mean you no harm. Let us walk out of here and your child lives."[PARAGRAPH:1]"A trade, girl? One life of ours for all of yours?" Orthus pulled a sharpened bone knife from his belt. "That doesn't sound like a good trade." Orthus' arm swung out, and the knife came flying towards Capria. She blinked, and before her eyes opened she could feel warm blood splash on her face. But not hers. The orc child went limp in her arms before it could scream.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You value life, human. Death is the currency I trade in." Orthus hefted his axe and started towards the humans.[PARAGRAPH:2]Blood splattered on Donal's face, and by the burning, he knew it belonged to the demon. He gritted his teeth and ducked under a leaping Hellhound, thrusting upward with his short sword. Its snarl turned to a yelp, but it still managed to kick his helmet off as it tumbled gracelessly to the ground. Donal raised his shield to fend off a fireball hurled by a towering fire elemental, shouting over his shoulder, "Are we about done here, my lord? I do think they are sorry to see us leaving."[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel grunted. "Another... another few minutes, my friends, and the elders shall have left this accursed place. I trust you can hold out?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"We will do what we must!" said Alessi. Donal's burly comrade swung his halberd in a wide arc, knocking a Gaersteed to its knees and unseating its rider. The Death Knight continued his charge, however, and pierced Alessi's left shoulder with a long ebon blade. The warrior dropped his pole-arm and staggered, perfectly exposed for the coup d'grace. Donal spun towards them, slicing down on the Demon Knight's arm and turning a lethal blow into merely an ugly gut wound.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Demon snarled, and knocked him to the ground with a quick shield bash. It advanced on Donal until an arrow flew into its chest. Then another hit, and a third, and fourth, until finally he fell.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Pull back and regroup!" said the marksman, before being set upon by a swarm of harpies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal sheathed his sword and helped his friend to his feet. "You're not dying before you see daylight, Alessi, I swear it." The pair stumbled back towards the portal, as their peers closed ranks behind them.[PARAGRAPH:2]Capria stumbled as she tried to back away from the advancing orcs. Her hand found a long spear, blackened with bits of burnt swine clinging to it. She lunged and thrust it into the throat of an advancing orc, who fell with a whimper, snapping her weapon in two as he fell. "C'mon, friends, we've all faced worse than this before!" She unsheathed her short sword. "Ring formation, boys and women to arms. Children and elderly in the center! We'll work our way towards the gate. Slay the beasts if they come, but hold your position!" An orc charged her, spear first. She prepared to dodge, but he dropped to the ground before he reached her, felled by a slung stone.[PARAGRAPH:1]The group began to move towards the gate of the palisade, past hovels. Behind them a wounded man staggered out of the flames, clutching his chest. A pair of goblins leapt upon him, stabbing repeatedly. He managed to grasp a handful of grass before breathing his last.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You will never escape me, humans," Orthus cried. Swinging viciously, he bowled into their formation, breaking the ranks and cleaving a young girl just below the ribs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria barely noticed the death of her best friend. She did see her sister dangling from the Orc King's hand. She dropped and rolled under the spikes, coming up directly in front of Orthus, too close for him to wield his Axe. Behind her the humans closed ranks.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Be glad I'm sick of death," Capria growled, plunging her sword into Orthus' gut up to the hilt. She didn't stay to finish him, but slung her sister over her shoulder and turned away. The worst of the orcs had been stopped already, and the freedom was in sight.[PARAGRAPH:2]"You're the last, Donal," said Sabathiel. The other soldiers had charged through the portal during the last lull in the melee. The ones who had survived the onslaught, at least.[PARAGRAPH:1]"And then you'll follow, my lord?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Someone must remain on this pedestal to keep the portal open. I will stay behind."[PARAGRAPH:1]"No you won't. My people need you, you must go through!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I cannot lead them in the next world as I did in this Infernal hell, Donal."[PARAGRAPH:1]"It's not a leader they need, there's wisdom and strength in even the young girls, like brave Capria. They need a symbol, to stay united in the real world, my lord. You must go through. I will hold open the doorway for you."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I cannot leave anyone behind, Donal!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal Lugh stood beside the angel, feeling an enormous weight descend upon him. "There's got to be another way out of here, Sabathiel. I'll find it, somewhere, and I'll make it back, if I have to kill every demon in Hell to do it." A moaning sound drew their attention to the corpses of their friends, beginning to rise as an imp on the cliff above them giggled and danced in a circle. Sabathiel and Donal exchanged one last glance, then the angel embraced the man, and turned and flew through the portal. The instant Donal stepped towards it in vain hope that the angel was wrong, but it vanished, and he sighed. Then he turned back towards the shambling corpses.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Alrighty, my friends, who's first?"</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_DECIUS</Tag>
		<English>Decius</English>
		<French>Decius</French>
		<German>Decius</German>
		<Italian>Decius</Italian>
		<Spanish>Decius</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_DECIUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The highlight of the new Capital city was the promenade overlooking the bay of Laurus, a dazzling court held up like an offering to the mercurial gods of wind and wave. Upon this meeting place and against the wall of the palace sat the Heron Throne, looking out to the horizon. Graceful gold filigree outlines the seat, showing sea horses frolicking in waves at the bottom and the namesake birds taking flight at the top.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius crested the stairs leading to the court. Seeing the matronly woman seated on the Heron Throne made him feel the weight of his own years, for he had first met the queen when she was in her prime and nearly as battle hardened as he had been. The years had been kind to Rhoanna, crowning her with wisdom and grace, but the greying hair and the wrinkles that accompanied her welcoming smile readily attested to the years since they had shared a crusade. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He nodded courteously and addressed her as an equal. "Queen Rhoanna. I am glad to see you well."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She arose, walked down the steps of the dais, and clasped his hand. "All who stood with us against Mulcarn's rebirth are ever welcome here. What tidings do you bring from the lands Myrh?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]They spoke briefly of the rebuilding of the respective nations, nothing unknown to the spies both employed but making official the news of their distant realms. Decius eyed the assembled courtiers and advisors, including his own attending sorcerer and captain before broaching the reason for his visit. "I fear the peace in my lands is tenuous at best. There is a dark taint spreading from the coast deep into the heart, one resistant to my attempts at infiltration or investigation."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rhoanna frowned. "The overlords."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Yes. Once again I see an empire riven by the sign of the Octopus. Gods know I will never see eye to eye with the Bannor, but their dim view of this cult was not wrong. Whole towns have fallen asleep for weeks, wakening in madness. Abolishing their temples has only driven them underground-literally in some cases. Their connection to the oceans is obvious and I need answers from the remnants of the Lanun."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Believe me, Decius, we know of this cult. It reaches into every port town, not least these in the Meditor Sea here. It is more than a simple pagan personality cult, but for some reason the actual source of its divine power has long been difficult to determine. Falamar once received a vision from an archangel of Danalin that told of some malevolent force corrupting the god of the seas. Uncovering the source and stemming the tide of the Octopus Overlords has been his quest since the slaying of Auric. He is even now at the royal docks preparing an expedition to find an island said to be to the key to this mystery."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That's not enough, Rhoanna."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We are doing what we can."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"All you have are empty words and deflection. We know most of Hannah's captains have sworn to Falamar. The last time I was tasked with carving out this cult I did so by burning Lanun cities."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rhoanna's eyebrows raised at his harsh tone. "Is that a threat, Decius?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I will do what I need to do to protect my empire. I find it interesting that you take that as a threat."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We will overlook the implications of your words due to our past alliance. All I have for you now is an oath on my honor that we view this cult as our enemy and an offer of cooperation in eradicating it if you reciprocate in good faith."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The sorcerer at Decius side leaned forward, whispering "I sense no deception, lord."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius gestured angrily at his to be silent and turned from the Heron throne with a last word to Rhoanna. "The truth will come out, and my enemies will pay, as ever. It will be simpler if you prove upright, but I have precious little faith to offer." Rhoanna paced the length of the promenade and gazed out to the cloudy sea as he left.[NEWLINE]A winding staircase carved into the bluff led down from the court of Rhoanna and Falamar directly to the docks. Past the guard stations and not far from the fish markets, the streets were crowded with beggars harassing the emissaries and merchants docking at the royal isle. Decius turned aside before the docks, taking a path up to a scenic cliff that offered a small measure of privacy, waving to his sorcerer to follow. He said to him, "You spoke out of turn, Jerrell."[NEWLINE]"Apologies, lord, but you seemed distrustful of your friends. I wanted you to have the information my magics could glean from them. Surely, that is why I am here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Partly, yes. I need to know who I can trust. Foreign kings have their own agenda, as do my vassals, as do the gods' tools. Everyone does." Decius grabbed the smaller man, lifted him over the cliff edge. Holding him over a precipitous drop, he added, "Don't they? You made me look a fool."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No more than your own paranoia did, my lord. Please, let us have this conversation rationally."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I sponsored your order so I could have a secular inquisition should I need it. But I wonder how strictly you work against my enemies."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As discreetly as possible Jerrell pulled on the aether, gathering power. "Lord, let me request again, set me back on the ground unharmed."[NEWLINE]Decius did so. "Just as I thought. You turn your power on me at a moment's chance, faithless dog."[NEWLINE]The sorcerer bent over, panting. "Only in self-defense. When you come to your senses we can ignore this rashness."[NEWLINE]"You have perverted my senses with your charms, traitor. Much as I wish to strike you down here and now for that affront, I just can't bring myself to. I am compelled to do you no direct harm. The most I can do is refrain from waving at that mercenary I hired to wait up the path."[NEWLINE]"What?" Decius stepped back and a crossbow bolt buried itself in the sorcerer's chest. Decius shook his head sharply and kicked the man into the bay.[NEWLINE]The sergeant of the Guild of the Nine slung his crossbow and came up to Decius. "You did not give the signal, lord. As you said, this meant the wizard was to die."[NEWLINE]"Thank you, Rone. I think we need to talk about expanding our contract." He sighed wearily. "My lands have need of a purge."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Falamar pushed through the crowded wharf. His boyish charms long gone, his seasoned features nonetheless drew every female eye in the crowd even before they recognized his royal garb. This time he returned no longing gazes, intent on the foreign ship preparing to leave. Its owner was boarding now, he saw. An old soldier in search of a battleground. "Decius!" The emperor of Myrh turned. He looked at Falamar a moment, then turned his back on him, issuing orders to his Captain and a man wearing mercenary colors. Falamar was undeterred by the rudeness, striding aboard. "Decius, you've threatened my wife, the Queen, and brought violence to my streets."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius gave the old pirate his attention, folding his arms across his chest as he said, "What of it Falamar?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"If you were my vassal instead of my ally, I'd keel haul you."[NEWLINE]"You can try to arrange that, if you'd like."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Like it? What I'd like is to help you, you arrogant, plagueboil. To have you help us. What have we done to earn your distrust?"[NEWLINE]Decius snorted. "My empire is more diverse than Kylorin's at its height. The Malakim remnants, ambitious vampires, Sheaim refugees, lost angels, Elven revolutionaries. Do you think I hold it together by trust? There is no trust on Erebus, only strength and will."[NEWLINE]"There was one who put his trust in you once, if the stories are true."[NEWLINE]Decius grabbed the collar of Falamar's coat. "More the fool, him! Death is my sword and deceit is my shield. There's naught but misery in my wake." The crew of the vessel paused their work, staring at the argument. Decius waved at them dismissively.[NEWLINE]"Is that a boast or a lament?" Falamar replied, unperturbed.[NEWLINE]Decius turned and leaned against the railing, gazing at the horizon. Falamar waited until finally he turned back. "What was it all for?"[NEWLINE]"You brought us the Nether blade, old comrade in arms, upon the bleakest battlefield I've ever seen. Were it not for that-and everything that led to that--there may be no civilization upon this world."[NEWLINE]"I fought my whole life to be in control. In the end, did I make a single choice of consequence? Every decision I made--every betrayal, every death, every show of mercy or burst of inspiration, all just so you could thrust that damned blade into Auric? We're all puppets."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That's not exactly how it went down-nevermind, I like your version." Falamar inhaled the sea breeze deeply. "Every time I step on a boat, she calls to me. The siren song of my first lover, she says 'Falamar, Falamar, away with me forever! You were not made to be a worm shackled to the dirt, dance upon the waves and be free.'" A smile played upon his lips as he gazed briefly back towards the Heron Throne looking down on them. "And yet, I always return. I get every breath of wind into my sails so I can step upon this shore and return to give counsel and succor to my wife and queen. Which is freer self? The one that heeds his whims or the one stays bound to vow made years ago?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius shrugged. "It'll take a greater bard than you to convince me the meaning of life is true love."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No, that's not what I'm getting at. We may be the playthings of greater beings--fine. But at the end of it all, we are what we choose to do. You are at another cross-road. Take a leap of faith, here, friend. You may lose something by trusting, but you will certainly lose everything if you descend into paranoia."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius grit his teeth, wavering. He remembered another boat in a Lanun port, long ago, where he had faced the choice of light or dark. After a time he said "Well. Give my official apologies to Rhoanna, please. I believe I came off as more antagonistic then I had intended."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Falamar smiled briefly. "I suppose I'll take that." Decius turned, and Falamar said, "Wait, that's not all. I have a clue to the Overlords. Two, actually. I think Rhoanna mentioned the Isle to you. There's something else, and I need your help. A wizard, or sorcerer, or something. Last seen in the Umbra Woods. He may be the key. I need you to find this man, this. Hemah."</English>
		<French>The highlight of the new Capital city was the promenade overlooking the bay of Laurus, a dazzling court held up like an offering to the mercurial gods of wind and wave. Upon this meeting place and against the wall of the palace sat the Heron Throne, looking out to the horizon. Graceful gold filigree outlines the seat, showing sea horses frolicking in waves at the bottom and the namesake birds taking flight at the top.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius crested the stairs leading to the court. Seeing the matronly woman seated on the Heron Throne made him feel the weight of his own years, for he had first met the queen when she was in her prime and nearly as battle hardened as he had been. The years had been kind to Rhoanna, crowning her with wisdom and grace, but the greying hair and the wrinkles that accompanied her welcoming smile readily attested to the years since they had shared a crusade. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He nodded courteously and addressed her as an equal. "Queen Rhoanna. I am glad to see you well."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She arose, walked down the steps of the dais, and clasped his hand. "All who stood with us against Mulcarn's rebirth are ever welcome here. What tidings do you bring from the lands Myrh?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]They spoke briefly of the rebuilding of the respective nations, nothing unknown to the spies both employed but making official the news of their distant realms. Decius eyed the assembled courtiers and advisors, including his own attending sorcerer and captain before broaching the reason for his visit. "I fear the peace in my lands is tenuous at best. There is a dark taint spreading from the coast deep into the heart, one resistant to my attempts at infiltration or investigation."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rhoanna frowned. "The overlords."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Yes. Once again I see an empire riven by the sign of the Octopus. Gods know I will never see eye to eye with the Bannor, but their dim view of this cult was not wrong. Whole towns have fallen asleep for weeks, wakening in madness. Abolishing their temples has only driven them underground-literally in some cases. Their connection to the oceans is obvious and I need answers from the remnants of the Lanun."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Believe me, Decius, we know of this cult. It reaches into every port town, not least these in the Meditor Sea here. It is more than a simple pagan personality cult, but for some reason the actual source of its divine power has long been difficult to determine. Falamar once received a vision from an archangel of Danalin that told of some malevolent force corrupting the god of the seas. Uncovering the source and stemming the tide of the Octopus Overlords has been his quest since the slaying of Auric. He is even now at the royal docks preparing an expedition to find an island said to be to the key to this mystery."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That's not enough, Rhoanna."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We are doing what we can."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"All you have are empty words and deflection. We know most of Hannah's captains have sworn to Falamar. The last time I was tasked with carving out this cult I did so by burning Lanun cities."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rhoanna's eyebrows raised at his harsh tone. "Is that a threat, Decius?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I will do what I need to do to protect my empire. I find it interesting that you take that as a threat."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We will overlook the implications of your words due to our past alliance. All I have for you now is an oath on my honor that we view this cult as our enemy and an offer of cooperation in eradicating it if you reciprocate in good faith."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The sorcerer at Decius side leaned forward, whispering "I sense no deception, lord."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius gestured angrily at his to be silent and turned from the Heron throne with a last word to Rhoanna. "The truth will come out, and my enemies will pay, as ever. It will be simpler if you prove upright, but I have precious little faith to offer." Rhoanna paced the length of the promenade and gazed out to the cloudy sea as he left.[NEWLINE]A winding staircase carved into the bluff led down from the court of Rhoanna and Falamar directly to the docks. Past the guard stations and not far from the fish markets, the streets were crowded with beggars harassing the emissaries and merchants docking at the royal isle. Decius turned aside before the docks, taking a path up to a scenic cliff that offered a small measure of privacy, waving to his sorcerer to follow. He said to him, "You spoke out of turn, Jerrell."[NEWLINE]"Apologies, lord, but you seemed distrustful of your friends. I wanted you to have the information my magics could glean from them. Surely, that is why I am here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Partly, yes. I need to know who I can trust. Foreign kings have their own agenda, as do my vassals, as do the gods' tools. Everyone does." Decius grabbed the smaller man, lifted him over the cliff edge. Holding him over a precipitous drop, he added, "Don't they? You made me look a fool."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No more than your own paranoia did, my lord. Please, let us have this conversation rationally."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I sponsored your order so I could have a secular inquisition should I need it. But I wonder how strictly you work against my enemies."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As discreetly as possible Jerrell pulled on the aether, gathering power. "Lord, let me request again, set me back on the ground unharmed."[NEWLINE]Decius did so. "Just as I thought. You turn your power on me at a moment's chance, faithless dog."[NEWLINE]The sorcerer bent over, panting. "Only in self-defense. When you come to your senses we can ignore this rashness."[NEWLINE]"You have perverted my senses with your charms, traitor. Much as I wish to strike you down here and now for that affront, I just can't bring myself to. I am compelled to do you no direct harm. The most I can do is refrain from waving at that mercenary I hired to wait up the path."[NEWLINE]"What?" Decius stepped back and a crossbow bolt buried itself in the sorcerer's chest. Decius shook his head sharply and kicked the man into the bay.[NEWLINE]The sergeant of the Guild of the Nine slung his crossbow and came up to Decius. "You did not give the signal, lord. As you said, this meant the wizard was to die."[NEWLINE]"Thank you, Rone. I think we need to talk about expanding our contract." He sighed wearily. "My lands have need of a purge."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Falamar pushed through the crowded wharf. His boyish charms long gone, his seasoned features nonetheless drew every female eye in the crowd even before they recognized his royal garb. This time he returned no longing gazes, intent on the foreign ship preparing to leave. Its owner was boarding now, he saw. An old soldier in search of a battleground. "Decius!" The emperor of Myrh turned. He looked at Falamar a moment, then turned his back on him, issuing orders to his Captain and a man wearing mercenary colors. Falamar was undeterred by the rudeness, striding aboard. "Decius, you've threatened my wife, the Queen, and brought violence to my streets."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius gave the old pirate his attention, folding his arms across his chest as he said, "What of it Falamar?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"If you were my vassal instead of my ally, I'd keel haul you."[NEWLINE]"You can try to arrange that, if you'd like."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Like it? What I'd like is to help you, you arrogant, plagueboil. To have you help us. What have we done to earn your distrust?"[NEWLINE]Decius snorted. "My empire is more diverse than Kylorin's at its height. The Malakim remnants, ambitious vampires, Sheaim refugees, lost angels, Elven revolutionaries. Do you think I hold it together by trust? There is no trust on Erebus, only strength and will."[NEWLINE]"There was one who put his trust in you once, if the stories are true."[NEWLINE]Decius grabbed the collar of Falamar's coat. "More the fool, him! Death is my sword and deceit is my shield. There's naught but misery in my wake." The crew of the vessel paused their work, staring at the argument. Decius waved at them dismissively.[NEWLINE]"Is that a boast or a lament?" Falamar replied, unperturbed.[NEWLINE]Decius turned and leaned against the railing, gazing at the horizon. Falamar waited until finally he turned back. "What was it all for?"[NEWLINE]"You brought us the Nether blade, old comrade in arms, upon the bleakest battlefield I've ever seen. Were it not for that-and everything that led to that--there may be no civilization upon this world."[NEWLINE]"I fought my whole life to be in control. In the end, did I make a single choice of consequence? Every decision I made--every betrayal, every death, every show of mercy or burst of inspiration, all just so you could thrust that damned blade into Auric? We're all puppets."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That's not exactly how it went down-nevermind, I like your version." Falamar inhaled the sea breeze deeply. "Every time I step on a boat, she calls to me. The siren song of my first lover, she says 'Falamar, Falamar, away with me forever! You were not made to be a worm shackled to the dirt, dance upon the waves and be free.'" A smile played upon his lips as he gazed briefly back towards the Heron Throne looking down on them. "And yet, I always return. I get every breath of wind into my sails so I can step upon this shore and return to give counsel and succor to my wife and queen. Which is freer self? The one that heeds his whims or the one stays bound to vow made years ago?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius shrugged. "It'll take a greater bard than you to convince me the meaning of life is true love."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No, that's not what I'm getting at. We may be the playthings of greater beings--fine. But at the end of it all, we are what we choose to do. You are at another cross-road. Take a leap of faith, here, friend. You may lose something by trusting, but you will certainly lose everything if you descend into paranoia."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius grit his teeth, wavering. He remembered another boat in a Lanun port, long ago, where he had faced the choice of light or dark. After a time he said "Well. Give my official apologies to Rhoanna, please. I believe I came off as more antagonistic then I had intended."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Falamar smiled briefly. "I suppose I'll take that." Decius turned, and Falamar said, "Wait, that's not all. I have a clue to the Overlords. Two, actually. I think Rhoanna mentioned the Isle to you. There's something else, and I need your help. A wizard, or sorcerer, or something. Last seen in the Umbra Woods. He may be the key. I need you to find this man, this. Hemah."</French>
		<German>The highlight of the new Capital city was the promenade overlooking the bay of Laurus, a dazzling court held up like an offering to the mercurial gods of wind and wave. Upon this meeting place and against the wall of the palace sat the Heron Throne, looking out to the horizon. Graceful gold filigree outlines the seat, showing sea horses frolicking in waves at the bottom and the namesake birds taking flight at the top.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius crested the stairs leading to the court. Seeing the matronly woman seated on the Heron Throne made him feel the weight of his own years, for he had first met the queen when she was in her prime and nearly as battle hardened as he had been. The years had been kind to Rhoanna, crowning her with wisdom and grace, but the greying hair and the wrinkles that accompanied her welcoming smile readily attested to the years since they had shared a crusade. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He nodded courteously and addressed her as an equal. "Queen Rhoanna. I am glad to see you well."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She arose, walked down the steps of the dais, and clasped his hand. "All who stood with us against Mulcarn's rebirth are ever welcome here. What tidings do you bring from the lands Myrh?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]They spoke briefly of the rebuilding of the respective nations, nothing unknown to the spies both employed but making official the news of their distant realms. Decius eyed the assembled courtiers and advisors, including his own attending sorcerer and captain before broaching the reason for his visit. "I fear the peace in my lands is tenuous at best. There is a dark taint spreading from the coast deep into the heart, one resistant to my attempts at infiltration or investigation."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rhoanna frowned. "The overlords."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Yes. Once again I see an empire riven by the sign of the Octopus. Gods know I will never see eye to eye with the Bannor, but their dim view of this cult was not wrong. Whole towns have fallen asleep for weeks, wakening in madness. Abolishing their temples has only driven them underground-literally in some cases. Their connection to the oceans is obvious and I need answers from the remnants of the Lanun."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Believe me, Decius, we know of this cult. It reaches into every port town, not least these in the Meditor Sea here. It is more than a simple pagan personality cult, but for some reason the actual source of its divine power has long been difficult to determine. Falamar once received a vision from an archangel of Danalin that told of some malevolent force corrupting the god of the seas. Uncovering the source and stemming the tide of the Octopus Overlords has been his quest since the slaying of Auric. He is even now at the royal docks preparing an expedition to find an island said to be to the key to this mystery."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That's not enough, Rhoanna."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We are doing what we can."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"All you have are empty words and deflection. We know most of Hannah's captains have sworn to Falamar. The last time I was tasked with carving out this cult I did so by burning Lanun cities."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rhoanna's eyebrows raised at his harsh tone. "Is that a threat, Decius?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I will do what I need to do to protect my empire. I find it interesting that you take that as a threat."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We will overlook the implications of your words due to our past alliance. All I have for you now is an oath on my honor that we view this cult as our enemy and an offer of cooperation in eradicating it if you reciprocate in good faith."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The sorcerer at Decius side leaned forward, whispering "I sense no deception, lord."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius gestured angrily at his to be silent and turned from the Heron throne with a last word to Rhoanna. "The truth will come out, and my enemies will pay, as ever. It will be simpler if you prove upright, but I have precious little faith to offer." Rhoanna paced the length of the promenade and gazed out to the cloudy sea as he left.[NEWLINE]A winding staircase carved into the bluff led down from the court of Rhoanna and Falamar directly to the docks. Past the guard stations and not far from the fish markets, the streets were crowded with beggars harassing the emissaries and merchants docking at the royal isle. Decius turned aside before the docks, taking a path up to a scenic cliff that offered a small measure of privacy, waving to his sorcerer to follow. He said to him, "You spoke out of turn, Jerrell."[NEWLINE]"Apologies, lord, but you seemed distrustful of your friends. I wanted you to have the information my magics could glean from them. Surely, that is why I am here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Partly, yes. I need to know who I can trust. Foreign kings have their own agenda, as do my vassals, as do the gods' tools. Everyone does." Decius grabbed the smaller man, lifted him over the cliff edge. Holding him over a precipitous drop, he added, "Don't they? You made me look a fool."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No more than your own paranoia did, my lord. Please, let us have this conversation rationally."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I sponsored your order so I could have a secular inquisition should I need it. But I wonder how strictly you work against my enemies."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As discreetly as possible Jerrell pulled on the aether, gathering power. "Lord, let me request again, set me back on the ground unharmed."[NEWLINE]Decius did so. "Just as I thought. You turn your power on me at a moment's chance, faithless dog."[NEWLINE]The sorcerer bent over, panting. "Only in self-defense. When you come to your senses we can ignore this rashness."[NEWLINE]"You have perverted my senses with your charms, traitor. Much as I wish to strike you down here and now for that affront, I just can't bring myself to. I am compelled to do you no direct harm. The most I can do is refrain from waving at that mercenary I hired to wait up the path."[NEWLINE]"What?" Decius stepped back and a crossbow bolt buried itself in the sorcerer's chest. Decius shook his head sharply and kicked the man into the bay.[NEWLINE]The sergeant of the Guild of the Nine slung his crossbow and came up to Decius. "You did not give the signal, lord. As you said, this meant the wizard was to die."[NEWLINE]"Thank you, Rone. I think we need to talk about expanding our contract." He sighed wearily. "My lands have need of a purge."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Falamar pushed through the crowded wharf. His boyish charms long gone, his seasoned features nonetheless drew every female eye in the crowd even before they recognized his royal garb. This time he returned no longing gazes, intent on the foreign ship preparing to leave. Its owner was boarding now, he saw. An old soldier in search of a battleground. "Decius!" The emperor of Myrh turned. He looked at Falamar a moment, then turned his back on him, issuing orders to his Captain and a man wearing mercenary colors. Falamar was undeterred by the rudeness, striding aboard. "Decius, you've threatened my wife, the Queen, and brought violence to my streets."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius gave the old pirate his attention, folding his arms across his chest as he said, "What of it Falamar?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"If you were my vassal instead of my ally, I'd keel haul you."[NEWLINE]"You can try to arrange that, if you'd like."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Like it? What I'd like is to help you, you arrogant, plagueboil. To have you help us. What have we done to earn your distrust?"[NEWLINE]Decius snorted. "My empire is more diverse than Kylorin's at its height. The Malakim remnants, ambitious vampires, Sheaim refugees, lost angels, Elven revolutionaries. Do you think I hold it together by trust? There is no trust on Erebus, only strength and will."[NEWLINE]"There was one who put his trust in you once, if the stories are true."[NEWLINE]Decius grabbed the collar of Falamar's coat. "More the fool, him! Death is my sword and deceit is my shield. There's naught but misery in my wake." The crew of the vessel paused their work, staring at the argument. Decius waved at them dismissively.[NEWLINE]"Is that a boast or a lament?" Falamar replied, unperturbed.[NEWLINE]Decius turned and leaned against the railing, gazing at the horizon. Falamar waited until finally he turned back. "What was it all for?"[NEWLINE]"You brought us the Nether blade, old comrade in arms, upon the bleakest battlefield I've ever seen. Were it not for that-and everything that led to that--there may be no civilization upon this world."[NEWLINE]"I fought my whole life to be in control. In the end, did I make a single choice of consequence? Every decision I made--every betrayal, every death, every show of mercy or burst of inspiration, all just so you could thrust that damned blade into Auric? We're all puppets."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That's not exactly how it went down-nevermind, I like your version." Falamar inhaled the sea breeze deeply. "Every time I step on a boat, she calls to me. The siren song of my first lover, she says 'Falamar, Falamar, away with me forever! You were not made to be a worm shackled to the dirt, dance upon the waves and be free.'" A smile played upon his lips as he gazed briefly back towards the Heron Throne looking down on them. "And yet, I always return. I get every breath of wind into my sails so I can step upon this shore and return to give counsel and succor to my wife and queen. Which is freer self? The one that heeds his whims or the one stays bound to vow made years ago?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius shrugged. "It'll take a greater bard than you to convince me the meaning of life is true love."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No, that's not what I'm getting at. We may be the playthings of greater beings--fine. But at the end of it all, we are what we choose to do. You are at another cross-road. Take a leap of faith, here, friend. You may lose something by trusting, but you will certainly lose everything if you descend into paranoia."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius grit his teeth, wavering. He remembered another boat in a Lanun port, long ago, where he had faced the choice of light or dark. After a time he said "Well. Give my official apologies to Rhoanna, please. I believe I came off as more antagonistic then I had intended."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Falamar smiled briefly. "I suppose I'll take that." Decius turned, and Falamar said, "Wait, that's not all. I have a clue to the Overlords. Two, actually. I think Rhoanna mentioned the Isle to you. There's something else, and I need your help. A wizard, or sorcerer, or something. Last seen in the Umbra Woods. He may be the key. I need you to find this man, this. Hemah."</German>
		<Italian>L'attrattiva principale della nuova Capitale era il lungomare che dava sulla baia di Laurus, un luogo estremamente luminoso tenuto come fosse un'offerta ai mutevoli dei del vento e delle onde. Sopra questo luogo d'incontro, e a ridosso delle mura del palazzo, vi era il Trono dell'Airone, posto come a guardare l'orizzonte. Il sedile era delineato da graziose filigrane d'oro, che mostravano dei cavallucci marini ondeggiare in basso e degli uccelli marini volare in alto.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius salì le scale che portavano al giardino. Decius senti il peso dei suoi anni quando vide la donna, dall'aspetto matronale, seduta sul Trono dell'Airone, avendo incontrato la regina la prima volta quando era nel fiore degli anni e agguerrita quasi quanto lui. Gli anni erano stati gentili con Rhoanna, portandogli saggezza e grazia, ma i capelli grigi e le rughe che accompagnavano il suo sorriso accogliente attestavano rapidamente gli anni passati da quando avevano condiviso una crociata. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Annuiì cortesemente e si rivolse a lei come a un pari. "Regina Rhoanna. Sono lieto di vedervi in salute".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Lei si alzò, scese i gradini della pedana e gli strinse la mano. "Tutti coloro che sono stati al nostro fianco contro la rinascità di Mulcarn sono sempre i benvenuti qui. Che notizie porti dalla terre di Myrh?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Parlarono brevemente della ricostruzione delle loro rispettive nazioni, nulla che già non sapesserò grazie alle spie che entrambi usavano, ma così rendevano ufficiali tali informazioni riguardanti regni lontani. Decius guardò i cortigiani e i consiglieri, compresi il mago e il capitano che erano con lui, prima di spiegare la ragione della sua visita. "Temo che la pace nelle mie terre sia precaria, nel caso migliore. Vi è una piaga oscura che si diffonde dalla costa sino all'entroterra, una piaga che ha resistito ai miei tentativi di infiltrazione o investigazione".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rhoanna aggrottò la fronte. "I Padroni".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Si. Ancora una volta vedo un'impero lacerato dai segni degli Octopus. Gli dei sanno che non vado d'accordo con i Bannor, ma la loro avversione per tale culto non è sbagliata. Interi paesi si sono addormentati per settimane, risvegliandosi impazziti. Vietare i loro templi li ha soltanto finire in clandestinità. La loro connessione all'oceano è ovvia e ho bisogno di risposte dai Lanun superstiti".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Credimi, Decius, sappiamo di questo culto. È presente in ogni città portuale, persino in quelle qui sul Mare Meditor. È più che un semplice culto della personalità pagano, ma per qualche ragione la vera fonte del suo potere divino è difficile da determinare. Falamar una volta ha ricevuto una visione da un'arcangelo di Danalin in cui gli diceva che qualche forza malvagia stava corrompendo il dio dei mari. Scoprire l'origine e contrastare i Padroni Octopus è la sua missione sin da quando Auric è stato ucciso. Persino ora è al porto regale, mentre prepara una spedizione per trovare un'isola che si dice sia la chiave per risolvere questo mistero".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Non è abbastanza, Rhoanna".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Stiamo facendo ciò che possiamo".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Tutto ciò che avete sono parole vuote e digressioni. Sappiamo che la maggior parte dei capitani di Hannah hanno giurato fedelta a Falamar. L'ultima volta che mi fu chiesto di estirpare questo culto io lo feci bruciando città Lanun".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Le sopracciglia di Rhoanna si alzarono in risposta al suo tono brusco. "È una minaccia, Decius?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Farò ciò che devo per proteggere il mio impero. Trovo interessante che tu la prenda come una minaccia".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Sorvoleremo sulle implicazioni delle tue parole in virtù della nostra passata alleanza. Tutto ciò che ho per te ora è un giuramento sul mio onore che noi vediamo questo culto come nostro nemico e che offriamo collaborazione nella sua eliminazione se tu ricambi in buona fede".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Il mago al fianco di Decius si sporse in avanti, sussurando "Non percepisco alcun inganno, signore".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius gli gesticolo arrabbiato di stare in silenzio e si voltò dal Trono dell'Airone con un'ultima frase per Rhoanna. "La verita verrà fuori, e i miei nemici la pagheranno, come sempre. Sarà più semplice se vi dimostrerete onesti, ma ho poca fiducia da offrire". Rhoanna misurò la lunghezza del lungomare e guardò verso il mare nuvoloso mentre Decius se ne andava.[NEWLINE]Una scala a chiocciola, scolpita nella scogliera, portava dalla corte di Rhoanna e Falamar direttamente al porto. Oltre il posto di guardia e non lontano dal mercato del pesce le strade erano piene di mendicanti che infastidivano gli ambasciatori e di mercanti che attraccavano all'isola regale. Prima di arrivare al porto Decius fece una deviazione, prendendo una strada che porta su un promontorio che forniva un pò di riservatezza, segnalando al suo mago di seguirlo. Disse al mago, "Hai parlato senza essere interpellato, Jerrell".[NEWLINE]"Perdonatemi, signore, ma sembravate diffidare dei vostri amici. Volovo soltanto che aveste le informazioni che la mia magia forniva su di loro. Sicuramente è il motivo per cui sono qui".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"In parte, si. Devo sapere di chi mi posso fidare. I re stranieri hanno i loro interessi, cosi come i miei vassalli e come pure gli strumenti degli dei. Chiunque ha i suoi". Decius afferrò il mago e lo sollevò oltre il bordo del promontorio. Tenendolo sopra il baratro aggiunse "Non è cosi? Mi hai fatto sembrare uno stupido".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Non più di quanto non faccia la vostra paranoia, mio signore. Per favore, discutiamo in modo razionale".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ho incentivato il vostro ordine cosi da avere un'inquisizione secolare nel caso ne avessi avuto bisogno. Ma mi chiedo quanto rigorosamente avete lavorato contro i miei nemici".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Nella maniera più discreta possibile Jerrell attinse all'etere, accumulando potere magico. "Signore, permettetemi di richiedervelo, rimettetemi a terra illeso".[NEWLINE]Decius lo fece. "Come pensavo. Tu usi il tuo potere contro di me quando ne hai l'opportunità, cane infedele".[NEWLINE]L'incantatore si chinò in avanti ansimando. "Solo per autodifesa. Quando tornate in voi potremo ignorare questo affronto".[NEWLINE]"Tu hai influenzato i miei sensi con la tua magia, traditore. Per quanto io desideri colpirti qui ed ora per tale affronto il mio corpo non segue i miei ordini. Sono costretto a non farti male direttamente. Il massimo che io possa fare è non fare un cenno al mercenario che ho ingaggiato per aspettare più avanti nella strada".[NEWLINE]"Cosa?" Decius indietreggiò e un quadrello di balestra si conficcò nel petto dell'incantatore. Decius scosse la testa bruscamente e spinse, con un calcio, l'uomo nella baia.[NEWLINE]Il sergente della Gilda dei Nove si mise a tracolla la balestra e raggiunse Decius. "Non avete fatto il cenno, signore. Come avevate detto, ciò significava che il mago doveva morire".[NEWLINE]"Grazie, Rone. Penso dovremmo parlare riguardo l'estensione del nostro contratto". Po sospirò stancamente. "Le mie terre hanno bisogno di un'epurazione".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Falamar si fece largo sul molo affollato. Il suo fascino giovanile era svanito da molto tempo, ma comunque, i suoi lineamenti maturi attirarono l'attenzione di ogni donna della folla ancor prima di riconoscere i suoi abiti regali. Questa volta non ricambiò nessuno di questi sguardi desiderosi concentrato come era sulla nave straniera che era in procinto di partire. Vide che il suo proprietario vi stava salendo a bordo ora. Un vecchio soldato in cerca di un campo di battaglia. "Decius!". L'imperatore di Myrh si voltò. Guardò per un momento Falamar e poi si rigirò, mentre dava ordini ai suoi Capitani e ad un'uomo che vestiva i colori dei mercenari. Falamar non diede peso a tale gesto mentre saliva a bordo. "Decius, hai minacciato mia moglie, la Regina, e portato la violenza nelle mie strade".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius concentrò la sua attenzione sul vecchio pirata, incrociando le sue braccia sul petto mentre diceva, "E quindi Falamar?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Se tu fossi un mio vassallo anziché un mio alleato, ti farei legare alla chiglia della mia nave".[NEWLINE]"Puoi provare a farlo, se ti fa piacere".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Piacere? Ciò che mi fa piacere è aiutare te, arrogante essere. Per aiutarci. Che cosa abbiamo fatto per meritarci tanta diffidenza?"[NEWLINE]Decius sbuffò. "Il mio impero è più etereogeneo di quello di Kylorin al suo apice. I Malakim superstiti, gli ambiziosi vampiri, i rifugiati Sheaim, gli angeli senza guida e dei rivoluzionari Elfici. Credi che io li tenga uniti con la fiducia? Non vi è alcuna fiducia su Erebus, solamente forza e volontà".[NEWLINE]"C'è stato uno che ha riposto la sua fiducia in te una volta, sempre che le storie siano vere".[NEWLINE]Decius afferrò il bavero del cappotto di Falamar. "Lui era uno stolto! La morte è la mia spada e l'inganno il mio scudo. Non c'è altro che miseria sulla mia scia". L'equipaggio del vascello smise di fare ciò che stava facendo e osservò la discussione. Decius gli fece cennò di tornare a lavoro.[NEWLINE]"È un vanto o un lamento?" Falamar rispose senza scomporsi.[NEWLINE]Decius si volse a guardare l'orizzonte sporgendosi dal parapetto. Falamar aspettò fino a quando non si voltò di nuovo. "Perché tutto questo?"[NEWLINE]"Tu ci hai portato la lama Nether, vecchio compagno d'armi, sul campo di battaglia più tetro che abbia mai visto. Non fosse stato per ciò, e ogni cosa che è successa prima di quello, non ci sarebbe alcuna civiltà su questo mondo".[NEWLINE]"Ho combattuto per tutta la mia vita per avere il controllo. Alla fine, ho fatto solo una scelta delle conseguenze? Ogni decisione che ho fatto, ogni tradimento, ogni morte, ogni momento di misericordia o di ispirazione, tutto soltanto perché tu potessi trafiggere Auric con quella dannata lama? Siamo tutti dei burattini".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Non è esattamente andata cosi, ma non importa, mi piace la tua versione". Falamar inspirò profondamente la brezza marina. "Ogni volta che io salgo su una nave lei mi chiama. La canzone da sirena del mio primo amore, dice 'Falamar, Falamar, vieni via con me per sempre! Non sei fatto per essere un verme incatenato a terra, danza sulle onde e sii libero'". Un sorriso comparve sul suo viso mentre guardava rapidamente verso il Trono dell'Airone. "Eppure io torno sempre. Gonfio le mie vele con quanto più vento riesco cosi da poter rimettere piede su questa spiaggia per portare consiglio e aiuto a mia moglie e regina. Chi è più libero? Colui che cede ai suoi capricci o chi rimane fedele a dei giuramenti fatti anni fa?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius scrollò le spalle. "Ci vorrà un bardo molto più abile di te per convincermi che il senso della vita è il vero amore".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No, non è questo il punto. Noi potremmo essere i giocattoli di esseri spueriori, bene. Ma alla fine di tutto noi siamo ciò che decidiamo di essere. Tu ora sei ad un'altro bivio. Abbi un pò di fede ora, amico. Potresti perdere qualcosa fidandoti, ma perderesti di sicuro tutto se ti fai prendere completamente dalla paranoia".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius strinse i denti, esitando. Ricordò di una volta in cui era sempre su una nave in un porto Lanun, tanto tempo fa, dove aveva dovuto scegliere tra la luce e l'oscurità. Dopo un pò disse: "Bene. Porta le mie scuse ufficiali a Rhoanna, per favore. Ritengo di esser stato più ostile di quanto volessi essere".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Falamar sorrise brevemente. "Per me va bene." Decius si voltò ma Falamar aggiunse, "Aspetta, questo non è tutto. Ho un'indizio sui Padroni. Due in realtà. Penso che Rhoanna ti abbia già accennato dell'Isola. C'è qualcos'altro, e ho bisogno del tuo aiuto. Un mago, o uno stregone o qualcosa di simile. Visto per l'ultima volta nelle Foreste Umbra. Lui potrebbe essere la chiave. Ho bisogno che tu trovi questo uomo, tale. Hemah."</Italian>
		<Spanish>The highlight of the new Capital city was the promenade overlooking the bay of Laurus, a dazzling court held up like an offering to the mercurial gods of wind and wave. Upon this meeting place and against the wall of the palace sat the Heron Throne, looking out to the horizon. Graceful gold filigree outlines the seat, showing sea horses frolicking in waves at the bottom and the namesake birds taking flight at the top.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius crested the stairs leading to the court. Seeing the matronly woman seated on the Heron Throne made him feel the weight of his own years, for he had first met the queen when she was in her prime and nearly as battle hardened as he had been. The years had been kind to Rhoanna, crowning her with wisdom and grace, but the greying hair and the wrinkles that accompanied her welcoming smile readily attested to the years since they had shared a crusade. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He nodded courteously and addressed her as an equal. "Queen Rhoanna. I am glad to see you well."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She arose, walked down the steps of the dais, and clasped his hand. "All who stood with us against Mulcarn's rebirth are ever welcome here. What tidings do you bring from the lands Myrh?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]They spoke briefly of the rebuilding of the respective nations, nothing unknown to the spies both employed but making official the news of their distant realms. Decius eyed the assembled courtiers and advisors, including his own attending sorcerer and captain before broaching the reason for his visit. "I fear the peace in my lands is tenuous at best. There is a dark taint spreading from the coast deep into the heart, one resistant to my attempts at infiltration or investigation."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rhoanna frowned. "The overlords."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Yes. Once again I see an empire riven by the sign of the Octopus. Gods know I will never see eye to eye with the Bannor, but their dim view of this cult was not wrong. Whole towns have fallen asleep for weeks, wakening in madness. Abolishing their temples has only driven them underground-literally in some cases. Their connection to the oceans is obvious and I need answers from the remnants of the Lanun."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Believe me, Decius, we know of this cult. It reaches into every port town, not least these in the Meditor Sea here. It is more than a simple pagan personality cult, but for some reason the actual source of its divine power has long been difficult to determine. Falamar once received a vision from an archangel of Danalin that told of some malevolent force corrupting the god of the seas. Uncovering the source and stemming the tide of the Octopus Overlords has been his quest since the slaying of Auric. He is even now at the royal docks preparing an expedition to find an island said to be to the key to this mystery."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That's not enough, Rhoanna."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We are doing what we can."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"All you have are empty words and deflection. We know most of Hannah's captains have sworn to Falamar. The last time I was tasked with carving out this cult I did so by burning Lanun cities."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rhoanna's eyebrows raised at his harsh tone. "Is that a threat, Decius?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I will do what I need to do to protect my empire. I find it interesting that you take that as a threat."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We will overlook the implications of your words due to our past alliance. All I have for you now is an oath on my honor that we view this cult as our enemy and an offer of cooperation in eradicating it if you reciprocate in good faith."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The sorcerer at Decius side leaned forward, whispering "I sense no deception, lord."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius gestured angrily at his to be silent and turned from the Heron throne with a last word to Rhoanna. "The truth will come out, and my enemies will pay, as ever. It will be simpler if you prove upright, but I have precious little faith to offer." Rhoanna paced the length of the promenade and gazed out to the cloudy sea as he left.[NEWLINE]A winding staircase carved into the bluff led down from the court of Rhoanna and Falamar directly to the docks. Past the guard stations and not far from the fish markets, the streets were crowded with beggars harassing the emissaries and merchants docking at the royal isle. Decius turned aside before the docks, taking a path up to a scenic cliff that offered a small measure of privacy, waving to his sorcerer to follow. He said to him, "You spoke out of turn, Jerrell."[NEWLINE]"Apologies, lord, but you seemed distrustful of your friends. I wanted you to have the information my magics could glean from them. Surely, that is why I am here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Partly, yes. I need to know who I can trust. Foreign kings have their own agenda, as do my vassals, as do the gods' tools. Everyone does." Decius grabbed the smaller man, lifted him over the cliff edge. Holding him over a precipitous drop, he added, "Don't they? You made me look a fool."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No more than your own paranoia did, my lord. Please, let us have this conversation rationally."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I sponsored your order so I could have a secular inquisition should I need it. But I wonder how strictly you work against my enemies."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As discreetly as possible Jerrell pulled on the aether, gathering power. "Lord, let me request again, set me back on the ground unharmed."[NEWLINE]Decius did so. "Just as I thought. You turn your power on me at a moment's chance, faithless dog."[NEWLINE]The sorcerer bent over, panting. "Only in self-defense. When you come to your senses we can ignore this rashness."[NEWLINE]"You have perverted my senses with your charms, traitor. Much as I wish to strike you down here and now for that affront, I just can't bring myself to. I am compelled to do you no direct harm. The most I can do is refrain from waving at that mercenary I hired to wait up the path."[NEWLINE]"What?" Decius stepped back and a crossbow bolt buried itself in the sorcerer's chest. Decius shook his head sharply and kicked the man into the bay.[NEWLINE]The sergeant of the Guild of the Nine slung his crossbow and came up to Decius. "You did not give the signal, lord. As you said, this meant the wizard was to die."[NEWLINE]"Thank you, Rone. I think we need to talk about expanding our contract." He sighed wearily. "My lands have need of a purge."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Falamar pushed through the crowded wharf. His boyish charms long gone, his seasoned features nonetheless drew every female eye in the crowd even before they recognized his royal garb. This time he returned no longing gazes, intent on the foreign ship preparing to leave. Its owner was boarding now, he saw. An old soldier in search of a battleground. "Decius!" The emperor of Myrh turned. He looked at Falamar a moment, then turned his back on him, issuing orders to his Captain and a man wearing mercenary colors. Falamar was undeterred by the rudeness, striding aboard. "Decius, you've threatened my wife, the Queen, and brought violence to my streets."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius gave the old pirate his attention, folding his arms across his chest as he said, "What of it Falamar?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"If you were my vassal instead of my ally, I'd keel haul you."[NEWLINE]"You can try to arrange that, if you'd like."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Like it? What I'd like is to help you, you arrogant, plagueboil. To have you help us. What have we done to earn your distrust?"[NEWLINE]Decius snorted. "My empire is more diverse than Kylorin's at its height. The Malakim remnants, ambitious vampires, Sheaim refugees, lost angels, Elven revolutionaries. Do you think I hold it together by trust? There is no trust on Erebus, only strength and will."[NEWLINE]"There was one who put his trust in you once, if the stories are true."[NEWLINE]Decius grabbed the collar of Falamar's coat. "More the fool, him! Death is my sword and deceit is my shield. There's naught but misery in my wake." The crew of the vessel paused their work, staring at the argument. Decius waved at them dismissively.[NEWLINE]"Is that a boast or a lament?" Falamar replied, unperturbed.[NEWLINE]Decius turned and leaned against the railing, gazing at the horizon. Falamar waited until finally he turned back. "What was it all for?"[NEWLINE]"You brought us the Nether blade, old comrade in arms, upon the bleakest battlefield I've ever seen. Were it not for that-and everything that led to that--there may be no civilization upon this world."[NEWLINE]"I fought my whole life to be in control. In the end, did I make a single choice of consequence? Every decision I made--every betrayal, every death, every show of mercy or burst of inspiration, all just so you could thrust that damned blade into Auric? We're all puppets."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That's not exactly how it went down-nevermind, I like your version." Falamar inhaled the sea breeze deeply. "Every time I step on a boat, she calls to me. The siren song of my first lover, she says 'Falamar, Falamar, away with me forever! You were not made to be a worm shackled to the dirt, dance upon the waves and be free.'" A smile played upon his lips as he gazed briefly back towards the Heron Throne looking down on them. "And yet, I always return. I get every breath of wind into my sails so I can step upon this shore and return to give counsel and succor to my wife and queen. Which is freer self? The one that heeds his whims or the one stays bound to vow made years ago?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius shrugged. "It'll take a greater bard than you to convince me the meaning of life is true love."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No, that's not what I'm getting at. We may be the playthings of greater beings--fine. But at the end of it all, we are what we choose to do. You are at another cross-road. Take a leap of faith, here, friend. You may lose something by trusting, but you will certainly lose everything if you descend into paranoia."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Decius grit his teeth, wavering. He remembered another boat in a Lanun port, long ago, where he had faced the choice of light or dark. After a time he said "Well. Give my official apologies to Rhoanna, please. I believe I came off as more antagonistic then I had intended."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Falamar smiled briefly. "I suppose I'll take that." Decius turned, and Falamar said, "Wait, that's not all. I have a clue to the Overlords. Two, actually. I think Rhoanna mentioned the Isle to you. There's something else, and I need your help. A wizard, or sorcerer, or something. Last seen in the Umbra Woods. He may be the key. I need you to find this man, this. Hemah."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_GAIUS</Tag>
		<English>Gaius Octavius</English>
		<French>Gaius Octavius</French>
		<German>Gaius Octavius</German>
		<Italian>Gaius Octavius</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gaius Octavius</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_GAIUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Brothers and sisters, citizens of the Bannor! I am Inquisitor Gaius Octavius, Greatest of the Bannor, True Chosen of Junil, Bearer of the Banner of Racial Purity!  The old leaders have failed us! We have escaped Hell, but its dark temptations and whispers haunt every corner of Erebus! I need not speak of the wicked heresies of the Veil, the depraved rites of the Overlords, the mad goals of the White Hand, or the shadowy lies of Esus, for all good servants of the Order know to put the vile believers of such madness to the blade! They should continue to do so, of course, but there is more work to be done!
I have seen, with my own very eyes, the dark secrets of the so-called "Brother Religions."  The Empyrean, the Fellowship, the Runes, all are as wicked and corrupt as the ritualists of the Ashen Veil, though they hide their own evils far more efecctively.  But nevertheless, their sins must be purged from this world, lest they corrupt this world, twisting it into their own depraved image!
The Empyrean would have us believe they seek "wisdom" and enlightenment. Lies, lies, lies! Within the halls of the Overcouncil, the elders of this false religion scheme to strip the righteous nations of this world of their sovregnity, of their independence, of the power they need to hold back the forces of Hell, forcing us to rely upon them for our defense! Our armies shall be disbanded, replaced by foreign-born Radiant Guardsmen! They shall seduce your daughters, impregnating them with the seeds of tainted blood! Say no to the Overcouncil, no to foreign goods, no to the dilution of the Bannor bloodlines!
The Runes of Kilmorph are naught but a Dwarvern religion! Need I remind you, that dwarves are sub-humans, wretched, impure, vile creatures, as bad as the foul Orcs? Every time the price of corn goes up, a Dwarf is behind it! Dwarvern councilmen play the Overcouncil just as surely as the rapacious Empyrean, though their motivation even more base than the desire for Bannor women. Nay, though none would doubt they'd have your daughters given the chance, their dreams are of gold, Bannor gold flowing into their vaults. Greed drives the Dwarvern race, to the man, and their religion is built upon this disgusting greed. All who worship the Runes of Mammon are dwarves, say I, in soul if not in body than in soul. Every Bannor who kneels before an earthen altar is a traitor! Send these abominations to Hell, says I!
Though they almost appear human, the Elves are no better than the Dwarves. And so to is their religion; the Fellowship of Leaves is built upon bloody sacrifice and cruel hunts! Honorable men are set loose, then hunted by elves and the traitors who have given their souls to the Fellowship! Some claim I have no proof of these claims, but that is only because they hide it, so enchanted by Elven whores, older than their own grandmothers, they'd give their pureborn sons and daughters to the bloodstained altars hidden deep within the sacred groves of the Fellowship!
Our old leaders will not put these "lesser" heretics to steel, as they so rightly deserve! They show restraint and mercy to those who only deserve suffering and death! I, Inquisitor Gaius, alone, stand against the tide of heresy disguised as "tolerance" and "diplomacy." Know this, brothers and sisters of the Bannor, that I am your only hope! Unite behind me! Know that the corrupt Bannor leadership fears me! They refused to allow me to take up arms the military, accusing me of being "mentally unfit for duty" because I refused to kneel down before a officers drawn from peasantry and foreigners. They kicked me out of the Temple of the Order when I began to ask questions they feared to answer, also accusing me of madness! Is it madness to ask why the inquisitors are not out in full force, why our taxes feed unbelievers and foreign-blooded mongrels? Follow me, and we shall restore the Church and the Nation to its true glory!</English>
		<French>Brothers and sisters, citizens of the Bannor! I am Inquisitor Gaius Octavius, Greatest of the Bannor, True Chosen of Junil, Bearer of the Banner of Racial Purity!  The old leaders have failed us! We have escaped Hell, but its dark temptations and whispers haunt every corner of Erebus! I need not speak of the wicked heresies of the Veil, the depraved rites of the Overlords, the mad goals of the White Hand, or the shadowy lies of Esus, for all good servants of the Order know to put the vile believers of such madness to the blade! They should continue to do so, of course, but there is more work to be done!
I have seen, with my own very eyes, the dark secrets of the so-called "Brother Religions."  The Empyrean, the Fellowship, the Runes, all are as wicked and corrupt as the ritualists of the Ashen Veil, though they hide their own evils far more efecctively.  But nevertheless, their sins must be purged from this world, lest they corrupt this world, twisting it into their own depraved image!
The Empyrean would have us believe they seek "wisdom" and enlightenment. Lies, lies, lies! Within the halls of the Overcouncil, the elders of this false religion scheme to strip the righteous nations of this world of their sovregnity, of their independence, of the power they need to hold back the forces of Hell, forcing us to rely upon them for our defense! Our armies shall be disbanded, replaced by foreign-born Radiant Guardsmen! They shall seduce your daughters, impregnating them with the seeds of tainted blood! Say no to the Overcouncil, no to foreign goods, no to the dilution of the Bannor bloodlines!
The Runes of Kilmorph are naught but a Dwarvern religion! Need I remind you, that dwarves are sub-humans, wretched, impure, vile creatures, as bad as the foul Orcs? Every time the price of corn goes up, a Dwarf is behind it! Dwarvern councilmen play the Overcouncil just as surely as the rapacious Empyrean, though their motivation even more base than the desire for Bannor women. Nay, though none would doubt they'd have your daughters given the chance, their dreams are of gold, Bannor gold flowing into their vaults. Greed drives the Dwarvern race, to the man, and their religion is built upon this disgusting greed. All who worship the Runes of Mammon are dwarves, say I, in soul if not in body than in soul. Every Bannor who kneels before an earthen altar is a traitor! Send these abominations to Hell, says I!
Though they almost appear human, the Elves are no better than the Dwarves. And so to is their religion; the Fellowship of Leaves is built upon bloody sacrifice and cruel hunts! Honorable men are set loose, then hunted by elves and the traitors who have given their souls to the Fellowship! Some claim I have no proof of these claims, but that is only because they hide it, so enchanted by Elven whores, older than their own grandmothers, they'd give their pureborn sons and daughters to the bloodstained altars hidden deep within the sacred groves of the Fellowship!
Our old leaders will not put these "lesser" heretics to steel, as they so rightly deserve! They show restraint and mercy to those who only deserve suffering and death! I, Inquisitor Gaius, alone, stand against the tide of heresy disguised as "tolerance" and "diplomacy." Know this, brothers and sisters of the Bannor, that I am your only hope! Unite behind me! Know that the corrupt Bannor leadership fears me! They refused to allow me to take up arms the military, accusing me of being "mentally unfit for duty" because I refused to kneel down before a officers drawn from peasantry and foreigners. They kicked me out of the Temple of the Order when I began to ask questions they feared to answer, also accusing me of madness! Is it madness to ask why the inquisitors are not out in full force, why our taxes feed unbelievers and foreign-blooded mongrels? Follow me, and we shall restore the Church and the Nation to its true glory!</French>
		<German>Brothers and sisters, citizens of the Bannor! I am Inquisitor Gaius Octavius, Greatest of the Bannor, True Chosen of Junil, Bearer of the Banner of Racial Purity!  The old leaders have failed us! We have escaped Hell, but its dark temptations and whispers haunt every corner of Erebus! I need not speak of the wicked heresies of the Veil, the depraved rites of the Overlords, the mad goals of the White Hand, or the shadowy lies of Esus, for all good servants of the Order know to put the vile believers of such madness to the blade! They should continue to do so, of course, but there is more work to be done!
		I have seen, with my own very eyes, the dark secrets of the so-called "Brother Religions."  The Empyrean, the Fellowship, the Runes, all are as wicked and corrupt as the ritualists of the Ashen Veil, though they hide their own evils far more efecctively.  But nevertheless, their sins must be purged from this world, lest they corrupt this world, twisting it into their own depraved image!
		The Empyrean would have us believe they seek "wisdom" and enlightenment. Lies, lies, lies! Within the halls of the Overcouncil, the elders of this false religion scheme to strip the righteous nations of this world of their sovregnity, of their independence, of the power they need to hold back the forces of Hell, forcing us to rely upon them for our defense! Our armies shall be disbanded, replaced by foreign-born Radiant Guardsmen! They shall seduce your daughters, impregnating them with the seeds of tainted blood! Say no to the Overcouncil, no to foreign goods, no to the dilution of the Bannor bloodlines!
		The Runes of Kilmorph are naught but a Dwarvern religion! Need I remind you, that dwarves are sub-humans, wretched, impure, vile creatures, as bad as the foul Orcs? Every time the price of corn goes up, a Dwarf is behind it! Dwarvern councilmen play the Overcouncil just as surely as the rapacious Empyrean, though their motivation even more base than the desire for Bannor women. Nay, though none would doubt they'd have your daughters given the chance, their dreams are of gold, Bannor gold flowing into their vaults. Greed drives the Dwarvern race, to the man, and their religion is built upon this disgusting greed. All who worship the Runes of Mammon are dwarves, say I, in soul if not in body than in soul. Every Bannor who kneels before an earthen altar is a traitor! Send these abominations to Hell, says I!
		Though they almost appear human, the Elves are no better than the Dwarves. And so to is their religion; the Fellowship of Leaves is built upon bloody sacrifice and cruel hunts! Honorable men are set loose, then hunted by elves and the traitors who have given their souls to the Fellowship! Some claim I have no proof of these claims, but that is only because they hide it, so enchanted by Elven whores, older than their own grandmothers, they'd give their pureborn sons and daughters to the bloodstained altars hidden deep within the sacred groves of the Fellowship!
		Our old leaders will not put these "lesser" heretics to steel, as they so rightly deserve! They show restraint and mercy to those who only deserve suffering and death! I, Inquisitor Gaius, alone, stand against the tide of heresy disguised as "tolerance" and "diplomacy." Know this, brothers and sisters of the Bannor, that I am your only hope! Unite behind me! Know that the corrupt Bannor leadership fears me! They refused to allow me to take up arms the military, accusing me of being "mentally unfit for duty" because I refused to kneel down before a officers drawn from peasantry and foreigners. They kicked me out of the Temple of the Order when I began to ask questions they feared to answer, also accusing me of madness! Is it madness to ask why the inquisitors are not out in full force, why our taxes feed unbelievers and foreign-blooded mongrels? Follow me, and we shall restore the Church and the Nation to its true glory!</German>
		<Italian>Fratelli e sorelle, cittadini Bannor! Io sono l'Inquisitore Gaius Octavius, il più Grande dei Bannor, il Vero Prescelto di Junil, il Portatore dello Stendardo della Purezza Razziale!  I vecchi leader sono venuti meno ai loro compiti! Siamo sfuggiti all'Inferno, ma le sue tentazioni oscure e i suoi sussurri infestano ogni angolo di Erebus! Non vi è bisogno che parli delle nefande eresie del Velo, dei depravati riti dei Padroni, dei folli obiettivi della Mano Bianca o delle oscure menzogne di Esus, perché tutti i bravi servitori dell'Ordine sanno che i vili seguaci di tali follie vanno passati a fil di spada! E si deve continuare a farlo, ovviamente, ma c'è anche molto altro lavoro da fare!
		Io ho visto, con i miei stessi occhi, gli oscuri segreti delle cosidette "Religioni Sorelle".  L'Empireo, la Confraternita, le Rune, tutte loro sono perverse e corrotte quanto i ritualisti del Velo Cinereo, sebbene nascondano le loro malvagità con maggiore abilità.  Ciononostante i loro peccati vanno eliminati da questo mondo in modo che non possano corromperlo, tramutandolo nella loro visione depravata!
		L'Empireo ci vuole far credere che stia cercando la "saggezza" e l'illuminazione. Bugie, bugie, bugie! Dentro le sale del Consiglio Supremo, gli anziani di questa falsa religione complottano per strappare alle nazioni giuste la loro sovranità, la loro indipendenza, e la forza necessaria a tenere a bada le forze dell'Inferno, costringendoci a fare affidamento a loro per la nostra difesa! I nostri eserciti verranno congedati e rimpiazzati da Guardie Radiose nate all'estero! Ed esse sedurranno le vostre figlie, ingravidandole con il seme di un sangue corrotto! Dite no al Consiglio Supremo, no alle merci straniere e no alla diluizione del sangue Bannor!
		Le Rune di Kilmorph non è altro che una religione Nanica! Devo forse ricordarvi che, i nani sono sub-umani, meschini, impuri, vili e cattivi quanto gli schifosi Orchi? Ogni volta che il prezzo del mais sale, vi è un Nano dietro all'aumento! I consiglieri Nanici indirizzano il Consiglio Supremo esattamente come gli ingordi Empirei, anche se le loro motivazioni sono più infime del desiderio delle donne Bannor. No, anche se nessuno dubiterebbe del fatto che, se ne avessero la possibilità, prenderebberò le vostre figlie, i loro sogni sono per l'oro, l'oro Bannor che finisce nelle loro sale sotterranee. L'avidità guida la razza nanica, e la loro religione è costruita su questa disgustosa avidità. Tutti quelli che venerano le Rune di Mammon sono nani, io dico, nell'anima se non nel corpo. Qualunque Bannor che si inginocchia davanti a un'altare di terra è un traditore! Spediamo questi abomini all'Inferno, io dico!
		Anche se sembrano quasi umani, gli Elfi non sono meglio dei Nani. E così è la loro religione; La Confraternità delle Foglie si fonda su sanguinosi sacrifici e cacce crudeli! Uomini onorevoli vengono liberati per poi essere cacciati dagli elfi e dai traditori che hanno dato la loro anima alla Confraternità! Alcuni sostengono che non ho alcuna prova a favore di quello che dico, ma questo è solo perché loro lo nascondono, e talmente sono incantati dalle prostitute Elfiche, che sono più vecchie delle loro nonne, che offrono i loro figli e le loro figlie agli altari insanguinati nascosti in profondita all'interno dei boschi sacri della Confraternità!
		I nostri vecchi leader non passeranno a fil di spada questi eretici "minori", come loro giustamente meritano! Ma mostrano moderazione e misericordia a coloro che meritano solo la sofferenza e la morte! Io, Inquisitore Gaius, da solo, mi ergo contro questa corrente eretica travestita da "tolleranza" e "diplomazia". Sappiate questo, fratelli e sorelle Bannor, che io sono la vostra unica speranza! Unitevi a me! Sappiate che la corrotta dirigenza Bannor mi teme! Non mi hanno permesso di unirmi all'esercito, accusandomi di essere "mentalmente inadatto al dovere" perché rifiutai di inginocchiarmi davanti a un ufficiale nato contadino o nato all'estero. Mi hanno cacciato dal Tempio dell'Ordine quando iniziai a fare domande a cui avevano paura di rispondere, inoltre accusandomi di pazzia! È pazzia chiedere perché gli inquisitori non sono in giro al massimo della loro potenza, perché le nostre tasse nutrono i miscredenti e bastardi dal suangue misto? Seguitemi, e ripristineremo la Chiesa e la Nazione alla loro vera gloria!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Brothers and sisters, citizens of the Bannor! I am Inquisitor Gaius Octavius, Greatest of the Bannor, True Chosen of Junil, Bearer of the Banner of Racial Purity!  The old leaders have failed us! We have escaped Hell, but its dark temptations and whispers haunt every corner of Erebus! I need not speak of the wicked heresies of the Veil, the depraved rites of the Overlords, the mad goals of the White Hand, or the shadowy lies of Esus, for all good servants of the Order know to put the vile believers of such madness to the blade! They should continue to do so, of course, but there is more work to be done!
I have seen, with my own very eyes, the dark secrets of the so-called "Brother Religions."  The Empyrean, the Fellowship, the Runes, all are as wicked and corrupt as the ritualists of the Ashen Veil, though they hide their own evils far more efecctively.  But nevertheless, their sins must be purged from this world, lest they corrupt this world, twisting it into their own depraved image!
The Empyrean would have us believe they seek "wisdom" and enlightenment. Lies, lies, lies! Within the halls of the Overcouncil, the elders of this false religion scheme to strip the righteous nations of this world of their sovregnity, of their independence, of the power they need to hold back the forces of Hell, forcing us to rely upon them for our defense! Our armies shall be disbanded, replaced by foreign-born Radiant Guardsmen! They shall seduce your daughters, impregnating them with the seeds of tainted blood! Say no to the Overcouncil, no to foreign goods, no to the dilution of the Bannor bloodlines!
The Runes of Kilmorph are naught but a Dwarvern religion! Need I remind you, that dwarves are sub-humans, wretched, impure, vile creatures, as bad as the foul Orcs? Every time the price of corn goes up, a Dwarf is behind it! Dwarvern councilmen play the Overcouncil just as surely as the rapacious Empyrean, though their motivation even more base than the desire for Bannor women. Nay, though none would doubt they'd have your daughters given the chance, their dreams are of gold, Bannor gold flowing into their vaults. Greed drives the Dwarvern race, to the man, and their religion is built upon this disgusting greed. All who worship the Runes of Mammon are dwarves, say I, in soul if not in body than in soul. Every Bannor who kneels before an earthen altar is a traitor! Send these abominations to Hell, says I!
Though they almost appear human, the Elves are no better than the Dwarves. And so to is their religion; the Fellowship of Leaves is built upon bloody sacrifice and cruel hunts! Honorable men are set loose, then hunted by elves and the traitors who have given their souls to the Fellowship! Some claim I have no proof of these claims, but that is only because they hide it, so enchanted by Elven whores, older than their own grandmothers, they'd give their pureborn sons and daughters to the bloodstained altars hidden deep within the sacred groves of the Fellowship!
Our old leaders will not put these "lesser" heretics to steel, as they so rightly deserve! They show restraint and mercy to those who only deserve suffering and death! I, Inquisitor Gaius, alone, stand against the tide of heresy disguised as "tolerance" and "diplomacy." Know this, brothers and sisters of the Bannor, that I am your only hope! Unite behind me! Know that the corrupt Bannor leadership fears me! They refused to allow me to take up arms the military, accusing me of being "mentally unfit for duty" because I refused to kneel down before a officers drawn from peasantry and foreigners. They kicked me out of the Temple of the Order when I began to ask questions they feared to answer, also accusing me of madness! Is it madness to ask why the inquisitors are not out in full force, why our taxes feed unbelievers and foreign-blooded mongrels? Follow me, and we shall restore the Church and the Nation to its true glory!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_OPHELIA</Tag>
		<English>Ophelia Rosenthal</English>
		<French>Ophelia Rosenthal</French>
		<German>Ophelia Rosenthal</German>
		<Italian>Ophelia Rosenthal</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ophelia Rosenthal</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_OPHELIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>If leading the Scions, Ophelia has the opportunity to take the Gift, adding the [LINK=TRAIT_DEATHTOUCHED]Deathtouched[\LINK] and [LINK=TRAIT_PERSONALITY_CULT]Personality Cult[\LINK] traits.
			They had left her.
			They had escaped where she had remained. Lost, cold, and alone, Ophelia had seen the bloodshed caused by both man and demon alike, and in this hell, the memories faded together where she could neither separate the demon from the man. Even Donal, the one whom had stayed behind, was as brutal and if not more lethal than the demons that chased her through the wastes.
			But neither demon nor man would ever find her. Having been abandoned, Ophelia had abandoned many of the Bannor's fanatical approaches to survival. And it was because of this that for the first time since she had fought alongside Capria as a Secondline-Woman, she had felt the surge of hope that was nonexistent in the place like this. In this hell where she had been abandoned, she had adapted.
			"Perhaps you are more like that fool Donal than you care to admit, Ms. Rosenthal." The voice was quick to shatter her mood as she spun around, the blade in her hand chipped and stained with the blood of many. But it pointed at nothing but the dusty winds, no foe whispering in her ear, no beast that warranted her sword through its chest. Her eyes darted to and fro, seeing nothing on the horizon.
			Seeing nothing but hearing the sounds of rope tearing, rocks tumbling against one another and the inevitable shattering as her traps had been destroyed by something. The sounds echoed across the broken fields, as Ophelia stood there watching precious hours of her labor be destroyed. As the last rock tumbled down from her makeshift rockslide, she knew that this would go on. That fleeting moment of hope was gone.
			It had been replaced by something far more sinister. A cold burning sensation on her soul. Perhaps it was the machinations of countless generations that had pushed her to this edge, or perhaps it was something else. But escape was the only option. Her head filled itself with ideas, plots, theories that she hadn't conceived before. But each idea, each thought, was foreign and malicious.
			And it was these ideas that had whispered in her ear the only way out of hell, was to be gated out. The path up Mulcarn's domain was too slow- she needed to be free of this wretched place. The seductive whispers of freedom filled her mind as the wastelands grew smaller to her, each step no longer taking the effort of a hundred and each day spent in the red haze she had been left in grew shorter as she found herself taking an almost macabre ecstasy from breaking each demon not of their strength, but of their will. She relished in the confusion and frustration as the enemy lost her trail, and laughed at their incompetence as she followed the whispering winds of the hells.
			Time held no meaning for Ophelia as she slipped from one vault, moving in the shadows and slipping by unnoticed. Demons no longer paid heed to her, mistaking her for another petitioner as she pushed between vaults and into her ultimate goal- the Vault of Cerdiwen. The whispers had told her where to go, how to get there, the sigils and mysteries she would need to decipher and ultimately, the way to navigate the vault. But no whisper, no false hope, no burning desire could prepare her as she slipped into the unmentionable abyss. She saw everything in the maelstrom and webways, secrets that pushed her mind to break and then break again, her perceptions shattered every instant. She perceived Furia's torture from the view of the Balseraph angel, gazed through the eyes of Nemed as he twisted and writhed in excruciating pain under the will of Os-Gabella, and felt Flauros pierce her flesh as Taerry, the poor Calabim girl whom was nothing more than a plaything the aristocrat. But to Ophelia, she was all of these people and had seen everything through their eyes. Their pain, their fears, their sorrows, but also their hopes, their dreams, and the futures that could have been. Ophelia didn't know if this was from the whispers or from Cerdiwen herself preying upon the trespassing Bannor, but she no longer cared as her lungs were filled with cold, crisp air. She was on Erebus again. But she had seen the visions of millions of souls, gazed into the very Avatar of Wrath as he was being formed. Things a mere mortal was never meant to see. And her very being was no longer part of her. Her gaze, where it had once been both frightened but and hopeful was now left sinister and distant. Her voice was controlled and her tone pert and quick, her temper now short but her reactions to be thought out and executed with precision. She was no longer Ophelia Rosenthal, but rather the sum of what she had seen.</English>
		<French>Ophelia has the opportunity to take the Gift if leading the Scions, adding the [LINK=TRAIT_DEATHTOUCHED]Deathtouched[\LINK], [LINK=TRAIT_AGNOSTIC]Agnostic[\LINK], and [LINK=TRAIT_PERSONALITY_CULT]Personality Cult[\LINK] traits.
			They had left her.
			They had escaped where she had remained. Lost, cold, and alone, Ophelia had seen the bloodshed caused by both man and demon alike, and in this hell, the memories faded together where she could neither separate the demon from the man. Even Donal, the one whom had stayed behind, was as brutal and if not more lethal than the demons that chased her through the wastes.
			But neither demon nor man would ever find her. Having been abandoned, Ophelia had abandoned many of the Bannor's fanatical approaches to survival. And it was because of this that for the first time since she had fought alongside Capria as a Secondline-Woman, she had felt the surge of hope that was nonexistent in the place like this. In this hell where she had been abandoned, she had adapted.
			"Perhaps you are more like that fool Donal than you care to admit, Ms. Rosenthal." The voice was quick to shatter her mood as she spun around, the blade in her hand chipped and stained with the blood of many. But it pointed at nothing but the dusty winds, no foe whispering in her ear, no beast that warranted her sword through its chest. Her eyes darted to and fro, seeing nothing on the horizon.
			Seeing nothing but hearing the sounds of rope tearing, rocks tumbling against one another and the inevitable shattering as her traps had been destroyed by something. The sounds echoed across the broken fields, as Ophelia stood there watching precious hours of her labor be destroyed. As the last rock tumbled down from her makeshift rockslide, she knew that this would go on. That fleeting moment of hope was gone.
			It had been replaced by something far more sinister. A cold burning sensation on her soul. Perhaps it was the machinations of countless generations that had pushed her to this edge, or perhaps it was something else. But escape was the only option. Her head filled itself with ideas, plots, theories that she hadn't conceived before. But each idea, each thought, was foreign and malicious.
			And it was these ideas that had whispered in her ear the only way out of hell, was to be gated out. The path up Mulcarn's domain was too slow- she needed to be free of this wretched place. The seductive whispers of freedom filled her mind as the wastelands grew smaller to her, each step no longer taking the effort of a hundred and each day spent in the red haze she had been left in grew shorter as she found herself taking an almost macabre ecstasy from breaking each demon not of their strength, but of their will. She relished in the confusion and frustration as the enemy lost her trail, and laughed at their incompetence as she followed the whispering winds of the hells.
			Time held no meaning for Ophelia as she slipped from one vault, moving in the shadows and slipping by unnoticed. Demons no longer paid heed to her, mistaking her for another petitioner as she pushed between vaults and into her ultimate goal- the Vault of Cerdiwen. The whispers had told her where to go, how to get there, the sigils and mysteries she would need to decipher and ultimately, the way to navigate the vault. But no whisper, no false hope, no burning desire could prepare her as she slipped into the unmentionable abyss. She saw everything in the maelstrom and webways, secrets that pushed her mind to break and then break again, her perceptions shattered every instant. She perceived Furia's torture from the view of the Balseraph angel, gazed through the eyes of Nemed as he twisted and writhed in excruciating pain under the will of Os-Gabella, and felt Flauros pierce her flesh as Taerry, the poor Calabim girl whom was nothing more than a plaything the aristocrat. But to Ophelia, she was all of these people and had seen everything through their eyes. Their pain, their fears, their sorrows, but also their hopes, their dreams, and the futures that could have been. Ophelia didn't know if this was from the whispers or from Cerdiwen herself preying upon the trespassing Bannor, but she no longer cared as her lungs were filled with cold, crisp air. She was on Erebus again. But she had seen the visions of millions of souls, gazed into the very Avatar of Wrath as he was being formed. Things a mere mortal was never meant to see. And her very being was no longer part of her. Her gaze, where it had once been both frightened but and hopeful was now left sinister and distant. Her voice was controlled and her tone pert and quick, her temper now short but her reactions to be thought out and executed with precision. She was no longer Ophelia Rosenthal, but rather the sum of what she had seen.</French>
		<German>Ophelia has the opportunity to take the Gift if leading the Scions, adding the [LINK=TRAIT_DEATHTOUCHED]Deathtouched[\LINK], [LINK=TRAIT_AGNOSTIC]Agnostic[\LINK], and [LINK=TRAIT_PERSONALITY_CULT]Personality Cult[\LINK] traits.
			They had left her.
			They had escaped where she had remained. Lost, cold, and alone, Ophelia had seen the bloodshed caused by both man and demon alike, and in this hell, the memories faded together where she could neither separate the demon from the man. Even Donal, the one whom had stayed behind, was as brutal and if not more lethal than the demons that chased her through the wastes.
			But neither demon nor man would ever find her. Having been abandoned, Ophelia had abandoned many of the Bannor's fanatical approaches to survival. And it was because of this that for the first time since she had fought alongside Capria as a Secondline-Woman, she had felt the surge of hope that was nonexistent in the place like this. In this hell where she had been abandoned, she had adapted.
			"Perhaps you are more like that fool Donal than you care to admit, Ms. Rosenthal." The voice was quick to shatter her mood as she spun around, the blade in her hand chipped and stained with the blood of many. But it pointed at nothing but the dusty winds, no foe whispering in her ear, no beast that warranted her sword through its chest. Her eyes darted to and fro, seeing nothing on the horizon.
			Seeing nothing but hearing the sounds of rope tearing, rocks tumbling against one another and the inevitable shattering as her traps had been destroyed by something. The sounds echoed across the broken fields, as Ophelia stood there watching precious hours of her labor be destroyed. As the last rock tumbled down from her makeshift rockslide, she knew that this would go on. That fleeting moment of hope was gone.
			It had been replaced by something far more sinister. A cold burning sensation on her soul. Perhaps it was the machinations of countless generations that had pushed her to this edge, or perhaps it was something else. But escape was the only option. Her head filled itself with ideas, plots, theories that she hadn't conceived before. But each idea, each thought, was foreign and malicious.
			And it was these ideas that had whispered in her ear the only way out of hell, was to be gated out. The path up Mulcarn's domain was too slow- she needed to be free of this wretched place. The seductive whispers of freedom filled her mind as the wastelands grew smaller to her, each step no longer taking the effort of a hundred and each day spent in the red haze she had been left in grew shorter as she found herself taking an almost macabre ecstasy from breaking each demon not of their strength, but of their will. She relished in the confusion and frustration as the enemy lost her trail, and laughed at their incompetence as she followed the whispering winds of the hells.
			Time held no meaning for Ophelia as she slipped from one vault, moving in the shadows and slipping by unnoticed. Demons no longer paid heed to her, mistaking her for another petitioner as she pushed between vaults and into her ultimate goal- the Vault of Cerdiwen. The whispers had told her where to go, how to get there, the sigils and mysteries she would need to decipher and ultimately, the way to navigate the vault. But no whisper, no false hope, no burning desire could prepare her as she slipped into the unmentionable abyss. She saw everything in the maelstrom and webways, secrets that pushed her mind to break and then break again, her perceptions shattered every instant. She perceived Furia's torture from the view of the Balseraph angel, gazed through the eyes of Nemed as he twisted and writhed in excruciating pain under the will of Os-Gabella, and felt Flauros pierce her flesh as Taerry, the poor Calabim girl whom was nothing more than a plaything the aristocrat. But to Ophelia, she was all of these people and had seen everything through their eyes. Their pain, their fears, their sorrows, but also their hopes, their dreams, and the futures that could have been. Ophelia didn't know if this was from the whispers or from Cerdiwen herself preying upon the trespassing Bannor, but she no longer cared as her lungs were filled with cold, crisp air. She was on Erebus again. But she had seen the visions of millions of souls, gazed into the very Avatar of Wrath as he was being formed. Things a mere mortal was never meant to see. And her very being was no longer part of her. Her gaze, where it had once been both frightened but and hopeful was now left sinister and distant. Her voice was controlled and her tone pert and quick, her temper now short but her reactions to be thought out and executed with precision. She was no longer Ophelia Rosenthal, but rather the sum of what she had seen.</German>
		<Italian>Ophelia ha l'opportunità di ricevere il Dono se sta guidando gli Eredi, ottenendo i tratti [LINK=TRAIT_DEATHTOUCHED]Toccato dalla Morte[\LINK], [LINK=TRAIT_AGNOSTIC]Agnostico[\LINK], e [LINK=TRAIT_PERSONALITY_CULT]Culto della Personalità[\LINK].
			La hanno abbandonata.
			Erano scappati da dove lei era rimasta. Smarrita, al freddo e sola, Ophelia aveva visto lo spargimento di sangue causato sia dagli uomini che dai demoni, e in questo inferno, i ricordi si mischiavano tra loro in tal modo che neppure lei riusciva a distinguere il demone dall'uomo. Persino Donal, colui che era rimasto indietro, era brutale quanto se non anche più letale dei demoni che la inseguivano per le distese infernali.
			Ma ne demone ne uomo la avrebberò mai trovata. Essendo stata abbandonata, Ophelia aveva abbandonato molti degli approcci fanatici dei Bannor alla sopravvivenza. E fu per questo che, per la prima volta da quando aveva combattuto al fianco di Capria come Donna di Rinforzo, sentì l'assenza dell'impeto di speranza in posti come questi. In questo inferno, in cui era stata abbandonata, lei si era adattata.
			"Forse sei molto più simile a quello stolto di Donal più di quanto tu voglia ammettere, Ms. Rosenthal." La voce fu rapida a spezzare il suo umore mentre si guardava attorno, la lama nella sua mano era scheggiata e macchiata dal sangue di molti. Ma non c'era altro cui puntarla che vento pieno di polvere, nessuno che gli sussurrava all'orecchio, nessuna bestia che meritasse la sua spada nel petto. I suoi occhi guizzavano da una parte all'altra, non vedendo nulla all'orizzonte.
			Non vedendo niente, ma sentendo il suono di una corda rompersi, di rocce che cascavano l'una su l'altra e l'inevitabile frastuono mentre le sue trappole venivano distrutte da qualcosa. Il rumore echeggiò nelle terre desolate, mentre Ophelia rimaneva a gaurdare ore preziose del suo lavoro venir distrutte. Mentre l'ultima roccia della frana cadeva, sapeva che non avrebbe smesso. Quel fugace momento di speranza era sparito.
			Era stato sostituito da qualcosa di molto più sinistro. Una fredda sensazione di bruciore nella sua anima. Forse erano le machinazioni di innumerevoli generazioni che l'avevano spinta sino a questo punto, o magari è stato qualcosa'altro. Ma la fuga era l'unica opzione. La sua testa si riempì da sola di idee, piani, teorie che non aveva mai pensato prima. Ma ogni idea, ogni pensiero, era estraneo e malizioso.
			E furono queste idee a sussurrargli all'orecchio l'unica via per uscire dall'inferno, doveva essere cacciata via. La strada per il dominio di Mulcarn era troppo lenta, aveva bisogno di essere libera da questo squallido posto. I seducenti sussurri di libertà riempirono la sua mente mentre le lande desolate diventavano più piccole per lei, ogni passo non prendeva più le energie di cento e ogni giorno passato nella foschia rossa diventata sempre più corto mentre si scopriva a provare un'estasi quasi macabra nel rompere non la forza ma la volonta di ogni demone. Si deliziava della confusione e frustrazione che il nemico provava quando perdeva la sua traccia, e rideva della loro incompetenza mentre lei seguiva i venti sussurranti degli inferni.
			Il tempo non aveva alcun significato per Ophelia mentre scivolava da un piano infernale all'altro, muovendosi nelle ombre e passando non vista. I demoni non gli prestavano più attenzione, scambiandola per un'altro supplicante mentre passava attraverso i vari piani per raggiungere il suo obiettivo finale, il Piano di Cerdiwen. I sussurri gli avevano detto dove andare, come fare per andarci, i sigilli e i misteri che avrebbe dovuto decifrare e infine, la strada per muoversi nel piano. Ma nessun sussurro, ne falsa speranza, o desiderio bruciante l'avrebbe potuta preparare al passaggio nell'abisso. Vide ogni cosa in quel vortice, segreti che frantumarono la sua mente ancora e ancora, ciò che percepiva andava in frantumi in ogni istante. Percepì la tortura di Furia dal punto di vista dell'angelo Balseraph, guardò attraverso gli occhi di Nemed mentre si contorceva per via di un dolore lancinante sotto il controllo di Os-Gabella, e sentì Flauros bucare la sua pelle come fosse Taerry, la povera ragazza Calabim che non era altro che un giocattolo per l'aristocratico. Ma Ophelia era stata tutte quelle persone e aveva visto tutto attraverso i loro occhi. Il loro dolore, le loro paure, i loro rimpianti, ma anche le loro speranze, i loro sogni, e i futuri che sarebbero potuti essere. Ophelia non sapeva se fosse per via dei sussurri o per via di Cerdiwen stessa che stava tormentando l'intruso Bannor, ma non se ne curò per molto quando i suoi polmoni si riempirono di un'aria fredda e frizzante. Era di nuovo su Erebus. Ma aveva visto ciò che vedevano milioni di anime, guardò addirittura dentro lo stesso Avatar della Rabbia mentre veniva creato. Cose che un semplice mortale non dovrebbe mai vedere. E il suo stesso essere non era più parte di lei. Il suo sguardo, un tempo sia spaventato che speranzoso era ora sinistro e distante. La sua voce era controllata e il suo tono era impertinente e veloce, il suo umore era repentino, ma le sue reazioni pensate ed eseguite con precisione. Lei non era più Ophelia Rosenthal, ma piuttosto la somma di tutto ciò che aveva visto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ophelia has the opportunity to take the Gift if leading the Scions, adding the [LINK=TRAIT_DEATHTOUCHED]Deathtouched[\LINK], [LINK=TRAIT_AGNOSTIC]Agnostic[\LINK], and [LINK=TRAIT_PERSONALITY_CULT]Personality Cult[\LINK] traits.
			They had left her.
			They had escaped where she had remained. Lost, cold, and alone, Ophelia had seen the bloodshed caused by both man and demon alike, and in this hell, the memories faded together where she could neither separate the demon from the man. Even Donal, the one whom had stayed behind, was as brutal and if not more lethal than the demons that chased her through the wastes.
			But neither demon nor man would ever find her. Having been abandoned, Ophelia had abandoned many of the Bannor's fanatical approaches to survival. And it was because of this that for the first time since she had fought alongside Capria as a Secondline-Woman, she had felt the surge of hope that was nonexistent in the place like this. In this hell where she had been abandoned, she had adapted.
			"Perhaps you are more like that fool Donal than you care to admit, Ms. Rosenthal." The voice was quick to shatter her mood as she spun around, the blade in her hand chipped and stained with the blood of many. But it pointed at nothing but the dusty winds, no foe whispering in her ear, no beast that warranted her sword through its chest. Her eyes darted to and fro, seeing nothing on the horizon.
			Seeing nothing but hearing the sounds of rope tearing, rocks tumbling against one another and the inevitable shattering as her traps had been destroyed by something. The sounds echoed across the broken fields, as Ophelia stood there watching precious hours of her labor be destroyed. As the last rock tumbled down from her makeshift rockslide, she knew that this would go on. That fleeting moment of hope was gone.
			It had been replaced by something far more sinister. A cold burning sensation on her soul. Perhaps it was the machinations of countless generations that had pushed her to this edge, or perhaps it was something else. But escape was the only option. Her head filled itself with ideas, plots, theories that she hadn't conceived before. But each idea, each thought, was foreign and malicious.
			And it was these ideas that had whispered in her ear the only way out of hell, was to be gated out. The path up Mulcarn's domain was too slow- she needed to be free of this wretched place. The seductive whispers of freedom filled her mind as the wastelands grew smaller to her, each step no longer taking the effort of a hundred and each day spent in the red haze she had been left in grew shorter as she found herself taking an almost macabre ecstasy from breaking each demon not of their strength, but of their will. She relished in the confusion and frustration as the enemy lost her trail, and laughed at their incompetence as she followed the whispering winds of the hells.
			Time held no meaning for Ophelia as she slipped from one vault, moving in the shadows and slipping by unnoticed. Demons no longer paid heed to her, mistaking her for another petitioner as she pushed between vaults and into her ultimate goal- the Vault of Cerdiwen. The whispers had told her where to go, how to get there, the sigils and mysteries she would need to decipher and ultimately, the way to navigate the vault. But no whisper, no false hope, no burning desire could prepare her as she slipped into the unmentionable abyss. She saw everything in the maelstrom and webways, secrets that pushed her mind to break and then break again, her perceptions shattered every instant. She perceived Furia's torture from the view of the Balseraph angel, gazed through the eyes of Nemed as he twisted and writhed in excruciating pain under the will of Os-Gabella, and felt Flauros pierce her flesh as Taerry, the poor Calabim girl whom was nothing more than a plaything the aristocrat. But to Ophelia, she was all of these people and had seen everything through their eyes. Their pain, their fears, their sorrows, but also their hopes, their dreams, and the futures that could have been. Ophelia didn't know if this was from the whispers or from Cerdiwen herself preying upon the trespassing Bannor, but she no longer cared as her lungs were filled with cold, crisp air. She was on Erebus again. But she had seen the visions of millions of souls, gazed into the very Avatar of Wrath as he was being formed. Things a mere mortal was never meant to see. And her very being was no longer part of her. Her gaze, where it had once been both frightened but and hopeful was now left sinister and distant. Her voice was controlled and her tone pert and quick, her temper now short but her reactions to be thought out and executed with precision. She was no longer Ophelia Rosenthal, but rather the sum of what she had seen.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SABATHIEL</Tag>
		<English>Sabathiel</English>
		<French>Sabathiel</French>
		<German>Sabathiel</German>
		<Italian>Sabathiel</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sabathiel</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SABATHIEL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Shaddis slipped quietly into the room. Although not comparable to the vast antechambers and lofty halls of the public part of the Halls of Sabathiel, the room was large enough, roughly cubic and a good six meters from floor to roof. The roof was vaulted, with supporting columns built into the four walls, dividing each wall into three segments.[PARAGRAPH:1]The room was also plunged into darkness, something which simply drew your attention to the fact that the huge figure lying on a carved stone bed in the centre of the room was emitting a faint glow. Sabathiel was sleeping again. He'd probably been sleeping since last Shaddis spoke to him, two weeks ago. [PARAGRAPH:1]It wasn't really sleep, Shaddis reflected. He wasn't quite sure what it was. It was like Sabathiel's body was there, on the stone bed, but his mind and soul weren't. The Deacon of Winds had never asked Sabathiel where his mind went when he lay like that. He wasn't sure he wanted to know. [PARAGRAPH:1]As Shaddis approached, there was a sucking sound, like a sharp intake of air, and Sabathiel sat bolt upright with startling suddenness. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Something has happened."[PARAGRAPH:1]The voice sounded like a million voices speaking softly at the same time, and it carried a note of simultaneous accusation and certainty that infuriated Shaddis. Sabathiel was scrutinizing him, probably finding out what was wrong even before Shaddis had a chance to say it. And the angel was right, both in the statement and in the accusatory tone. Something HAD happened, and Shaddis was at fault, albeit indirectly. [PARAGRAPH:1]"They will be punished, of course. We must teach them that they cannot defy Law and hope to avoid repercussions. But I am disappointed in you, deacon. You knew about this. You could have stopped it earlier." [PARAGRAPH:1]Shaddis bowed his head in shame. He had known, but he hadn't found it important. Dealing with it at this early stage would have required taking appalling measures. So he had left the problem alone, hoping it would burn itself out. Instead it had exploded. The cleaning up would be a mess.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel floated to his feet. As he did, the room erupted with multi-hued light. The sight never ceased to awe Shaddis. Every section of wall was now a huge window looking out across a landscape far below. It was as if the room was at the top of an impossibly tall tower. But the view was not uniform. Each window overlooked a different landscape: In one window, all you could see was mountains, ice and snow. Another showed rolling hills, fields and peaceful pastures. A third looked out across an endless desert. [PARAGRAPH:1]The angelic ruler of the Bannor drifted across to a window that showed the sprawling urban vista of the capital. He stood there in silence, his hands clasped behind his back, for quite some time. Shaddis didn't speak. Holding a conversation with Sabathiel was a frustrating affair-the angel knew what you were going to say before you said it, and generally answered before you even had a chance to open your mouth. So the Deacon waited patiently for his master to break the silence. [PARAGRAPH:1]Finally, Sabathiel let out a long, shuddering sigh. It reminded Shaddis of a wind whistling through a mountain pass. Still facing his city, Sabathiel started to speak: [PARAGRAPH:1]"I don't blame you. After all, you're only human. You're all only human. Invaluable tools in Junil's service, but still only mortal flesh, fallible and prone to faltering. Sometimes, my friend, mercy must take a back seat to peace, stability and Law. This was one of those times, and you failed to recognize it. You reached the limits of your human capacities. I'm not angry. I have no real reason to be disappointed either. But you are a product of my people, of my children, those whom I lead into the light, those I protected through Mulcarn's reign. I suppose... I suppose I have expected too much from you." [PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel paused. To gather his thoughts, perhaps. Who knew? His mind appeared to work on an entirely different plane. While humans had to stumble through their choices, hoping the one they made was the best possible, the angel simply knew. He was capable of total mercilessness, of deceit and exquisite cruelty, but the results of an action commanded by Sabathiel would always be better than any alternative course of action could have brought. The angel, however heartless and wrong he seemed at the time, was always right. The window suddenly started showing many different views, flickering past at an astonishing speed. [PARAGRAPH:1]"So much to watch. So many to care for. So many things that can go awry. I wish, oh, how I wish, I could take a more direct part in the affairs of my people. These things would not happen. I would be there to stop them. But I am not strong enough. Not yet. I need to conserve what little strength I still possess. Someday, after you are gone, perhaps, but some day soon, I will need it. We will all need it."</English>
		<French>[TAB]Shaddis slipped quietly into the room. Although not comparable to the vast antechambers and lofty halls of the public part of the Halls of Sabathiel, the room was large enough, roughly cubic and a good six meters from floor to roof. The roof was vaulted, with supporting columns built into the four walls, dividing each wall into three segments.[PARAGRAPH:1]The room was also plunged into darkness, something which simply drew your attention to the fact that the huge figure lying on a carved stone bed in the centre of the room was emitting a faint glow. Sabathiel was sleeping again. He'd probably been sleeping since last Shaddis spoke to him, two weeks ago. [PARAGRAPH:1]It wasn't really sleep, Shaddis reflected. He wasn't quite sure what it was. It was like Sabathiel's body was there, on the stone bed, but his mind and soul weren't. The Deacon of Winds had never asked Sabathiel where his mind went when he lay like that. He wasn't sure he wanted to know. [PARAGRAPH:1]As Shaddis approached, there was a sucking sound, like a sharp intake of air, and Sabathiel sat bolt upright with startling suddenness. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Something has happened."[PARAGRAPH:1]The voice sounded like a million voices speaking softly at the same time, and it carried a note of simultaneous accusation and certainty that infuriated Shaddis. Sabathiel was scrutinizing him, probably finding out what was wrong even before Shaddis had a chance to say it. And the angel was right, both in the statement and in the accusatory tone. Something HAD happened, and Shaddis was at fault, albeit indirectly. [PARAGRAPH:1]"They will be punished, of course. We must teach them that they cannot defy Law and hope to avoid repercussions. But I am disappointed in you, deacon. You knew about this. You could have stopped it earlier." [PARAGRAPH:1]Shaddis bowed his head in shame. He had known, but he hadn't found it important. Dealing with it at this early stage would have required taking appalling measures. So he had left the problem alone, hoping it would burn itself out. Instead it had exploded. The cleaning up would be a mess.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel floated to his feet. As he did, the room erupted with multi-hued light. The sight never ceased to awe Shaddis. Every section of wall was now a huge window looking out across a landscape far below. It was as if the room was at the top of an impossibly tall tower. But the view was not uniform. Each window overlooked a different landscape: In one window, all you could see was mountains, ice and snow. Another showed rolling hills, fields and peaceful pastures. A third looked out across an endless desert. [PARAGRAPH:1]The angelic ruler of the Bannor drifted across to a window that showed the sprawling urban vista of the capital. He stood there in silence, his hands clasped behind his back, for quite some time. Shaddis didn't speak. Holding a conversation with Sabathiel was a frustrating affair-the angel knew what you were going to say before you said it, and generally answered before you even had a chance to open your mouth. So the Deacon waited patiently for his master to break the silence. [PARAGRAPH:1]Finally, Sabathiel let out a long, shuddering sigh. It reminded Shaddis of a wind whistling through a mountain pass. Still facing his city, Sabathiel started to speak: [PARAGRAPH:1]"I don't blame you. After all, you're only human. You're all only human. Invaluable tools in Junil's service, but still only mortal flesh, fallible and prone to faltering. Sometimes, my friend, mercy must take a back seat to peace, stability and Law. This was one of those times, and you failed to recognize it. You reached the limits of your human capacities. I'm not angry. I have no real reason to be disappointed either. But you are a product of my people, of my children, those whom I lead into the light, those I protected through Mulcarn's reign. I suppose... I suppose I have expected too much from you." [PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel paused. To gather his thoughts, perhaps. Who knew? His mind appeared to work on an entirely different plane. While humans had to stumble through their choices, hoping the one they made was the best possible, the angel simply knew. He was capable of total mercilessness, of deceit and exquisite cruelty, but the results of an action commanded by Sabathiel would always be better than any alternative course of action could have brought. The angel, however heartless and wrong he seemed at the time, was always right. The window suddenly started showing many different views, flickering past at an astonishing speed. [PARAGRAPH:1]"So much to watch. So many to care for. So many things that can go awry. I wish, oh, how I wish, I could take a more direct part in the affairs of my people. These things would not happen. I would be there to stop them. But I am not strong enough. Not yet. I need to conserve what little strength I still possess. Someday, after you are gone, perhaps, but some day soon, I will need it. We will all need it."</French>
		<German>[TAB]Shaddis schlüpfte leise in den Raum. Obwohl dieser nicht mit den enormen Vorräumen und erhabenen Gewölben der öffentlichen Bereiche der Sabathiels Hallen vergleichbar war, so war der würfelförmige und etwa sechs Meter hohe Raum dennoch von komfortabler Größe. Das gewölbte Dach wurde von zwölf Säulen getragen, welche so in die vier Wände eingearbeitet waren, dass sie jede Wand in drei Bereiche teilten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Raum war in Dunkelheit gehüllt. Dadurch wurde die Aufmerksamkeit des Betrachters auf die Tatsache gelenkt, dass die auf einem aus Stein gemeißelten Bett in der Mitte des Raumes liegende riesige Gestalt ein sanftes Licht ausstrahlte. Sabathiel schlief wieder  oder vermutlich immer noch seit Shaddis das letzte Mal vor etwa zwei Wochen mit ihm gesprochen hatte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Es war kein wirklicher Schlaf, überlegte Shaddis. Er war nicht ganz sicher was es eigentlich war. Es schien, als wäre nur Sabathiels Körper dort auf dem steinernen Bett, nicht aber sein Geist und seine Seele. Der Diakon des Windes hatte Sabathiel nie gefragt, wohin seine Gedanken wanderten, wenn er so dalag wie jetzt. Er war sich nicht einmal sicher, ob er es überhaupt wissen wollte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als Shaddis sich näherte, hörte er ein saugendes Geräusch, gleich einem schneidendes Einatmen, und Sabathiel saß plötzlich kerzengrade aufrecht.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Es ist etwas passiert"[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Stimme klang wie zahllose verschiedene Stimmen, die leise alle auf einmal sprachen. Sie übermittelte einen Hauch von Anklage und gleichzeitig Bestimmtheit, was Shaddis wütend machte. Sabathiel musterte ihn prüfend, vermutlich um herauszufinden was es war, noch bevor Shaddis eine Chance hatte, es zu sagen. Und der Engel hatte Recht, sowohl mit der Feststellung, als auch mit dem vorwurfsvollen Ton. Es war TATSÄCHLICH etwas vorgefallen und Shaddis war dafür verantwortlich wenn auch nur indirekt.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sie werden natürlich bestraft. Wir müssen ihnen beibringen, dass sie dem Gesetz nicht in der Hoffnung trotzen können, den Konsequenzen zu entgehen. Aber ich bin von Dir enttäuscht, Diakon. Du wusstest davon. Du hättest es verhindern können.[PARAGRAPH:1]Shaddis senkte verschämt den Kopf. Er hatte es gewusst, hielt es aber nicht für notwendig zu handeln. Ein früheres Einschreiten hätte erschreckend aufwendige Maßnahmen erfordert. Daher hatte er das Problem in der Hoffnung ignoriert, dass es sich von selber erledigen würde. Stattdessen ist es eskaliert und nun würden die Aufräumarbeiten ein einziger Schlamassel werden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel erhob sich schwebend. Als er dies tat erstrahlte der Raum in einem vielfarbigen Licht. Dieser Anblick hörte nie auf, Shaddis zu beeindrucken. In jedem Bereich der Wände war nun jeweils ein riesiges Fenster, welches Ausblick auf die weit unten liegende Landschaft gewährte. Es war, als ob sich der Raum an der Spitze eines unglaublich hohen Turmes befände. Aber die Aussicht war nicht überall gleich. Durch ein Fenster konnte man nichts als Berge sehen, bedeckt mit Schnee und Eis. Ein anderes Fenster zeigte Hügellandschaften, Felder und blühende Weiden. Ein Drittes schaute über endlose Wüsten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der engelsgleiche Herrscher der Bannor glitt zu einem Fenster hinüber, welches das ausufernde urbane Bild der Hauptstadt zeigte. Schweigend stand er dort eine lange Zeit, die Arme hinter seinem Rücken verschränkt. Shaddis schwieg ebenfalls. Ein Gespräch mit Sabathiel zu führen war eine frustrierende Angelegenheit - der Engel wusste was man sagen wollte, noch bevor man den Mund aufmachte. Daher wartete der Diakon geduldig auf seinen Meister.[PARAGRAPH:1] Letztendlich entfuhr Sabathiel ein langer, schaudernder Seufzer, der Shaddis an das Geräusch eines Windes erinnerte, der durch einen Gebirgspass pfiff. Immer noch zur Stadt gewandt begann Sabathiel zu sprechen:[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich mache Dir keinen Vorwurf. Du bist schließlich nur ein Mensch. Ihr seid alle nur Menschen. Unbezahlbare Werkzeuge im Dienste Junils, aber trotzdem bloß sterbliche Hüllen, fehlbar und geneigt im falschen Moment zu zögern. Manchmal, Freund, muss Gnade zugunsten von Frieden, Stabilität und Gesetz zurückstecken. Dies war so ein Moment und du hast versäumt ihn zu bemerken. Du hast die Grenzen deiner menschlichen Fähigkeiten erreicht. Ich bin nicht wütend auch habe ich keinen wirklichen Grund, enttäuscht zu sein. Aber Du bist ein Zögling meines Volkes, von meinen Kindern, welche ich in das Licht führte und welche ich während Mulcarns Herrschaft beschützte... Ich glaube, ich habe einfach zu viel von Dir erwartet."[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel hielt inne, vielleicht um seine Gedanken zu sammeln. Wer weiß? Sein Geist schien auf einer völlig anderen Wahrnehmungsebene zu arbeiten. Während Menschen von Entscheidung zu Entscheidung stolperten, immer in der Hoffnung die best mögliche getroffen zu haben, wusste der Engel einfach. Er war in der Lage zu absoluter Gnadenlosigkeit, Tücke und ausgesprochener Grausamkeit; aber das Resultat jeder von Sabathiel getroffener Entscheidung würde immer besser sein, als jede erdenkliche alternative Handlungsweise. Der Engel, so herzlos und falsch er im Moment auch erscheinen mochte, hatte immer Recht. Auf einmal begann das Fenster viele andere Aussichten zu zeigen, welche in unglaublicher Geschwindigkeit vorbeizogen.[PARAGRAPH:1]"So viel zu beobachten. So viele, für die man Sorgen muss. So viele Dinge, die schief gehen können. Ich wünschte... oh wie ich wünschte eine weitaus direktere Rolle in den Angelegenheiten meines Volkes einnehmen zu können. Ereignisse wie diese würden nicht passieren. Ich wäre da, um sie zu verhindern. Aber ich bin nicht stark genug. Noch nicht. Ich muss den Rest an Kraft aufsparen, den ich noch besitze. Eines Tages, wenn Du nicht mehr da bist vielleicht. Aber schon bald werde ich es brauchen. Wir werden es alle brauchen."</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Shaddis scivolò silenziosamente dentro la stanza. Anche se non paragonabile alle vaste anticamere e alle imponenti sale delle parte pubblica delle Sale di Sabathiel, la stanza era grande abbastanza, grosso modo cubica e sei mentri buoni dal pavimento al tetto. Il tetto era a volta, con le colonne di supporto costruite dentro le quattro mura, che dividevano il muro in tre parti.[PARAGRAPH:1]La stanza era inoltre immersa nell'oscurità, il che attira l'attenzione sulla grande figura che giace su un letto di pietra lavorata al centro della stanza in quanto essa emette un debole bagliore. Sabathiel stava di nuovo dormendo. Probabilmente stava ancora dormendo da quando Shaddis gli ha parlato l'ultima volta, ovvero due settimane prima. [PARAGRAPH:1]Non stava veramente dormendo, Shaddis riflettè. Non era sicuro di cosa fosse. Era come se il corpo di Sabathiel era li, sul letto di pietra, ma senza la sua mente e la sua anima. Il Diacono dei Venti non aveva mai chiesto a Sabathiel dove andava la sua mente quando giaceva in quel modo. Ma non era sicuro di volerlo sapere. [PARAGRAPH:1]Mentre Shaddis si avvicinava, ci fu un suono come di una lunga inspirazione, e Sabathiel si sedette in posizione verticale con sorprendente rapidità. [PARAGRAPH:1]"È successo qualcosa".[PARAGRAPH:1]La voce sembrava un milione di voci che parlavano dolcemente allo stesso tempo, e aveva un tono d'accusa e di certezza simultanea che fecero infuriare Shaddis. Sabathiel lo stava analizzando, probabilmente scoprendo cosa non andava ancora prima che Shaddis potesse dirlo. E l'angelo aveva ragione, sia nella dichiarazione che nel tono accusatorio. Qualcosa ERA successo, e la colpa era di Shaddis, anche se indirettamente. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Saranno puniti, ovviamente. Dobbiamo insegnargli che non possono sfidare la Legge e sperare di evitarne le conseguenze. Ma sono deluso da te, diacono. Sapevi di questo. Avresti potuto fermarlo prima". [PARAGRAPH:1]Shaddis chinò il capo per la vergogna. Lui sapeva, ma non l'aveva ritenuto importante. Occuparsene nella fase iniziale avrebbe richiesto l'adozione di misure terribili. Quindi aveva ignorato il problema, sperando che si risolvesse da solo. E invece era esploso. Ora sistemarlo sarebbe stato un casino.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel si alzò in piedi. E mentre lui si alzava la stanza si riempì di una luce multicolore. Shaddis ne rimaneva sempre stupito. Ogni sezione del muro era ora un'enorme finestra che dava su su un panorama molto più in basso. Era come se la stanza fosse in cima a una torre incredibilmente alta. Ma il panorama non era uniforme. Ogni finestra si affacciava su un paesaggio diverso: in una si potevano vedere solo montagne, ghiaccio e neve. Un'altra mostrava delle colline, dei campi e dei pacifici pascoli. Una terza dava su un deserto senza fine. [PARAGRAPH:1]L'angelico sovrano dei Bannor andò verso la finestra che mostrava il vasto panorama urbano della capitale. E rimase li in silenzio, con le mani incrociate dietro la schiena, per un pò di tempo. Shaddis non parlò. Discutere con Sabathiel era una cosa frustrante, l'angelo sapeva cosa stavi per dire ancora prima che la dicessi effettivamente, e di solito rispondeva ancora prima che tu aprissi la bocca. Quindi il Diacono aspettò pazientemente che fosse il suo signore a rompere il silenzio. [PARAGRAPH:1]Alla fine, Sabathiel emise un lungo sospiro. Ricordò a Shaddis di un vento che fischia attraverso un passo di montagna. Ancora guardando la sua città, Sabathiel iniziò a parlare: [PARAGRAPH:1]"Non è colpa tua. Dopotutto, sei solo umano. Siete tutti umani. Degli strumenti inestimabili al servizio di Junil, ma pur sempre di carne mortale e inclini a commettere errori. A volte, amico mio, la pietà deve essere messa da parte per la pace, la stabilità e la Legge. Questo era uno di quiei momenti, e tu non sei riuscito a capirlo. Hai raggiunto i limiti delle tue capacità umane. Non sono arrabbiato. Non ho neppure alcuna ragione per rimanere deluso. Ma tu sei il prodotto del mio popolo, dei miei figli, di coloro che ho guidato dentro la luce e di coloro che ho protetto durante il regno di Mulcarn. Credo... Credo di aver preteso troppo da te". [PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel fece una pausa. Forse per riordinare i suoi pensieri. Chi lo sa? La sua mente sembrava lavorare su un piano completamente diverso. Mentre gli umani dovevano convivere con le loro scelte, sperando di aver fatto la scelta migliore, l'angelo sapeva semplicemente quali fossero. Era capace di essere completamente spietato, di ingannare e di essere estremamente crudele, ma i risultati di un'azione ordinata da Sabathiel erano sempre migliori di qualsiasi alternativa possibile. L'angelo, per quanto poteva sembrare senza cuore e in errore in quei momenti, aveva sempre ragione. La finestra improvvisamente iniziò a mostrare diversi panorami, cambiando a una velocità sorprendente. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Così tanto da guardare. Cosi tanti di cui occuparsi. Così tante cose che possono andare storte. Vorrei cosi tanto poter prendere parte in maniera più diretta negli affari del mio popolo. Queste cose non accadrebbero. Ci penserei io a fermarle. Ma non sono abbastanza forte. Non ancora. Devo conservare quel poco di forza che mi rimane. Un giorno, quando non ci sarai più, forse, ma un giorno a breve, ne avrò bisogno. Ne avremo tutti bisogno".</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Shaddis slipped quietly into the room. Although not comparable to the vast antechambers and lofty halls of the public part of the Halls of Sabathiel, the room was large enough, roughly cubic and a good six meters from floor to roof. The roof was vaulted, with supporting columns built into the four walls, dividing each wall into three segments.[PARAGRAPH:1]The room was also plunged into darkness, something which simply drew your attention to the fact that the huge figure lying on a carved stone bed in the centre of the room was emitting a faint glow. Sabathiel was sleeping again. He'd probably been sleeping since last Shaddis spoke to him, two weeks ago. [PARAGRAPH:1]It wasn't really sleep, Shaddis reflected. He wasn't quite sure what it was. It was like Sabathiel's body was there, on the stone bed, but his mind and soul weren't. The Deacon of Winds had never asked Sabathiel where his mind went when he lay like that. He wasn't sure he wanted to know. [PARAGRAPH:1]As Shaddis approached, there was a sucking sound, like a sharp intake of air, and Sabathiel sat bolt upright with startling suddenness. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Something has happened."[PARAGRAPH:1]The voice sounded like a million voices speaking softly at the same time, and it carried a note of simultaneous accusation and certainty that infuriated Shaddis. Sabathiel was scrutinizing him, probably finding out what was wrong even before Shaddis had a chance to say it. And the angel was right, both in the statement and in the accusatory tone. Something HAD happened, and Shaddis was at fault, albeit indirectly. [PARAGRAPH:1]"They will be punished, of course. We must teach them that they cannot defy Law and hope to avoid repercussions. But I am disappointed in you, deacon. You knew about this. You could have stopped it earlier." [PARAGRAPH:1]Shaddis bowed his head in shame. He had known, but he hadn't found it important. Dealing with it at this early stage would have required taking appalling measures. So he had left the problem alone, hoping it would burn itself out. Instead it had exploded. The cleaning up would be a mess.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel floated to his feet. As he did, the room erupted with multi-hued light. The sight never ceased to awe Shaddis. Every section of wall was now a huge window looking out across a landscape far below. It was as if the room was at the top of an impossibly tall tower. But the view was not uniform. Each window overlooked a different landscape: In one window, all you could see was mountains, ice and snow. Another showed rolling hills, fields and peaceful pastures. A third looked out across an endless desert. [PARAGRAPH:1]The angelic ruler of the Bannor drifted across to a window that showed the sprawling urban vista of the capital. He stood there in silence, his hands clasped behind his back, for quite some time. Shaddis didn't speak. Holding a conversation with Sabathiel was a frustrating affair-the angel knew what you were going to say before you said it, and generally answered before you even had a chance to open your mouth. So the Deacon waited patiently for his master to break the silence. [PARAGRAPH:1]Finally, Sabathiel let out a long, shuddering sigh. It reminded Shaddis of a wind whistling through a mountain pass. Still facing his city, Sabathiel started to speak: [PARAGRAPH:1]"I don't blame you. After all, you're only human. You're all only human. Invaluable tools in Junil's service, but still only mortal flesh, fallible and prone to faltering. Sometimes, my friend, mercy must take a back seat to peace, stability and Law. This was one of those times, and you failed to recognize it. You reached the limits of your human capacities. I'm not angry. I have no real reason to be disappointed either. But you are a product of my people, of my children, those whom I lead into the light, those I protected through Mulcarn's reign. I suppose... I suppose I have expected too much from you." [PARAGRAPH:1]Sabathiel paused. To gather his thoughts, perhaps. Who knew? His mind appeared to work on an entirely different plane. While humans had to stumble through their choices, hoping the one they made was the best possible, the angel simply knew. He was capable of total mercilessness, of deceit and exquisite cruelty, but the results of an action commanded by Sabathiel would always be better than any alternative course of action could have brought. The angel, however heartless and wrong he seemed at the time, was always right. The window suddenly started showing many different views, flickering past at an astonishing speed. [PARAGRAPH:1]"So much to watch. So many to care for. So many things that can go awry. I wish, oh, how I wish, I could take a more direct part in the affairs of my people. These things would not happen. I would be there to stop them. But I am not strong enough. Not yet. I need to conserve what little strength I still possess. Someday, after you are gone, perhaps, but some day soon, I will need it. We will all need it."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_TETHIRA</Tag>
		<English>Tethira</English>
		<French>Tethira</French>
		<German>Tethira</German>
		<Italian>Tethira</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tethira</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GALLOWS</Tag>
		<English>Gallows</English>
		<French>Potence</French>
		<German>Galgen</German>
		<Italian>Patibolo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gallows</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GALLOWS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Bannor society men condemned to death for breaking oaths can be given temporary reprieve from execution if they serve in the military.  They sacrifice their title, property, relationships and even their name.  To everyone else it is as if they died on the gallows.[PARAGRAPH:1]These men are known as Forsworn Brothers, and no matter their valor or accomplishment their execution awaits them at the end of the war.  Their only reward is the opportunity to die in battle instead of in a criminals noose, and they pursue this goal with relentless devotion.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Au sein de la société Bannor, les hommes condamnés à mort pour avoir violé leurs serments peuvent disposer d'un répit temporaire s'ils s'engagent dans l'armées. Ils sacrifient leur titre, leur patrimoine, leurs relations et même leur nom. Pour le reste du monde, c'est comme s'ils étaient morts pendus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ces hommes sont connus commes les Frères Parjures et, indépendamment de leur bravoure et de leurs actions, l'exécution les attend toujours à la fin de la guerre. La seule récompense qu'ils peuvent obtenir est la mort au combat plutôt qu'au bout d'une corde ; ils poursuivent cet objectif avec une dévotion sans relâche.</French>
		<German>[TAB]In der Gesellschaft der Bannor können Männer, die wegen Eidbruchs zum Tode verurteilt worden sind, eine einstweilige Begnadigung erhalten, wenn sie in der Armee dienen. Sie opfern ihre Titel, ihren Besitz, ihre Beziehungen und manchmal auch ihren Namen. Für alle anderen ist es so, als ob sie am Galgen gestorben wären.[PARAGRAPH:1]Diese Männer sind bekannt als die Meineidigen Brüder, und unabhängig von ihrem Mut und ihren Leistungen erwartet sie am Ende des Krieges ihre Exekution. Ihre einzige Belohnung ist die Chance, in der Schlacht zu sterben statt in einer Schlinge um ihren Hals und sie streben dieses Ziel mit unbeirrbarer Hingabe an.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Nella società Bannor i condannati a morte per aver infranto dei giuramenti possono ottenere una sospensione della pena se servono nell'esercito. Rinunciano al loro titolo, alle loro prorpietà, alle loro relazioni e persino al loro nome. Per tutti gli altri è come se morisserò sulla forca.[PARAGRAPH:1]Queste persone sono conosciute come Fratelli Rinnegati, e non importa il loro valore o i loro risultati la loro esecuzione li attende alla fine della guerra. La loro unica ricompensa è la possibilità di morire in battaglia invece che con il cappio, e perseguono questo obiettivo con un'implacabile dedizione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]In Bannor society men condemned to death for breaking oaths can be given temporary reprieve from execution if they serve in the military.  They sacrifice their title, property, relationships and even their name.  To everyone else it is as if they died on the gallows.[PARAGRAPH:1]These men are known as Forsworn Brothers, and no matter their valor or accomplishment their execution awaits them at the end of the war.  Their only reward is the opportunity to die in battle instead of in a criminals noose, and they pursue this goal with relentless devotion.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_BANNOR</Tag>
		<English>Bannor Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Bannor</French>
		<German>Palast der Bannor</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo dei Bannor</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Bannor</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_MORALE</Tag>
		<English>Morale</English>
		<French>Moral</French>
		<German>Moral</German>
		<Italian>Morale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Morale</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RALLY</Tag>
		<English>Rally</English>
		<French>Rallier</French>
		<German>Zu den Waffen!</German>
		<Italian>Adunata</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rally</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RALLY_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Creates a Demagog in each of your cities and in each of your Town improvements[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires the Crusade civic</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Crée un Démagogue dans chacune de vos villes et de vos aménagements Villes[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requiert la Doctrine Croisade</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erschafft einen Demagogen in allen Städten und Kleinstädten [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Benötigt die Gesellschaftsform Kreuzzug</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Crea un Demagogo in ognuna delle tue città e in ogni miglioramento Paese[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Richiede la forma di governo Crociata</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Creates a Demagog in each of your cities and in each of your Town improvements[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires the Crusade civic</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COMMANDER_BANNOR_CAPTAIN</Tag>
		<English>Captain</English>
		<French>Capitaine</French>
		<German>Kapitän</German>
		<Italian>Capitano</Italian>
		<Spanish>Captain</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COMMANDER_BANNOR_CAPTAIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[BOLD]Discipline[\BOLD][NEWLINE]What other word comes to mind when thinking of Bannor soldiers?[NEWLINE]You have to be disciplined when fighting against the armies of hell.[NEWLINE]And where does discipline come from? Training. And who does the training?[NEWLINE][BOLD]The captains[\BOLD].[PARAGRAPH:2]The Bannor have taken the art that is leadership and turned it into a science. There are stores of records of Bannor captains defeating enemy forces who are twice their size and better equipped. I need not remind my readers of the slaughter at Boulderment Pass. Such victories were common amongst the best captains.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Surviving page from a Dural book of History[\ITALICS]</English>
		<French>[BOLD]Discipline[\BOLD][NEWLINE]What other word comes to mind when thinking of Bannor soldiers?[NEWLINE]You have to be disciplined when fighting against the armies of hell.[NEWLINE]And where does discipline come from? Training. And who does the training?[NEWLINE][BOLD]The captains[\BOLD].[PARAGRAPH:2]The Bannor have taken the art that is leadership and turned it into a science. There are stores of records of Bannor captains defeating enemy forces who are twice their size and better equipped. I need not remind my readers of the slaughter at Boulderment Pass. Such victories were common amongst the best captains.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Surviving page from a Dural book of History[\ITALICS]</French>
		<German>[BOLD]Discipline[\BOLD][NEWLINE]What other word comes to mind when thinking of Bannor soldiers?[NEWLINE]You have to be disciplined when fighting against the armies of hell.[NEWLINE]And where does discipline come from? Training. And who does the training?[NEWLINE][BOLD]The captains[\BOLD].[PARAGRAPH:2]The Bannor have taken the art that is leadership and turned it into a science. There are stores of records of Bannor captains defeating enemy forces who are twice their size and better equipped. I need not remind my readers of the slaughter at Boulderment Pass. Such victories were common amongst the best captains.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Surviving page from a Dural book of History[\ITALICS]</German>
		<Italian>[BOLD]Disciplina[\BOLD][NEWLINE]Quale altra parola viene in mente quando si pensa ai soldati Bannor?[NEWLINE]Si deve essere disciplinati quando si combattono gli eserciti dell'Inferno.[NEWLINE]E da dove arriva questa disciplina? Dall'addestramento. E chi è che cura l'addestramento?[NEWLINE][BOLD]I capitani[\BOLD].[PARAGRAPH:2]I Bannor hanno preso l'arte del comandare e ne hanno fatto una scienza. Ci sono un sacco di racconti di capitani Bannor che sconfiggono forze nemiche che avevano il doppio degli uomini ed erano meglio equipaggiate. Non c'è bisogno che io ricordi ai miei lettori del massacro del Passo Boulderment. Tali vittorie sono comuni tra i migliori capitani.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Pagina superstite di un libro di Storia Dural[\ITALICS]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[BOLD]Discipline[\BOLD][NEWLINE]What other word comes to mind when thinking of Bannor soldiers?[NEWLINE]You have to be disciplined when fighting against the armies of hell.[NEWLINE]And where does discipline come from? Training. And who does the training?[NEWLINE][BOLD]The captains[\BOLD].[PARAGRAPH:2]The Bannor have taken the art that is leadership and turned it into a science. There are stores of records of Bannor captains defeating enemy forces who are twice their size and better equipped. I need not remind my readers of the slaughter at Boulderment Pass. Such victories were common amongst the best captains.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Surviving page from a Dural book of History[\ITALICS]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CLERIC</Tag>
		<English>Cleric</English>
		<French>Cleric</French>
		<German>Kleriker</German>
		<Italian>Chierico</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cleric</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CLERIC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The order of a Cleric is something uniquely Bannor - combat medics that march out with the troops, as capable of fighting as keeping others fighting.  While the rules of their order prevent the use of any ranged or bladed weapons, a solid hit from a staff-wielding cleric has ended many an enemy of law and order.</English>
		<French>The order of a Cleric is something uniquely Bannor - combat medics that march out with the troops, as capable of fighting as keeping others fighting.  While the rules of their order prevent the use of any ranged or bladed weapons, a solid hit from a staff-wielding cleric has ended many an enemy of law and order.</French>
		<German>The order of a Cleric is something uniquely Bannor - combat medics that march out with the troops, as capable of fighting as keeping others fighting.  While the rules of their order prevent the use of any ranged or bladed weapons, a solid hit from a staff-wielding cleric has ended many an enemy of law and order.</German>
		<Italian>L'ordine dei Chierici è una cosa unicamente Bannor - medici combattenti che stanno insieme alle truppe, equamente capaci di combattere e mantenere gli altri capaci di combattere. Le regole del loro ordine vietano loro di usare armi dalla distanza o lame, nonostante ciò non sono pochi i nemici della legge e dell'ordine caduti colpiti duramente dal bastone di un chierico.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The order of a Cleric is something uniquely Bannor - combat medics that march out with the troops, as capable of fighting as keeping others fighting.  While the rules of their order prevent the use of any ranged or bladed weapons, a solid hit from a staff-wielding cleric has ended many an enemy of law and order.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CLERIC_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Bannor Clerics, available with the Pagan Temple, are very early combat Disciple units. While only as strong as Warriors, they can use all tiers of weapons, making them useful even late.  They can also heal the stack they are in, keeping your war rolling. Clerics cannot pillage improvements.</English>
		<French>Bannor Clerics, available with the Pagan Temple, are very early combat Disciple units. While only as strong as Warriors, they can use all tiers of weapons, making them useful even late.  They can also heal the stack they are in, keeping your war rolling. Clerics cannot pillage improvements.</French>
		<German>Bannor Clerics, available with the Pagan Temple, are very early combat Disciple units. While only as strong as Warriors, they can use all tiers of weapons, making them useful even late.  They can also heal the stack they are in, keeping your war rolling. Clerics cannot pillage improvements.</German>
		<Italian>I Chierici Bannor, disponibili con il Tempio Pagano, sono delle unità Discepolo da combattimento disponibili da molto presto. Anche se la loro forza è pari soltanto a quella dei guerrieri al contrario di quest'ultimi possono usare tutti i tipi di armi, ciò li rende utili anche nelle fasi avanzate del gioco. Inoltre possono ache curare il gruppo di cui fanno parte, permettendoti di mantenere in moto la tua guerra. I Chierici non possono saccheggiare i miglioramenti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bannor Clerics, available with the Pagan Temple, are very early combat Disciple units. While only as strong as Warriors, they can use all tiers of weapons, making them useful even late.  They can also heal the stack they are in, keeping your war rolling. Clerics cannot pillage improvements.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DEMAGOG</Tag>
		<English>Demagog</English>
		<French>Démagogue</French>
		<German>Demagoge</German>
		<Italian>Demagogo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Demagog</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DEMAGOG_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Demagog can only be built during a Crusade (religion civic option). The unit is nearly as powerful as a Champion with only half the cost. Demagogs abandon their empire when the Crusade is ended.</English>
		<French>The Demagog can only be built during a Crusade (religion civic option). The unit is nearly as powerful as a Champion with only half the cost. Demagogs abandon their empire when the Crusade is ended.</French>
		<German>Der Demagoge kann nur während eines Kreuzzuges erschaffen werden. (städtische Option der Religion "die Weisung"). Er ist annähernd so stark wie der Waffenmeister, jedoch kostet er die Hälfte dessen als der Waffenmeister. Demagogen verlassen ihr Reich, wenn der Kreuzzug vorüber ist.</German>
		<Italian>Il Demagogo può essere prodotto soltanto durante una Crociata (forma di governo unica Bannor della sezione affiliazione). Quest'unità ha quasi la stessa forza di un Campione ma costa soltanto la metà. I Demagoghi abbandoneranno il tuo impero una volta conclusa la Crociata.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Demagog can only be built during a Crusade (religion civic option). The unit is nearly as powerful as a Champion with only half the cost. Demagogs abandon their empire when the Crusade is ended.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DEMAGOG_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Demagog is designed for fast mobilization, costing half as much as a champion. But they will abandon you when the crusade is over.</English>
		<French>Le Démagogue est conçu pour une mobilisation rapide, coûtant moitié moins qu'un Soldat avec Masse. Mais ils vous quitteront lorsque la croisade sera terminée.</French>
		<German>Der Demagoge ist konzipiert für eine schnelle Mobilmachung, da er die Hälfte dessen kostet als der Meister. Aber, sobald der Kreuzzug beendet ist, wird er dich verlassen.</German>
		<Italian>Il Demagogo è pensato per una rapida mobilitizazzione, costando soltanto la metà di un Campione. Ma ti abbandoneranno una volta conclusa la Crociata.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Demagog is designed for fast mobilization, costing half as much as a champion. But they will abandon you when the crusade is over.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DONAL</Tag>
		<English>Donal Lugh</English>
		<French>Donal Lugh</French>
		<German>Donal Lugh</German>
		<Italian>Donal Lugh</Italian>
		<Spanish>Donal Lugh</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DONAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Donal is the hero of the Bannor and a legendary slayer of demons and the undead. He is able to recruit units in cities and, unlike the Great Commander, is not sacrificed by doing so. If Donal proves the legends true, and kills demons and the undead, he will regain the ability to recruit and can build a huge army if he survives his own battles.[PARAGRAPH:2]The hound that tracked him almost looked normal, until it turned and growled. Half of the face was rotted away, and the skull beneath was scratched and chipped, with a dark pit for an eye socket. But it had no trouble seeing its prey. It leapt for Donal's throat.[PARAGRAPH:1]This was far from the first Hellhound Donal had seen. Reflex took over, and he dropped and rolled to avoid the fangs. His crude weapons flew to his hands. Donal and the hound circled each other, feinting and pulling back, until in a flash it was over. Donal dodged the lunge, and sunk his blade into the demon's neck, pinning it to the ground. It growled and thrashed about almost comically, trying to free itself and continue the attack.[PARAGRAPH:1]"C'mon, boy, play dead," Donal said, slamming his shield down upon the hound's skull. Both shattered, and the thrashing stopped. "That's a good dog."[PARAGRAPH:1]He didn't laugh at his jokes any longer. He had stopped amusing himself some time ago. Ten years or a thousand, he had no idea and had stopped caring. Since his people left Hell, there was no one else to laugh either, and yet still he quipped as he grimly fought the inhabitants of this realm. In the home of the King of Despair, his biggest battle was maintaining the one thing that sustained him, hope.[PARAGRAPH:2]"We have no hope, Capria. We must abandon the siege."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Capria turned to face her nephew. "We cannot, Mattius! You heard what I heard from Fanariel's lips. The Sheaim have made a breakthrough. With Agares' guidance.' We must press on!" Capria trembled as she spoke, her aging frame failing her more and more lately. Perhaps she would be steadier if she met her council without full battle armor on, but to be war leader of the Bannor and not be ever battle ready?[PARAGRAPH:1]"Indeed we must," agreed the High Priest. He was young, much younger than the regent he addressed, but he spoke with supreme confidence. "The heresies stemming from Galveholm are provocation enough to mobilize. Sabathiel therefore sees no reason for us to even associate with elven brigands like this Fanariel."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius snorted. "I'm sure Sabathiel knows a better way to get a spy into Sheaim lands, but he hasn't been exactly forthcoming lately."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Does the Head of House Venerat doubt the authority of the priesthood to speak for..."[PARAGRAPH:1]"What Mattius was pointing out, Elmin," Capria jumped in, "is that we need to prioritize our missions. The Clans have been building strength, our ambassadors have been expelled from the Lanun capital, and"[PARAGRAPH:1]The war council was interrupted by a tremendous quake, throwing them all to the ground. Capria's reflexes triumphed over the limitations of age; she bounced to her feet and raced out of the tent. The camp was showing the benefits of Bannor discipline and were in formation around the commanders' tent, ready to repel the attack.[PARAGRAPH:1]But it was not an opening magical salvo for an attack. The army watched as the trees and brush on the hillside below them withered and died, the sun was obscured by a dreary haze, and fires erupted on the horizon. It was a scene Capria remembered well from her childhood, and nightmares ever since. 70 years ago they had escaped Hell, and now it had come for them.[PARAGRAPH:2]He had scoured this Hell looking for an escape. Never mind that it was an infinite plane, he swore he'd seen every inch of it twice. He had been chased every step of the way by the minions of Agares and Bhall, and managed to either elude them, or fend them off. All to see this day.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal saw a portal to the mortal realm stretching out in the valley below him. A rift in dimensions, fluctuating wildly. And around it was arrayed an army of demons. Cavorting Imps, a contingent of Ruhin, a virtual city of manes... and the biggest Balor Donal had seen. And they were leaving. "Oh, not without me, you don't," he muttered as he started down the hillside. "I don't know where you're going, but it's got to be better than here."[PARAGRAPH:1]The demons marched through, as the rift slowly began to close.[PARAGRAPH:2]The demons were on the march. The first battle with them had caused the Bannor army to rout, and since then they had been pushed back to Tor Lehan, the nearest settlement to the corrupted lands. From its battlements Capria could see flames at the border to the Infernal lands all through the night. So far the priests' blessings had kept the corruption at bay, but not the corrupted. They surrounded the settlement, the demons that had haunted her in her youth. Only the most courageous soldiers remained to stand against them.[PARAGRAPH:1]The battle was joined at dawn. It quickly turned against them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius stood alongside his aunt at the battle lines. "If I'm to die, I'm honored to do so beside one of the heroes of legends."[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria nodded, swinging her two-handed sword. "I'd rather live. But if the Bannor do not stand to face this dire threat, who will?" An image at the edge of her field of vision made her turn, coming face to face with a monstrous pit beast.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The trick to these beasties is to get them from behind," shouted an old friend as the Pit Beast was felled. "The wings limit their peripheral vision."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Who... my god, is that you? Donal Lugh?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"In the flesh, for a pleasant change."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius gasped. "Then the legends... are all true? We are the Bannor of Sabathiel!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The tide of battle turned. The Bannor lost as many as survived, but the town was saved, and the forces of Hell pushed back for today. The news of the victory spread, shaming those who had fled, and inspiring a new generation. This was the war that Sabathiel had saved them for, and it was only beginning. But the first victory was theirs.</English>
		<French>Donal is the hero of the Bannor and a legendary slayer of demons and the undead. He is able to recruit units in cities and, unlike the Great Commander, is not sacrificed by doing so. If Donal proves the legends true, and kills demons and the undead, he will regain the ability to recruit and can build a huge army if he survives his own battles.[PARAGRAPH:2]The hound that tracked him almost looked normal, until it turned and growled. Half of the face was rotted away, and the skull beneath was scratched and chipped, with a dark pit for an eye socket. But it had no trouble seeing its prey. It leapt for Donal's throat.[PARAGRAPH:1]This was far from the first Hellhound Donal had seen. Reflex took over, and he dropped and rolled to avoid the fangs. His crude weapons flew to his hands. Donal and the hound circled each other, feinting and pulling back, until in a flash it was over. Donal dodged the lunge, and sunk his blade into the demon's neck, pinning it to the ground. It growled and thrashed about almost comically, trying to free itself and continue the attack.[PARAGRAPH:1]"C'mon, boy, play dead," Donal said, slamming his shield down upon the hound's skull. Both shattered, and the thrashing stopped. "That's a good dog."[PARAGRAPH:1]He didn't laugh at his jokes any longer. He had stopped amusing himself some time ago. Ten years or a thousand, he had no idea and had stopped caring. Since his people left Hell, there was no one else to laugh either, and yet still he quipped as he grimly fought the inhabitants of this realm. In the home of the King of Despair, his biggest battle was maintaining the one thing that sustained him, hope.[PARAGRAPH:2]"We have no hope, Capria. We must abandon the siege."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Capria turned to face her nephew. "We cannot, Mattius! You heard what I heard from Fanariel's lips. The Sheaim have made a breakthrough. With Agares' guidance.' We must press on!" Capria trembled as she spoke, her aging frame failing her more and more lately. Perhaps she would be steadier if she met her council without full battle armor on, but to be war leader of the Bannor and not be ever battle ready?[PARAGRAPH:1]"Indeed we must," agreed the High Priest. He was young, much younger than the regent he addressed, but he spoke with supreme confidence. "The heresies stemming from Galveholm are provocation enough to mobilize. Sabathiel therefore sees no reason for us to even associate with elven brigands like this Fanariel."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius snorted. "I'm sure Sabathiel knows a better way to get a spy into Sheaim lands, but he hasn't been exactly forthcoming lately."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Does the Head of House Venerat doubt the authority of the priesthood to speak for..."[PARAGRAPH:1]"What Mattius was pointing out, Elmin," Capria jumped in, "is that we need to prioritize our missions. The Clans have been building strength, our ambassadors have been expelled from the Lanun capital, and"[PARAGRAPH:1]The war council was interrupted by a tremendous quake, throwing them all to the ground. Capria's reflexes triumphed over the limitations of age; she bounced to her feet and raced out of the tent. The camp was showing the benefits of Bannor discipline and were in formation around the commanders' tent, ready to repel the attack.[PARAGRAPH:1]But it was not an opening magical salvo for an attack. The army watched as the trees and brush on the hillside below them withered and died, the sun was obscured by a dreary haze, and fires erupted on the horizon. It was a scene Capria remembered well from her childhood, and nightmares ever since. 70 years ago they had escaped Hell, and now it had come for them.[PARAGRAPH:2]He had scoured this Hell looking for an escape. Never mind that it was an infinite plane, he swore he'd seen every inch of it twice. He had been chased every step of the way by the minions of Agares and Bhall, and managed to either elude them, or fend them off. All to see this day.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal saw a portal to the mortal realm stretching out in the valley below him. A rift in dimensions, fluctuating wildly. And around it was arrayed an army of demons. Cavorting Imps, a contingent of Ruhin, a virtual city of manes... and the biggest Balor Donal had seen. And they were leaving. "Oh, not without me, you don't," he muttered as he started down the hillside. "I don't know where you're going, but it's got to be better than here."[PARAGRAPH:1]The demons marched through, as the rift slowly began to close.[PARAGRAPH:2]The demons were on the march. The first battle with them had caused the Bannor army to rout, and since then they had been pushed back to Tor Lehan, the nearest settlement to the corrupted lands. From its battlements Capria could see flames at the border to the Infernal lands all through the night. So far the priests' blessings had kept the corruption at bay, but not the corrupted. They surrounded the settlement, the demons that had haunted her in her youth. Only the most courageous soldiers remained to stand against them.[PARAGRAPH:1]The battle was joined at dawn. It quickly turned against them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius stood alongside his aunt at the battle lines. "If I'm to die, I'm honored to do so beside one of the heroes of legends."[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria nodded, swinging her two-handed sword. "I'd rather live. But if the Bannor do not stand to face this dire threat, who will?" An image at the edge of her field of vision made her turn, coming face to face with a monstrous pit beast.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The trick to these beasties is to get them from behind," shouted an old friend as the Pit Beast was felled. "The wings limit their peripheral vision."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Who... my god, is that you? Donal Lugh?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"In the flesh, for a pleasant change."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius gasped. "Then the legends... are all true? We are the Bannor of Sabathiel!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The tide of battle turned. The Bannor lost as many as survived, but the town was saved, and the forces of Hell pushed back for today. The news of the victory spread, shaming those who had fled, and inspiring a new generation. This was the war that Sabathiel had saved them for, and it was only beginning. But the first victory was theirs.</French>
		<German>Donal ist der Held der Bannor und ein legendärer Dämonen- und Untotenschlächter. Er kann in Städten Einheiten rekrutieren und muss sich dabei, im Gegensatz zum Großen Feldherrn, nicht opfern. Wenn Donal die Legenden wahr werden lässt und Dämonen und Untote tötet, erhält er die Fähigkeit zu rekrutieren zurück und kann auf diese Weise eine große Armee aufstellen, vorausgesetzt, er überlebt seine eigenen Schlachten.[PARAGRAPH:2]Der Hund, der ihn verfolgte, sah fast normal aus, bis er knurrend seine andere Seite zeigte. Die Hälfte seines Gesichtes ist weggefault und der Schädel darunter ist zerkratzt und zerschlagen, mit einem dunklen Loch als Augenhöhle. Trotzdem sieht er seine Beute problemlos und so ging er Donal an die Gurgel.[PARAGRAPH:1]Es war beileibe nicht der erste Höllenhund, den Donal sah. Reflexartig ließ er sich fallen und rollte zur Seite, um den Reißzähnen zu entgehen. Schnell hatte er seine groben Waffen zu Hand. Donal und der Hund belauerten sich, täuschten Angriffe vor um gleich wieder zurückzuziehen, bis es plötzlich vorüber war. Donal täuschte einen Ausfallschritt an und trieb seine Klinge durch das Genick des Dämons in den Boden. Der knurrte und zappelte fast lachhaft, im Versuch, sich selbst zu befreien und den Angriff fortzusetzen.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Komm schon, spiele tot", sagte Donal und rammte dem Hund seinen Schild auf den Schädel. Beides ging zu Bruch, und das Zappeln hörte auf. "Guter Hund!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Er lachte schon lange nicht mehr über seine Witze, schon seit Jahren nicht mehr. Ob seit zehn oder tausend Jahren, das wusste er nicht und es interessierte ihn auch nicht mehr. Seit sein Volk die Hölle verlassen hatte, gab es niemanden mehr, mit dem er hätte lachen können, aber er machte noch immer seine Witze während er grimmig gegen die Bewohner dieses Reiches kämpfte. Im Gebiet des Königs der Verzweiflung war sein größter Kampf, das nicht zu verlieren, was ihn durchhalten ließ, seine Hoffnung.[PARAGRAPH:2]"Es gibt keine Hoffnung, Capria. Wir müssen die Belagerung aufgeben."[PARAGRAPH:1] Capria drehte sich zu ihrem Neffen um: "Wir können nicht, Mattius! Du hast gehört, was Fanariel sagte. Die Sheaim haben den Durchbruch geschafft. Mit Agares Hilfe. "Wir müssen weitermachen!" Capria zitterte als sie sprach, ihre alte Rüstung zerfiel langsam. Vielleicht hätte sie ruhiger gestanden, wenn sie ihrem Berater ohne ihre volle Kampfausrüstung gegenübergestanden hätte, aber was ist ein Kriegsführer der Bannor, der nicht allzeit zur Schlacht bereit ist?[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ja, das müssen wir" stimmte der Hohepriester zu. Er war jung, viel jünger als der Herrscher ihn schätzte, aber er sprach mit viel Zuversicht. "Die Ketzereien von Gaveholm sind Grund genug für die Mobilmachung. Sabathiel sieht darum noch nicht mal einen Grund, sich mit Banditen der Elfen, wie dieser Fanariel, zu verbünden."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius schnaubte: "Ich bin sicher, Sabathiel kennt eine bessere Möglichkeit, einen Spion auf das Gebiet der Sheaim zu schmuggeln, aber er war letztens nicht gerade sehr miteilsam." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Zweifelt das Haupt des Hauses Venerat etwa an der Autorität der Priesterschaft, in seinem Namen zu sprechen?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was Mattius sagen wollte, Elmin" unterbrach Capria, "wir müssen unsere Aufgaben nach Prioritäten einteilen. Die Klans sind stark geworden, unser Botschafter wurde aus der Hauptstadt der Lanun ausgewiesen und..."[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Versammlung wurde von einem gewaltigen Beben unterbrochen, das alle zu Boden warf. Caprias Reflexe besiegten die Schwäche des Alters, sie sprang auf und rannte aus dem Zelt. Das Lager war gemäß der straffen Organisation der Bannor in regelmäßigen Formationen um das Zelt der Heerführers herum aufgebaut, bereit Angriffe abzuwehren.[PARAGRAPH:1]Aber das war nicht die übliche magische Eröffnungssalve für einen Angriff. Die Armee sah, wie die Büsche und Bäume unterhalb am Hang verwelkten und starben, die Sonne wurde von einem trüben Dunst verhüllt und Flammen stiegen am Horizont auf. Capria kannte diese Szene aus ihrer Kindheit, und aus ihren Alpträumen. Vor 70 Jahren waren sie aus der Hölle geflohen und nun kam sie zu ihnen.[PARAGRAPH:2]Er hatte jeden Winkel der Hölle nach einem Ausgang durchsucht. Ungeachtet dass sie eine endlose Ebene ist, könnte er schwören, jeden Zentimeter mindestens zweimal gesehen zu haben. Er wurde auf Schritt und Tritt von den Günstlingen von Agares und Bhall verfolgt, konnte ihnen aber immer ausweichen oder sie abwehren. Und alles, nur um diesen Tag zu erleben.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal sah das Portal zur Welt der Sterblichen im Tal unter ihm. Eine willkürlich flackernde Verwerfung der Dimensionen. Und drum herum eine Ansammlung von Dämonenarmeen. Herumspringend Kobolde, ein Aufgebot von Ruhin, eine virtuelle Stadt der Gester der Verfallenen... und den größten Balor, den Donal je gesehen hatte. Und sie gingen durch das Portal. "Nicht ohne mich, niemals!", murmelte er und rannte den Hügel hinunter. "Ich weiß nicht wohin ihr geht, aber es ist dort bestimmt besser als hier."[PARAGRAPH:1] Die Dämonen gingen hindurch, und die Verwerfung begann langsam sich zu schließen.[PARAGRAPH:2]Die Dämonen waren im Vorwärtsgang. Die erste Schlacht mit ihnen zwang die Bannorarmee in die Flucht, seitdem konnten sie aber bis Tor Lehan, die dem verdorbenen Land am nächsten gelegene Siedlung, zurückgedrängt werden. In ihren Schlachten konnte Capria die Flammen am Rand des infernalischen Landes die ganze Nacht über erblicken. Bis dahin hatten die Gebete der Priester das Verderben im Zaum halten können, nicht aber die Verdorbenen. Sie umzingelten die Siedlung, die Dämonen, die sie schon in ihrer Jungend gejagt hatten. Nur die mutigsten Soldaten stellten sich ihnen entgegen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Schlacht begann im Morgengrauen. Und bald lief alles gegen sie.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius stand neben seiner Tante im Schlachtfeld. "Wenn ich sterbe, bin ich stolz darauf, neben einer legendären Heldin zu sterben."[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria nickte und schwang ihr beidhändiges Schwert. "Ich würde lieber leben. Aber wenn die Bannor dieser schrecklichen Bedrohung nicht standhalten, wer wird es dann?" Etwas in ihrem Augenwinkel ließ sie sich umdrehen, und sie stand einer monströsen Grubenbestie direkt gegenüber.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Der Trick ist, diese Biester von hinten zu bekommen." Rief ein alter Freund, als die Grubenbestie gefällt war. "Ihre Flügel schränken ihre Sicht ziemlich ein."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Wer... um alles in der Welt, bist du's? Donal Lugh?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Leibhaftig, ausnahmsweise."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius staunte: "Dann sind die Legenden... sind sie alle wahr? Wir sind die Bannor von Sabathiel!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Schlacht wendete sich. Die Bannor verloren die Hälfte ihrer Leute, aber die Stadt wurde gerettet und die Kräfte der Hölle wurden vorerst zurückgeschlagen. Die Kunde des Sieges verbreitete sich schnell, beschämte die, die geflohen waren und inspirierte eine ganz neue Generation. Für diesen Krieg hatte Sabathiel sie vorher beschützt, und das war erst der Anfang. Aber der erste Sieg gehörte ihnen.</German>
		<Italian>Donal è l'eroe dei Bannor e un leggendario sterminatore di demoni e non-morti. Può inoltre reclutare unità nelle città come i Grandi Comandanti. Se Donal dimostra la verità delle leggende, e uccide demoni e non-morti, ritotterrà l'abilità di reclutare le unità potendo cosi creare grandi armate se sopravvive alle battaglie.[PARAGRAPH:2]Il segugio che lo seguiva sembrava quasi normale, almeno fino a quando non si voltò e ringhiò. Aveva metà del muso completamente marcio e il teschio era graffiato e scheggiato, oltre ad avere una cavita oculare completamente vuota. Nonostante ciò non aveva problemi a vedere la sua preda. Saltò puntando alla gola di Donal.[PARAGRAPH:1]Questo non era il primo Segugio Infernale affrontato da Donal. L'istinto prese il controllo, si abbassò e rotolò via evitando le zanne. Le sue rozze armi "volarono" nelle sue mani. Donal e il segugio giravano in cerchio, fintando e inditreggiando fino a quando, in un attimo, era tutto finito. Donal schivò l'affondo, e affondò la sua lama nel collo del demone, inchiodandolo al terreno. Ringhiava e si agitava in maniera quasi comica, mentre cercava di liberarsi per continuare l'attacco.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Andiamo, piccolo, fai il morto" Donal disse mentre con lo scudo spaccava la testa del segugio. Si rupperò entrambi e i movimenti cessarono. "Che bravo cane".[PARAGRAPH:1]Non rideva più alle sue battute. Avevano smesso di divertirlo da un pò di tempo. Da dieci o mille anni, non ne aveva idea e aveva smesso di importargli. Da quando il suo popolo aveva abbandonato l'Inferno non c'era nessun'altro con cui ridere comunque, eppure continuava a scherzare quando combatteva gli abitanti di questo reame. Nella casa del Re della Disperazione, la sua più grande battaglia era mantenere l'unica cosa che lo faceva andare avanti, la speranza.[PARAGRAPH:2]"Non abbiamo alcuna speranza, Capria. Dobbiamo abbandonare l'assedio".[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria si volto verso il nipote. "Non possiamo, Mattius! Hai sentito anche tu ciò che ha detto Fanariel. Gli Sheaim hanno fatto progressi. Con la guida di Agares. Dobbiamo continuare!" Capria tremolò mentre parlava, il suo corpo subiva gli effetti della vecchiaia sempre più spesso. Forse sarebbe stata più stabile se incontrava il suo consiglio senza indossare l'armatura da battaglia completa, ma come si potrebbe essere un condottiero dei Bannor e non essere sempre pronti per la battaglia?[PARAGRAPH:1]"In effetti dobbiamo" disse il Sommo Sacerdote. Lui era giovane, molto più giovane del reggente a cui si rivolgeva, ma parlava con una sicurezza enorme. "Le eresie provenienti da Galveholm sono una provocazione sufficente ad intervenire. Sabathiel pertanto non vede alcuna ragione per cui noi dovremmo associarci con dei briganti elfici come questo Fanariel".[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius sbuffò. "Sono sicuro che Sabathiel conosce un metodo migliore per far entrare una spia nelle terre Sheaim, ma non è stato molto disponibile ultimamente".[PARAGRAPH:1]"Il Capo della Casa Venerat dubita dell'autorità del clero di parlare per..."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ciò che Mattius stava facendo notare, Elmin," Capria si intromise, "è che dobbiamo definire la priorità delle nostre missioni. I Clan stanno ricostruendo le loro forze, i nostri ambasciatori sono stati espulsi dalla capitale dei Lanun e"[PARAGRAPH:1]Il consiglio di guerra fu interrottò da una fortissima scossa, facendo cadere tutti a terra. L'istinto di Capria vinse contro le limitazioni dell'età; si rialzò rapidamente e corse fuori dalla tenda. Il campo mostrava i risultati della disciplina Bannor ed era in formazione attorno alla tenda del comandante, pronto a respingere l'attacco.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ma non era uno sbarramento offensivo magico per un'attacco. L'esercito osservava mentre gli alberi e i cespugli ai piedi della collina si seccavano e morivano, il sole veniva oscurato da una foschia lugubre e degli incendi scoppiavano all'orizzonte. Era una scena che Capria ricordava molto bene dalla sua infanzia, e che vedeva nei suoi incubi. 70 anni fa erano fuggiti dall'Inferno, e ora lui era venuto per loro.[PARAGRAPH:2]Aveva setacciato l'Inferno in cerca di una via di fuga. Non importava che fosse un piano infinito, avrebbe giurato che che aveva visto ogni centimetro di esso due volte. Era stato inseguito sempre dai servitori di Agares e Bhall, e riusci sempre a evitarli o respingerli. Tutto ciò per vedere questo giorno.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal vide un portale che dava sul piano dei mortali in fondo alla valle sotto di lui. Uno squarcio tra le dimensioni, tremendamente instabile. E attorno ad esso vi era schierato un esercito di demoni. Degli Imp che danzavano, un contingente di Ruhin, una città virtuale di Mani... e il più grande Balor che Donal avesse mai visto. E tutti loro stavano partendo. "Oh, non andrete via senza di me" mormorò mentre iniziava a scendere. "Non so dove stiate andando, ma dev'essere si sicuro meglio di questo posto".[PARAGRAPH:1]I demoni lo attraversarono, e lo squarcio iniziò lentamente a chiudersi.[PARAGRAPH:2]I demoni erano in marcia. Il primo scontro con loro aveva fatto finire in rotta l'esercito Bannor, e da quel momento i Bannor erano stati respinti sino a Tor Lehan, l'insediamento più vicino alle terre corrotte. Dagli spalti Capria poteva vedere le fiamme al limite delle terre Infernali per tutta la notte. Finora le benedizioni dei preti avevano tenuto la corruzzione a bada, ma non i corrotti. Circondavano l'insediamento, i demoni che la perseguitavano durante la sua infanzia. Solo i soldati più coraggiosi erano rimasti ad affrontarli.[PARAGRAPH:1]La battaglia iniziò all'alba. Volse rapidamente in loro sfavore.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius rimase affianco a sua zia nella battaglia. "Se devo morire, sono onorato di farlo al fianco di un'eroe delle leggende".[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria annuì, mentre agitava il suo spadone a due mani. "Io preferirei vivere. Ma se i Bannor non affrontano questa terribile minaccia, chi lo fara?" Un'immagine al margine del suo campo visivo la fece girare, finendo faccia a faccia con una mostruosa bestia della fossa.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Il trucco consiste nel prendere queste bestie da dietro" urlò un vecchio amico mentre la Bestia della Fossa cascava a terra. "Le ali limitano la loro visione periferica".[PARAGRAPH:1]"Chi... mio dio, sei tu? Donal Lugh?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"In carne e ossa, un piacevole cambio".[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius rimase senza fiato. "Allora le leggende... è tutto vero? Noi siamo i Bannor di Sabathiel!"[PARAGRAPH:1]L'esito della battaglia fu ribaltato. I Bannor perserò tanti uomini quanti ne sopravvisserò, ma la città fu salvata, e le forze dell'Inferno respinte indietro almeno per oggi. La notizia della vittoria si diffuse, umiliando coloro che erano scappati e inspirando una nuova generazione. Questa era la guerra per cui Sabathiel li aveva salvati, ed era solo l'inizio. Ma la prima vittoria era loro.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Donal is the hero of the Bannor and a legendary slayer of demons and the undead. He is able to recruit units in cities and, unlike the Great Commander, is not sacrificed by doing so. If Donal proves the legends true, and kills demons and the undead, he will regain the ability to recruit and can build a huge army if he survives his own battles.[PARAGRAPH:2]The hound that tracked him almost looked normal, until it turned and growled. Half of the face was rotted away, and the skull beneath was scratched and chipped, with a dark pit for an eye socket. But it had no trouble seeing its prey. It leapt for Donal's throat.[PARAGRAPH:1]This was far from the first Hellhound Donal had seen. Reflex took over, and he dropped and rolled to avoid the fangs. His crude weapons flew to his hands. Donal and the hound circled each other, feinting and pulling back, until in a flash it was over. Donal dodged the lunge, and sunk his blade into the demon's neck, pinning it to the ground. It growled and thrashed about almost comically, trying to free itself and continue the attack.[PARAGRAPH:1]"C'mon, boy, play dead," Donal said, slamming his shield down upon the hound's skull. Both shattered, and the thrashing stopped. "That's a good dog."[PARAGRAPH:1]He didn't laugh at his jokes any longer. He had stopped amusing himself some time ago. Ten years or a thousand, he had no idea and had stopped caring. Since his people left Hell, there was no one else to laugh either, and yet still he quipped as he grimly fought the inhabitants of this realm. In the home of the King of Despair, his biggest battle was maintaining the one thing that sustained him, hope.[PARAGRAPH:2]"We have no hope, Capria. We must abandon the siege."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Capria turned to face her nephew. "We cannot, Mattius! You heard what I heard from Fanariel's lips. The Sheaim have made a breakthrough. With Agares' guidance.' We must press on!" Capria trembled as she spoke, her aging frame failing her more and more lately. Perhaps she would be steadier if she met her council without full battle armor on, but to be war leader of the Bannor and not be ever battle ready?[PARAGRAPH:1]"Indeed we must," agreed the High Priest. He was young, much younger than the regent he addressed, but he spoke with supreme confidence. "The heresies stemming from Galveholm are provocation enough to mobilize. Sabathiel therefore sees no reason for us to even associate with elven brigands like this Fanariel."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius snorted. "I'm sure Sabathiel knows a better way to get a spy into Sheaim lands, but he hasn't been exactly forthcoming lately."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Does the Head of House Venerat doubt the authority of the priesthood to speak for..."[PARAGRAPH:1]"What Mattius was pointing out, Elmin," Capria jumped in, "is that we need to prioritize our missions. The Clans have been building strength, our ambassadors have been expelled from the Lanun capital, and"[PARAGRAPH:1]The war council was interrupted by a tremendous quake, throwing them all to the ground. Capria's reflexes triumphed over the limitations of age; she bounced to her feet and raced out of the tent. The camp was showing the benefits of Bannor discipline and were in formation around the commanders' tent, ready to repel the attack.[PARAGRAPH:1]But it was not an opening magical salvo for an attack. The army watched as the trees and brush on the hillside below them withered and died, the sun was obscured by a dreary haze, and fires erupted on the horizon. It was a scene Capria remembered well from her childhood, and nightmares ever since. 70 years ago they had escaped Hell, and now it had come for them.[PARAGRAPH:2]He had scoured this Hell looking for an escape. Never mind that it was an infinite plane, he swore he'd seen every inch of it twice. He had been chased every step of the way by the minions of Agares and Bhall, and managed to either elude them, or fend them off. All to see this day.[PARAGRAPH:1]Donal saw a portal to the mortal realm stretching out in the valley below him. A rift in dimensions, fluctuating wildly. And around it was arrayed an army of demons. Cavorting Imps, a contingent of Ruhin, a virtual city of manes... and the biggest Balor Donal had seen. And they were leaving. "Oh, not without me, you don't," he muttered as he started down the hillside. "I don't know where you're going, but it's got to be better than here."[PARAGRAPH:1]The demons marched through, as the rift slowly began to close.[PARAGRAPH:2]The demons were on the march. The first battle with them had caused the Bannor army to rout, and since then they had been pushed back to Tor Lehan, the nearest settlement to the corrupted lands. From its battlements Capria could see flames at the border to the Infernal lands all through the night. So far the priests' blessings had kept the corruption at bay, but not the corrupted. They surrounded the settlement, the demons that had haunted her in her youth. Only the most courageous soldiers remained to stand against them.[PARAGRAPH:1]The battle was joined at dawn. It quickly turned against them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius stood alongside his aunt at the battle lines. "If I'm to die, I'm honored to do so beside one of the heroes of legends."[PARAGRAPH:1]Capria nodded, swinging her two-handed sword. "I'd rather live. But if the Bannor do not stand to face this dire threat, who will?" An image at the edge of her field of vision made her turn, coming face to face with a monstrous pit beast.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The trick to these beasties is to get them from behind," shouted an old friend as the Pit Beast was felled. "The wings limit their peripheral vision."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Who... my god, is that you? Donal Lugh?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"In the flesh, for a pleasant change."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mattius gasped. "Then the legends... are all true? We are the Bannor of Sabathiel!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The tide of battle turned. The Bannor lost as many as survived, but the town was saved, and the forces of Hell pushed back for today. The news of the victory spread, shaming those who had fled, and inspiring a new generation. This was the war that Sabathiel had saved them for, and it was only beginning. But the first victory was theirs.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DONAL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Bannor hero can recruit a random assortment of units. This ability is regained once he kills a demon or undead. He also has a defense increase from his unique equipment.</English>
		<French>The Bannor hero can recruit a random assortment of units. This ability is regained once he kills a demon or undead. He also has a defense increase from his unique equipment.</French>
		<German>Der Held der Bannor kann ein zufälliges Sortiment an Einheiten rekrutieren und Einheiten mit dem Zauber "Tapferkeit" inspirieren.</German>
		<Italian>L'eroe Bannor può reclutare un'assortimento di unità casuali. Questa abilità viene riottenuta quando uccide un demone o un non-morto. Inoltre la sua forza in difesa viene aumentata dal suo equipaggiamento unico.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Bannor hero can recruit a random assortment of units. This ability is regained once he kills a demon or undead. He also has a defense increase from his unique equipment.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FLAGBEARER</Tag>
		<English>Flagbearer</English>
		<French>Porte-Étendard</French>
		<German>Fahnenträger</German>
		<Italian>Portabandiera</Italian>
		<Spanish>Flagbearer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FLAGBEARER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A Flagbearer passes the Morale promotion to all living allied units within 1 tile.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Un Porte-étendard donne la promotion Moral toute les unités vivantes dans 1 case de rayon.</French>
		<German>Ein Fahnenträger überträgt die Moralbeförderung an alle lebenden verbündeten Einheiten des Geländefeldes.</German>
		<Italian>Il Portabandiera passa la promozione Morale ad ogni unità vivente alleata entro 1 casella di distanza.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A Flagbearer passes the Morale promotion to all living allied units within 1 tile.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FLAGBEARER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Useful added to your stacks, Flagbearers will give allied units nearby a bonus to attack and city attack.</English>
		<French>Utiles quand ajouté à vos piles, les Porte-Étendards donneront aux unités alliées proches un bonus en attaque et en attaque de ville.</French>
		<German>Nützlich, wenn sie zu euren Truppenverbänden hinzugefügt sind, werden Flaggenträger allen allierten Einheiten in der Nähe einen Bonus für Angriff und Stadtangriff verleihen.</German>
		<Italian>Molto utile quando unito ai tuoi gruppi, i Portabandiera daranno alle unita viventi alleate vicine un bonus alla forza e all'attacco contro le città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Useful added to your stacks, Flagbearers will give allied units nearby a bonus to attack and city attack.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GARRISON_CAPTAIN</Tag>
		<English>Garrison Captain</English>
		<French>Capitaine de garnison </French>
		<German>Garnisonsvorsteher</German>
		<Italian>Capitano della Guarnigione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Garrison Captain</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DEMON_HUNTER</Tag>
		<English>Demon Hunter</English>
		<French>Chasseur de Démons</French>
		<German>Demon Hunter</German>
		<Italian>Demon Hunter</Italian>
		<Spanish>Demon Hunter</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DEMON_HUNTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The best hunters in Bannor lands are trained to track and kill not animals or great beasts but demons. They are the second line of defense against any otherworldly threat that managed to slip through the border.</English>
		<French>The best hunters in Bannor lands are trained to track and kill not animals or great beasts but demons. They are the second line of defense against any otherworldly threat that managed to slip through the border.</French>
		<German>The best hunters in Bannor lands are trained to track and kill not animals or great beasts but demons. They are the second line of defense against any otherworldly threat that managed to slip through the border.</German>
		<Italian>The best hunters in Bannor lands are trained to track and kill not animals or great beasts but demons. They are the second line of defense against any otherworldly threat that managed to slip through the border.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The best hunters in Bannor lands are trained to track and kill not animals or great beasts but demons. They are the second line of defense against any otherworldly threat that managed to slip through the border.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
