<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SVARTALFAR_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Svartálfur:Svartálfar</English>
		<French>Svartálfur:Svartálfur:Svartálfar:Svartálfar</French>
		<German>Svartálfur:Svartálfar</German>
		<Italian>Svartálfur:Svartálfar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Svartálfur:Svartálfar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SVARTALFAR_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Svartálfheimr</English>
		<French>Svartálfheimr</French>
		<German>Svartálfheimr</German>
		<Italian>Svartálfheimr</Italian>
		<Spanish>Svartálfheimr</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SVARTALFAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]During the Age of Magic, the elves were ruled by two separate courts. The Seelie court (the fairer and more spiritual) ruled during the spring and summer, and the Unseelie court (the more arcane and malevolent) ruled during the autumn and winter. When Sucellus died, the elven prayers went unanswered. Because the Unseelie court was in power when it happened, they decreed that the elven deity was gone and that Esus would be adopted in his place. Normally, the Seelie court would wait for spring and then reverse the ruling, but spring never came as the Age of Ice began. The Unseelie court saw this as a symbol of their dominance and began to punish elves that refused to stop worshipping Sucellus. This caused a bloody civil war within the elven nation during a time when their numbers were already hard-hit. The Age of Ice eventually stopped the war as bands were separated by expanses they couldn't cross. Now that the Age of Ice is over, they are free to reach out and begin their war anew.</English>
		<French>Durant l'Âge de la Magie, les elfes étaient dirigés par deux Cours distinctes. La Cour du Printemps (la plus juste et spirituelle) dirigeait durant le printemps et l'été, et la Cour de l'Hiver (la plus malveillante et la plus versée dans les arcanes) qui régnait durant l'automne et l'hiver. Lorsque Sucellus mourut, les prières elfes restèrent sans réponse. Parce que la Cour de l'Hiver était au pouvoir à ce moment, ils décrétèrent que la divinité elfique était partie et qu'Esus la remplacerait. Normalement, la Cour du Printemps aurait dû attendre le printemps pour révoquer cette décision mais le printemps ne vint jamais et l'Âge de Glace commença. La Cour de l'Hiver y vit un symbole de sa domination et commença à punir les elfes qui refusaient d'abandonner le culte de Sucellus. Cela causa une guerre civile sanglante pour la nation elfe à une époque où leur nombre était déjà fortement réduit. L'Âge de Glace mit fin à la guerre, les groupes étant séparés par des étendues qu'ils ne pouvaient traverser. Maintenant que l'Âge de Glace est terminé, ils sont libres de s'étendre et de recommencer leur guerre.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Während des Zeitalters der Magie wurden die Elfen von zwei verschiedenen Höfen regiert. Der Selige Hof (der gerechtere und spirituellere) herrschte während Frühling und Sommer und der Unselige Hof (der magischere und böswilligere) in Herbst und Winter. Als Sucellus starb, blieben die Gebete der Elfen ungehört. Weil in dem Moment, als dies geschah, der Unselige Hof die Macht inne hatte, verkündete dessen Königin, dass der Gott der Elfen tot sei und Esus nun an seine Stelle treten würde. Normalerweise hätte der Selige Hof im Frühling diese Entscheidung rückgängig machen können, aber der Frühling kam nie, da das Zeitalter des Eises begann. Der Unselige Hof deutete das als Gunst für seine Herrschaft und begann, Elfen zu bestrafen, die weiterhin Sucellus verehrten. Zu einer Zeit, in der ihre Zahl ohnehin schon sehr gering war, löste dies einen blutigen Bürgerkrieg unter den Elfen aus. Das Zeitalter des Eises beendete den Krieg vorerst, weil die beiden Gruppen durch unüberwindliche Barrieren voneinander getrennt wurden. Nun da das Zeitalter des Eises vorüber ist, können sie wieder ausziehen und den Krieg von neuem beginnen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]During the Age of Magic, the elves were ruled by two separate courts. The Seelie court (the fairer and more spiritual) ruled during the spring and summer, and the Unseelie court (the more arcane and malevolent) ruled during the autumn and winter. When Sucellus died, the elven prayers went unanswered. Because the Unseelie court was in power when it happened, they decreed that the elven deity was gone and that Esus would be adopted in his place. Normally, the Seelie court would wait for spring and then reverse the ruling, but spring never came as the Age of Ice began. The Unseelie court saw this as a symbol of their dominance and began to punish elves that refused to stop worshipping Sucellus. This caused a bloody civil war within the elven nation during a time when their numbers were already hard-hit. The Age of Ice eventually stopped the war as bands were separated by expanses they couldn't cross. Now that the Age of Ice is over, they are free to reach out and begin their war anew.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Durante la Edad de la Magia, los elfos estaban gobernados por dos cortes separadas.  La Corte Seelie (la más justa y más espiritual) dirigida durante la primavera y el verano, y la Corte Unseelie (la más arcana y malevolente) dirigida durante el otoño y el invierno.  Cuando Sucellus murió, los oradores elfos dejaron de ser respondidos.  Por el hecho de que Unseelie estaba en el poder cuando ocurrió, decretaron que la deidad élfica se había ido y que Esus debía ser adoptado en su lugar.  Normalmente, la Corte Seelie habría esperado por la primavera y entonces invertir el gobierno, pero la primavera nunca llegó, pues empezó la Edad de Hielo.  La Corte Unseelie vió esto como un símbolo de su dominio y empezó a castigar a los elfos que se negaron a dejar de adorar a Sucellus.  Esto causó una sangrienta guerra civil en la nación élfica en una época en la que su número ya había sido herido de gravedad.  La Edad de Hielo detuvo la guerra porque los bandos se fueron separando por extensiones que no podían cruzar.  Ahora que la Edad de Hielo ha terminado, son libres de volver a alcanzarse y retomar su guerra donde la dejaron.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SVARTALFAR_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Svartálfar</English>
		<French>Svartálfar</French>
		<German>Svartálfar</German>
		<Italian>Svartálfar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Svartálfar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_FAERYL</Tag>
		<English>Faeryl Viconia</English>
		<French>Faeryl Viconia</French>
		<German>Faeryl Viconia</German>
		<Italian>Faeryl Viconia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Faeryl Viconia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_FAERYL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Faeryl steeled herself outside of the chamber. She was queen now, but still the elves fawned over Arendel. Faeryl had just begun her 6-month winter reign, when nothing productive could be accomplished. Then, when spring came and meaningful change could be enacted, tradition forced her to pass it back to her weaker cousin.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was little she could do but grit her teeth and head into the chamber. Arendel was inside, no doubt pouting over the temporary loss of her crown as she did every year.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I trust your stay has been comfortable?" Faeryl asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course, I am always amazed at the beauty of the Unseelie court, and the courtesy of its residents."[PARAGRAPH:1]Faeryl nodded. This was a part of the game they both pretended to play. Cordial and gracious in action, while secretly hating other. Yet Arendel seemed even more melancholy than usual. Faeryl almost smiled at the thought that something serious might be wrong in Arendel's perfect life. She couldn't resist asking.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Arendel, what concerns you? Is your family well?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, they are well. It is kind of you to ask. I have been bothered, and I apologize for that, it is certainly nothing to do with you or the Unseelie court. I don't know what it is, I just feel like we are in a dangerous time. Winter is coming so early this year; we have just performed the rite of autumn and the scouts are already reporting some snowfall. The priests are having powerful dreams and the forests aren't dropping into their winter slumber, instead they seem to be reblossoming."[PARAGRAPH:1]Faeryl choked back her initial reaction. Arendel didn't trust that she would be able to handle whatever lay ahead. Isn't it enough that she is left only with the useless part of they year as it is, does the Seelie court want that too? But Faeryl took a breath and forced a calmer response.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You have been listening to Yvain, he was here saying the same things and warning of some event he couldn't name. You should rest and forget the strains of leadership. You will need to be ready when winter ends and I pass the crown back to you. Until then, should anything occur, I will handle it."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course, my queen, I am sorry to trouble you with my own worrying."[PARAGRAPH:1]"It is fine, Arendel, that is what the time of rest is for. While you rule you think of nothing but the elven empire, and never of yourself. Now care for yourself. Perhaps the winter will be strong this year and Sucellus sends the new seed to help sustain us through it. I must go, there is a lot to do today. I hope you will join us for dinner."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course" Arendel said, "and I promise to be a more amenable guest."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Just make sure you come or else I will bring the meal here and we will sit in front of this window you favor, and leave the rest of the guests wondering what to do without their queens."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arendel smiled. Faeryl imagined throwing her through that window.</English>
		<French>Faeryl s'arrêta devant la chambre. Elle était reine maintenant, mais les elfes flattaient toujours Arendel. Faeryl venait de commencer son règne des six mois d'hiver, durant lesquels rien de productif ne pouvait être accompli. Puis lorsque le printemps vint et que des changements pouvaient être amorcés, la tradition la forçait à rendre le pouvoir à sa faible cousine.[PARAGRAPH:1]Elle ne pouvait rien faire d'autre que serrer les dents et entrer dans la chambre. Arendel y était, ruminant sans doute la perte temporaire de sa couronne comme elle le faisait tous les ans.[PARAGRAPH:1]"J'espère que ton séjour a été agréable ?" demanda Faeryl.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bien sûr, j'ai toujours été émerveillée par la beauté de la Cour de l'Hiver, et par la courtoisie de ses résidents."[PARAGRAPH:1]Faeryl acquiesça. Cela faisait partie du jeu qu'elles prétendaient jouer toutes les deux. Gracieuses et courtoises en paroles , mais haïssant secrètement l'autre. Toutefois Arendel semblait encore plus mélancolique qu'à l'habitude. Faeryl sourit presque à la pensée que quelque chose de vraiment mauvais pouvait arriver dans la vie parfaite d'Arendel. Elle ne put s'empêcher de poser la question.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Arendel, qu'est ce qui t'inquiète ? Ta famille va-t-elle bien ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oui, ils vont bien, merci de t'en soucier. J'ai été inquiète, et je m'en excuse, cela n'ayant absolument rien à voir avec toi ou la Cour de l'Hiver. Je ne sais pas ce ce qu'il se passe, j'ai juste l'impression que nous vivons une époque dangereuse. L'hiver arrive si tôt cette année ; on vient à peine d'accomplir les rites de l'automne et les éclaireurs rapportent déjà des chutes de neiges. Les prêtres font des rêves puissants et les forêts n'entrent pas dans leur hibernation mais semblent au contraire refleurir."[PARAGRAPH:1]Faeryl réprima sa réaction initiale. Arendel ne la croyait pas capable de gérer ce qui se présenterait. N'était-ce pas assez de ne lui laisser que la période inutile de l'année, ou la cour Seelie la voulait-elle également ? Mais Faeryl prit une grande inspiration et se força à répondre calmement.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tu as écouté Yvain, il disait la même chose et mettait en garde contre un évènement qu'il ne pouvait pas nommer. Tu devrais te reposer et oublier les fardeaux du pouvoir. Tu devras être prête lorsque l'hiver se terminera et que je te redonnerai la couronne. Jusque là, quoiqu'il se passe, je m'en occuperai."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bien sûr, ma reine, je suis désolée de vous troubler avec mes propres inquiétudes."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ce n'est rien, Arendel, c'est à cela que sert le temps de repos. Quand tu règnes, tu ne penses a rien d'autre que l'empire elfe, et jamais à toi-même. Maintenant occupe-toi de toi. Peut-être que l'hiver sera dur cette année et que Sucellus nous envoie plus de grains pour nous aider à le supporter. Je dois y aller, il y a beaucoup à faire aujourd'hui. J'espère que tu te joindras à nous pour le dîner."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bien sûr", dit Arendel, "et je promets d'être une invitée plus avenante."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Assure-toi de venir ou sinon j'apporterai le repas ici et nous nous assiérons devant cette fenêtre que tu chéris, laissant les autres invités se demander quoi faire sans leurs reines."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arendel sourit. Faeryl s'imagina la défenestrer.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Faeryl festigte sich außerhalb der Kammer. Sie war jetzt Königin, aber die Elfen scharwenzelten immer noch um Arendel herum. Faeryl hatte gerade erst ihre 6-Monatige Winterherrschaft begonnen, in der nichts produktives erreicht werden konnte. Dann, wenn der Frühling kam, und bedeutsame Veränderungen herbeigeführt hätten werden können, zwang sie die Tradition, die Herrschaft an ihre schwächere Cousine zurück zu geben.[PARAGRAPH:1]Es gab wenig was sie dagegen tun konnte, außer mit den Zähnen zu knirschen, und die Kammer zu betreten. Arendel war darinnen, und schmollte ohne Zweifel über den temporären Verlust der Königin, wie sie es jedes Jahr tat.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich hoffe, dein Aufenthalt hier war angenehm?", fragte Faeryl.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Natürlich, ich bin immer wieder überrascht von der Schönheit des Hofes der Unseelie, und der Höflichkeit seiner Bewohner."[PARAGRAPH:1]Faeryl nickte. Das gehörte zum Spiel, das sie beide zu spielen vorgaben. Herzlich und galant in ihren Taten, während sie einander im Geheimen hassten. Dennoch wirkte Arendel sogar noch melancholischer als sonst. Faeryl lächelte fast, bei dem Gedanken, dass etwas Ernstes in Arendels sonst so perfektem Leben schief gehen könnte. Sie konnte nicht widerstehen, zu fragen.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Arendel, was bedrückt dich? Geht es deiner Familie nicht gut?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Doch, sie ist wohlauf. Es ist nett von Euch, danach zu fragen." Arendel versuchte, ihre mürrische Stimmung zu erklären: "Ich bin einfach bedrückt, und ich entschuldige mich dafür, es hat sicher nichts mit Euch oder Eurem Hof zu tun. Ich weiß nicht, woher es kommt, ich fühle nur irgendwie, dass wir in eine gefährliche Zeit kommen. Der Winter kommt dieses Jahr so früh; wir haben gerade erst die Herbstriten vollendet, und die Kundschafter berichten schon von ersten Schneefällen. Unsere Priester haben gewaltige Träume und die Wälder fallen nicht in Winterschlaf, stattdessen scheint es, als ob sie wieder aufblühen."[PARAGRAPH:1]Faeryl schluckte ihre ursprüngliche Reaktion hinunter. Arendel glaubte also nicht, dass sie fähig genug wäre, mit dem fertig zu werden, was auch immer auf sie zukam. War es nicht genug, dass ihr nur der nutzlose Teil des Jahres blieb, so wie es jetzt war, wollte der Hof der Seelie diesen jetzt auch? Aber Faeryl holte Atem, und zwang sich zu einer ruhigeren Antwort.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Du hast also mit Yvain gesprochen. Er war auch hier, und hat ebenfalls von dunklen Hinweisen gesprochen, die uns vor irgendetwas warnen sollen, von dem er selbst noch nicht weiss, was es ist. Du solltest ruhen, und dich von den Anstrengungen des Herrschens erholen. Du musst bereit sein, wenn der Winter vorbei ist, und ich die Krone wieder übergeben muss. Wenn jedoch vor Ende des Winters etwas geschieht, werde ich mich darum kümmern."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Natürlich, meine Königin, es tut mir leid, Euch mit meinen Sorgen belastet zu haben."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Es ist gut, Arendel, dafür ist die Zeit der Ruhe da. Wenn du herrschst, denkst du an nichts als das Elfenreich, und niemals an dich selbst. Jetzt kümmere dich um dich. Vielleicht wird es ein harter Winter und Sucellus schickt uns seine neue Saat um uns zu helfen, ihn zu überstehen. Ich muss jetzt gehen, es gibt viel zu erledigen. Ich hoffe, wir sehen dich beim Abendessen."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Natürlich", antwortete Arendel, "und ich verspreche, ein erfreulicherer Gast zu sein."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Schau nur, dass du kommst, denn sonst lasse ich das Mahl hierher bringen, und wir essen es bei diesem Fenster, das du so magst, und lassen den Rest der Gäste sich fragen, was sie ohne ihre beiden Königinnen machen sollen."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arendel lächelte. Faeryl stellte sich vor, sie durch dieses Fenster zu schmeißen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Faeryl steeled herself outside of the chamber. She was queen now, but still the elves fawned over Arendel. Faeryl had just begun her 6-month winter reign, when nothing productive could be accomplished. Then, when spring came and meaningful change could be enacted, tradition forced her to pass it back to her weaker cousin.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was little she could do but grit her teeth and head into the chamber. Arendel was inside, no doubt pouting over the temporary loss of her crown as she did every year.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I trust your stay has been comfortable?" Faeryl asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course, I am always amazed at the beauty of the Unseelie court, and the courtesy of its residents."[PARAGRAPH:1]Faeryl nodded. This was a part of the game they both pretended to play. Cordial and gracious in action, while secretly hating other. Yet Arendel seemed even more melancholy than usual. Faeryl almost smiled at the thought that something serious might be wrong in Arendel's perfect life. She couldn't resist asking.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Arendel, what concerns you? Is your family well?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, they are well. It is kind of you to ask. I have been bothered, and I apologize for that, it is certainly nothing to do with you or the Unseelie court. I don't know what it is, I just feel like we are in a dangerous time. Winter is coming so early this year; we have just performed the rite of autumn and the scouts are already reporting some snowfall. The priests are having powerful dreams and the forests aren't dropping into their winter slumber, instead they seem to be reblossoming."[PARAGRAPH:1]Faeryl choked back her initial reaction. Arendel didn't trust that she would be able to handle whatever lay ahead. Isn't it enough that she is left only with the useless part of they year as it is, does the Seelie court want that too? But Faeryl took a breath and forced a calmer response.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You have been listening to Yvain, he was here saying the same things and warning of some event he couldn't name. You should rest and forget the strains of leadership. You will need to be ready when winter ends and I pass the crown back to you. Until then, should anything occur, I will handle it."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course, my queen, I am sorry to trouble you with my own worrying."[PARAGRAPH:1]"It is fine, Arendel, that is what the time of rest is for. While you rule you think of nothing but the elven empire, and never of yourself. Now care for yourself. Perhaps the winter will be strong this year and Sucellus sends the new seed to help sustain us through it. I must go, there is a lot to do today. I hope you will join us for dinner."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course" Arendel said, "and I promise to be a more amenable guest."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Just make sure you come or else I will bring the meal here and we will sit in front of this window you favor, and leave the rest of the guests wondering what to do without their queens."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arendel smiled. Faeryl imagined throwing her through that window.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Faeryl steeled herself outside of the chamber. She was queen now, but still the elves fawned over Arendel. Faeryl had just begun her 6-month winter reign, when nothing productive could be accomplished. Then, when spring came and meaningful change could be enacted, tradition forced her to pass it back to her weaker cousin.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was little she could do but grit her teeth and head into the chamber. Arendel was inside, no doubt pouting over the temporary loss of her crown as she did every year.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I trust your stay has been comfortable?" Faeryl asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course, I am always amazed at the beauty of the Unseelie court, and the courtesy of its residents."[PARAGRAPH:1]Faeryl nodded. This was a part of the game they both pretended to play. Cordial and gracious in action, while secretly hating other. Yet Arendel seemed even more melancholy than usual. Faeryl almost smiled at the thought that something serious might be wrong in Arendel's perfect life. She couldn't resist asking.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Arendel, what concerns you? Is your family well?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, they are well. It is kind of you to ask. I have been bothered, and I apologize for that, it is certainly nothing to do with you or the Unseelie court. I don't know what it is, I just feel like we are in a dangerous time. Winter is coming so early this year; we have just performed the rite of autumn and the scouts are already reporting some snowfall. The priests are having powerful dreams and the forests aren't dropping into their winter slumber, instead they seem to be reblossoming."[PARAGRAPH:1]Faeryl choked back her initial reaction. Arendel didn't trust that she would be able to handle whatever lay ahead. Isn't it enough that she is left only with the useless part of they year as it is, does the Seelie court want that too? But Faeryl took a breath and forced a calmer response.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You have been listening to Yvain, he was here saying the same things and warning of some event he couldn't name. You should rest and forget the strains of leadership. You will need to be ready when winter ends and I pass the crown back to you. Until then, should anything occur, I will handle it."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course, my queen, I am sorry to trouble you with my own worrying."[PARAGRAPH:1]"It is fine, Arendel, that is what the time of rest is for. While you rule you think of nothing but the elven empire, and never of yourself. Now care for yourself. Perhaps the winter will be strong this year and Sucellus sends the new seed to help sustain us through it. I must go, there is a lot to do today. I hope you will join us for dinner."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Of course" Arendel said, "and I promise to be a more amenable guest."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Just make sure you come or else I will bring the meal here and we will sit in front of this window you favor, and leave the rest of the guests wondering what to do without their queens."[PARAGRAPH:1]Arendel smiled. Faeryl imagined throwing her through that window.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_RIVANNA</Tag>
		<English>Rivanna the Wraith Lord</English>
		<French>Rivanna, Seigneur Fantomatique</French>
		<German>Rivanna die Geisterkönigin</German>
		<Italian>Rivanna the Wraith Lord</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rivanna the Wraith Lord</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_VOLANNA</Tag>
		<English>Volanna</English>
		<French>Volanna</French>
		<German>Volanna</German>
		<Italian>Volanna</Italian>
		<Spanish>Volanna</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_SVARTALFAR</Tag>
		<English>Svartalfar Palace</English>
		<French>Palais svartálfur</French>
		<German>Palast der Svartalfar</German>
		<Italian>Svartalfar Palace</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Svartalfar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHROUDED_WOODS</Tag>
		<English>Shrouded Woods</English>
		<French>Bois Secret</French>
		<German>Verschleierte Wälder</German>
		<Italian>Shrouded Woods</Italian>
		<Spanish>Shrouded Woods</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHROUDED_WOODS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>A shrouded wood is used to train Svartalfar recon units in forest stealth. Any recon unit visiting this building will gain the ability to become invisible in forests and ancient forests.</English>
		<French>Le Bois Secret est utilisé pour entrainer les unités de reconnaissances svartálfar au camouflage forestier. Toute unité de reconnaissance visitant ces bois obtiendra la possibilité de devenir invisible dans les forêts et les forêts anciennes.</French>
		<German>Ein Verschleierter Wald wird genutzt, um die Svartalfarischen Aufklärungseinheiten in der Waldtarnung auszubilden. Jede Aufklärungseinheit, die dieses "Gebäude" besucht, erhält die Fähigkeit, sich in Wald und Altem Wald unsichtbar zu machen.</German>
		<Italian>A shrouded wood is used to train Svartalfar recon units in forest stealth. Any recon unit visiting this building will gain the ability to become invisible in forests and ancient forests.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A shrouded wood is used to train Svartalfar recon units in forest stealth. Any recon unit visiting this building will gain the ability to become invisible in forests and ancient forests.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHROUDED_WOODS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"But there is a boundary to their realm- the boundary of the dark, horrible, lofty forest. There, like the waves about the Hebrides, the low underwood is agitated continually. But there is no wind throughout the heaven. And the tall primeval trees rock eternally hither and thither with a crashing and mighty sound. And from their high summits, one by one, drop everlasting dews. And at the roots strange poisonous flowers lie writhing in perturbed slumber. And overhead, with a rustling and loud noise, the gray clouds rush westwardly forever, until they roll, a cataract, over the fiery wall of the horizon. But there is no wind throughout the heaven. And by the shores of the river, there is neither quiet nor silence. " [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]    e.a.p.</English>
		<French>"Mais il y a un lien vers leur royaume - le lien de la sombre, horrible forêt gigantesque. Ici, comme les vagues sur un archipel, le sous-bois est perpétuellement agité. Mais il n'y a pas de vent dans les cieux. Et les grand arbres primordiaux d'ici et là bas se balancent, produisant un son puissant. Et de leurs hauts sommets, une par une, tombent des gouttes de rosée sans fin. Et aux racines d'étranges fleurs empoisonnées gisent contorsionnées comme dans un sommeil perturbé. Et par-dessus tout, avec un bruissement bruyant, les nuages gris foncent sans fin vers l'ouest, jusqu'à basculer, telle une cataracte, par delà l'horizon brillant. Mais il n'y a pas de vent dans les cieux. Et sur les berges de la rivière, il n'y a ni calme ni silence."[PARAGRAPH:2]E.A.P.</French>
		<German>"Aber ihr Reich hat eine Grenze - diese Grenze ist ein hoher, dunkler, schreckensvoller Wald. Das niedrige Unterholz ist, wie die Wellen um die Hebriden, in immerwährender Bewegung. Und doch regt sich kein Hauch am Himmel. Und die ungeheuren Urwaldbäume schwanken ewig hin und her mit machtvollem Brausen. Und aus ihren hohen Wipfeln fällt Tropfen auf Tropfen, ein ewiger Tau. Und um ihre Wurzeln winden sich seltsame, giftige Blumen in unruhigem Schlummer. Und über ihren Häuptern eilen die grauen Wolken mit lautem Rauschen immer westwärts, bis sie als Katarakt über die feurigen Mauern des Horizontes herabstürzen. Und doch regt sich kein Hauch am Himmel. Und an den Ufern des Flusses ist nicht Ruhe noch Schweigen." [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]    e.a.p.</German>
		<Italian>"But there is a boundary to their realm- the boundary of the dark, horrible, lofty forest. There, like the waves about the Hebrides, the low underwood is agitated continually. But there is no wind throughout the heaven. And the tall primeval trees rock eternally hither and thither with a crashing and mighty sound. And from their high summits, one by one, drop everlasting dews. And at the roots strange poisonous flowers lie writhing in perturbed slumber. And overhead, with a rustling and loud noise, the gray clouds rush westwardly forever, until they roll, a cataract, over the fiery wall of the horizon. But there is no wind throughout the heaven. And by the shores of the river, there is neither quiet nor silence. " [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]    e.a.p.</Italian>
		<Spanish>"But there is a boundary to their realm- the boundary of the dark, horrible, lofty forest. There, like the waves about the Hebrides, the low underwood is agitated continually. But there is no wind throughout the heaven. And the tall primeval trees rock eternally hither and thither with a crashing and mighty sound. And from their high summits, one by one, drop everlasting dews. And at the roots strange poisonous flowers lie writhing in perturbed slumber. And overhead, with a rustling and loud noise, the gray clouds rush westwardly forever, until they roll, a cataract, over the fiery wall of the horizon. But there is no wind throughout the heaven. And by the shores of the river, there is neither quiet nor silence. " [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]    e.a.p.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_VEIL_OF_NIGHT</Tag>
		<English>Veil of Night</English>
		<French>Voile de Nuit</French>
		<German>Schleier der Nacht</German>
		<Italian>Veil of Night</Italian>
		<Spanish>Veil of Night</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_VEIL_OF_NIGHT_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]All your units gain [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]Hidden Nationality[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Toutes vos unités gagnent la [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]Nationalité Cachée[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Alle eure Einheiten erhalten die Beförderung [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]Verborgene Nationalität[\LINK]</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]All your units gain [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]Hidden Nationality[\LINK]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]All your units gain [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]Hidden Nationality[\LINK]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ALAZKAN</Tag>
		<English>Alazkan the Assassin</English>
		<French>Alazkan l'Assassin</French>
		<German>Alazkan der Meuchelmörder</German>
		<Italian>Alazkan the Assassin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Alazkan the Assassin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ALAZKAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Luchuirp sculptor carefully chipped through the stone. Alazkan didn't believe the dwarf could damage the treasure inside the statue but he wasn't taking any chances. If the statue had to be broken apart, he would find the most talented to do it.[PARAGRAPH:1]The dwarf blew loose marble away from where he was chiseling, then looked at Alazkan in surprise. A polished piece of jet black could be seen within the white stone.[PARAGRAPH:1]"That's it," Alazkan said, "be careful."[PARAGRAPH:1]To further make his point Alazkan pushed the point of his sword into dwarfs back. It cut easily through the thick leather and made a shallow cut in the sculptors shoulder. The dwarf gasped in pain but continued working carefully to remove the black piece from the statue without damaging it.[PARAGRAPH:1]When he was done a jagged shard of black was revealed. It looked like an opal but flat and about the size of small buckler. On one side it was smooth and so black it looked like a hole in whatever it was laid upon. The other side was polished and reflected Alazkan's image...[PARAGRAPH:1]The sculptor ran for the door. Alazkan looked up only to see a ghostly image of himself burst across the room and then hobble the dwarf with a strike to the back of his knees. The dwarf fell and Alazkan watched his image jump onto him, stab again and the dwarf was dead.[PARAGRAPH:1]In a few seconds the image disappeared. Alazkan wrapped the black shard into his cloak, this would be very handy indeed. Then a Svartalfar hunter Alazkan had assigned to keep guard opened the door.[PARAGRAPH:1]"They are coming" she said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Good," Alazkan replied, "we are done here."[PARAGRAPH:1]The Luchuirp moved slowly through the forest. A small punitive expedition responding to the sculptors message. They were too late, but it didn't matter, they'd soon regret trying to make retribution upon the servants of the Winter Court. They traveled like elephants, crashing along the path, making a great ruckus, trampling the brush and plants on the lightly worn path into the dust. Alazkan crouched among his sisters, his fellow warriors, and waited for them to come.[PARAGRAPH:1]In a roomy, well-furnished and comfortable tent, far away from the dark and miserable forest the soldiers were slogging through, the Luchuirp commanders gathered around a mage with a scrying glass, listening to his report of their progress. The tent and all the ones around it were set up in a clearing, which was hacked and burned out of the all-encroaching forests that covered and obscured the lands of Faeryl Viconia, the Queen of Mischief. The generals didn't put themselves in harm's way, they had to be detached from their little army in order to make cool, correct decisions unhindered by the chaos of a surrounding skirmish. But right now, nothing demanded their attention, so they discussed what they would do when the soldiers reached the closest settlement.[PARAGRAPH:1]On a stretch where the path narrowed slightly and the shadows seemed to deepen, the Svartalfar struck. Banshees, witches, amazons, lashing out from the darkness, retreating, and lashing out again, cutting short a man's life every time. Jinxes, curses, knives, darts, arrows and all manner of projectiles flying out between the shadows and the foliage, leaving pain and terror in their wake. Poisoned men raved like lunatics, the wounded screamed and the soldiers yelled and cried in confusion. Alazkan danced and flitted among the confused mass of soldiers. A thrust here, a slash there, with the grace and efficiency of endless practice. Crossbowmen fired bolts blindly, hoping to hit something in the trees, but as often as not hitting their allies, fighting vicious hand-to-hand battles with the Svartalfar in an attempt to strike back at their hidden tormentors. Those who broke and fled along the path were caught in hidden traps, just as lethal as their live foes. The battle was going badly for the Luchuirp, it was going worse than badly, it was disastrous. If it weren't for the fact that they were trapped, it would have been a rout. As it was, ever dwindling pockets of desperate survivors were doing their best to take as many elvish vixens with them as possible before their inevitable demise, fighting with the rage and bitterness of desperate men. Then the spells came.[PARAGRAPH:1]Action among the graying men in the elaborate tent had been swift and decisive. The battle was lost, the men dead anyway. What difference did it make who killed them in the final reckoning? They may as well use the opportunity to strike a blow at their shadowy foes. At least then the soldiers would not have died entirely in vain. The general, a hard man in glittering, polished armor with little practical use, had not hesitated in ordering the mages to saturate the battlefield with their ethereal doom.[PARAGRAPH:1]The fire rained down from the sky, meteors, lightning and fireballs splitting the trees and sending flaming splinters and shards flying between the combatants. Great chunks of earth flew up where meteors struck and heat waves threw bodies around like rag dolls or vaporized unfortunates where they stood. The forest floor was turned to mud, a mud made not of water and dirt, but of blood, and sap, and earth and ash. A cratered wasteland, every bit as hellish as the lands of the Infernal, where elves and dwarves lay, sliced and burned, united in undignified, violent death, a horrific, ever convulsing monument to hatred, composed of limbs, flames and entrails.[PARAGRAPH:1]The scene was pure chaos, the horrible banshee wails of mangled Svartalfar mixing with the despairing, incomprehensible cries of the dwarves that were being sacrificed by their comrades in arms. Survivors sought any cover they could find, skittering desperately away from the destruction. When two foes found the same hole to hide in, a brief fight would erupt, leaving only the victor to cower in safety until another challenger arrived. The air reeked with the odor of the freshly slaughtered, mingled with smoke, earth and the odd smell of magic left behind. And all the while the spells thundered down, pummeling the site again, and again, and again.[PARAGRAPH:1]The men in the tent listened impassively or paced around the tent as the mage conveyed his impressions from the battle. The crackles and fizzes of the mages working their craft could be clearly heard through the thin walls, as could the duller, more distant whooshes and booms of the spells hitting home. Surely, no one could survive such destruction? A great blow was struck this day, a blow which those accursed elves would not soon forget. The generals congratulated each other. Still, they were suitably somber about losing so many brave, but sadly expendable, warriors.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alazkan made his escape, dodging the first blasts and sweeping through the forest, running with determination in the direction in which the fiery trails of meteors and fireballs pointed him. Soon, the other Svartalfar survivors would follow. They knew where the Luchuirp made their camp, but it was easy to use the smoky trails as guides, to get there all the faster. But Alazkan was far, far ahead of them. Already, he could see the flashes of spell casting through the foliage.[PARAGRAPH:1]A commotion sounded from outside the generals' tent. The man in the ceremonial armor raised an eyebrow, then quickly wound a small, one-hand crossbow. Others grabbed swords and axes, hefting them in preparation of defending themselves. They felt secure that they were far enough away from the fight, but one never knew if their foe had sent a small force to them as well. Although they would have to be many to get past the guard squad at the door, it was wise to be on the safe side. The commotion was drawing nearer, after all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alazkan was already in the camp. He knew where the generals' tent was and he was determined to battle his way there. Guards and camp followers fell like leaves in autumn trying to stop him, as he sliced, cut, danced and dodged his way closer, ever closer to his goal. He fell upon the guards outside the tent like divine retribution, cutting them apart with artistic grace and great gore. He was fury, he was revenge, he was a force of nature. And now, he was bursting through the door.[PARAGRAPH:1]The general leveled his crossbow and fired. The bolt drove home with a very final thud.[PARAGRAPH:1]While the men in the tent watched Alazkan's image crumple to the ground and fade, Alazkan stepped from the shadows to complete his mission. His doppelganger had done the job he was meant to do, distract and confuse, so Alazkan could eliminate his quarry and get out alive. The shock generated by his sudden appearance gave his victims no opportunity to act before they were all, without exception, dispatched to the vault of their god. Alazkan, pleased with how easy it had been, spent the rest of the day having sport with the mages and guards, until his allies came and he ran out of quarry.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the dust settled and the ground drank blood, the trees and the mist of the Svartalfar forests closed over the site of the battle and the little camp. The vermin were purged by poison and traps, and the Svartalfar household could return to order and peace.</English>
		<French>Le scuplteur luchuri perça précautionneusement la pierre. Alazkan ne pensait pas que le nain pourrait endommager le trésor à l'intérieur de la statue, mais il ne souhaitait prendre aucun risque. Si la statue devait être mise en pièces, il trouverait le meilleur pour le faire.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le nain dégagea des morceaux de marbre de l'endroit qu'il ciselait, puis regarda Alakzan avec surprise. Un pièce polie d'un noir de jais était visible au milieu de la pierre blanche.[PARAGRAPH:1]"C'est ça," dit Alakzan, "soyez prudent."[PARAGRAPH:1]Pour appuyer son propos, Alakzan posa la pointe de son épée dans le dos du nain. Elle transperça facilement le cuir épais et fit une entaille superficielle dans l'épaule su sculpteur. Le nain grogna de douleur mais continua de travailler avec précaution à enlever la pièce noire de la statue sans l'endommager.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quand il eut fini, un éclat noir et acéré était révélé. Il ressemblait à une opale, mais plat et à peu près de la taille d'un petit bouclier. Sur une des faces il était lisse et si noir qu'il ressemblait à un trou, qu'importe sur quoi il était posé. L'autre côté était poli et reflétait l'image d'Alakzan...[PARAGRAPH:1]Le sculpteur se précipita vers la porte. Alakzan ne leva les yeux que pour voir une image fantômatique de lui-même traverser la pièce en un éclair et immobiliser le nain avec une frappe à l'arrière de ses genoux. Le nain tomba et Alakzan regarda son image sauter sur lui, frapper à nouveau, et le nain était mort.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quelques instants plus tard l'image avait disparu. Alakzan enveloppa l'éclat noir dans sa cape, ça sera visiblement très utile. Un chasseur svartálfur désigné par Alazkan pour faire le guet ouvrit alors la porte.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ils arrivent" dit-elle.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bien," répondit Alazkan, "nous en avons fini ici."[PARAGRAPH:1]Les luchuris se déplaçaient lentement au travers de la forêt. Une petite expédition punitive répondant au message du sculpteur. Ils étaient arrivés trop tard, mais ça n'avait pas d'importance, ils regretteraient bien assez tôt leur tentative de vengeance envers les serviteurs de la Cour de l'Hiver. Ils se déplaçaient tels des éléphants, renversant tout sur leur passage, faisant un bruit du diable, foulant au pied les plantes et buissons du petit chemin discret. Alazkan s'accroupit au milieu de ses s&#156;urs, ses compagnons d'armes, et les attendit.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dans une tente spacieuse, confortable et bien équipée, loin de la forêt sombre et misérable dans laquelles les soldats se traînaient, les chefs luchuris se regroupèrent autour d'un mage et de son orbe de divination, écoutant le compte-rendu de leur progression. La tente et les autres autour étaient installées dans une clairière, qui avait été créée en abattant et brûlant les forêts envahissantes qui couvraient et obscurcissaient les terres de Faeryl Viconia, la Reine de la Discorde. Les généraux ne se mettaient pas en danger, car ils devaient rester détachés de leurs troupes pour pouvoir prendre des décisions correctes et réfléchies, sans être influencés par le chaos d'une escarmouche à laquelle ils participeraient. Mais pour l'instant rien ne requiérait leur attention, et ils discutaient de la marche à suivre quand les soldats atteidraient le village le plus proche.[PARAGRAPHE:1]Sur une portion du chemin qui se rétrecissait et où les ombres semblaient s'épaissir, les svartálfar frappèrent. Banshees, sorcières, amazones surgissaient des ténèbres, se repliaient, et surgissaient encore, emportant à chaque fois la vie d'un homme. Mauvais sorts, malédictions, couteaux, dards, flèches et tous types de projectiles volaient entre les ombres et le feuillage, laissant une trainée de douleur et de terreur dans leur sillage. Les hommes empoisonnés se débattaient comme des fous, les blessés s'époumonaient et les soldats criaient et hurlaient dans une totale confusion. Alazkan dansait et voltigeait au milieu de l'amas confus de soldats. Une poussée par ci, un coup par là, avec la grâce et l'efficacité d'une pratique de toujours. Les arbalétriers tiraient à l'aveuglette, espérant toucher quelque chose dans les arbres, mais autant que ne pas toucher leurs alliés, se battant férocemment au corps-à-corps avec les svartálfar dans une tentative désespérée de repousser leurs bourreaux. Ceux qui rompirent les rangs et fuirent furent attrapés par des pièges cachés, tout aussi mortels que leurs adversaires vivants. La bataille tournait mal pour les luchuris. En fait elle tournait plus que mal, elle tournait au désastre. S'il n'avaient pas été piégés, le désastre se serait transformé en déroute. Mais étant piégés, chaque poche évanescente de survivants désespérés faisait de son mieux pour emporter le plus possible de ces maudits elfes dans leur tombe, se battant avec l'énergie du désespoir. Puis vinrent les sorts.[PARAGRAPH:1]La décision des hommes grisonnants dans la tente de commandement fut prompte et décisive. La bataille était perdue, les hommes morts de toutes les façons. Quelle différence peut faire la manière dont ils seront morts au final ? Autant utiliser cette opportunité de frapper leurs opposants des ombres. Au moins les soldats ne seront pas morts en vain. Le général, un homme dans une armure brillante et polie peu pratique, n'avait pas hésité à ordonner aux mages de saturer le champ de bataille avec leur puissance éthérique.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le feu tombait du ciel, des météors, la foudre et des boules de feu fendant les arbres et envoyant des copeaux et des échardes enflammés voler au milieu des combattants. De gros pans de terre s'envolèrent là où les météores avaient frappé et des vagues de chaleur envoyèrent valser les corps comme des poupées de chiffons ou vaporisèrent les infortunés sur place. Le sol de la forêt s'était transformé en boue, une boue constituée non pas d'eau et de saleté mais de sang, de sève, de terre et de cendre. Un paysage de désolation constellé de cratères, tout aussi cataclysmique que les terres infernales, où gisent elfes et nains, découpés, brûlés, uni par une mort indigne et violente, monument revulsant à la haine, composé de membres, de flammes et d'entrailles.[PARAGRAPH:1]La scène était une porte ouverte sur le chaos, les horribles gémissements fantômatiques des svartálfar mutilés mélangés aux cris de désespoir et d'incompréhension des nains qui avaient été sacrifiés par leurs compagnons d'armes. Les survivant cherchèrent n'importe quel couvert, fuyant désespérément la destruction. Quand deux ennemis trouvaient le même trou pour se cacher, un bref combat s'engageait, ne laissant que le vainqueur se terrer en sécurité, jusqu'à l'arrivée d'un autre prétendant. L'air embaumait le massacre récent, mêlé avec la fumée, la terre et l'étrange odeur laissée par la magie. Et pendant tout ce temps les sorts continuaient de s'abattre, martelant à nouveau le site, et encore, et encore.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les hommes de la tente écoutaient stoïquement ou en faisant les cent pas tandis que le mage transmettait ses impressions du champ de bataille. Les craquements et bourdonnements des mages au travail pouvaient aisément être entendus au travers des murs fins, de même que les woosh et boums plus sourds et distants des sorts frappant leur cible. À coup sûr, nul n'aurait pu survivre à une telle destruction ? Un grand coup fut porté ce jour là, un coup que ces maudits elfes n'oubliraient pas de sitôt. LEs généraux se congratulèrent mutuellement. Ils étaient pourtant amers comme il se doit suite à la perte de tant de braves mais tristement sacrifiables guerriers.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alazkan s'était échappé, esquivant les premiers impacts et déferlant dans la forêt, courant avec détermination dans la direction que les fières trainées des météores et boules de feu lui indiquaient. Bientôt, les autres svartálfar survivants le rejoindraient. Ils savaient où les luchuris avaient monté leur camp, mais il était facile d'utiliser les trainées de fumées comme guide pour s'y rendre le plus vite possible. Mais Alazkan était loin, loin devant. Il pouvait déjà voir les flashs des sorts lancés au travers du feuillage.[PARAGRAPH:1]Du remue-ménage fut entendu à l'extérieur de la tente des généraux. L'homme en armure de cérémonie leva un sourcil, puis dégaina rapidement une arbalète à une main. Les autres attrapèrent épées et haches, les levant pour se préparer à se protéger. Ils étaient confiants dans le fait d'être assez loins du combat, mais nul ne pouvait savoir si leur adversaire avait également lancé une petite attaque contre eux. Bien qu'ils devraient être nombreux pour franchir l'escouade de protection à la porte, il était sage d'être du bon côté.Le tumulte se rapprochait, après tout.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alazkan était déjà dans le camp. Il savait où se trouvait la tente des généraux et était déterminé à se frayer un chemin jusqu'à eux. Les gardes et aides de camp tombaient comme des feuilles en automne en tentant de l'arrêter, tandis qu'il tranchait, coupait, dansait et esquivait sur son chemin, toujours plus proche de son but. Il tomba sur les gardes à l'extérieur de la tente comme un châtiment divin, les découpant avec une grâce artistique et des gerbes de sang. Il était furie, il était revenche, il était une force de la nature. Et à présent, il surgissait au travers de la porte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le général leva son arbalète et tira. Le carreau fit mouche avec un bruit très sourd.[PARAGRAPH:1]Tandis que les hommes regardaient l'image d'Alazkan se froisser sur le sol et disparaitre, Alazkan sortit des ombres pour terminer sa mission. Son doppelganger avait bien rempli son rôle, distrayant et créant la confusion, ce qui permettait à Alazkan d'éliminer sa proie et s'en sortir vivant. Le choc provoqué par son apparition soudaine ne laissa à ses victimes aucune chance de réagir avant qu'elles soient toutes, sans exception, envoyées recontrer leur dieu. Alazkan, content de voir à quel point ça avait été facile, passa le reste de la journée à s'amuser avec les mages et les gardes, jusqu'à ce que lui et ses alliés soient à court de proies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Tandis que la poussière retombait et la terre buvait le sang, les arbres et la brume des foret svartálfar recouvrirent le site de la bataille et le petit camp. La vermine avait été éradiquée par le poison et les pièges, et la maison svartálfur pouvait retourner à l'ordre et la paix.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Sie bewegten sich langsam durch den Wald. Eine kleine Strafexpedition, mit dem Ziel einige Bäume zu verbrennen, ein paar Svartalfarische Frauen zu schänden und eine handvoll Trolle zu häuten. Ihre Auftrag: Genugtuung einzufordern für die Grenzverletzungen gegenüber ihrer Heimat. Vielleicht hatten die Svartalfar einige Kinder entführt oder Schabernack mit den Herden getrieben. Wer wusste das schon? Es war einerlei. Sie  hatten die Frechheit besessen, sich in Vergeltung gegenüber den Dienern des Winter Konzils zu versuchen  und sie würden es bald bereuen. Jetzt bahnten sie sich ihren Weg wie eine Herde Elefanten, es war ein war ein einziges Tohuwabohu, Büsche wie Pflanzen am Rande des wenig genutzten Pfades wurden gleichermaßen von ihnen niedergetrampelt. Alazkan lag zusammen mit seinen Schwestern, seinen treuen Mitstreiterinnen, auf der Lauer und wartete, dass sie näher kamen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Weit weg von dem dunklen, tristen Wald, durch den sich die Soldaten kämpften, scharte sich in einem geräumigen und komfortabel eingerichteten Zelt eine kleine Gruppe um einen Magier und seine Glaskugel, alle lauschten gebannt der Schilderung über den Fortschritt der Soldaten. Das Zelt und alle anderen um drumherum waren auf einer kleinen Waldlichtung aufgebaut, genauer gesagt, einer von Menschenhand geschaffenen Lichtung, die mit Axt und Feuer dem alles überwuchernden Wald abgerungen worden war. Dies war das Reich von Faeryl Vinconia, der Königin der Störenfriede, ein schattiger Ort, von den hohen, ausladenden Bäumen in fahles Licht getaucht. Die Generäle hatten es nicht für notwendig gehalten, sich in Gefahr zu begeben. Stattdessen hatten sie sich von ihrer kleinen Armee getrennt, um die Befehle ruhig und geordnet geben zu können, ungehindert vom Chaos während der Schlacht. Aber zu diesem Zeitpunkt hatte noch nichts ihrer Aufmerksamkeit bedurft und so diskutierten sie darüber, was sie tun sollten, wenn die Soldaten das erste Dorf erreichen würden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als die Soldaten einen Abschnitt erreichten, an dem sich der Weg verengte und das Zwielicht des Waldes noch dunkler schien, schlugen die Svartalfar zu. Todesfeen, Hexen und Amazonen tauchten aus der Dunkelheit auf, verschwanden wieder, nur um erneut aus den Schatten zu preschen und einen weiteren Unglücklichen niederzustrecken. Flüche und Verwünschungen, Messer und Speere, Pfeile und alle anderen Arten von Projektilen gingen aus der Dunkelheit auf die Soldaten nieder. Wo auch immer die Elfen hinzielten, traf Tod und Verderben die unglücklichen Verteidiger: Vergiftete rannten umher wie Wahnsinnige, Verwundete schrieen vor Schmerz und die übrigen überraschten Soldaten warfen einander Befehle zu, die im Chaos völlig untergingen. Alazkan bahnte sich leichtfüßig seinen Weg durch den verwirrten Haufen, es sah aus als würde er einen einzigen großen Tanz aufführen. Dort ein Hieb, hier ein Schlag, anmutig und tödlich war sein Stahl, geschärft durch Jahre der Übung. Die Armbrustschützen schossen blind in die Dunkelheit, doch statt die Svartalfar trafen sie meist nur ihre eigenen Leute, die versuchten, ihre schattenhaften Angreifer in heftigen Kämpfen Mann gegen Mann zurückzutreiben. Andere rannten in Panik den Pfad weiter und lösten Fallen aus, die mindestens genauso tödlich waren, wie die Elfen. Der Kampf  verlief schlecht für die Menschen, viel schlimmer noch, er war eigentlich ein einziges Desaster. Wären die Soldaten nicht umzingelt gewesen, hätte es nur in einer Niederlage geendet. Aber so kämpften die Männer in immer kleiner werdenden Grüppchen und versuchten, trotz ihres gewissen Todes, so viele Elfen wie möglich zu erschlagen. Sie kämpften voll Zorn, Unerbittlichkeit und Verzweiflung. Doch dann kamen die Zauber.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Beschluss der ergrauten Männer in dem aufwendig eingerichteten Zelt war schnell und bestimmt gefällt worden. Der Kampf war verloren, die Männer ohnehin alle dem Tod geweiht. Welchen Unterschied hätte es jetzt noch gemacht, durch wessen Hand sie zu Tode gekommen wären? Sie konnten ebenso gut die Gelegenheit nutzen und ihren schattenhaften Feinden zumindest noch einen letzten Schlag versetzen. Wenigstens wären die Soldaten dann nicht völlig umsonst gestorben. Der General, ein abgebrühter Mann, gekleidet in eine schimmernd polierte Rüstung, die wohl bestenfalls als Zierde geeignet war, hatte nicht einen Moment gezögert, als er seinen Magiern den Befehl gab, das Schlachtfeld mit ätherischer Verdammnis zu tränken.[PARAGRAPH:1]Feuer regnete vom Himmel, Meteoriten, Blitze und Feuerbälle zerfetzten die Bäume, brennende Splitter flogen zwischen den Kämpfenden umher. Riesige Erstücke wurden in die Luft geworfen, als die ersten Meteoriten aufschlugen, Schock- und Hitzewellen schleuderten Leiber wie Puppen fort oder äscherten die Unglücklichen an Ort und Stelle ein. Der gesamte Waldboden verwandelte sich in Matsch, doch es war kein natürlicher Schlamm aus Wasser und Erde, sondern eine eklige ölige Mischung aus Blut und Säften, Erde und Asche. Am Ende war das Schlachtfeld ein kraterübersätes Stück Ödland, gleich den verwüsteten Landen der Infernal. Dort lagen sie nun, Svartalfar und Menschen, zerfetzt und verbrannt, am Ende vereint durch ihren grausamen und würdelosen Tod, zusammengefügt zu einem ewiges Mahnmal des Hasses, erbaut aus den Gliedern und Innereien der Unglücklichen und bedeckt von lodernden Flammen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Das Geschehen war ein einziges großes Chaos. Fürchterliche Todesschreie von zermalmten Svartalfar mischten sich mit den verzweifelten Rufen der verständnislosen Männer, die gerade von ihren eigenen Kameraden geopfert wurden. Überlebende suchten verzweifelt nach jeder Deckung, die sie finden konnten, um Abstand von den zerstörerischen Urgewalten zu gewinnen. Wann immer sich zwei Gegner in einem Erdloch trafen, flammte ein kurzer und schmutziger Kampf ums Überleben auf, bis nur noch einer in Sicherheit war, zumindest solange, bis der nächste Herausforderer auf die sichere Deckung zuhielt. Die Luft erfüllte sich mit dem Geruch von abgeschlagenem und verbranntem Fleisch, gemischt mit dem Duft von Rauch, Erde und Magie. Und währenddessen schlugen gingen immer mehr und mehr Zaubersprüche auf das Schlachtfeld nieder, immer mehr und mehr...[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Männer im Zelt hörten nur teilnahmslos zu, wie der Magier seine Eindrücke von der Schlacht wiedergab. Das Knistern und Zischen der Zaubersprüche, die die Magier woben, konnte ebenso durch die Dünnen Zeltwände gehört werden, wie die dumpfen und fernen Einschläge der in das Ziel. Sicherlich konnte niemand solche Zerstörung überleben! Heute war den verfluchten Elfen ein Schlag versetzt worden, den sie nicht so schnell vergessen würden. Die Generäle gratulierten einander. Natürlich waren ihre Gedanken noch immer ein wenig düster, weil sie so viele Tapfere Männer verloren hatten  aber die gemeinen Soldaten waren ja schließlich ersetzbar.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alle Svartalfar die es vermochten, flohen aus dem Hexenkessel voll tödlicher Magie. Auch Alazkan war die Flucht gelungen, er wich den ersten Druckwellen aus und rannte im Zick-Zack durch den Wald, immer weiter auf den Ort zu, den ihm die Feuerschweife der Zauber wiesen. Schon bald würden ihnen auch die anderen überlebenden Svartalfar folgen. Sie wussten, wo die Menschen ihr Lager aufgeschlagen hatten und dank den Rauchfahnen war es noch einfacher, sie zu finden. Alazkan erreichte das Lager weit vor den Anderen, er konnte schon das Aufblitzen der Zaubersprüche durch Blattwerk erkennen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kampflärm erklang von Außerhalb des Stabszeltes. Der Mann in der förmlichen Rüstung zog eine Augenbraue hoch und begann dann damit, eine kleine einhändige Armbrust zu spannen. Andere griffen nach Schwertern oder Äxten und bereiteten ihre Verteidigung vor. Sie waren sicher, dass sie weit genug von der Schlacht entfernt waren, aber man konnte nie wissen, ob der Feind nicht auch eine kleine Truppe zu ihnen geschickt hatte. Zwar müssten es viele sein, wenn sie an den Torwachen vorbeikommen wollten, aber man wollte lieber auf Nummer sicher gehen  immerhin rückte die lang ersehnte Beförderung näher.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alazkan war bereits im Inneren des Lagers. Er wusste, wo sich das Zelt der Generäle befand - direkt im Zentrum - und er war fest entschlossen, sich den Weg dorthin freizukämpfen. Die Wächter und ihre Lagerbewohner versuchten ihn zu stoppen, doch sie fielen alle wie welkes Laub im Herbst, während er sich mit einer Mischung aus Schlägen und tänzelnden Schritten immer näher an sein Ziel heranarbeitete. Die Wachen vor dem Zelt glaubten, die göttliche Strafe selbst sei über sie gekommen, so behände und tödlich fiel er über sie her. Er war Wut, er war Rache, er war eine Naturgewalt. Und nun stürmte er durch den Eingang in das Zelt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der General hob seine Armbrust und schoss. Der Bolzen bohrte sich mit einem dumpfen Geräusch in seinen Gegenüber.[PARAGRAPH:1]Während die Männer im Zelt beobachteten, wie das Spiegelbild lautlos zu Boden sank und langsam verblasste, nahm Alazkan seine Chance wahr, aus dem Schatten zu treten und die Mission zu beenden. Der Doppelgänger hatte seine Aufgabe vorzüglich erfüllt, alle Feinde waren abgelenkt und verwirrt. Nun konnte er seine Beute töten und sich lebend aus dem Staub machen. Der Schock, den sein plötzliches Auftreten zwischen den Männern erzeugte, war noch nicht gänzlich aus den Gesichtern gewichen, als ihre Seelen auch schon allesamt auf dem Weg zu ihrem Schöpfer waren. Alazkan lächelte befriedigt darüber, wie einfach es dieses mal doch gewesen war. Er verbrachte den Rest des Tages damit, die übrigen Wächter und Magier zur Strecke zu bringen, bis seine Verbündeten ankamen und er keine Beute mehr fand.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als sich der Staub legte und der Boden das Blut trank, begannen Nebel und Bäume die beiden Schlachtfelder zu bedecken. Das elende Ungeziefer war durch Gift und Fallen beseitigt worden. Und endlich kehrten im Hause der Svartalfar wieder Ruhe und Ordnung ein.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]The Luchuirp sculptor carefully chipped through the stone. Alazkan didn't believe the dwarf could damage the treasure inside the statue but he wasn't taking any chances. If the statue had to be broken apart, he would find the most talented to do it.[PARAGRAPH:1]The dwarf blew loose marble away from where he was chiseling, then looked at Alazkan in surprise. A polished piece of jet black could be seen within the white stone.[PARAGRAPH:1]"That's it," Alazkan said, "be careful."[PARAGRAPH:1]To further make his point Alazkan pushed the point of his sword into dwarfs back. It cut easily through the thick leather and made a shallow cut in the sculptors shoulder. The dwarf gasped in pain but continued working carefully to remove the black piece from the statue without damaging it.[PARAGRAPH:1]When he was done a jagged shard of black was revealed. It looked like an opal but flat and about the size of small buckler. On one side it was smooth and so black it looked like a hole in whatever it was laid upon. The other side was polished and reflected Alazkan's image...[PARAGRAPH:1]The sculptor ran for the door. Alazkan looked up only to see a ghostly image of himself burst across the room and then hobble the dwarf with a strike to the back of his knees. The dwarf fell and Alazkan watched his image jump onto him, stab again and the dwarf was dead.[PARAGRAPH:1]In a few seconds the image disappeared. Alazkan wrapped the black shard into his cloak, this would be very handy indeed. Then a Svartalfar hunter Alazkan had assigned to keep guard opened the door.[PARAGRAPH:1]"They are coming" she said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Good," Alazkan replied, "we are done here."[PARAGRAPH:1]The Luchuirp moved slowly through the forest. A small punitive expedition responding to the sculptors message. They were too late, but it didn't matter, they'd soon regret trying to make retribution upon the servants of the Winter Court. They traveled like elephants, crashing along the path, making a great ruckus, trampling the brush and plants on the lightly worn path into the dust. Alazkan crouched among his sisters, his fellow warriors, and waited for them to come.[PARAGRAPH:1]In a roomy, well-furnished and comfortable tent, far away from the dark and miserable forest the soldiers were slogging through, the Luchuirp commanders gathered around a mage with a scrying glass, listening to his report of their progress. The tent and all the ones around it were set up in a clearing, which was hacked and burned out of the all-encroaching forests that covered and obscured the lands of Faeryl Viconia, the Queen of Mischief. The generals didn't put themselves in harm's way, they had to be detached from their little army in order to make cool, correct decisions unhindered by the chaos of a surrounding skirmish. But right now, nothing demanded their attention, so they discussed what they would do when the soldiers reached the closest settlement.[PARAGRAPH:1]On a stretch where the path narrowed slightly and the shadows seemed to deepen, the Svartalfar struck. Banshees, witches, amazons, lashing out from the darkness, retreating, and lashing out again, cutting short a man's life every time. Jinxes, curses, knives, darts, arrows and all manner of projectiles flying out between the shadows and the foliage, leaving pain and terror in their wake. Poisoned men raved like lunatics, the wounded screamed and the soldiers yelled and cried in confusion. Alazkan danced and flitted among the confused mass of soldiers. A thrust here, a slash there, with the grace and efficiency of endless practice. Crossbowmen fired bolts blindly, hoping to hit something in the trees, but as often as not hitting their allies, fighting vicious hand-to-hand battles with the Svartalfar in an attempt to strike back at their hidden tormentors. Those who broke and fled along the path were caught in hidden traps, just as lethal as their live foes. The battle was going badly for the Luchuirp, it was going worse than badly, it was disastrous. If it weren't for the fact that they were trapped, it would have been a rout. As it was, ever dwindling pockets of desperate survivors were doing their best to take as many elvish vixens with them as possible before their inevitable demise, fighting with the rage and bitterness of desperate men. Then the spells came.[PARAGRAPH:1]Action among the graying men in the elaborate tent had been swift and decisive. The battle was lost, the men dead anyway. What difference did it make who killed them in the final reckoning? They may as well use the opportunity to strike a blow at their shadowy foes. At least then the soldiers would not have died entirely in vain. The general, a hard man in glittering, polished armor with little practical use, had not hesitated in ordering the mages to saturate the battlefield with their ethereal doom.[PARAGRAPH:1]The fire rained down from the sky, meteors, lightning and fireballs splitting the trees and sending flaming splinters and shards flying between the combatants. Great chunks of earth flew up where meteors struck and heat waves threw bodies around like rag dolls or vaporized unfortunates where they stood. The forest floor was turned to mud, a mud made not of water and dirt, but of blood, and sap, and earth and ash. A cratered wasteland, every bit as hellish as the lands of the Infernal, where elves and dwarves lay, sliced and burned, united in undignified, violent death, a horrific, ever convulsing monument to hatred, composed of limbs, flames and entrails.[PARAGRAPH:1]The scene was pure chaos, the horrible banshee wails of mangled Svartalfar mixing with the despairing, incomprehensible cries of the dwarves that were being sacrificed by their comrades in arms. Survivors sought any cover they could find, skittering desperately away from the destruction. When two foes found the same hole to hide in, a brief fight would erupt, leaving only the victor to cower in safety until another challenger arrived. The air reeked with the odor of the freshly slaughtered, mingled with smoke, earth and the odd smell of magic left behind. And all the while the spells thundered down, pummeling the site again, and again, and again.[PARAGRAPH:1]The men in the tent listened impassively or paced around the tent as the mage conveyed his impressions from the battle. The crackles and fizzes of the mages working their craft could be clearly heard through the thin walls, as could the duller, more distant whooshes and booms of the spells hitting home. Surely, no one could survive such destruction? A great blow was struck this day, a blow which those accursed elves would not soon forget. The generals congratulated each other. Still, they were suitably somber about losing so many brave, but sadly expendable, warriors.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alazkan made his escape, dodging the first blasts and sweeping through the forest, running with determination in the direction in which the fiery trails of meteors and fireballs pointed him. Soon, the other Svartalfar survivors would follow. They knew where the Luchuirp made their camp, but it was easy to use the smoky trails as guides, to get there all the faster. But Alazkan was far, far ahead of them. Already, he could see the flashes of spell casting through the foliage.[PARAGRAPH:1]A commotion sounded from outside the generals' tent. The man in the ceremonial armor raised an eyebrow, then quickly wound a small, one-hand crossbow. Others grabbed swords and axes, hefting them in preparation of defending themselves. They felt secure that they were far enough away from the fight, but one never knew if their foe had sent a small force to them as well. Although they would have to be many to get past the guard squad at the door, it was wise to be on the safe side. The commotion was drawing nearer, after all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alazkan was already in the camp. He knew where the generals' tent was and he was determined to battle his way there. Guards and camp followers fell like leaves in autumn trying to stop him, as he sliced, cut, danced and dodged his way closer, ever closer to his goal. He fell upon the guards outside the tent like divine retribution, cutting them apart with artistic grace and great gore. He was fury, he was revenge, he was a force of nature. And now, he was bursting through the door.[PARAGRAPH:1]The general leveled his crossbow and fired. The bolt drove home with a very final thud.[PARAGRAPH:1]While the men in the tent watched Alazkan's image crumple to the ground and fade, Alazkan stepped from the shadows to complete his mission. His doppelganger had done the job he was meant to do, distract and confuse, so Alazkan could eliminate his quarry and get out alive. The shock generated by his sudden appearance gave his victims no opportunity to act before they were all, without exception, dispatched to the vault of their god. Alazkan, pleased with how easy it had been, spent the rest of the day having sport with the mages and guards, until his allies came and he ran out of quarry.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the dust settled and the ground drank blood, the trees and the mist of the Svartalfar forests closed over the site of the battle and the little camp. The vermin were purged by poison and traps, and the Svartalfar household could return to order and peace.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Luchuirp sculptor carefully chipped through the stone. Alazkan didn't believe the dwarf could damage the treasure inside the statue but he wasn't taking any chances. If the statue had to be broken apart, he would find the most talented to do it.[PARAGRAPH:1]The dwarf blew loose marble away from where he was chiseling, then looked at Alazkan in surprise. A polished piece of jet black could be seen within the white stone.[PARAGRAPH:1]"That's it," Alazkan said, "be careful."[PARAGRAPH:1]To further make his point Alazkan pushed the point of his sword into dwarfs back. It cut easily through the thick leather and made a shallow cut in the sculptors shoulder. The dwarf gasped in pain but continued working carefully to remove the black piece from the statue without damaging it.[PARAGRAPH:1]When he was done a jagged shard of black was revealed. It looked like an opal but flat and about the size of small buckler. On one side it was smooth and so black it looked like a hole in whatever it was laid upon. The other side was polished and reflected Alazkan's image...[PARAGRAPH:1]The sculptor ran for the door. Alazkan looked up only to see a ghostly image of himself burst across the room and then hobble the dwarf with a strike to the back of his knees. The dwarf fell and Alazkan watched his image jump onto him, stab again and the dwarf was dead.[PARAGRAPH:1]In a few seconds the image disappeared. Alazkan wrapped the black shard into his cloak, this would be very handy indeed. Then a Svartalfar hunter Alazkan had assigned to keep guard opened the door.[PARAGRAPH:1]"They are coming" she said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Good," Alazkan replied, "we are done here."[PARAGRAPH:1]The Luchuirp moved slowly through the forest. A small punitive expedition responding to the sculptors message. They were too late, but it didn't matter, they'd soon regret trying to make retribution upon the servants of the Winter Court. They traveled like elephants, crashing along the path, making a great ruckus, trampling the brush and plants on the lightly worn path into the dust. Alazkan crouched among his sisters, his fellow warriors, and waited for them to come.[PARAGRAPH:1]In a roomy, well-furnished and comfortable tent, far away from the dark and miserable forest the soldiers were slogging through, the Luchuirp commanders gathered around a mage with a scrying glass, listening to his report of their progress. The tent and all the ones around it were set up in a clearing, which was hacked and burned out of the all-encroaching forests that covered and obscured the lands of Faeryl Viconia, the Queen of Mischief. The generals didn't put themselves in harm's way, they had to be detached from their little army in order to make cool, correct decisions unhindered by the chaos of a surrounding skirmish. But right now, nothing demanded their attention, so they discussed what they would do when the soldiers reached the closest settlement.[PARAGRAPH:1]On a stretch where the path narrowed slightly and the shadows seemed to deepen, the Svartalfar struck. Banshees, witches, amazons, lashing out from the darkness, retreating, and lashing out again, cutting short a man's life every time. Jinxes, curses, knives, darts, arrows and all manner of projectiles flying out between the shadows and the foliage, leaving pain and terror in their wake. Poisoned men raved like lunatics, the wounded screamed and the soldiers yelled and cried in confusion. Alazkan danced and flitted among the confused mass of soldiers. A thrust here, a slash there, with the grace and efficiency of endless practice. Crossbowmen fired bolts blindly, hoping to hit something in the trees, but as often as not hitting their allies, fighting vicious hand-to-hand battles with the Svartalfar in an attempt to strike back at their hidden tormentors. Those who broke and fled along the path were caught in hidden traps, just as lethal as their live foes. The battle was going badly for the Luchuirp, it was going worse than badly, it was disastrous. If it weren't for the fact that they were trapped, it would have been a rout. As it was, ever dwindling pockets of desperate survivors were doing their best to take as many elvish vixens with them as possible before their inevitable demise, fighting with the rage and bitterness of desperate men. Then the spells came.[PARAGRAPH:1]Action among the graying men in the elaborate tent had been swift and decisive. The battle was lost, the men dead anyway. What difference did it make who killed them in the final reckoning? They may as well use the opportunity to strike a blow at their shadowy foes. At least then the soldiers would not have died entirely in vain. The general, a hard man in glittering, polished armor with little practical use, had not hesitated in ordering the mages to saturate the battlefield with their ethereal doom.[PARAGRAPH:1]The fire rained down from the sky, meteors, lightning and fireballs splitting the trees and sending flaming splinters and shards flying between the combatants. Great chunks of earth flew up where meteors struck and heat waves threw bodies around like rag dolls or vaporized unfortunates where they stood. The forest floor was turned to mud, a mud made not of water and dirt, but of blood, and sap, and earth and ash. A cratered wasteland, every bit as hellish as the lands of the Infernal, where elves and dwarves lay, sliced and burned, united in undignified, violent death, a horrific, ever convulsing monument to hatred, composed of limbs, flames and entrails.[PARAGRAPH:1]The scene was pure chaos, the horrible banshee wails of mangled Svartalfar mixing with the despairing, incomprehensible cries of the dwarves that were being sacrificed by their comrades in arms. Survivors sought any cover they could find, skittering desperately away from the destruction. When two foes found the same hole to hide in, a brief fight would erupt, leaving only the victor to cower in safety until another challenger arrived. The air reeked with the odor of the freshly slaughtered, mingled with smoke, earth and the odd smell of magic left behind. And all the while the spells thundered down, pummeling the site again, and again, and again.[PARAGRAPH:1]The men in the tent listened impassively or paced around the tent as the mage conveyed his impressions from the battle. The crackles and fizzes of the mages working their craft could be clearly heard through the thin walls, as could the duller, more distant whooshes and booms of the spells hitting home. Surely, no one could survive such destruction? A great blow was struck this day, a blow which those accursed elves would not soon forget. The generals congratulated each other. Still, they were suitably somber about losing so many brave, but sadly expendable, warriors.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alazkan made his escape, dodging the first blasts and sweeping through the forest, running with determination in the direction in which the fiery trails of meteors and fireballs pointed him. Soon, the other Svartalfar survivors would follow. They knew where the Luchuirp made their camp, but it was easy to use the smoky trails as guides, to get there all the faster. But Alazkan was far, far ahead of them. Already, he could see the flashes of spell casting through the foliage.[PARAGRAPH:1]A commotion sounded from outside the generals' tent. The man in the ceremonial armor raised an eyebrow, then quickly wound a small, one-hand crossbow. Others grabbed swords and axes, hefting them in preparation of defending themselves. They felt secure that they were far enough away from the fight, but one never knew if their foe had sent a small force to them as well. Although they would have to be many to get past the guard squad at the door, it was wise to be on the safe side. The commotion was drawing nearer, after all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alazkan was already in the camp. He knew where the generals' tent was and he was determined to battle his way there. Guards and camp followers fell like leaves in autumn trying to stop him, as he sliced, cut, danced and dodged his way closer, ever closer to his goal. He fell upon the guards outside the tent like divine retribution, cutting them apart with artistic grace and great gore. He was fury, he was revenge, he was a force of nature. And now, he was bursting through the door.[PARAGRAPH:1]The general leveled his crossbow and fired. The bolt drove home with a very final thud.[PARAGRAPH:1]While the men in the tent watched Alazkan's image crumple to the ground and fade, Alazkan stepped from the shadows to complete his mission. His doppelganger had done the job he was meant to do, distract and confuse, so Alazkan could eliminate his quarry and get out alive. The shock generated by his sudden appearance gave his victims no opportunity to act before they were all, without exception, dispatched to the vault of their god. Alazkan, pleased with how easy it had been, spent the rest of the day having sport with the mages and guards, until his allies came and he ran out of quarry.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the dust settled and the ground drank blood, the trees and the mist of the Svartalfar forests closed over the site of the battle and the little camp. The vermin were purged by poison and traps, and the Svartalfar household could return to order and peace.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ALAZKAN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Alazkan starts with the hidden nationality and hero promotions, a potent combination for harassment of supposed allies, but most useful is his mirror ability, which summons an illusionary duplicate. Illusions cannot kill units, but are perfect for weakening any defender for Alazkan to kill without leaving him left weakened for retaliation. Both Alazkan and his mirror image will have the marksman promotion as well.</English>
		<French>Alazkan démarre avec la [LINK=PROMOTION_HIDDEN_NATIONALITY]nationalité cachée[\LINK] et la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_HERO]héros[\LINK], une combinaison utile pour harasser les supposés alliés, mais particulièrement utile pour sa capacité miroir, qui invoque un double illusoire. Les illusions ne peuvent pas tuer les unités, mais sont parfaites pour affaiblir n'importe quel défenseur, permettant à Alazkan de tuer sans se trouver affaibli en cas de réplique. De plus, Alazkan et son image miroir possèdent la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_MARKSMAN]tireur d'élite[\LINK].</French>
		<German>Alazkan beginnt mit versteckter Nationalität und der "Held"-Beförderung, eine mächtige Kombination zur Störung eines vermeintlichen Verbündeten, doch besonders nützlich ist seine "Spiegel"-Fähigkeit, die einen illusionären Doppelgänger beschwört. Illusionen können keine Einheiten töten, doch sind sie perfekt um Verteidiger zu schwächen, sodass Alazkan sie töten kann ohne geschwächt und anfällig für einen Gegenschlag aus dem Kampf hervorzugehen. Außerdem haben sowohl Alazkan als auch sein Doppelgänger die Scharfschützen-Beförderung.</German>
		<Italian>Alazkan starts with the hidden nationality and hero promotions, a potent combination for harassment of supposed allies, but most useful is his mirror ability, which summons an illusionary duplicate. Illusions cannot kill units, but are perfect for weakening any defender for Alazkan to kill without leaving him left weakened for retaliation. Both Alazkan and his mirror image will have the marksman promotion as well.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Alazkan starts with the hidden nationality and hero promotions, a potent combination for harassment of supposed allies, but most useful is his mirror ability, which summons an illusionary duplicate. Illusions cannot kill units, but are perfect for weakening any defender for Alazkan to kill without leaving him left weakened for retaliation. Both Alazkan and his mirror image will have the marksman promotion as well.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_ALAZKAN_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>The sculptor ran for the door. Alazkan looked up and watched a ghostly image of himself dash across the room and hobble the dwarf with a strike to the back of his knees. The dwarf fell and Alazkan watched his image jump onto him. Another stab, and the dwarf was dead. In a few seconds the image disappeared. Alazkan wrapped the black shard into his cloak. This would be very handy indeed. Then the Svartalfar huntress serving as Alazkan's guard opened the door.[PARAGRAPH:1]"They are coming" she said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Good," Alazkan replied, "we are done here."</English>
		<French>Le sculpteur se précipita vers la porte. Alakzan ne leva les yeux que pour voir une image fantômatique de lui-même traverser la pièce en un éclair et immobiliser le nain avec une frappe à l'arrière de ses genoux. Le nain tomba et Alakzan regarda son image sauter sur lui, frapper à nouveau, et le nain était mort.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quelques instants plus tard l'image avait disparu. Alakzan enveloppa l'éclat noir dans sa cape, ça sera visiblement très utile. Un chasseur svartálfur désigné par Alazkan pour faire le guet ouvrit alors la porte.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ils arrivent" dit-elle.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bien," répondit Alazkan, "nous en avons fini ici."</French>
		<German>Der Bildhauer rannte zur T&#252;r. Alazkan blickte hoch und beobachtete, wie ein geisterhaftes Abbild seiner selbst durch den Raum jagte und den Zwerg mit einem Schlag in die Knie zwang. Der Zwerg fiel und Alazkan sah, wie das Abbild sich auf ihn st&#246;rzte. Ein Sto&#223; und der Zwerg war tot. Innerhalb weniger Sekunden verschwand das Abbild. Alazkan verbarg die Scherbe in seinem Mantel. Sie war tats&#228;chlich sehr n&#252;tzlich. [PARAGRAPH:1]Dann &#246;ffnete die Svartalfarische J&#228;gerin die T&#252;r und sagte: "Sie kommen. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Gut," antwortet Alazkan, "wir sind hier fertig."</German>
		<Italian>The sculptor ran for the door. Alazkan looked up and watched a ghostly image of himself dash across the room and hobble the dwarf with a strike to the back of his knees. The dwarf fell and Alazkan watched his image jump onto him. Another stab, and the dwarf was dead. In a few seconds the image disappeared. Alazkan wrapped the black shard into his cloak. This would be very handy indeed. Then the Svartalfar huntress serving as Alazkan's guard opened the door.[PARAGRAPH:1]"They are coming" she said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Good," Alazkan replied, "we are done here."</Italian>
		<Spanish>The sculptor ran for the door. Alazkan looked up and watched a ghostly image of himself dash across the room and hobble the dwarf with a strike to the back of his knees. The dwarf fell and Alazkan watched his image jump onto him. Another stab, and the dwarf was dead. In a few seconds the image disappeared. Alazkan wrapped the black shard into his cloak. This would be very handy indeed. Then the Svartalfar huntress serving as Alazkan's guard opened the door.[PARAGRAPH:1]"They are coming" she said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Good," Alazkan replied, "we are done here."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ILLUSIONIST</Tag>
		<English>Illusionist</English>
		<French>Illusioniste</French>
		<German>Illusionist</German>
		<Italian>Illusionist</Italian>
		<Spanish>Illusionist</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ILLUSIONIST_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Illusionists are similar to mages except that any creature they summon is an illusionary version of the creature. Illusions are unable to kill opponents in combat, but can reduce them almost to the point of death. This may seem like disadvantage until you consider that it leaves an opponent weakened an available to be killed by another, which can then gain experience from the battle.</English>
		<French>Les illusionnistes sont similaires aux mages, à ceci près que toute créature qu'ils invoquent est une version illusoire de la créature. Les illusions sont incapables de tuer un adversaire au combat, mais peut les affaiblir jusqu'à la limite de la mort. Ça peut paraître un désavantage, mais seulement jusqu'à ce que vous réalisiez que ça laisse un adversaire affaibli et prêt à être tué par un autre, qui pourra gagner de l'expérience de combat.</French>
		<German>Illusionists are similar to mages except that any creature they summon is an illusionary version of the creature. Illusions are unable to kill opponents in combat, but can reduce them almost to the point of death. This may seem like disadvantage until you consider that it leaves an opponent weakened an available to be killed by another, which can then gain experience from the battle.</German>
		<Italian>Illusionists are similar to mages except that any creature they summon is an illusionary version of the creature. Illusions are unable to kill opponents in combat, but can reduce them almost to the point of death. This may seem like disadvantage until you consider that it leaves an opponent weakened an available to be killed by another, which can then gain experience from the battle.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Illusionists are similar to mages except that any creature they summon is an illusionary version of the creature. Illusions are unable to kill opponents in combat, but can reduce them almost to the point of death. This may seem like disadvantage until you consider that it leaves an opponent weakened an available to be killed by another, which can then gain experience from the battle.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NYXKIN</Tag>
		<English>Nyxkin</English>
		<French>Nyxkin</French>
		<German>Nyxkin</German>
		<Italian>Nyxkin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nyxkin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
