<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALTAR_OF_THE_LUONNOTAR</Tag>
		<English>Altar of the Luonnotar</English>
		<French>Autel des Luonnotar</French>
		<German>Altar des Luonnotar </German>
		<Italian>Altare dei Luonnotar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Altar de los Luonnotar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALTAR_OF_THE_LUONNOTAR_ANOINTED</Tag>
		<English>Altar of the Luonnotar (anointed)</English>
		<French>Autel des Luonnotar (oint)</French>
		<German>Altar des Luonnotar (gesalbt)</German>
		<Italian>Altare dei Luonnotar (unto)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Altar de los Luonnotar (ungido)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALTAR_OF_THE_LUONNOTAR_BLESSED</Tag>
		<English>Altar of the Luonnotar (blessed)</English>
		<French>Autel des Luonnotar (béni)</French>
		<German>Altar des Luonnotar (gesegnet)</German>
		<Italian>Altare dei Luonnotar (benedetto)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Altar de los Luonnotar (bendecido)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALTAR_OF_THE_LUONNOTAR_CONSECRATED</Tag>
		<English>Altar of the Luonnotar (consecrated)</English>
		<French>Autel des Luonnotar (consacré)</French>
		<German>Altar des Luonnotar (geweiht)</German>
		<Italian>Altare dei Luonnotar (consacrato)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Altar de los Luonnotar (consagrado)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALTAR_OF_THE_LUONNOTAR_DIVINE</Tag>
		<English>Altar of the Luonnotar (divine)</English>
		<French>Autel des Luonnotar (divin)</French>
		<German>Altar des Luonnotar (göttlich)</German>
		<Italian>Altare dei Luonnotar (divino)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Altar de los Luonnotar (divino)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALTAR_OF_THE_LUONNOTAR_EXALTED</Tag>
		<English>Altar of the Luonnotar (exalted)</English>
		<French>Autel des Luonnotar (exalté)</French>
		<German>Altar des Luonnotar (verherrlicht)</German>
		<Italian>Altare dei Luonnotar (glorificato)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Altar de los  Luonnotar (sublime)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALTAR_OF_THE_LUONNOTAR_FINAL</Tag>
		<English>Altar of the Luonnotar (final)</English>
		<French>Autel des Luonnotar (final)</French>
		<German>Altar des Luonnotar (endgültig)</German>
		<Italian>Altare dei Luonnotar (finale)</Italian>
		<Spanish>Altar de los Luonnotar (final)</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ALTAR_OF_THE_LUONNOTAR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The first 6 pieces of the Altar can only be created by sacrificing a Great Prophet, and even then only by Good or Neutral civilizations. The last piece has to be built.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Les Luonnotar proclament que ce bloc de pierre est l'endroit où s'est tenu le Démiurge lorsqu'il vint en sa création avant la chute d'Agares. Chaque religion a un mythe différent sur l'origine de la pierre, mais aucune ne conteste sa puissance, toutes les unités créées par l'empire la possédant sont bénies.[PARAGRAPH:2]Les six premières parties de l'autel ne peuvent être construites qu'en sacrifiant un Prophète Illustre ou un Luonnotar, et seulement par une civilisation Bonne ou Neutre. La dernière partie doit être construite.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Luonnotar beteuern, dass der einzig wahre Gott auf diesem Stück Stein stand, als er vor dem Untergang von Agares auf die Erde kam. Jede Religion kennt ihren eigenen Mythos über die Herkunft dieses Steins, aber keine bestreitet seine Macht; jede Einheit, die in dem Reich aufgestellt wird, welches den Stein besitzt, erhält die Beförderung "Gesegnet".[PARAGRAPH:2]Die ersten sechs Teile des Altars können nur durch die Opferung eines Großen Propheten oder eines Luonnotar errichtet werden, und nur von Zivilisationen, die gut oder neutral sind. Der letzte Teil muss gebaut werden.</German>
		<Italian>I primi 6 pezzi dell'Altare possono essere creati solamente sacrificando un Grande Profeta, opzione disponibile solo alle civiltà Buone o Neutrali. L'ultimo pezzo dev'essere costruito nosrmalmente invece.</Italian>
		<Spanish>TAB]Los Luonnotar proclaman que este eslabón de piedra fue sobre el que el dios verdadero se mantuvo en pie cuando vino a la creación antes de la caída de Agares. Cada religión tiene un mito diferente acerca del origen de la piedra, pero ninguna disputa su control; todas las unidades creadas en el imperio que la posea serán Bendecidas.[PARAGRAPH:2]Las primeras 6 piezas del Altar sólo pueden ser creadas sacrificando un Gran Profeta o un Luonnotar, y solamente por civilizaciones Buenas o Neutrales. La última pieza debe ser construida.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AQUAE_SUCELLUS</Tag>
		<English>Aquae Sucellus</English>
		<French>Aquae Sucellus</French>
		<German>Sucellus' Träne</German>
		<Italian>Aquae Sucellus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aquae Sucellus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AQUAE_SUCELLUS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Improves the health of all of the building civilization's cities on the same continent. Improves the heal rate of units in the city, and cures any that start the turn in the city of [LINK=PROMOTION_DISEASED]Disease[\LINK], [LINK=PROMOTION_WITHERED]Withered[\LINK], and [LINK=PROMOTION_PLAGUED]Plagued[\LINK] afflictions.</English>
		<French>Améliore la santé de toutes les villes de la civilisation sur le même continent. Augment le taux de guérison des unités dans la ville et soigne la Maladie, l'Atrophie et la Peste pour toutes les unités présentes dans la ville au début du tour.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Verbessert die Gesundheit aller Städte des Erbauers auf dem Kontinent. Erhöht die Genesungsrate stationierter Einheiten und heilt kranke, atrophierte und verseuchte Einheiten, wenn sie die Runde in dieser Stadt beginnen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Migliora la salute di tutte le città, della civiltà che lo costruisce, sullo stesso continente. Migliora il tasso di guarigione delle unità in città, e cura chiunque sia [LINK=PROMOTION_DISEASED]Malato[\LINK], [LINK=PROMOTION_WITHERED]Avvizzito[\LINK] e [LINK=PROMOTION_PLAGUED]Appestato[\LINK] se inizia il turno in città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Mejora la salud de todos los edificios de las ciudades de la civilización en el mismo continente. Mejora el índice de curación de las unidades en la ciudad, y cura de Enfermedad, Debilidad y Plaga a cualquiera que empiece el turno en la ciudad.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BAZAAR_OF_MAMMON</Tag>
		<English>Bazaar of Mammon</English>
		<French>Bazar de Mammon</French>
		<German>Basar des Mammon</German>
		<Italian>Bazar di Mammon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bazar de Mammon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BAZAAR_OF_MAMMON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Commerce is the lifeblood of an empire. A farmer sells his prize horse to buy seed for next season, and the tax collector takes enough off the top to equip a footman. A noble buys a tapestry imported from across the continent, and the King's campaign can continue for another month. As such, it is not discontent that is the greatest threat to a ruler's ambition. Bread and carnivals can assuage unhappiness, or garrison troops should those measures fail. Rather a people's satisfaction has the potential to deplete the treasury and starve an empire. If the farmer is content with a smaller gain, from where does the soldier's arms come? If the noble is pleased with his bare halls, shall the war end sooner? Indeed, if the soldiers themselves do not yearn for a better life than their fathers, why will they quit the farm for a mercenary life?[PARAGRAPH:1]In light of this, the Stewards of Inequity make an offer which even rulers devoted to Junil have a hard time declining. Let the royal market be seeded with a relic of the King of Avarice here, or one of his praying acolytes there. Let his temples be unmolested in your capital. The people's hearts shall take up a little-just a little-greed. So will their labors be intensified with avarice, and the nation profit.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alas, such hubris has brought down empires. There is no such thing as a little greed, for Mammon is not a master content to share his subjects, and a people enslaved by their own base appetites are rare to rise to the nobler callings of man.</English>
		<French>Le Commerce est le sang d'un empire. Un fermier vend son cheval pour acheter des graines pour la saison suivante, et le collecteur de taxes prend assez pour équiper un milicien. Un noble achète une tapisserie importée de l'autre vout du continent, la campagne du Roi continue pour un autre mois. C'est pourquoi il n'est pas étonnant qu'il s'agit de la plus grande menace pour l'ambition d'un dirigeant. les pain et les fêtes peuvent calmer le mécontentement, ou la garnison si ces mesures échouent. La satisfaction du peuple a le potentiel pour vider la trésorerie et affamer un empire. Si le fermier est content avec un plus faible gain, d'ou viendront les armes du soldat?Si le noble est satisfait de ses murs nus, la guerre finira-t-elle plus tôt?Et même, si les soldats ne recherchaient pas une meilleure vie que celle de leur père, pourquoi quitteraient -ils leur ferme pour une vie de mercenaire?[PARAGRAPH:1]A la lumière de cela, les Intendants de l'Inéquité ont fait une offre que meme les dirigeants fanatiques de Junil peuvent difficilement décliner.Laissons dans le marché royal une relique du Roi de l'Avarice ici, ou l'un des ses acolytes priant là. Construisons ses temples intouchables dans notre capitale. Le c&#156;ur du peuple prendra alors un peu - juste un peu- d'avidité. Ainsi leur travail sera intensifié par l'avarice , et la nation en profitera.[PARAGRAPH:1] Hélas , une telle démesure a brisé des empires. Il n'est pas de petite avidité , et Mammon n'est pas un maitre prêt à partager ses sujets , et un peuple asservi à ses propre appétits est rarement apte à de plus nobles désirs de l'Homme.</French>
		<German>Handel ist der Puls eines jeden Reiches. Verkauft der Bauer sein bestes Pferd um Saatgut für das kommende Jahr zu kaufen, so nimmt ihm der Steuereintreiber genug davon ab, einen Krieger davon auszurüsten. Kauft der Adlige einen Gobelin vom anderen Ende der Welt, so kann des Königs Feldzug einen weiteren Monat andauern. Dies zeigt, nicht Unzufriedenheit ist die größte Bedrohung herrschaftlichen Ehrgeizes. Brot und Spiele vermögen das Volk zu beschwichtigen oder königlichen Truppen es niederzuwerfen. Im Gegenteil vermag Zufriedenheit, den Reichtum zu mindern und das Reich dadurch auszuhungern. Nimmt der Bauer die magere Ernte hin, woher bekommt der Krieger seine Waffen? Genügen dem Adligen seine leeren Hallen, wird der Krieg dadurch früher enden? Tatsache ist doch, wenn die Söldner nicht von einem besseren Leben als dem ihrer Väter träumen würden - warum sollten sie dann den Hof für ein Leben im Krieg aufgeben?[PARAGRAPH:1]Im Lichte dessen macht die Ungerichtigkeit ein Angebot, welches ein Herrscher selbst als Anhänger der Weisung nur schwer ablehnen kann. Bestückt den königlichen Markt mit Zeichen königlicher Habsucht hier, oder einem seiner Ministranten dort. Verlegt seine Tempel in Eure Hauptstadt. Pflanzt nur ein wenig Gier in die Herzen des Volks. So wird dessen Tun vom Streben nach mehr getrieben sein, zum Wohle der Nation.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ach, wieviele Länder sind an solch Hybris zugrunde gegangen! So etwas wie "ein wenig Gier" gibt es nicht, denn der Mammon ist kein Besitz von dem man abgeben will - und wer seinem Hunger danach einmal erlegen ist, der wird nur schwer zu nobler Gesinnung finden.</German>
		<Italian>Il commercio è la linfa vitale di un impero. Un contadino vende il suo miglior cavallo per comprare i semi per la prossima stagione, e l'esattore delle tasse prende il necessario per equipaggiare un soldato. Un nobile acquista un'arazzo importato dall'altra parte del continente, e la campagna del Re può continuare per un'altro mese. E cosi, non è il malcontento il pericolo più grande all'ambizione del sovrano. Pane e spettacoli possono mitigare il malcontento, altrimenti metti unità come guarnigione se quelle misure non dovesserò funzionare. Ovviamente la soddisfazione di una popolazione può portare a stagnare le finanze e far morire un impero. Se il contadino si accontenta di un guadagno minore, da dove arrivano i soldi per le armi per il soldato? Se il nobile è soddisfatto delle sue sale spoglie, la guerra dovrebbe finire prima? Ovviamente, se i soldati stessi non desiderassero una vita migliore di quella dei loro padri, perché abbandonerebberò la fattoria per una vita da mercenario?[PARAGRAPH:1]Alla luce di ciò, gli Amministratori della Disuguaglianza fanno un offerta che persino i sovrani devoti a Junil trovano difficile rifiutare. Lascia che il mercato regale abbia una reliquia del Re dell'Avarizia, o uno dei suoi accoliti che prega. Lascia i suoi templi nella capitale indisturbati. Il cuore delle persone diventarà un pò, solo un pò, più avido. Cosi il loro lavoro sarà intensificato dall'avarizia, e la nazione ne beneficierà.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ahimè, tale arroganza ha fatto crollare imperi. Non esiste una piccola avidità, perché Mammon non è un signore a cui vada di condividere i sudditi, e le persone schiave dei loro appetiti basilari difficilmente sentono la chiamata delle azioni più nobili.</Italian>
		<Spanish>El Comercio es la sangría de un imperio. Un granjero vende su preciado caballo para comprar semillas para la siguiente estanción, y el recaudador de impuestos colecta lo suficiente como para llenar el equipo de un hombre de a pie. Un noble compra un tapiz importado desde el otro lado del continente, y la campaña del Rey puede continuar otro mes. Así que esto es porque no es la insatisfacción la mayor amenaza para la ambición de un dirigente. El pan y los carnavales pueden calmar la infelicidad, o las tropas estacionadas harían que esas medidas fallaran. Por el contrario la satisfacción de la gente tiene el potencial de acabar con el tesoro y matar de hambre al imperio. Si el granjero está contento con una pequeña ganancia, ¿de dónde vienen las armas de los soldados? Si el noble está satisfecho con sus salas desnudas, ¿acabaría antes la guerra? De hecho, si los soldados no anhelan una vida mejor que sus padres, ¿por qué dejarán la granja por una vida de mercenario?[PARAGRAPH:1]A la luz de esto, los Encargados de la Desigualdad hacen una oferta que incluso a los devotos dirigentes de Junil les costaría declinar. Dejad que le mercado real sea instalado con una reliquia del Rey de la Avaricia aquí, o una de sus acólitos rezando allí. Dejad que sus templos no sean molestados en vuestra ciudad. Los corazones de la gente obtendrán un poco -sólo un poco- de codicia. De esta forma las labores se verán intensificadas con avaricia, y el beneficio de la nación.[PARAGRAPH:1]Al final, tan soberbia desmedida ha provocado la caída de imperios. No hay nada como un poco de codicia, Mammon no es un maestro que comparte sus conocimientos con avidez,y la gente esclavizada por sus propios apetitos básicos son difíciles de animar y llevar hacia la llamada más noble del hombre.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BONE_PALACE</Tag>
		<English>Bone Palace</English>
		<French>Palais d'Os</French>
		<German>Knochenpalast</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo d'Ossa</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio de Hueso</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BONE_PALACE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Legend says that a dragon was found so deep in slumber that his scales, teeth and horns were removed without him waking. More and more daring hunters stripped pieces from the dragon until he died, still locked within his dreams. The flesh was stripped and eaten, the hide cured and turned into armor. When only the bones were left, a Doviello warlord made it into his palace.[PARAGRAPH:1]Over the following centuries, marble towers, battlements, and fortifications were added to the palace until the original bones were completely hidden by the new construction, if they ever really existed. Those convinced of the legend say that the dragon's spirit still sleeps and that he will one day awake, most likely to destroy those that are living within his bones.</English>
		<French>[TAB]La légende raconte qu'un dragon a été découvert si profondément endormi que ses écailles, ses dents et ses cornes ont été enlevées sans le réveiller. Les chasseurs de plus en plus téméraires ont enlevé les parties du dragon jusqu'à ce qu'il meurt, toujours enfermé dans ses rêves. La chair a été enlevée et mangée, le cuir tanné et confectionné en armure. Quand seulement les os restèrent, un seigneur de guerre Doviello en a fait son palais.[PARAGRAPH:1]Au cours des siècles suivants, les tours de marbre, les créneaux et les fortifications ont été rajoutés au palais jusqu'à ce que les os originaux soient complètement cachés par les nouvelles constructions, s'ils ont jamais vraiment existé. Ceux convaincu de la légende disent que l'esprit du dragon dort toujours et qu'un jour il se réveillera, fort probablement pour détruire ceux qui vivent dans ses os.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Eine Legende erzählt, dass ein Drachen so tief im Schlaf versunken war, dass ihm Schuppen, Zähne und Hörner entfernt werden konnten, ohne dass er erwachte. Immer mehr waghalsige Jäger schnitten Stücke aus seinem Leib, dass der Drache, noch immer in seinen Träumen gefangen, schließlich starb. Sein Fleisch wurde verzehrt, seine Haut getrocknet und für Rüstungen verwendet. Als nur noch die Knochen übrig waren, machte ein Kriegsfürst der Doviello seinen Palast daraus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Während der folgenden Jahrhunderte wurde der Palast durch marmorne Türme, Mauerzinnen und Befestigungsanlagen erweitert, bis die Knochen vollständig unter den neuen Erweiterungen verschwunden waren. Die, die an die Legende glauben, sind überzeugt, dass der Geist des Drachen noch immer schläft und dass er eines Tages erwachen wird, um die zu zerstören, die in seinen Knochen wohnen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Le leggende raccontano che un drago fu trovato che dormiva cosi profondamente che le sue scaglie, denti e corna furono rimosse senza che lui si svegliò. Cacciatori sempre più audaci staccarono pezzi dal drago fino a quando non morì, ancora immerso nei suoi sogni. La carne fu staccata e mangiata, la pelle trattata e usata per armature. Quando solo le ossa rimasero, un signore della guerra Doviello le usò per creare il suo palazzo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Nei successivi secoli, torri di marmo, merli, e fortificazioni furono aggiunte al palazzo fino a quando le ossa originali furono completamente nascoste dalle nuove costruzioni, se sono mai esistite veramente. Coloro che credono alla leggenda dicono che lo spirito del drago ancora dorme e che un giorno si sveglierà, molto probabilmente per distruggere coloro che vivono all'interno delle sue ossa.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Cuenta la leyenda que una vez se encontró un dragón tan profundamente dormido que sus escamas, dientes y cuernos se le fueron arrebatado sin siquiera ser despertado. Cada vez más y más cazadores osados fueron quitándole trozos al dragón hasta que éste murió, aún estando atado a sus sueños. Su carne fue cortada y devorada, y su piel tratada y convertida en una armadura. Cuando sólo quedaron los huesos, un señor de la guerra Doviello mandó con ellos construir un palacio para sí.[PARAGRAPH:1]Durante los siguientes siglos, torres de marfil, almenas y fortificaciones se fueron anexionando al palacio hasta que los huesos originales quedaron completamente escondidos bajo la nueva edificiación, si es que existieron realmente. Aquellos que creen en la leyenda dicen que el espíritu del dragón aún duerme y que despertará algún día, seguramente para destruir a aquellos que viven dentro de sus huesos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BREWERY</Tag>
		<English>Deruptus Brewing House</English>
		<French>Brasserie Deruptus</French>
		<German>Brauhaus</German>
		<Italian>Birreria Deruptus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cervecería</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BREWERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Provides [LINK=BONUS_ALE]Ale[\LINK] resource. Also increases commerce in the city by 10% if Corn, Rice, or Wheat is available and grants +2 xp to dwarves built in the city. It can only be built along a river.</English>
		<French>Augmente le bonheur de 1 si du maïs, du riz ou du blé sont disponibles. La brasserie doit être construite sur la berge d'une rivière. Les nains construits dans la ville commencent avec 2 EXP supplémentaires.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Erhöht die Zufriedenheit um +1 wenn Mais, Reis oder Weizen verfügbar sind. Brauhäuser können nur an Flüssen gebaut werden.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Fornisce la risorsa [LINK=BONUS_ALE]Birra[\LINK]. Aumenta inoltre il commercio del 10% se il Granoturco, Riso, o il Frumento è disponibile e fornisce +2 PE (XP) ai nani creati in città. Può essere costruita solo in una città sul fiume.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Aumenta la felicidad en 1 si hay Maíz, Arroz o Trigo, y proporciona +2 de xp a los enanos instruidos en la ciudad. Las cervecerías sólo pueden construirse al lado de un río.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAMINUS_AUREUS</Tag>
		<English>Caminus Aureus</English>
		<French>Caminus Aureus</French>
		<German>Goldener Amboss</German>
		<Italian>Caminus Aureus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Caminus Aureus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATACOMB_LIBRALUS</Tag>
		<English>Catacomb Libralus</English>
		<French>Catacombes Libralus</French>
		<German>Katakomben von Libralus</German>
		<Italian>Catacomba Libralus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Catacumba Libralus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATACOMB_LIBRALUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Sebill arrived at a door marked "Acquisitions." The coachman escorted her to the door and gave it two hard knocks. It opened to reveal a miniscule butcher. The dwarf looked up at the coachman and noted Sebill. "Good! Good!" he said and ushered them into what looked like a carpenter's workshop-only one in which the wood bled when cut. "I commend you on your haste; we here are great appreciators of body magic, you know. You ought to be well paid for your effort. Do you need new horses?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"They are well," answered the coachman, "they're of strong breed and can withstand the spells. With enough food and rest tonight they'll have their stamina back."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"They're fine animals, aren't they?" the dwarf said affably, clearing tools off a table. He was joined by a graying female dwarf wearing an equally dirty apron. "Splendid!" she said. "Let's get started. I'm Odea, he's Hahm, in case he didn't introduce himself."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Anton," said the coachman.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Odea turned to examine Sebill. "Let's get a look at you... Even better than I expected! Let's get you on the table." Anton stepped forward to help lift Sebill, but saw it was unnecessary as Odea, despite her size, moved Sebill to the dwarf-sized table without effort. Odea smiled, "She's empty. No organs. I asked our clients in Nubia to clean her to prevent spoiling. Kept out of the sun the bodies can make the trip in adequate shape." Anton nodded. Odea thought he seemed uneasy. "I'm sorry, did you know her?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No, no... I have no idea who she is, or why she's important to the nobles. She doesn't look like an aristocrat." He paused, then motioned toward the door, "I have the rest of the delivery in my carriage."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Her blood I'm sure. Would you fetch that? Hahm needs to check it and make sure the preservers held up. There are a number of naturally occurring blood thinners in just about every land, but ours are better. I have some theories about speeding the reactions to make the ink less corrosive, but that would require entropy mana which can be hard to come by..."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Outside, Anton gave the blood to Hahm and moved his horses into the shade. This was his first visit to the Luchuirp lands. He admitted to himself that he'd always been a little racist toward dwarves, but couldn't think of any reason why. He looked at and admired the structure of the Catacomb Libralus; from what he'd heard he assumed it was nothing more than a one-trick curiosity shop. It was originally built as a catacomb open to all, until necromancers developed a habit of exploiting it, leading to the pejoration of the name "Free-Use Catacombs." Later it was acquired by a wealthy polymath, who turned it into the institution that is now commonly nicknamed the "Catacomb Librarius." Above ground it was a simple structure with short walls and an entrance adorned with arches and pillars.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton returned to the workshop to see Odea in the process of skinning Sebill. Incisions ran up the middle of her chest, along her collarbone, and above her hips. Odea was paring the fatty membrane holding skin to muscle as she pulled the skin upward. Anton groaned at the sight, which alerted Odea that he'd returned. She explained, her enthusiasm outweighing her sympathy for Anton's uneasiness, "The skin's in good shape. We use it all. Her back-because its smoother and thicker-will be tanned and used to make the cover. The rest we stretch into vellum for the pages." Odea paused, Anton was staring at Sebill's body. "It's not pretty, I know. This is an honorable afterlife though. I used to do golemcraft, but animating a golem is like rolling a stone down a hill-it's predictable, it's all it does. Books are the perfect synthesis of form and function, body and spirit, mythos and logos. They are us in every way." She put down her knife, and Anton sat on short ladder. Odea continued, "We can put any talent to use here. Do you practice magic?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I do some, just tricks to help my deliveries-speed the horses, hide my wares. Just dabblings."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ice! Imagine what you could do with ice mana! We could add people from any corner of Erebus to our collection. You could make your fortune just transporting food to soldiers. Ah, if only we could get some..." Anton laughed. He'd thought of this before. Odea continued, "We use a range of magic here: body helps us transform the person, but that's mostly handiwork; our diviners use spirit magic to contact the dead; and enchanters can infuse the books with special properties. Luckily we're in a land where necromancy is outlawed, or we'd have a lot to worry about. Should I take you to see some of our collection?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Thank you," he replied, "but I have to stable my horses first. I should find an inn."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Fine by me. I need to work and I can't have distractions. Come back later for a tour." Odea smiled, "Now get out of here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A week had passed since Anton delivered Sebill. He'd gone north to meet a Calabim rendezvous who took the carriage, leaving Anton with a horse. Now returning to the fortified city, he spent the evening at a public house, waiting for nightfall. He made his way back to the Catacomb Libralus and to the door marked "Acquisitions." He knocked. If Odea answered he'd have an excuse for being there. If she didn't, then things would be according to plan. He picked the lock and slipped inside. There was barely any light and he waited for his eyes to adjust. The tables were clean and the tools put away. A door in back opened to a lantern-lit corridor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When he entered the main hall he realized he'd underestimated the age and grandeur of this place. He thought the library at his former mages' guild was large, but he'd never seen this many books. The hall was lined with shelves of books in every skin color, all facing out. Numerous corridors descended into the catacombs, all filled with books. Anton despaired when he wondered how he would find a single book in all this, until he saw the years inscribed above the corridors' arches.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He entered the most recent corridor, which had just started to be used in the last five years. He walked straight to the end of the row. A small engraving was underneath the last book. Some Malakim name; the book was too dark anyway and had a tattoo of a lion on the cover. The second-to-last book was a pale tan, like a dry meadow. The engraving underneath read "unknown" and named the year of death. The book before that was grayish green and had a single horn jutting out from the spine. He picked up the tan one. It was about two hands tall and a little less wide. The cover was soft-it was leather after all. The spine was sturdy. Bone? He imagined it was her sternum, and thought of her breasts, one skinless, the other just dead. He opened the cover and ran his finger along the inside spine. The pages were sewn to the cover using string made of brown hair. There was writing on the first page, in ink that was still reddish and had not faded into brown. It said: My dear Ain-You'll never read this, but please know that I love you eternally. A chill shook him. He tucked Sebill's book into his pack and returned to the main hall.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He looked at the dates above the arches, and walked down the next corridor. Both sides of the corridor were lined with books facing each other. A jumble of names grew in his head as he scanned the engravings.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Are you looking for something, Anton?" He spun to see Odea in the middle of the corridor. She looked relaxed; he tried his best to appear the same. Her apron was gone and she was dressed comfortably, striking Anton as quite pretty.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Um... yes. A book. A book of... my grandfather."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Anything else?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"...No."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"What was his name?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton glanced toward the main hall to see if Odea was alone. "Gerard Cormand."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know of him! Quite the revolutionary in his day. Did you know him?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I didn't. My father opposed his politics and left the city, taking his family along. I was born on a farm."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Your grandfather was murdered before the revolution ended, wasn't he?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Yes. I have to know that it wasn't... my father."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Your grandfather is here," she pointed farther down the corridor. Anton cautiously followed her lead. "Our diviners enjoy limited success as a writing tool for the dead, allowing them to make a final statement."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The dead write?" probed Anton.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We ask them if there's anything they'd like to say. They're usually thinking about what they would have done differently in life, so they're full of advice. They might eulogize themselves, or tell their entire life's story-we give the diviners a short vacation to recover after those. These are good souls, mind you; we don't even want to know the dangers of making an unscrupulous book."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That woman," thought Anton, "what had she done to make her so valuable to the Calabim?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Victims of murder usually have something to say..." Odea stopped walking and motioned toward a book, smaller than Sebill's and paler.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton said, "Would he have named his killer?" Odea didn't answer, and Anton lifted his grandfather's book. He opened it and read: I liked the fleshy sins best. He turned the pages: blank. He sighed deeply, and put the book down. Odea took a step back. "Are you going to return the other book too?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton faced Odea with a widened stance. "No. I'm sorry, but I'm stealing it." He held a knife at her eye level and took a slow step toward her.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I can't stop you," she said calmly. "This is a mistake though. These books are extremely dangerous in the wrong hands. They must never leave."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know. Your ‘clients' haven't given me any choice though." They circled each other in a cautious dance. Seeing the main hall clear, Anton left through the front door.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Outside the city walls, Anton snuck to his horse, mounted her, and pointed her back north. He hadn't ridden far when a sudden strong wind, or that's what it felt like, threw him off his horse, spilling his pack. He saw in the dark the looming shape of a gargoyle, its wings blocking the light from the city. He ran, and would have died on the spot if it weren't for his haste spell. Instead, he died at the forest's edge a short length away, while the Book of Sebill remained beside the road.</English>
		<French>Sebill arrived at a door marked "Acquisitions." The coachman escorted her to the door and gave it two hard knocks. It opened to reveal a miniscule butcher. The dwarf looked up at the coachman and noted Sebill. "Good! Good!" he said and ushered them into what looked like a carpenter's workshop-only one in which the wood bled when cut. "I commend you on your haste; we here are great appreciators of body magic, you know. You ought to be well paid for your effort. Do you need new horses?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"They are well," answered the coachman, "they're of strong breed and can withstand the spells. With enough food and rest tonight they'll have their stamina back."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"They're fine animals, aren't they?" the dwarf said affably, clearing tools off a table. He was joined by a graying female dwarf wearing an equally dirty apron. "Splendid!" she said. "Let's get started. I'm Odea, he's Hahm, in case he didn't introduce himself."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Anton," said the coachman.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Odea turned to examine Sebill. "Let's get a look at you... Even better than I expected! Let's get you on the table." Anton stepped forward to help lift Sebill, but saw it was unnecessary as Odea, despite her size, moved Sebill to the dwarf-sized table without effort. Odea smiled, "She's empty. No organs. I asked our clients in Nubia to clean her to prevent spoiling. Kept out of the sun the bodies can make the trip in adequate shape." Anton nodded. Odea thought he seemed uneasy. "I'm sorry, did you know her?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No, no... I have no idea who she is, or why she's important to the nobles. She doesn't look like an aristocrat." He paused, then motioned toward the door, "I have the rest of the delivery in my carriage."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Her blood I'm sure. Would you fetch that? Hahm needs to check it and make sure the preservers held up. There are a number of naturally occurring blood thinners in just about every land, but ours are better. I have some theories about speeding the reactions to make the ink less corrosive, but that would require entropy mana which can be hard to come by..."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Outside, Anton gave the blood to Hahm and moved his horses into the shade. This was his first visit to the Luchuirp lands. He admitted to himself that he'd always been a little racist toward dwarves, but couldn't think of any reason why. He looked at and admired the structure of the Catacomb Libralus; from what he'd heard he assumed it was nothing more than a one-trick curiosity shop. It was originally built as a catacomb open to all, until necromancers developed a habit of exploiting it, leading to the pejoration of the name "Free-Use Catacombs." Later it was acquired by a wealthy polymath, who turned it into the institution that is now commonly nicknamed the "Catacomb Librarius." Above ground it was a simple structure with short walls and an entrance adorned with arches and pillars.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton returned to the workshop to see Odea in the process of skinning Sebill. Incisions ran up the middle of her chest, along her collarbone, and above her hips. Odea was paring the fatty membrane holding skin to muscle as she pulled the skin upward. Anton groaned at the sight, which alerted Odea that he'd returned. She explained, her enthusiasm outweighing her sympathy for Anton's uneasiness, "The skin's in good shape. We use it all. Her back-because its smoother and thicker-will be tanned and used to make the cover. The rest we stretch into vellum for the pages." Odea paused, Anton was staring at Sebill's body. "It's not pretty, I know. This is an honorable afterlife though. I used to do golemcraft, but animating a golem is like rolling a stone down a hill-it's predictable, it's all it does. Books are the perfect synthesis of form and function, body and spirit, mythos and logos. They are us in every way." She put down her knife, and Anton sat on short ladder. Odea continued, "We can put any talent to use here. Do you practice magic?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I do some, just tricks to help my deliveries-speed the horses, hide my wares. Just dabblings."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ice! Imagine what you could do with ice mana! We could add people from any corner of Erebus to our collection. You could make your fortune just transporting food to soldiers. Ah, if only we could get some..." Anton laughed. He'd thought of this before. Odea continued, "We use a range of magic here: body helps us transform the person, but that's mostly handiwork; our diviners use spirit magic to contact the dead; and enchanters can infuse the books with special properties. Luckily we're in a land where necromancy is outlawed, or we'd have a lot to worry about. Should I take you to see some of our collection?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Thank you," he replied, "but I have to stable my horses first. I should find an inn."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Fine by me. I need to work and I can't have distractions. Come back later for a tour." Odea smiled, "Now get out of here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A week had passed since Anton delivered Sebill. He'd gone north to meet a Calabim rendezvous who took the carriage, leaving Anton with a horse. Now returning to the fortified city, he spent the evening at a public house, waiting for nightfall. He made his way back to the Catacomb Libralus and to the door marked "Acquisitions." He knocked. If Odea answered he'd have an excuse for being there. If she didn't, then things would be according to plan. He picked the lock and slipped inside. There was barely any light and he waited for his eyes to adjust. The tables were clean and the tools put away. A door in back opened to a lantern-lit corridor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When he entered the main hall he realized he'd underestimated the age and grandeur of this place. He thought the library at his former mages' guild was large, but he'd never seen this many books. The hall was lined with shelves of books in every skin color, all facing out. Numerous corridors descended into the catacombs, all filled with books. Anton despaired when he wondered how he would find a single book in all this, until he saw the years inscribed above the corridors' arches.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He entered the most recent corridor, which had just started to be used in the last five years. He walked straight to the end of the row. A small engraving was underneath the last book. Some Malakim name; the book was too dark anyway and had a tattoo of a lion on the cover. The second-to-last book was a pale tan, like a dry meadow. The engraving underneath read "unknown" and named the year of death. The book before that was grayish green and had a single horn jutting out from the spine. He picked up the tan one. It was about two hands tall and a little less wide. The cover was soft-it was leather after all. The spine was sturdy. Bone? He imagined it was her sternum, and thought of her breasts, one skinless, the other just dead. He opened the cover and ran his finger along the inside spine. The pages were sewn to the cover using string made of brown hair. There was writing on the first page, in ink that was still reddish and had not faded into brown. It said: My dear Ain-You'll never read this, but please know that I love you eternally. A chill shook him. He tucked Sebill's book into his pack and returned to the main hall.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He looked at the dates above the arches, and walked down the next corridor. Both sides of the corridor were lined with books facing each other. A jumble of names grew in his head as he scanned the engravings.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Are you looking for something, Anton?" He spun to see Odea in the middle of the corridor. She looked relaxed; he tried his best to appear the same. Her apron was gone and she was dressed comfortably, striking Anton as quite pretty.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Um... yes. A book. A book of... my grandfather."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Anything else?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"...No."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"What was his name?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton glanced toward the main hall to see if Odea was alone. "Gerard Cormand."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know of him! Quite the revolutionary in his day. Did you know him?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I didn't. My father opposed his politics and left the city, taking his family along. I was born on a farm."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Your grandfather was murdered before the revolution ended, wasn't he?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Yes. I have to know that it wasn't... my father."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Your grandfather is here," she pointed farther down the corridor. Anton cautiously followed her lead. "Our diviners enjoy limited success as a writing tool for the dead, allowing them to make a final statement."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The dead write?" probed Anton.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We ask them if there's anything they'd like to say. They're usually thinking about what they would have done differently in life, so they're full of advice. They might eulogize themselves, or tell their entire life's story-we give the diviners a short vacation to recover after those. These are good souls, mind you; we don't even want to know the dangers of making an unscrupulous book."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That woman," thought Anton, "what had she done to make her so valuable to the Calabim?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Victims of murder usually have something to say..." Odea stopped walking and motioned toward a book, smaller than Sebill's and paler.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton said, "Would he have named his killer?" Odea didn't answer, and Anton lifted his grandfather's book. He opened it and read: I liked the fleshy sins best. He turned the pages: blank. He sighed deeply, and put the book down. Odea took a step back. "Are you going to return the other book too?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton faced Odea with a widened stance. "No. I'm sorry, but I'm stealing it." He held a knife at her eye level and took a slow step toward her.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I can't stop you," she said calmly. "This is a mistake though. These books are extremely dangerous in the wrong hands. They must never leave."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know. Your ‘clients' haven't given me any choice though." They circled each other in a cautious dance. Seeing the main hall clear, Anton left through the front door.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Outside the city walls, Anton snuck to his horse, mounted her, and pointed her back north. He hadn't ridden far when a sudden strong wind, or that's what it felt like, threw him off his horse, spilling his pack. He saw in the dark the looming shape of a gargoyle, its wings blocking the light from the city. He ran, and would have died on the spot if it weren't for his haste spell. Instead, he died at the forest's edge a short length away, while the Book of Sebill remained beside the road.</French>
		<German>Sebill arrived at a door marked "Acquisitions." The coachman escorted her to the door and gave it two hard knocks. It opened to reveal a miniscule butcher. The dwarf looked up at the coachman and noted Sebill. "Good! Good!" he said and ushered them into what looked like a carpenter's workshop-only one in which the wood bled when cut. "I commend you on your haste; we here are great appreciators of body magic, you know. You ought to be well paid for your effort. Do you need new horses?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"They are well," answered the coachman, "they're of strong breed and can withstand the spells. With enough food and rest tonight they'll have their stamina back."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"They're fine animals, aren't they?" the dwarf said affably, clearing tools off a table. He was joined by a graying female dwarf wearing an equally dirty apron. "Splendid!" she said. "Let's get started. I'm Odea, he's Hahm, in case he didn't introduce himself."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Anton," said the coachman.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Odea turned to examine Sebill. "Let's get a look at you... Even better than I expected! Let's get you on the table." Anton stepped forward to help lift Sebill, but saw it was unnecessary as Odea, despite her size, moved Sebill to the dwarf-sized table without effort. Odea smiled, "She's empty. No organs. I asked our clients in Nubia to clean her to prevent spoiling. Kept out of the sun the bodies can make the trip in adequate shape." Anton nodded. Odea thought he seemed uneasy. "I'm sorry, did you know her?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No, no... I have no idea who she is, or why she's important to the nobles. She doesn't look like an aristocrat." He paused, then motioned toward the door, "I have the rest of the delivery in my carriage."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Her blood I'm sure. Would you fetch that? Hahm needs to check it and make sure the preservers held up. There are a number of naturally occurring blood thinners in just about every land, but ours are better. I have some theories about speeding the reactions to make the ink less corrosive, but that would require entropy mana which can be hard to come by..."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Outside, Anton gave the blood to Hahm and moved his horses into the shade. This was his first visit to the Luchuirp lands. He admitted to himself that he'd always been a little racist toward dwarves, but couldn't think of any reason why. He looked at and admired the structure of the Catacomb Libralus; from what he'd heard he assumed it was nothing more than a one-trick curiosity shop. It was originally built as a catacomb open to all, until necromancers developed a habit of exploiting it, leading to the pejoration of the name "Free-Use Catacombs." Later it was acquired by a wealthy polymath, who turned it into the institution that is now commonly nicknamed the "Catacomb Librarius." Above ground it was a simple structure with short walls and an entrance adorned with arches and pillars.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton returned to the workshop to see Odea in the process of skinning Sebill. Incisions ran up the middle of her chest, along her collarbone, and above her hips. Odea was paring the fatty membrane holding skin to muscle as she pulled the skin upward. Anton groaned at the sight, which alerted Odea that he'd returned. She explained, her enthusiasm outweighing her sympathy for Anton's uneasiness, "The skin's in good shape. We use it all. Her back-because its smoother and thicker-will be tanned and used to make the cover. The rest we stretch into vellum for the pages." Odea paused, Anton was staring at Sebill's body. "It's not pretty, I know. This is an honorable afterlife though. I used to do golemcraft, but animating a golem is like rolling a stone down a hill-it's predictable, it's all it does. Books are the perfect synthesis of form and function, body and spirit, mythos and logos. They are us in every way." She put down her knife, and Anton sat on short ladder. Odea continued, "We can put any talent to use here. Do you practice magic?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I do some, just tricks to help my deliveries-speed the horses, hide my wares. Just dabblings."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ice! Imagine what you could do with ice mana! We could add people from any corner of Erebus to our collection. You could make your fortune just transporting food to soldiers. Ah, if only we could get some..." Anton laughed. He'd thought of this before. Odea continued, "We use a range of magic here: body helps us transform the person, but that's mostly handiwork; our diviners use spirit magic to contact the dead; and enchanters can infuse the books with special properties. Luckily we're in a land where necromancy is outlawed, or we'd have a lot to worry about. Should I take you to see some of our collection?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Thank you," he replied, "but I have to stable my horses first. I should find an inn."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Fine by me. I need to work and I can't have distractions. Come back later for a tour." Odea smiled, "Now get out of here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A week had passed since Anton delivered Sebill. He'd gone north to meet a Calabim rendezvous who took the carriage, leaving Anton with a horse. Now returning to the fortified city, he spent the evening at a public house, waiting for nightfall. He made his way back to the Catacomb Libralus and to the door marked "Acquisitions." He knocked. If Odea answered he'd have an excuse for being there. If she didn't, then things would be according to plan. He picked the lock and slipped inside. There was barely any light and he waited for his eyes to adjust. The tables were clean and the tools put away. A door in back opened to a lantern-lit corridor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When he entered the main hall he realized he'd underestimated the age and grandeur of this place. He thought the library at his former mages' guild was large, but he'd never seen this many books. The hall was lined with shelves of books in every skin color, all facing out. Numerous corridors descended into the catacombs, all filled with books. Anton despaired when he wondered how he would find a single book in all this, until he saw the years inscribed above the corridors' arches.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He entered the most recent corridor, which had just started to be used in the last five years. He walked straight to the end of the row. A small engraving was underneath the last book. Some Malakim name; the book was too dark anyway and had a tattoo of a lion on the cover. The second-to-last book was a pale tan, like a dry meadow. The engraving underneath read "unknown" and named the year of death. The book before that was grayish green and had a single horn jutting out from the spine. He picked up the tan one. It was about two hands tall and a little less wide. The cover was soft-it was leather after all. The spine was sturdy. Bone? He imagined it was her sternum, and thought of her breasts, one skinless, the other just dead. He opened the cover and ran his finger along the inside spine. The pages were sewn to the cover using string made of brown hair. There was writing on the first page, in ink that was still reddish and had not faded into brown. It said: My dear Ain-You'll never read this, but please know that I love you eternally. A chill shook him. He tucked Sebill's book into his pack and returned to the main hall.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He looked at the dates above the arches, and walked down the next corridor. Both sides of the corridor were lined with books facing each other. A jumble of names grew in his head as he scanned the engravings.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Are you looking for something, Anton?" He spun to see Odea in the middle of the corridor. She looked relaxed; he tried his best to appear the same. Her apron was gone and she was dressed comfortably, striking Anton as quite pretty.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Um... yes. A book. A book of... my grandfather."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Anything else?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"...No."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"What was his name?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton glanced toward the main hall to see if Odea was alone. "Gerard Cormand."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know of him! Quite the revolutionary in his day. Did you know him?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I didn't. My father opposed his politics and left the city, taking his family along. I was born on a farm."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Your grandfather was murdered before the revolution ended, wasn't he?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Yes. I have to know that it wasn't... my father."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Your grandfather is here," she pointed farther down the corridor. Anton cautiously followed her lead. "Our diviners enjoy limited success as a writing tool for the dead, allowing them to make a final statement."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The dead write?" probed Anton.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We ask them if there's anything they'd like to say. They're usually thinking about what they would have done differently in life, so they're full of advice. They might eulogize themselves, or tell their entire life's story-we give the diviners a short vacation to recover after those. These are good souls, mind you; we don't even want to know the dangers of making an unscrupulous book."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That woman," thought Anton, "what had she done to make her so valuable to the Calabim?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Victims of murder usually have something to say..." Odea stopped walking and motioned toward a book, smaller than Sebill's and paler.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton said, "Would he have named his killer?" Odea didn't answer, and Anton lifted his grandfather's book. He opened it and read: I liked the fleshy sins best. He turned the pages: blank. He sighed deeply, and put the book down. Odea took a step back. "Are you going to return the other book too?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton faced Odea with a widened stance. "No. I'm sorry, but I'm stealing it." He held a knife at her eye level and took a slow step toward her.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I can't stop you," she said calmly. "This is a mistake though. These books are extremely dangerous in the wrong hands. They must never leave."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know. Your ‘clients' haven't given me any choice though." They circled each other in a cautious dance. Seeing the main hall clear, Anton left through the front door.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Outside the city walls, Anton snuck to his horse, mounted her, and pointed her back north. He hadn't ridden far when a sudden strong wind, or that's what it felt like, threw him off his horse, spilling his pack. He saw in the dark the looming shape of a gargoyle, its wings blocking the light from the city. He ran, and would have died on the spot if it weren't for his haste spell. Instead, he died at the forest's edge a short length away, while the Book of Sebill remained beside the road.</German>
		<Italian>Sebill arrivò a una porta contrassegnata "Acquisizioni". Il cocchiere l'accompagnò alla porta e bussò forte due volte. Si aprì rivelando un minuscolo maccellaio. Il nano guardo il cocchiere e notò Sebill. "Bene! Bene!" disse facendoli entrare in quello che poteva sembrare il laboratorio di un carpentiere, solo se il legno sanguina quando viene tagliato. "Mi congratulo per la vostra celerità; noi qui siamo grandi estimatori della magia del corpo sapete. Spero verrai ben pagato per il tuo lavoro. Hai bisogno di nuovi cavalli?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Loro stanno bene," rispose il cocchiere, "sono di razzo robusta e possono sopportare le magie. Con sufficente cibo e riposo stanotte recupereranno le forze."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Sono dei bei animali, non è vero?" il nano disse affabilmete, togliendo gli strumenti dal tavolo. Si unì a lui un nana brizzolata che indossava un grembiule altrettanto sporco. "Splendido!" disse lei. "Mettiamoci al lavoro. Sono Odea e lui è Hahm, nel caso non si sia presentato."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Anton," disse il cocchiere.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Odea si voltò ad esaminare Sebill. "Diamoti un'occhiata... Anche meglio di quanto mi aspettavo! Mettiamoti sul tavolo." Anton si fece avanti per aiutare a sollevare Sebill, ma vide che non era necessario mentre Odea, nonostante le sue dimensioni, spostava Sebill verso il piccolo tavolo. Odea sorrise, "È vuota. Niente organi. Ho chiesto ai nostri clienti di Nubia di ripulirla per evitare la decomposizione. Se tenuti lontani dal sole i corpi possono fare un viaggio quasi senza problemi." Anton annuì. Odea pensò che era a disagio. "Mi dispiace, la conoscevi?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No, no... Non ho idea di chi fosse, o perché sia importante per i nobili. Non sembra un aristocratica". Attese un pò, poi si diresse verso la porta, "Ho il resto della spedizione nella mia carrozza."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Il suo sangue sicuramente. Puoi andare a prenderlo? Hahm deve controllarlo e assicurarsi che i conservanti siano ancora attivi. CI sono un certo numero di fluidificanti del sangue naturali in ogni terra, ma i nostri sono migliori. Ho qualche teoria sul come accellerare la reazione per rendere l'inchiostro meno corrosivo, ma ciò richiede mana dell'entropia, che può essere difficile da recuperare..."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Fuori, Anton diede il sangue ad Hahm e spostò i suoi cavalli nell'ombra. Questa era la sua prima volta nelle terre Luchuirp. Riconobbe che era sempre stato un pò razzista verso i nani, ma non riusciva a pensare a nessun motivo del perché. Contemplò la struttura del Catacomba Libralus; da quello che aveva sentito pensava non fosse altro che un negozio di curiosità unico. È stata costruita originalmente come una catacomba aperta a tutti, fino a quando i nocromanti non svilupparono l'abitudine di sfruttarla, portando alla creazione del nome "Catacombe ad Uso Gratuito". Più tardi fu comprata da un ricco tuttologo, che la trasformo in un'istituzione che ora viene comunamente soprannominata "Catacomba Librarius". In superfice è una struttura semplice, con muri bassi, e un'ingresso adornato con archi e pilastri.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton ritornò al laboratorio vedendo Odea scuoiare Sebill. Le incisioni erano al centro del petto, lungo la clavicola, e sopra l'anca. Odea stava tagliando la membrana che teneva la pelle legata al muscolo man mano che tirava la pelle in alto. Anton emise un  verso a quella vista, che allertò Odea del suo ritorno. Lei spiego, la sua simpatia per il disagio di Anton superata dal suo entusiasmo, "La pelle è in buono stato. La usiamo tutta. La schiena, perché più liscia e spessa, sarà conciata e usata per fare la copertina. Il resto lo usiamo per fare le pagine." Odea si fermò, Anton stava fissando il corpo di Sebill. "Non è bello, lo so. Questa è comunque un'onorevole vita dopo la morte. Ero solita creare golem, ma animare un golem è come far rotolare un sasso giu da una collina, è prevedibile, in tutto ciò che fa. I libri sono la sintesi perfetta di forma e funzione, corpo e spirito, miti e leggende. Sono noi, in ogni modo". Posò il coltello, e Anton sedette su una piccola scaletta. Odea continuò, "Abbiamo lavoro per chiunque qui. Tu pratichi la magia?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Qualcosina, solo trucchetti per facilitare le mie consegne, far andare più veloce i miei cavalli o nascondere le merci."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ghiaccio! Immagina cosa potresti fare con del mana del ghiaccio! Potremmo aggiungere persone da ogni angolo di Erebus alla nostra collezione. Potresti fare una fortuna solamente trasportando il cibo ai soldati. Ah, se solo potessimo ottenere un pò di..." Anton rise. Lui ci aveva già pensato. Odea continuò, "Usiamo diverse magie qui: quella del corpo ci aiuta a trasformare la persona, ma quello è maggiormente un lavoro manuale; i nostri divinatori usano la magia dello spirito per contattare i morti; e gli incantatori possono infondere i libri con capacità speciali. Fortunatamente siamo in un posto dove la necromanzia non è fuorilegge, altrimenti avremmo parecchio di cui preoccuparci. Ti va di vedere qualcuna delle nostre collezioni?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Grazie," Anton rispose, "ma devo pensare ai miei cavalli prima. Dovrei trovare una locanda."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Va bene. Devo lavorare e non posso avere distrazioni. Torna più tardi per un giro." Odea sorrise, "Ora fuori di qui."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Passò una settimana da quando Anton consegnò Sebill. Lui andò a nord per incontrare un Calabim con cui aveva appuntamento che prese la sua carrozza, lasciando un cavallo ad Anton. Ora tornava alla città fortificata, passò la sera in un'osteria, aspettando la notte. Tornò alla Catacomba Libralus e alla porta contrassegnata "Acquisizioni". Bussò. Se Odea rispondeva aveva già una scusa sul perché era di nuovo li. Se non rispondeva, le cose sarebbero andate secondo il piano. Scassinò la serratura e scivolò dentro. Non c'era quasi luce e attese che i suoi occhi si abituarono. I tavoli erano puliti e gli strumenti messi al loro posto. Una porta sul retro si apriva su un corridoio illuminato da una lanterna.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Quando entrò nella sala principale capì che aveva sottovalutato l'età e la grandezza di questo posto. Pensava che la biblioteca della sue vecchia gilda dei maghi fosse ampia, ma non aveva mai visto cosi tanti libri. La sala era piena di scaffali con libri in pelle di ogni colore, tutti rivolti verso l'esterno. Numerosi corridoi scendevano nelle catacombe, tutti pieni di libri. Anton si disperò quando pensò a come avrebbe fatto a trovare un singolo libro tra tutti questi, ma poi vide gli anni iscritti sugli archi dei corridoi.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Entrò nel corridoio più recente, iniziato ad usare solo negli ultimi cinque anni. Camminando direttamente verso la fine della fila. C'era una piccola iscrizione sotto l'ultimo libro. Qualche nome Malakim; comunque il libro era troppo scuro e aveva il tatuaggio di un leone sulla copertina. Il penultimo era di color marrone chiaro, come un prato secco. L'incisione sottostante recitava "sconosciuto" insieme all'anno della morte. Il libro prima era grigio verde con un singolo corno che fuoriusciva dal dorso. Prese quello color marrone chiaro. Era alto circa due mani e largo poco di meno. La copertina era leggera, era cuoio dopo tutto. Il dorso era rigido. Osso? Immaginò fosse lo sterno di lei, e penso ai suoi seni, uno senza pelle, l'altro semplicemente morto. Aprì la copertina e fece scorrere il dito lungo il dorso. Le pagine erano state cucite alla copertina usando corde fatte di capelli castani. C'erano delle scritte sulla prima pagina, in un inchiostro che era ancora rossastro e non era ancora diventato marrone. Diceva: Mio caro Ain, Non leggerai mai questo, ma spero tu sappia che ti amerò per sempre. Un brivido lo scosse. Mise il libro di Sebill nella sacca e tornò alla sala principale.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Guardò alle date sopra gli archi, ed entrò nel corridoio successivo. Entrambi i lati del corridoio erano pieni di libri che si fronteggiavano. Un miscuglio di nomi si formo nella sua testa mentre leggeva le iscrizioni.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Stai cercando qualcosa, Anton?" Si girò per vedere Odea al centro del corridoio. Sembrava rilassata; fece del suo meglio per apparire altrettanto rilassato. Il suo grembiule era sparito ed era vestita in maniera confortevole, stupendo Anton in quanto piuttosto carina.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Um... si. Un libro. Un libro di... mio nonno."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Qualcos'altro?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"...No."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Qual'è il suo nome?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton guardò verso la sala principale per vedere se Odea era da sola. "Gerard Cormand."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Lo conosco! Abbastanza rivoluzionario per i suoi tempi. Lo conoscevi?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No. Mio padre si opponeva alle sue politiche e lasciò la città, portandosi dietro la famiglia. Io sono nato in una fattoria."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Tuo nonno fu ucciso prima che la rivoluzione finisse, non è vero?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Si. Devo sapere che non è stato... mio padre."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Tuo nonno è li," indicando più in la nel corridoio. Anton seguì la sua guida cautamente. "I nostri divinatori ebbero un successo limitato come strumenti di scrittura dei morti, permettendogli di fare un ultima dichiarazione."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I morti scrivono?" chiese Anton.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Gli chiediamo se c'è qualcosa che vorrebbero dire. Di solito stanno riflettendo su cosa avrebbero fatto diversamente nella vita, quindi hanno un sacco di consigli. Potrebbero elogiare se stessi, o raccontare la storia della loro vita, dopo diamo una breve vacanza ai divinatori per recuperare le forze. Queste sono anime buone, chiariamoci; non vogliamo neppure contemplare i pericoli del fare un libro senza scrupoli."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Quella donna," pensò Anton, "cosa deve aver fatto per renderla cosi preziosa per i Calabim?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Le vittime di omicidio di solito hanno qualcosa da dire..." Odea smise di camminare e si diresse verso un libro, più piccolo di quello di Sebill e più chiaro.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton disse, "Avrà detto il nome dell'omicida?" Odea non rispose, e Anton sollevò il libro di suo nonno. Lo aprì e lesse: Mi piacevano i peccati carnali. Voltò le pagine: vuote. Sospirò profondamente, e mise il libro a posto. Odea fece un passo indietro. "Restituirai anche l'altro libro?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton affrontò Odea con una posizione allargata. "No. Mi dispiace, lo sto rubando". Teneva un coltello all'altezza degli occhi di lei e prese a muoversi lentamente verso di lei.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Non posso fermarti," lei disse calma. "Ma questo è un'errore. Questi libri sono estremamente pericolosi nelle mani sbagliate. Non devono mai uscire."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Lo so. I vostri "clienti" non mi hanno lasciato scelta però." Giravano in tondo in una cauta danza. Vedendo la sala principale libera, Anton uscì dalla porta principale.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Fuori dalle mura cittadine, Anton raggiunse il suo cavallo, ci montò sopra, e si diresse verso nord. Non era andato molto lontano quando un'improvviso vento, o quello che a lui sembrava vento, lo fece cadere da cavallo, facendogli cadere la sacca. Vide nel buio la sagoma di un gargoyle, le sue ali che bloccavano la luce della città. Corse, e sarebbe morto sul posto se non fosse stato per la magia Rapidità. Invece, morì al limite della foresta poco più in la, mentre il Libro di Sebill rimase vicino alla strada.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sebill arrived at a door marked "Acquisitions." The coachman escorted her to the door and gave it two hard knocks. It opened to reveal a miniscule butcher. The dwarf looked up at the coachman and noted Sebill. "Good! Good!" he said and ushered them into what looked like a carpenter's workshop-only one in which the wood bled when cut. "I commend you on your haste; we here are great appreciators of body magic, you know. You ought to be well paid for your effort. Do you need new horses?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"They are well," answered the coachman, "they're of strong breed and can withstand the spells. With enough food and rest tonight they'll have their stamina back."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"They're fine animals, aren't they?" the dwarf said affably, clearing tools off a table. He was joined by a graying female dwarf wearing an equally dirty apron. "Splendid!" she said. "Let's get started. I'm Odea, he's Hahm, in case he didn't introduce himself."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Anton," said the coachman.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Odea turned to examine Sebill. "Let's get a look at you... Even better than I expected! Let's get you on the table." Anton stepped forward to help lift Sebill, but saw it was unnecessary as Odea, despite her size, moved Sebill to the dwarf-sized table without effort. Odea smiled, "She's empty. No organs. I asked our clients in Nubia to clean her to prevent spoiling. Kept out of the sun the bodies can make the trip in adequate shape." Anton nodded. Odea thought he seemed uneasy. "I'm sorry, did you know her?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"No, no... I have no idea who she is, or why she's important to the nobles. She doesn't look like an aristocrat." He paused, then motioned toward the door, "I have the rest of the delivery in my carriage."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Her blood I'm sure. Would you fetch that? Hahm needs to check it and make sure the preservers held up. There are a number of naturally occurring blood thinners in just about every land, but ours are better. I have some theories about speeding the reactions to make the ink less corrosive, but that would require entropy mana which can be hard to come by..."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Outside, Anton gave the blood to Hahm and moved his horses into the shade. This was his first visit to the Luchuirp lands. He admitted to himself that he'd always been a little racist toward dwarves, but couldn't think of any reason why. He looked at and admired the structure of the Catacomb Libralus; from what he'd heard he assumed it was nothing more than a one-trick curiosity shop. It was originally built as a catacomb open to all, until necromancers developed a habit of exploiting it, leading to the pejoration of the name "Free-Use Catacombs." Later it was acquired by a wealthy polymath, who turned it into the institution that is now commonly nicknamed the "Catacomb Librarius." Above ground it was a simple structure with short walls and an entrance adorned with arches and pillars.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton returned to the workshop to see Odea in the process of skinning Sebill. Incisions ran up the middle of her chest, along her collarbone, and above her hips. Odea was paring the fatty membrane holding skin to muscle as she pulled the skin upward. Anton groaned at the sight, which alerted Odea that he'd returned. She explained, her enthusiasm outweighing her sympathy for Anton's uneasiness, "The skin's in good shape. We use it all. Her back-because its smoother and thicker-will be tanned and used to make the cover. The rest we stretch into vellum for the pages." Odea paused, Anton was staring at Sebill's body. "It's not pretty, I know. This is an honorable afterlife though. I used to do golemcraft, but animating a golem is like rolling a stone down a hill-it's predictable, it's all it does. Books are the perfect synthesis of form and function, body and spirit, mythos and logos. They are us in every way." She put down her knife, and Anton sat on short ladder. Odea continued, "We can put any talent to use here. Do you practice magic?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I do some, just tricks to help my deliveries-speed the horses, hide my wares. Just dabblings."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ice! Imagine what you could do with ice mana! We could add people from any corner of Erebus to our collection. You could make your fortune just transporting food to soldiers. Ah, if only we could get some..." Anton laughed. He'd thought of this before. Odea continued, "We use a range of magic here: body helps us transform the person, but that's mostly handiwork; our diviners use spirit magic to contact the dead; and enchanters can infuse the books with special properties. Luckily we're in a land where necromancy is outlawed, or we'd have a lot to worry about. Should I take you to see some of our collection?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Thank you," he replied, "but I have to stable my horses first. I should find an inn."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Fine by me. I need to work and I can't have distractions. Come back later for a tour." Odea smiled, "Now get out of here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A week had passed since Anton delivered Sebill. He'd gone north to meet a Calabim rendezvous who took the carriage, leaving Anton with a horse. Now returning to the fortified city, he spent the evening at a public house, waiting for nightfall. He made his way back to the Catacomb Libralus and to the door marked "Acquisitions." He knocked. If Odea answered he'd have an excuse for being there. If she didn't, then things would be according to plan. He picked the lock and slipped inside. There was barely any light and he waited for his eyes to adjust. The tables were clean and the tools put away. A door in back opened to a lantern-lit corridor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When he entered the main hall he realized he'd underestimated the age and grandeur of this place. He thought the library at his former mages' guild was large, but he'd never seen this many books. The hall was lined with shelves of books in every skin color, all facing out. Numerous corridors descended into the catacombs, all filled with books. Anton despaired when he wondered how he would find a single book in all this, until he saw the years inscribed above the corridors' arches.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He entered the most recent corridor, which had just started to be used in the last five years. He walked straight to the end of the row. A small engraving was underneath the last book. Some Malakim name; the book was too dark anyway and had a tattoo of a lion on the cover. The second-to-last book was a pale tan, like a dry meadow. The engraving underneath read "unknown" and named the year of death. The book before that was grayish green and had a single horn jutting out from the spine. He picked up the tan one. It was about two hands tall and a little less wide. The cover was soft-it was leather after all. The spine was sturdy. Bone? He imagined it was her sternum, and thought of her breasts, one skinless, the other just dead. He opened the cover and ran his finger along the inside spine. The pages were sewn to the cover using string made of brown hair. There was writing on the first page, in ink that was still reddish and had not faded into brown. It said: My dear Ain-You'll never read this, but please know that I love you eternally. A chill shook him. He tucked Sebill's book into his pack and returned to the main hall.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He looked at the dates above the arches, and walked down the next corridor. Both sides of the corridor were lined with books facing each other. A jumble of names grew in his head as he scanned the engravings.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Are you looking for something, Anton?" He spun to see Odea in the middle of the corridor. She looked relaxed; he tried his best to appear the same. Her apron was gone and she was dressed comfortably, striking Anton as quite pretty.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Um... yes. A book. A book of... my grandfather."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Anything else?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"...No."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"What was his name?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton glanced toward the main hall to see if Odea was alone. "Gerard Cormand."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know of him! Quite the revolutionary in his day. Did you know him?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I didn't. My father opposed his politics and left the city, taking his family along. I was born on a farm."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Your grandfather was murdered before the revolution ended, wasn't he?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Yes. I have to know that it wasn't... my father."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Your grandfather is here," she pointed farther down the corridor. Anton cautiously followed her lead. "Our diviners enjoy limited success as a writing tool for the dead, allowing them to make a final statement."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The dead write?" probed Anton.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We ask them if there's anything they'd like to say. They're usually thinking about what they would have done differently in life, so they're full of advice. They might eulogize themselves, or tell their entire life's story-we give the diviners a short vacation to recover after those. These are good souls, mind you; we don't even want to know the dangers of making an unscrupulous book."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"That woman," thought Anton, "what had she done to make her so valuable to the Calabim?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Victims of murder usually have something to say..." Odea stopped walking and motioned toward a book, smaller than Sebill's and paler.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton said, "Would he have named his killer?" Odea didn't answer, and Anton lifted his grandfather's book. He opened it and read: I liked the fleshy sins best. He turned the pages: blank. He sighed deeply, and put the book down. Odea took a step back. "Are you going to return the other book too?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anton faced Odea with a widened stance. "No. I'm sorry, but I'm stealing it." He held a knife at her eye level and took a slow step toward her.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I can't stop you," she said calmly. "This is a mistake though. These books are extremely dangerous in the wrong hands. They must never leave."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know. Your ‘clients' haven't given me any choice though." They circled each other in a cautious dance. Seeing the main hall clear, Anton left through the front door.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Outside the city walls, Anton snuck to his horse, mounted her, and pointed her back north. He hadn't ridden far when a sudden strong wind, or that's what it felt like, threw him off his horse, spilling his pack. He saw in the dark the looming shape of a gargoyle, its wings blocking the light from the city. He ran, and would have died on the spot if it weren't for his haste spell. Instead, he died at the forest's edge a short length away, while the Book of Sebill remained beside the road.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CELESTIAL_COMPASS</Tag>
		<English>Celestial Compass</English>
		<French>Compas Céleste</French>
		<German>Himmlischer Kompass</German>
		<Italian>Bussola Celestiale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Compás Celeste</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CELESTIAL_COMPASS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Most compasses tell you where to go. This one tells you who, what, when and why as well.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Anonymous[\ITALICS]</English>
		<French>La plupart des compas vous indiquent où aller. Celui-ci vous indique aussi le qui, le quoi, le quand et le pourquoi.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Anonyme[\ITALICS]</French>
		<German>Most compasses tell you where to go. This one tells you who, what, when and why as well.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Anonymous[\ITALICS]</German>
		<Italian>Molte bussole ti dicono dove andare. Questa ti dice pure chi, cosa, quando e perché.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Anonimo[\ITALICS]</Italian>
		<Spanish>Most compasses tell you where to go. This one tells you who, what, when and why as well.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Anonymous[\ITALICS]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CITY_OF_A_THOUSAND_SLUMS</Tag>
		<English>City of a Thousand Slums</English>
		<French>Cité aux Mille Taudis</French>
		<German>Stadt der tausend Slums</German>
		<Italian>Città dei Mille Bassifondi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ciudad de los Mil Barrios</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CODE_OF_JUNIL</Tag>
		<English>Code of Junil</English>
		<French>Code de Junil</French>
		<German>Kodex von Junil</German>
		<Italian>Codice di Junil</Italian>
		<Spanish>Código de Junil</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CODE_OF_JUNIL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Resolve the weaknesses of your heart[NEWLINE]Obey the laws of your providence[NEWLINE]Yield to the goodness that surrounds you[NEWLINE]Grant silence to those who betray it[NEWLINE]Bring wrath upon those who will destroy[NEWLINE]Inspire love of the righteous law[NEWLINE]Vest in yourself the Code of Junil</English>
		<French>Maîtrisez les faiblesses de votre c&#156;ur,[NEWLINE]Obéissez aux lois de la providence,[NEWLINE]Abandonnez-vous au bien qui vous embrasse,[NEWLINE]Forcez au silence ceux qui le trahissent,[NEWLINE]Foudroyez de votre courroux les destructeurs,[NEWLINE]Inspirez foi en la loi et la justice,[NEWLINE]Soyez investi du Code de Junil</French>
		<German>Überwinde die Schwäche in Deinem Herzen,[NEWLINE]Befolge die Gebote der Weisung,[NEWLINE]Überlasse Dich ganz der Güte mit der sie dich umgibt,[NEWLINE]Gewähre jenen Ruhe die sie betrügen,[NEWLINE]Bringe jenen Verderben die zerstören,[NEWLINE]Wecke die Liebe zu ihr und ihren Geboten,[NEWLINE]Der Kodex von Junil ist auf Dich übergegangen</German>
		<Italian>Sciogli le debolezze del tuo cuore[NEWLINE]Obbedisci alle leggi della tua provvidenza[NEWLINE]Cedi al bontà che ti circonda[NEWLINE]Porta il silenzio a chi la tradisce[NEWLINE]Porta la tua ira a coloro che la distruggono[NEWLINE]Inspira l'amore per la giusta legge[NEWLINE]Vestiti del Codice di Junil</Italian>
		<Spanish>Resolved las debilidades de vuestro corazón,[NEWLINE]Obedeced las leyes con providencia,[NEWLINE]Rendíos a la bondad que os rodea,[NEWLINE]Silenciad a aquellos que la traicionan,[NEWLINE]Llevad la furia sobre aquellos que destruyen,[NEWLINE]Inspirad el amor de la ley justa,[NEWLINE]Ornamentaros con el Código de Junil</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DIES_DIEI</Tag>
		<English>Dies Diei</English>
		<French>Dies Diei</French>
		<German>Der Tag der Tage</German>
		<Italian>Dies Diei</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dies Diei</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EYES_AND_EARS_NETWORK</Tag>
		<English>The Eyes and Ears Network</English>
		<French>Réseau des Yeux et des Oreilles</French>
		<German>Netzwerk der Augen und Ohren</German>
		<Italian>Rete degli Occhi e delle Orecchie</Italian>
		<Spanish>Red de Ojos y Oídos</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EYES_AND_EARS_NETWORK_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Grants a technology to your civilization for free, if three players you have open borders agreements with already have it.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can See Research</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Vous offre une technologie gratuite si trois joueurs avec qui vous avez un accord de Libre Passage la possèdent.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Peut voir l'état des recherches</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Ihr erhaltet alle Technologien, welche bereits von mindestens 3 Zivilisationen erforscht wurden und mit denen Ihr offene Grenzen vereinbart habt.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Forschung sichtbar</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce una tecnologia gratis se altri tre giocatori, con cui hai il diritto di passaggio, la possiedono.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Visione ricerche</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Da gratis una tecnología gratis a la civilización que lo construya cuando tres jugadores con los que tenga acuerdo de apertura de fronteras la posean.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Puede ver investigaci&#243;n</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EYES_AND_EARS_NETWORK_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Grants a technology to your civilization for free, if three players you have open borders agreements with already have it.</English>
		<French>Multipliez les accords de libre-passage : vous profiterez ainsi des recherches des autres joueurs dès que 3 d'entre eux l'ont découverte.[NEWLINE]Vous pouvez passer votre recherche à O% et investir vos économies dans l'expansion territoriale et l'amélioration de votre armée, ou encore vous focaliser sur une seule branche technologique. Ah, et n'oubliez pas de vendre les technologies aux civilisations en retard. Tout bénéfice est bon à prendre.[NEWLINE]Par ailleurs, la connaissance des recherches des autres joueurs vous permet d'anticiper les mauvaises surprises.</French>
		<German>Ihr erhaltet alle Technologien, welche bereits von mindestens 3 Zivilisationen erforscht wurden und mit denen Ihr offene Grenzen vereinbart habt.</German>
		<Italian>Fornisce una tecnologia gratis se altri tre giocatori, con cui hai il diritto di passaggio, la possiedono.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Da gratis una tecnología gratis a la civilización que lo construya cuando tres jugadores con los que tenga acuerdo de apertura de fronteras la posean.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FORBIDDEN_PALACE</Tag>
		<English>Summer Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Interdit</French>
		<German>Verbotener Palast</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo Estivo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Prohibido</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FORM_OF_THE_TITAN</Tag>
		<English>Form of the Titan</English>
		<French>Forme du Titan</French>
		<German>Flamme Odins</German>
		<Italian>Statua del Titano</Italian>
		<Spanish>Forma del Titán</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_LIBRARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The library's majesty would be a thing of legend. Sebill's view from the fifth floor spanned from the northern slums out to Nubia's western wall and beyond that to where the countryside was trampled underfoot by mountains. Moving a crate of books, new acquisitions from the latest campaigns, she broke her gaze from the window. She was at odds with herself; technically, she'd achieved her goal and become a chief librarian at the world's greatest library. It was what she had promised her childhood friends she'd do, then they in turn would dream up something they thought was even more fantastic. Yet here she was. Slaving. Forced into her wishes' fulfillment by ravenous men under a new moon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Her town was alight with burning houses as she woke to the screams. She shook her husband awake, scrambled for her weapon, and used it on the first blood-drenched man who burst into the bedroom. His comrades behind him overpowered her. All she could remember feeling at that moment was insult at the fact that they showed no desire to kill her. Instead, one man constrained her on the bed while they dragged her husband outside. She shrieked and swung her fists, until an attacker brought a torch into the room. In the light the men saw the bedroom and its bookshelf-lined walls. Their faces flushed with joy and they shouted congratulations to each other. That was when they knocked her unconscious.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]...there's no noise what's going on? I'm deaf no I'm dead oh good there's noise the chains oh damn me the chains. How dare they keep me down here what did they do to her the next time one of them comes down here I'll wrap these chains around him... Where is everybody I'm alone I'm alone they'll never come for me I'll die here what have they done with her I'll starve here if my heart doesn't explode first I just want to tear them to pieces! Can't stop shaking the walls are too noisy I can't hear myself how can I... Huh? They're coming those are footsteps I'll kill them and I'll get out and find her oh I'll never see her again... One footsteps two feet could it be her they don't sound hard... oh my angel what if it's her she's come to kill me oh my angel it is her![\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill hadn't seen her husband since. And now there she was, the woman she'd always wanted to be. Only the library wasn't what she'd hoped for. It was supposed to be a paragon of learning, open to all, with a collection spanning history and all of Erebus. This was a perversion, a library of spoils, built on the sudden whim of that monstrous queen Alexis to actually know something about the people she and her brother were slaughtering. And she'd let Flauros build it! It was a wonder he had any slaves left over to clean up the blood of those who built it. Sebill was horrified to hear that Alexis had been the one to finally build Erebus's greatest library, now known as the Library of Alexis. Sebill never wanted anything to do with it, but now she was its chief archivist. It was more of a wound than a title. Still, she had books. She passed the time by imagining that the library had been built by someone else: perhaps in the Kuriotate lands it would be a bridge across race and politics; in Amurite lands its knowledge would be treated with proper respect.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Books, protected by sturdy leather covers, were durable and could last ages if properly cared for. But books in Erebus were only as permanent as societies allowed. Warring nations expunged conquered peoples' libraries with the rest of their culture. The Age of Ice preserved the previous ages' treasures well, as long as firewood was more plentiful than books. The real damage came with the destruction of literate societies who knew the value of old histories and treatises. Still, Sebill thought, maybe Alexis's collection will serve some good in the long run. Perhaps Sebill's dreams were not totally lost. Spending her days cataloging family histories, journals, folktales, scientific works, philosophies, and everything else brought in from homes and palace libraries gave her faith that one day this could be shared with the world.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She unloaded the books onto the table-They were her books. She stared at them, telling herself that this was inevitable, and yet she was holding the books that belonged to her and her former neighbors. She tried to detach herself, but opening the covers felt like tearing new flesh off wounds. "Is this the last I'll ever see of my life?" she despaired. One book confirmed that it would be: a ledger, a report of the raid on her town.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]it's her it's her she came for me she sees me she'll kill me I have to kill her I'm scared I hate her I hate those men that's a sharp knife I'm going to die I should die I'm worthless I'm afraid hate hate them her skin cuts so fine[\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Come on you. Drink up."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]blood! she's bleeding I can taste it already these chains hurt I want her to notice me let me go I must taste her fingers the cut is so sharp I can feel the cut on my tongue I'm okay I'll be okay she loves me I'm home I'm hers her hand is so soft it could tear me to pieces I want her to she can have me all in little bits she'll protect me my angel my angel I'll climb under her shadow her dress I'll be engulfed in her darkness her peaceful darkness she'll hold me and I'll be okay I'll be hers I'll be nothing in her abyss she loves me she will always protect me...[\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sneaking out was unnecessary. Sebill doubted it was because they trusted her; perhaps they were certain they could find her if she ran off. The masters ignored other slaves, but had to address her because of the role they gave her. Eye contact was rare, but they had an odd way of acknowledging her presence by letting her know they were smelling her. Tonight she was betting they wouldn't find her quickly enough.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The ledger had listed the spoils, the "acquisitions." House #6 Contents. Books: 156. Woman: Educated: For especial use, she read. Man: Drunk, superior physical condition: For conscription in Red Barracks. Weapons only other items of value. She knew of the so-called "Red Barracks." Other librarians spoke fearfully, sorrowfully, of their loved ones sent there.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She agonized during the following nights. After her life had been destroyed her only possible comfort was having all the world's books and time enough at last to read. Now that had become her hell. The only truth she wanted was outside the library. She had to find the Red Barracks.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And she did. She was ushered right in through the front doors the moment she was spotted sneaking underneath a window. She protested, feigned ignorance, fought, but was pulled before a woman wrapping her hand in a bandage. Sebill froze; her. Alexis looked at Sebill with a sneer.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Mistress, we found her snooping. She looks like-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I don't care what she is. Come. Bring her." She turned and walked with her saturating, scarlet-bandaged hand at her side.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Bring her in here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill was thrown to the floor in a small, windowless room. The light from the room outside shone past her, and onto a man chained to the wall. Sebill bounced to her feet, but was stunned when she saw him.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ain! Oh!" she shouted and ran to him. He stared at her without recognition and his lips trembled with senseless mutterings. Alexis entered the room and watched with contempt as Sebill tried to get Ain to look at her. Ain was transfixed by Alexis. Suddenly a look of eagerness showed on his face and he noticed Sebill for the first time.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ain! It's me, dear!" She shook Ain and rubbed his cheeks in growing hysteria. Her eyes widened in both fear and hope when Ain looked at her. In him she saw savagery mixed with his eagerness to please. Four eyes with four different emotions looked at each other across the chasm of their broken lives. Ain then looked to Alexis, who remained still and observant in the doorway. She was glad-tonight she had something interesting to give the new recruit. She was losing interest in tossing unsatisfactory guards to these things.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill, nearly sobbing, tried futilely to find her husband in this man. Ain, however, flourished in the queen's attention. Sebill was too confused to react when Ain grabbed her throat and throttled her. He found little resistance from her body as Alexis's blood burned inside him. His wife's essence slipped away and Ain looked to his queen for affirmation.</English>
		<French>The library's majesty would be a thing of legend. Sebill's view from the fifth floor spanned from the northern slums out to Nubia's western wall and beyond that to where the countryside was trampled underfoot by mountains. Moving a crate of books, new acquisitions from the latest campaigns, she broke her gaze from the window. She was at odds with herself; technically, she'd achieved her goal and become a chief librarian at the world's greatest library. It was what she had promised her childhood friends she'd do, then they in turn would dream up something they thought was even more fantastic. Yet here she was. Slaving. Forced into her wishes' fulfillment by ravenous men under a new moon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Her town was alight with burning houses as she woke to the screams. She shook her husband awake, scrambled for her weapon, and used it on the first blood-drenched man who burst into the bedroom. His comrades behind him overpowered her. All she could remember feeling at that moment was insult at the fact that they showed no desire to kill her. Instead, one man constrained her on the bed while they dragged her husband outside. She shrieked and swung her fists, until an attacker brought a torch into the room. In the light the men saw the bedroom and its bookshelf-lined walls. Their faces flushed with joy and they shouted congratulations to each other. That was when they knocked her unconscious.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]...there's no noise what's going on? I'm deaf no I'm dead oh good there's noise the chains oh damn me the chains. How dare they keep me down here what did they do to her the next time one of them comes down here I'll wrap these chains around him... Where is everybody I'm alone I'm alone they'll never come for me I'll die here what have they done with her I'll starve here if my heart doesn't explode first I just want to tear them to pieces! Can't stop shaking the walls are too noisy I can't hear myself how can I... Huh? They're coming those are footsteps I'll kill them and I'll get out and find her oh I'll never see her again... One footsteps two feet could it be her they don't sound hard... oh my angel what if it's her she's come to kill me oh my angel it is her![\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill hadn't seen her husband since. And now there she was, the woman she'd always wanted to be. Only the library wasn't what she'd hoped for. It was supposed to be a paragon of learning, open to all, with a collection spanning history and all of Erebus. This was a perversion, a library of spoils, built on the sudden whim of that monstrous queen Alexis to actually know something about the people she and her brother were slaughtering. And she'd let Flauros build it! It was a wonder he had any slaves left over to clean up the blood of those who built it. Sebill was horrified to hear that Alexis had been the one to finally build Erebus's greatest library, now known as the Library of Alexis. Sebill never wanted anything to do with it, but now she was its chief archivist. It was more of a wound than a title. Still, she had books. She passed the time by imagining that the library had been built by someone else: perhaps in the Kuriotate lands it would be a bridge across race and politics; in Amurite lands its knowledge would be treated with proper respect.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Books, protected by sturdy leather covers, were durable and could last ages if properly cared for. But books in Erebus were only as permanent as societies allowed. Warring nations expunged conquered peoples' libraries with the rest of their culture. The Age of Ice preserved the previous ages' treasures well, as long as firewood was more plentiful than books. The real damage came with the destruction of literate societies who knew the value of old histories and treatises. Still, Sebill thought, maybe Alexis's collection will serve some good in the long run. Perhaps Sebill's dreams were not totally lost. Spending her days cataloging family histories, journals, folktales, scientific works, philosophies, and everything else brought in from homes and palace libraries gave her faith that one day this could be shared with the world.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She unloaded the books onto the table-They were her books. She stared at them, telling herself that this was inevitable, and yet she was holding the books that belonged to her and her former neighbors. She tried to detach herself, but opening the covers felt like tearing new flesh off wounds. "Is this the last I'll ever see of my life?" she despaired. One book confirmed that it would be: a ledger, a report of the raid on her town.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]it's her it's her she came for me she sees me she'll kill me I have to kill her I'm scared I hate her I hate those men that's a sharp knife I'm going to die I should die I'm worthless I'm afraid hate hate them her skin cuts so fine[\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Come on you. Drink up."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]blood! she's bleeding I can taste it already these chains hurt I want her to notice me let me go I must taste her fingers the cut is so sharp I can feel the cut on my tongue I'm okay I'll be okay she loves me I'm home I'm hers her hand is so soft it could tear me to pieces I want her to she can have me all in little bits she'll protect me my angel my angel I'll climb under her shadow her dress I'll be engulfed in her darkness her peaceful darkness she'll hold me and I'll be okay I'll be hers I'll be nothing in her abyss she loves me she will always protect me...[\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sneaking out was unnecessary. Sebill doubted it was because they trusted her; perhaps they were certain they could find her if she ran off. The masters ignored other slaves, but had to address her because of the role they gave her. Eye contact was rare, but they had an odd way of acknowledging her presence by letting her know they were smelling her. Tonight she was betting they wouldn't find her quickly enough.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The ledger had listed the spoils, the "acquisitions." House #6 Contents. Books: 156. Woman: Educated: For especial use, she read. Man: Drunk, superior physical condition: For conscription in Red Barracks. Weapons only other items of value. She knew of the so-called "Red Barracks." Other librarians spoke fearfully, sorrowfully, of their loved ones sent there.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She agonized during the following nights. After her life had been destroyed her only possible comfort was having all the world's books and time enough at last to read. Now that had become her hell. The only truth she wanted was outside the library. She had to find the Red Barracks.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And she did. She was ushered right in through the front doors the moment she was spotted sneaking underneath a window. She protested, feigned ignorance, fought, but was pulled before a woman wrapping her hand in a bandage. Sebill froze; her. Alexis looked at Sebill with a sneer.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Mistress, we found her snooping. She looks like-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I don't care what she is. Come. Bring her." She turned and walked with her saturating, scarlet-bandaged hand at her side.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Bring her in here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill was thrown to the floor in a small, windowless room. The light from the room outside shone past her, and onto a man chained to the wall. Sebill bounced to her feet, but was stunned when she saw him.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ain! Oh!" she shouted and ran to him. He stared at her without recognition and his lips trembled with senseless mutterings. Alexis entered the room and watched with contempt as Sebill tried to get Ain to look at her. Ain was transfixed by Alexis. Suddenly a look of eagerness showed on his face and he noticed Sebill for the first time.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ain! It's me, dear!" She shook Ain and rubbed his cheeks in growing hysteria. Her eyes widened in both fear and hope when Ain looked at her. In him she saw savagery mixed with his eagerness to please. Four eyes with four different emotions looked at each other across the chasm of their broken lives. Ain then looked to Alexis, who remained still and observant in the doorway. She was glad-tonight she had something interesting to give the new recruit. She was losing interest in tossing unsatisfactory guards to these things.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill, nearly sobbing, tried futilely to find her husband in this man. Ain, however, flourished in the queen's attention. Sebill was too confused to react when Ain grabbed her throat and throttled her. He found little resistance from her body as Alexis's blood burned inside him. His wife's essence slipped away and Ain looked to his queen for affirmation.</French>
		<German>The library's majesty would be a thing of legend. Sebill's view from the fifth floor spanned from the northern slums out to Nubia's western wall and beyond that to where the countryside was trampled underfoot by mountains. Moving a crate of books, new acquisitions from the latest campaigns, she broke her gaze from the window. She was at odds with herself; technically, she'd achieved her goal and become a chief librarian at the world's greatest library. It was what she had promised her childhood friends she'd do, then they in turn would dream up something they thought was even more fantastic. Yet here she was. Slaving. Forced into her wishes' fulfillment by ravenous men under a new moon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Her town was alight with burning houses as she woke to the screams. She shook her husband awake, scrambled for her weapon, and used it on the first blood-drenched man who burst into the bedroom. His comrades behind him overpowered her. All she could remember feeling at that moment was insult at the fact that they showed no desire to kill her. Instead, one man constrained her on the bed while they dragged her husband outside. She shrieked and swung her fists, until an attacker brought a torch into the room. In the light the men saw the bedroom and its bookshelf-lined walls. Their faces flushed with joy and they shouted congratulations to each other. That was when they knocked her unconscious.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]...there's no noise what's going on? I'm deaf no I'm dead oh good there's noise the chains oh damn me the chains. How dare they keep me down here what did they do to her the next time one of them comes down here I'll wrap these chains around him... Where is everybody I'm alone I'm alone they'll never come for me I'll die here what have they done with her I'll starve here if my heart doesn't explode first I just want to tear them to pieces! Can't stop shaking the walls are too noisy I can't hear myself how can I... Huh? They're coming those are footsteps I'll kill them and I'll get out and find her oh I'll never see her again... One footsteps two feet could it be her they don't sound hard... oh my angel what if it's her she's come to kill me oh my angel it is her![\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill hadn't seen her husband since. And now there she was, the woman she'd always wanted to be. Only the library wasn't what she'd hoped for. It was supposed to be a paragon of learning, open to all, with a collection spanning history and all of Erebus. This was a perversion, a library of spoils, built on the sudden whim of that monstrous queen Alexis to actually know something about the people she and her brother were slaughtering. And she'd let Flauros build it! It was a wonder he had any slaves left over to clean up the blood of those who built it. Sebill was horrified to hear that Alexis had been the one to finally build Erebus's greatest library, now known as the Library of Alexis. Sebill never wanted anything to do with it, but now she was its chief archivist. It was more of a wound than a title. Still, she had books. She passed the time by imagining that the library had been built by someone else: perhaps in the Kuriotate lands it would be a bridge across race and politics; in Amurite lands its knowledge would be treated with proper respect.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Books, protected by sturdy leather covers, were durable and could last ages if properly cared for. But books in Erebus were only as permanent as societies allowed. Warring nations expunged conquered peoples' libraries with the rest of their culture. The Age of Ice preserved the previous ages' treasures well, as long as firewood was more plentiful than books. The real damage came with the destruction of literate societies who knew the value of old histories and treatises. Still, Sebill thought, maybe Alexis's collection will serve some good in the long run. Perhaps Sebill's dreams were not totally lost. Spending her days cataloging family histories, journals, folktales, scientific works, philosophies, and everything else brought in from homes and palace libraries gave her faith that one day this could be shared with the world.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She unloaded the books onto the table-They were her books. She stared at them, telling herself that this was inevitable, and yet she was holding the books that belonged to her and her former neighbors. She tried to detach herself, but opening the covers felt like tearing new flesh off wounds. "Is this the last I'll ever see of my life?" she despaired. One book confirmed that it would be: a ledger, a report of the raid on her town.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]it's her it's her she came for me she sees me she'll kill me I have to kill her I'm scared I hate her I hate those men that's a sharp knife I'm going to die I should die I'm worthless I'm afraid hate hate them her skin cuts so fine[\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Come on you. Drink up."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]blood! she's bleeding I can taste it already these chains hurt I want her to notice me let me go I must taste her fingers the cut is so sharp I can feel the cut on my tongue I'm okay I'll be okay she loves me I'm home I'm hers her hand is so soft it could tear me to pieces I want her to she can have me all in little bits she'll protect me my angel my angel I'll climb under her shadow her dress I'll be engulfed in her darkness her peaceful darkness she'll hold me and I'll be okay I'll be hers I'll be nothing in her abyss she loves me she will always protect me...[\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sneaking out was unnecessary. Sebill doubted it was because they trusted her; perhaps they were certain they could find her if she ran off. The masters ignored other slaves, but had to address her because of the role they gave her. Eye contact was rare, but they had an odd way of acknowledging her presence by letting her know they were smelling her. Tonight she was betting they wouldn't find her quickly enough.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The ledger had listed the spoils, the "acquisitions." House #6 Contents. Books: 156. Woman: Educated: For especial use, she read. Man: Drunk, superior physical condition: For conscription in Red Barracks. Weapons only other items of value. She knew of the so-called "Red Barracks." Other librarians spoke fearfully, sorrowfully, of their loved ones sent there.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She agonized during the following nights. After her life had been destroyed her only possible comfort was having all the world's books and time enough at last to read. Now that had become her hell. The only truth she wanted was outside the library. She had to find the Red Barracks.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And she did. She was ushered right in through the front doors the moment she was spotted sneaking underneath a window. She protested, feigned ignorance, fought, but was pulled before a woman wrapping her hand in a bandage. Sebill froze; her. Alexis looked at Sebill with a sneer.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Mistress, we found her snooping. She looks like-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I don't care what she is. Come. Bring her." She turned and walked with her saturating, scarlet-bandaged hand at her side.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Bring her in here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill was thrown to the floor in a small, windowless room. The light from the room outside shone past her, and onto a man chained to the wall. Sebill bounced to her feet, but was stunned when she saw him.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ain! Oh!" she shouted and ran to him. He stared at her without recognition and his lips trembled with senseless mutterings. Alexis entered the room and watched with contempt as Sebill tried to get Ain to look at her. Ain was transfixed by Alexis. Suddenly a look of eagerness showed on his face and he noticed Sebill for the first time.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ain! It's me, dear!" She shook Ain and rubbed his cheeks in growing hysteria. Her eyes widened in both fear and hope when Ain looked at her. In him she saw savagery mixed with his eagerness to please. Four eyes with four different emotions looked at each other across the chasm of their broken lives. Ain then looked to Alexis, who remained still and observant in the doorway. She was glad-tonight she had something interesting to give the new recruit. She was losing interest in tossing unsatisfactory guards to these things.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill, nearly sobbing, tried futilely to find her husband in this man. Ain, however, flourished in the queen's attention. Sebill was too confused to react when Ain grabbed her throat and throttled her. He found little resistance from her body as Alexis's blood burned inside him. His wife's essence slipped away and Ain looked to his queen for affirmation.</German>
		<Italian>La maestosità della biblioteca sarebbe stata leggendaria. Il panorama che Sebill vedeva dal quinto piano si estendeva dai bassifondi a nord sino alle mura occidentali di Nubia e oltre quelle sino a dove la la campagna veniva schiacciata dalle montagne. Spostando una cassa di libri, nuove acquisizioni dalle ultime campagne, distolse lo sguardo dalla finestra. Era in conflitto con se stessa; tecnicamente aveva raggiunto il suo obiettivo diventando il capo bibliotecario della più grande biblioteca al mondo. Era ciò che aveva promesso avrebbe fatto ai suoi amici d'infanzia, poi loro a turno avrebberò detto qualcosa che secondo loro sarebbe stato meglio. Eppure eccola qui. Lavorando come uno schiavo. Costretta da uomini avari all'adempimento dei suoi sogni sotto una luna nuova.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]La sua città era illuminata da case che bruciavano quando si svegliò per via delle urla. Scosse il marito per svegliarlo, prese in fretta la sua arma, e la usò sul primo uomo, ricoperto di sangue, che irruppe nella stanza da letto. I suoi compagni la soverchiarono. Tutto ciò che ricordava di sentire in quel momento erano insulti e il fatto che non mostravano alcuna intenzione di ucciderla. Invece, un'uomo la buttò sul letto mentre gli altri trascinavano il marito fuori. Lei urlò e agitò i pugni, fino a quando un invasore non portò una torcia nella stanza. Con la luce videro la stanza con le pareti piene di scaffali. Le loro facce si riempirono di gioia e si congratularono a vicenda. Fu allora che la colpirono facendola svenire.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]...non c'è nessun suono? Sono sordo no sono morto oh bene ci sono rumori catene oh accidenti a me catene. Come osavano tenerlo qui sotto cosa gli faranno la prossima volta che uno di loro va da lei la prossima volta che uno di loro scende qui avvolgerò queste catene attorno a lui... Dove sono tutti sono solo sono solo nessuno verrà per me morirò qui cosa gli avranno fatto morirò di fame qui se il mio cuore non scoppia prima li voglio fare a pezzi! Non posso smettere di tremare i muri sono troppo rumorosi non posso sentire me stesso come posso... Huh? Stanno arrivando quello è rumore di passi li ucciderò e uscirò e la troverò oh non la vedrò mai più... Un passo due piedi poteva essere lei non sembravano pesanti... oh mio angelo cosa se è lei venuta ad uccidermi oh mio angelo è lei![\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill non vedeva suo marito da allora. E ora eccola li, la donna che ha sempre voluto essere. Solo la biblioteca non era come sperava. Doveva essere un ricettaccolo di conoscenza, aperta a tutti, con una collezione che attraversava la storia di Erebus. Questa era una perversione, Una biblioteca di razzie, costruita sul capriccio improvviso di quella mostruosa regina Alexis per sapere effettivamente qualcosa sulle persone che lei e suo fratello stavano massacrando. E lei permise a Flauros di costruirla! È incredibile che avesse ancora schiavi per pulire il sangue di coloro che la hanno costruita. Sebill era rimasta inorridita sapendo che Alexis era stata colei che aveva costruito la biblioteca più grande di Erebus, ora conosciuta come la Biblioteca di Alexis. Sebill non ci aveva mai voluto a che fare, ma ora ne era il capo archivista. Era più una ferita che un titolo. Comunque, lei aveva i libri. Passava il tempo immaginando che la biblioteca era stata costruita da qualcun'altro: magari nelle terre dei Kuriotate sarebbe stato un ponte tra razze diverse e politica; nelle terre degli Amurite la sua conoscenza sarebbe stata trattata col dovuto rispetto.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I libri, protetti da robuste copertine in pelle, erano duraturi e potevano durare secoli se propriamente custoditi. Ma i libri in Erebus erano permanenti solo quanto le società permettevano. Le nazioni in guerra cancellavano le biblioteche degli sconfitti insieme alla loro cultura. L'Era del Ghiaccio preservò bene i tesori delle ere precedenti, almeno fino a quando il legno da ardere era più disponibile dei libri. Il vero danno è stato la distruzione di società istruite che conoscevano il valore di vecchie storie e trattati. Comunque, Sebill pensò, forse la collezione di Alexis farà un pò di bene sul lungo termine. Forse i sogni di Sebill erano ancora possibili. Passando i giorni catalogando storie di famiglie, giornali, racconti popolari, trattati scientifici, trattati filosofici, e qualsiasi altra cosa che gli portavano da biblioteche di case e palazzi gli dava speranza che un giorno tutto questo sarebbe stato condiviso col mondo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Scaricò i libri sul tavolo, quelli erano i suoi libri. Iniziò da quelli, dicendo a se stessa che tanto era inevitabile, eppure continuava a tenersi i suoi libri e quelli dei suoi vecchi vicini di casa. Provò a distaccarsi, ma aprire le copertine era come riaprire delle ferite. "Questo sarà l'ultimo che vedrò nella mia vita?" si disperò. Un libro glielo confermò: un libro mastro, un rapporto sul raid della sua città.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]è lei è lei è venuta per me mi vede mi ucciderà devo ucciderla sono spaventato la odio odio quegli uomini quello è un coltello affilato morirò dovrei morire non ho valore ho paura odio li odio la sua pelle si taglia cosi bene[\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Andiamo. Bevi."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]sangue! sta sanguinando posso già gustarlo queste catene fanno male voglio che mi noti lasciami andare devo assaggiare le sue dita il taglio è cosi tagliente posso sentire il taglio sulla mia lingua sto bene starò bene lei mi ama sono a casa sono suo la sua mano è cosi soffice può farmi a pezzi la voglio cosi lei può avermi in piccoli pezzi mi proteggerà mio angelo mio angelo salirò sotto la sua ombra il suo vestito sarò avvolto dalla sua oscurità la sua pacifica oscurità mi tratterrà e io staro bene sarò suo sarò niente nel suo abisso mi ama lei mi proteggerà sempre...[\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Uscire furtivamente non era necessario. Sebill dubitava che fosse perché si fidavano di lei; probabilmente erano sicuri che la avrebbero ritrovata se scappava. I padroni ignoravano gli altri schiavi, ma dovevano ascoltare lei per via del ruolo che gli avevano dato. Il contatto visivo era raro, ma avevano uno strano modo di farle capire che sapevano della sua presenza facendogli capire che sentivano il suo odore. Stanotte scommetteva sul fatto che non l'avrebbero trovata abbastanza in fretta.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Il libro mastro elencava le razzie, le "acquisizioni". Contenuti Casa #6. Libri: 156. Donna: Educata: Per uso speciale, lesse. Uomo: Ubriaco, condizioni fisiche superiori: coscritto nelle Caserme Rosse. Le armi unici altri oggetti di valore. Conosceva le cosidettte "Caserme Rosse". Gli altri bibliotecari ne parlavano con paura, e con sofferenza, dei loro amati mandati li.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Lei era agonizzante nelle notti succesive. Dopo la distruzione della sua vita il suo unico conforto possibile era quello di avere tutti i libri del mondo e abbastanza tempo per leggerli. Ora quello era diventato il suo inferno. L'unica verità che voleva era fuori dalla biblioteca. Doveva trovare le Caserme Rosse.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]E cosi fece. Fu introdotta attraverso le porte principali nel momento in cui fu vista muoversi furtivamente sotto una finestra. Lei protestò, finse di non sapere, combattè, ma fu portata davanti a una donna che si avvolgeva le mani in una benda. Sebill raggelò; lei. Alexis guardò a Sebill con un ghigno sul viso.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Padrona, la abbiamo trovata a ficcare il naso. Sembrava-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Non mi interessa. Vieni. Porta anche lei." Lei si voltò e camminò con la sua mano bendata, sempre più rossa, al suo fianco.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Portala qui."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill fu gettata sul pavimento in una piccola stanza senza finestre. La luce dell'altra stanza illuminava da dietro di lei un'uomo incatenato alla parete. Sebill saltò in piedi, ma rimase colpita quando lo vide.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ain! Oh!" urlò e corse da lui. Lui la fissò senza riconoscerla e le sue labbra tremavano con borbottii senza senso. Alexis entrò nella stanza e guardò con disprezzo mentre Sebill cercava di convincere Ain a guardarla. Ain rimase pietrificato da Alexis. Improvvisamente uno sguardo di impazienza apparì sul suo volto e notò Sebill per la prima volta.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ain! Sono io, caro!" Scosse Ain sfregandogli le guance con isteria crescente. Lei spalancò gli occhi, per la paura e la speranza, quando Ain la guardò. In lui vide la ferocia mischiata con la sua impazienza di compiacere. Due paia di occhi con due diverse emozioni si guardavano attraverso la voragine delle loro vite spezzate. Ain poi guardò ad Alexis, che rimase ferma ad osservare sulla porta. Era felice, stanotte aveva qualcosa di interessante da dare alla nuova recluta. Stava perdendo interesse nel lanciare guardie insoddisfacenti a quelle cose.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill era vicina al piangere, provò futilmente a trovare suo marito in quell'uomo. Ain, tuttavia, gioiva dell'attenzione della regina. Sebill era troppo confusa per reagire quando Ain l'afferrò per la gola e la strangolò. Ci fu scarsa resistenza da parte di lei mentre il sangue di Alexis bruciava dentro di lui. L'essenza vitale della moglie svanì e Ain guardò  la sua regina per un segno di incoraggiamento</Italian>
		<Spanish>The library's majesty would be a thing of legend. Sebill's view from the fifth floor spanned from the northern slums out to Nubia's western wall and beyond that to where the countryside was trampled underfoot by mountains. Moving a crate of books, new acquisitions from the latest campaigns, she broke her gaze from the window. She was at odds with herself; technically, she'd achieved her goal and become a chief librarian at the world's greatest library. It was what she had promised her childhood friends she'd do, then they in turn would dream up something they thought was even more fantastic. Yet here she was. Slaving. Forced into her wishes' fulfillment by ravenous men under a new moon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Her town was alight with burning houses as she woke to the screams. She shook her husband awake, scrambled for her weapon, and used it on the first blood-drenched man who burst into the bedroom. His comrades behind him overpowered her. All she could remember feeling at that moment was insult at the fact that they showed no desire to kill her. Instead, one man constrained her on the bed while they dragged her husband outside. She shrieked and swung her fists, until an attacker brought a torch into the room. In the light the men saw the bedroom and its bookshelf-lined walls. Their faces flushed with joy and they shouted congratulations to each other. That was when they knocked her unconscious.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]...there's no noise what's going on? I'm deaf no I'm dead oh good there's noise the chains oh damn me the chains. How dare they keep me down here what did they do to her the next time one of them comes down here I'll wrap these chains around him... Where is everybody I'm alone I'm alone they'll never come for me I'll die here what have they done with her I'll starve here if my heart doesn't explode first I just want to tear them to pieces! Can't stop shaking the walls are too noisy I can't hear myself how can I... Huh? They're coming those are footsteps I'll kill them and I'll get out and find her oh I'll never see her again... One footsteps two feet could it be her they don't sound hard... oh my angel what if it's her she's come to kill me oh my angel it is her![\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill hadn't seen her husband since. And now there she was, the woman she'd always wanted to be. Only the library wasn't what she'd hoped for. It was supposed to be a paragon of learning, open to all, with a collection spanning history and all of Erebus. This was a perversion, a library of spoils, built on the sudden whim of that monstrous queen Alexis to actually know something about the people she and her brother were slaughtering. And she'd let Flauros build it! It was a wonder he had any slaves left over to clean up the blood of those who built it. Sebill was horrified to hear that Alexis had been the one to finally build Erebus's greatest library, now known as the Library of Alexis. Sebill never wanted anything to do with it, but now she was its chief archivist. It was more of a wound than a title. Still, she had books. She passed the time by imagining that the library had been built by someone else: perhaps in the Kuriotate lands it would be a bridge across race and politics; in Amurite lands its knowledge would be treated with proper respect.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Books, protected by sturdy leather covers, were durable and could last ages if properly cared for. But books in Erebus were only as permanent as societies allowed. Warring nations expunged conquered peoples' libraries with the rest of their culture. The Age of Ice preserved the previous ages' treasures well, as long as firewood was more plentiful than books. The real damage came with the destruction of literate societies who knew the value of old histories and treatises. Still, Sebill thought, maybe Alexis's collection will serve some good in the long run. Perhaps Sebill's dreams were not totally lost. Spending her days cataloging family histories, journals, folktales, scientific works, philosophies, and everything else brought in from homes and palace libraries gave her faith that one day this could be shared with the world.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She unloaded the books onto the table-They were her books. She stared at them, telling herself that this was inevitable, and yet she was holding the books that belonged to her and her former neighbors. She tried to detach herself, but opening the covers felt like tearing new flesh off wounds. "Is this the last I'll ever see of my life?" she despaired. One book confirmed that it would be: a ledger, a report of the raid on her town.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]it's her it's her she came for me she sees me she'll kill me I have to kill her I'm scared I hate her I hate those men that's a sharp knife I'm going to die I should die I'm worthless I'm afraid hate hate them her skin cuts so fine[\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Come on you. Drink up."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]blood! she's bleeding I can taste it already these chains hurt I want her to notice me let me go I must taste her fingers the cut is so sharp I can feel the cut on my tongue I'm okay I'll be okay she loves me I'm home I'm hers her hand is so soft it could tear me to pieces I want her to she can have me all in little bits she'll protect me my angel my angel I'll climb under her shadow her dress I'll be engulfed in her darkness her peaceful darkness she'll hold me and I'll be okay I'll be hers I'll be nothing in her abyss she loves me she will always protect me...[\BOLD][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sneaking out was unnecessary. Sebill doubted it was because they trusted her; perhaps they were certain they could find her if she ran off. The masters ignored other slaves, but had to address her because of the role they gave her. Eye contact was rare, but they had an odd way of acknowledging her presence by letting her know they were smelling her. Tonight she was betting they wouldn't find her quickly enough.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The ledger had listed the spoils, the "acquisitions." House #6 Contents. Books: 156. Woman: Educated: For especial use, she read. Man: Drunk, superior physical condition: For conscription in Red Barracks. Weapons only other items of value. She knew of the so-called "Red Barracks." Other librarians spoke fearfully, sorrowfully, of their loved ones sent there.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]She agonized during the following nights. After her life had been destroyed her only possible comfort was having all the world's books and time enough at last to read. Now that had become her hell. The only truth she wanted was outside the library. She had to find the Red Barracks.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And she did. She was ushered right in through the front doors the moment she was spotted sneaking underneath a window. She protested, feigned ignorance, fought, but was pulled before a woman wrapping her hand in a bandage. Sebill froze; her. Alexis looked at Sebill with a sneer.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Mistress, we found her snooping. She looks like-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I don't care what she is. Come. Bring her." She turned and walked with her saturating, scarlet-bandaged hand at her side.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Bring her in here."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill was thrown to the floor in a small, windowless room. The light from the room outside shone past her, and onto a man chained to the wall. Sebill bounced to her feet, but was stunned when she saw him.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ain! Oh!" she shouted and ran to him. He stared at her without recognition and his lips trembled with senseless mutterings. Alexis entered the room and watched with contempt as Sebill tried to get Ain to look at her. Ain was transfixed by Alexis. Suddenly a look of eagerness showed on his face and he noticed Sebill for the first time.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ain! It's me, dear!" She shook Ain and rubbed his cheeks in growing hysteria. Her eyes widened in both fear and hope when Ain looked at her. In him she saw savagery mixed with his eagerness to please. Four eyes with four different emotions looked at each other across the chasm of their broken lives. Ain then looked to Alexis, who remained still and observant in the doorway. She was glad-tonight she had something interesting to give the new recruit. She was losing interest in tossing unsatisfactory guards to these things.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Sebill, nearly sobbing, tried futilely to find her husband in this man. Ain, however, flourished in the queen's attention. Sebill was too confused to react when Ain grabbed her throat and throttled her. He found little resistance from her body as Alexis's blood burned inside him. His wife's essence slipped away and Ain looked to his queen for affirmation.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_LIGHTHOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Pharos was a marble watchtower and lighthouse estimated to be 300 feet high, the primary function of the lighthouse was to guide approaching ships to the harbor on an otherwise unmarked coast. Some civilizations burned fires on the top of the tower and some used mirrors to reflect sunlight. Since ships rarely sailed along coasts at night, there was little need for the lighthouse after dark.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le Grand Phare était une tour de guet et un phare en marbre d'une hauteur estimée de 90 mètres, la fonction principale du phare était de guider les navires en approche vers le port le long du côte sans point de repère. Certaines civilisations firent brûler des feux au sommet de la tour et d'autres utilisèrent des miroirs pour refléter la lumière du soleil. Comme les bateaux naviguaient rarement de nuit le long des côtes, il était peu utilisé après la tombée de la nuit.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Der Pharos war ein marmorner Aussichts- und Leuchtturm, schätzungsweise 100 m hoch. Seine Hauptfunktion bestand darin, an einer Küste ohne andere markante Orientierungspunkte Schiffe sicher in den Hafen zu führen. Einige Zivilisationen unterhielten ein Feuer in der Turmspitze, andere benutzten Spiegel, um das Sonnenlicht zu reflektieren. Da sich Schiffe normalerweise nachts nicht in die Nähe der Küsten wagten, bestand kaum Notwendigkeit für einen Leuchtturm nach Einbruch der Dunkelheit.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il Grande Faro era una torre di guardia, oltre a un faro, di marmo di un'altezza stimata di 90 metri, la sua funzione primaria era quella di guidare le navi in arrivo al porto su una costa altrimenti senza segnalazioni. Qualche civiltà accendeva dei fuochi sulle torri e altre usavano degli specchi per riflettere la luce del sole. Siccome le navi raramente navigavano sotto costa di notte, c'era poco bisogno del faro dopo il tramonto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El Gran Faro fue una inestimable torre de vigilancia y un faro que se estima tenía 90 metros de altura. Su función principal era guiar a los barcos cercanos al puerto por una costa que estaría de lo contrario sin marcar. Algunas civilizaciones hacían hogueras en lo alto de la torre y algunas otras reflejaban la luz del sol con espejos. Normalmente los barcos no navegaban por las costas por la noche, así que había poca necesidad de un faro de noche.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GUILD_OF_HAMMERS</Tag>
		<English>Guild of Smiths</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Guilde des Marteleurs</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Hallen der Architektur</German>
		<Italian>Gilda dei Fabbri</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gremio de Herreros</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GUILD_OF_HAMMERS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Guild of Smiths is a beautiful and ornate structure, built of stone and marble, and topped by a golden dome measuring over 100 feet in diameter. An extremely difficult engineering challenge, the dome has collapsed several times during its existence. Four graceful towers stand at the corners of the building. The interior of the building is a marvelous space of columns and arches extending up to the dome, which appears almost to float atop the building. The interior is sheathed in colored marble and golden mosaics depicting legendary scenes and images of kings.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The Guild of Smiths is a beautiful and ornate structure, built of stone and marble, and topped by a golden dome measuring over 100 feet in diameter. An extremely difficult engineering challenge, the dome has collapsed several times during its existence. Four graceful towers stand at the corners of the building. The interior of the building is a marvelous space of columns and arches extending up to the dome, which appears almost to float atop the building. The interior is sheathed in colored marble and golden mosaics depicting legendary scenes and images of kings.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Hallen der Architektur sind eine herrliche, reich geschmückte Anlage aus Stein und Marmor. Sie wird von einer goldenen Kuppel gekrönt, die über 30 m Durchmesser hat – eine sehr schwierige Konstruktion für die Ingenieure. Schon mehrfach ist die Kuppel in sich zusammengebrochen. Vier anmutige Türme zieren die Ecken des Gebäudes. Das Innere besteht aus einer phantastischen Halle mit Säulen und Bögen, die sich bis in die wie schwerelos darüber schwebende Kuppel hinauf schwingen. Die Wände sind mit farbigem Marmor ausgekleidet und goldene Mosaike zeigen legendäre Szenen und Bilder der Könige.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La Gilda dei Fabbri è una bellissima struttura decorata, costruita con pietra e marmo, e sormontata da una cupola dorata di oltre 30 metri di diamentro. Un'impresa ingegnieristica estremamente difficile, la cupola collassò diverse volte nella sua esistenza. Ci sono quattro torri in corrispondenza degli angoli dell'edificio. All'interno si trovano fantastiche colonne e archi che arrivano sino alla cupola, che sembra come se fluttuase sopra l'edificio. L'interno è rivestito di marmo colorato e mosaici dorati raffiguranti scene leggendarie e immagini di re.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Guild of Smiths is a beautiful and ornate structure, built of stone and marble, and topped by a golden dome measuring over 100 feet in diameter. An extremely difficult engineering challenge, the dome has collapsed several times during its existence. Four graceful towers stand at the corners of the building. The interior of the building is a marvelous space of columns and arches extending up to the dome, which appears almost to float atop the building. The interior is sheathed in colored marble and golden mosaics depicting legendary scenes and images of kings.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GUILD_OF_THE_NINE</Tag>
		<English>Guild of the Nine</English>
		<French>Guilde des Neuf</French>
		<German>Gilde der Neun</German>
		<Italian>Gilda dei Nove</Italian>
		<Spanish>Guild of the Nine</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRAND_MENAGERIE</Tag>
		<English>Grand Menagerie</English>
		<French>Grande Ménagerie</French>
		<German>Große Menagerie</German>
		<Italian>Gran Serraglio</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gran Zoológico</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRAND_MENAGERIE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Grand Menagerie can only be built if a player has created an animal pen of every type in the city.</English>
		<French>[TAB] La Grande Ménagerie ne peut être créée que si un joueur a créé une cage pour chaque type d'animal dans la ville.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Große Menagerie kann nur von Spielern gebaut werden die einen Tierkäfig von jedem Typ in der Stadt gebaut haben.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il Gran Serraglio può essere costruito solo dopo che il giocatore ha creato una gabbia per ogni tipo di animale nella città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El Gran Zoológico sólo puede ser construido por el jugador que haya creado un corral de todas las clases de animales en la ciudad.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HALL_OF_KINGS</Tag>
		<English>Hall of Kings</English>
		<French>Salle des Rois</French>
		<German>Ruhmeshalle der Könige</German>
		<Italian>Sala dei Re</Italian>
		<Spanish>Salón de los Reyes</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HALL_OF_KINGS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The beauty of the Hall of Kings has long served as a testament to the mixture of strong religious beliefs and the love of art shared by the people of the Age of Rebirth. Few visitors to the Hall of Kings have failed to be moved by the artist's dedication to his subject, or his feeling for the nature of human struggle, suffering, and spiritual triumph.</English>
		<French>La beauté de la Salle des Rois a servi durant longtemps de testament pour la mixture des fortes convictions religieuses et de l'amour de l'art partagé par les gens de l'Âge de Renaissance. Peu de visiteurs de la Salle des Rois ont manqué d'être transportés par le dévouement de l'artiste envers son sujet, ou son sentiment pour la nature de la lutte humaine, de la souffrance et du triomphe spirituel.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Schönheit der Ruhmeshalle der Könige gilt seit langem als Beweis für die Verbindung von starker Religiosität und Kunstsinnigkeit bei den Menschen des Zeitalters der Wiedergeburt. Nur wenige Besucher der Ruhmeshalle der Könige konnten sich der Hingabe des Künstlers an seine Darstellungen, bzw. seinem Gespür für die menschlichen Anstrengungen, das Leiden und den Triumph des Geistes entziehen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La bellezza della Sala dei Re è servita a lungo come testamento del miscuglio di forti credenze religiose e amore per l'arte, condivise dalle persone nell'Era della Rinascita. Pochi visitatori della Sala dei Re non sono rimasti commossi dalla dedizione degli artisti per le loro opere, o per il sentimento di conflitto, sofferenza, e trionfo spirituale umano.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]La belleza del Salón de los Reyes ha servido durante mucho como testamento de la combinación entre la fuerte convicción religiosa y el amor al arte de las gentes de la Edad del Renacimiento. Son pocos los visitantes del Salón de los Reyes los que no han sido atrapados por la dedicación del artista a su obra, o su sentimiento de la naturaleza de la fuerza, el sufrimiento y el triunfo espiritual del ser humano.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEROIC_EPIC</Tag><!-- overwrites vanilla tag because of French typos -->
		<English>Heroic Epic</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Épop&#233;e h&#233;ro&#239;que</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Heldenepos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Poema epico</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>la Epopeya heroica:las Epopeyas heroicas</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEROIC_EPIC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Be they from the Age of Ice, the Age of Magic, or all the way back to the Age of Dragons, these stories are about men that became legends. They encourage all that hear them, and make their hearers strive to be more than they currently are.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Qu'elles datent de l'Âge de Glace, de l'Âge de la Magie ou encore plus loin de l'Âge des Dragons, ces histoires parlent d'hommes qui sont devenus des légendes.  Elles encouragent ceux qui les écoutent et les motive à se surpasser.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Seien sie aus dem Zeitalter des Eises, dem Zeitalter der Magie, oder gar aus dem Zeitalter der Drachen, diese Geschichten handeln von Männern, die zu Legenden geworden sind. Sie ermutigen alle, die sie hören, und regen die Hörer an, danach zu eifern, mehr zu sein als im Augenblick.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Che siano dall'Era del Ghiaccio, dall'Era della Magia, o addirittura dalla lontana Era dei Draghi, queste storie parlano di uomini che divennerò leggende. Esse incoraggiano tutti coloro che le sentono, e spingono coloro che le ascoltano a migliorare se stessi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Ya sean de la Edad de Hielo, la Edad de la Magia, o de tiempo atrás hasta la Edad de los Dragones, estas historias cuentan como unos hombres o mujeres se convirtieron en leyenda. Llenan de valentía a todo aquel que las lea, y hace que sus oyentes aspiren a ser algo más grande de lo que ya son.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEROIC_EPIC_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Heroic Epic[COLOR_REVERT] doubles its city's production when creating military units. This is useful if you expect to do a lot of fighting. It also increases its cities chances of generating a [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Great Commander[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<French>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]L'Épopée Héroïque[COLOR_REVERT] double la production d'unités militaires. C'est très utile si vous vous attendez à beaucoup de combat. Elle augmente aussi la probabilité que la ville génère un [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Commandant Illustre[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Der [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Heldenepos[COLOR_REVERT] verdoppelt die Produktion von Militäreinheiten in der Stadt. Dies ist überaus nützlich, wenn man viele Schlachten schlägt. Außerdem erhöht das Gebäude die Wahrscheinlichkeit für einen [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Genialen Feldherrn[COLOR_REVERT]</German>
		<Italian>Il [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Poema Epico[COLOR_REVERT] raddoppia la produzione della città quando si creano unità militari. Questo è molto utile se ti aspetti di dover combattere un sacco. Aumenta inoltre le probabilità per la città di generare un [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Grande Comandante[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>La [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Epopeya Heróica[COLOR_REVERT] dobla la producción de unidades militares de una ciudad. Esto es muy útil si se espera muchos combates. También incrementa las probabilidades de que la ciudad genere un [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Gran Comandante[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HERON_THRONE</Tag>
		<English>Heron Throne</English>
		<French>Trône des Hérons</French>
		<German>Herons Thron</German>
		<Italian>Trono dell'Airone</Italian>
		<Spanish>Heron Throne</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MASTERS_HALL</Tag>
		<English>Masters Hall</English>
		<French>Hall des Maîtres</French>
		<German>Halle der Meister</German>
		<Italian>Sala dei Maestri</Italian>
		<Spanish>Masters Hall</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MASTERS_HALL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Gathering place for the best craftsman of Erebus.  Can significantly increase the productivity of a city, and would increase it more should someone hide the ale.</English>
		<French>Lieu de regroupement pour les meilleurs artisans d'Erebus. Accroît considérablement la productivité d'une ville, et le ferait encore plus si quelqu'un se décidait à confisquer la bière.</French>
		<German>Versammlungsplatz für die besten Handwerker auf Erebus.  Kann die Produktion einer Stadt signifikant steigern - und würde sie weiter steigern, sofern jemand das Bier versteckt.</German>
		<Italian>Luogo di ritrovo per i migliori artigiani di Erebus. Può incrementare significativamente la produttività di una città, e l'aumenterebbe ancora di più se qualcuno nascondesse la birra.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gathering place for the best craftsman of Erebus.  Can significantly increase the productivity of a city, and would increase it more should someone hide the ale.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MERCURIAN_GATE</Tag>
		<English>Mercurian Gate</English>
		<French>Portail Mercurien</French>
		<German>Tor der Mercurians</German>
		<Italian>Portale dei Mercurian</Italian>
		<Spanish>Portal Mercurian</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MERCURIAN_GATE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Once the Mercurian Gate is completed the Mercurians will enter the world and join the side of whoever built the gate. The builder will have to give the city where the gate is built to the Mercurians.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Mercurians are angels, but angels with only one purpose, to destroy the legions of hell. They care little for the means required to achieve that end, and will battle as loyally beside the cruel Calabim as they will the compassionate Elohim, as long as the Infernal remains their common enemy.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Player that builds this wonder will have the option of abandoning control of his civilization and taking control of the Mercurians instead. It can not be built in a capital city.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le Portail Mercurien peut seulement être construit après que les Infernaux sont entrés dans le monde. Une fois terminé, les Mercuriens viendront sur terre et rejoindront le camp de celui qui a construit le portail. Le constructeur devra donner aux Mercuriens la ville où le portail a été construit.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les Mercuriens sont des anges, mais des anges qui n'ont qu'un seul objectif : détruire les légions de l'Enfer. Ils se moquent bien des moyens pour arriver à leur fin, et ils combattront loyalement aussi bien aux cotés des cruels Calabims comme aux cotés des compatissants Elohims, aussi longtemps que les Infernaux restent leur ennemi commun.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le joueur qui construit cette merveille aura l'option d'abandonner le contrôle de sa civilisation et prendre à la place le contrôle des Mercuriens. Il ne peut pas être construit dans une capitale.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Das Tor der Mercurians kann erst gebaut werden, wenn die Infernalischen  diese Welt betreten haben. Wenn es vollendet ist, werden Mercurians in unsere Welt kommen und an dessen Seite kämpfen, der das Tor erbaut hat. Die Stadt, in der es erbaut wurden, muss den Mercurians übergeben werden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Mercurians sind Engel mit nur einer einzigen Aufgabe: die Ausgeburten der Hölle zu zerstören. Sie kümmern sich kaum darum, mit welchen Mitteln sie das erreichen können und kämpfen loyal mit den grausamen Calabim wie auch mit den mitfühlenden Elohim, solange nur die Infernalischen deren Feinde sind.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Spieler, der dieses Wunder errichtet, kann seine Zivilisation aufgeben und statt dessen die Kontrolle über die Mercurians übernehmen. Das Tor kann nicht in der Hauptstadt gebaut werden.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Una volta che il Portale dei Mercurian è stato costruito i Mercurian entreranno nel mondo e si uniranno alla squadra di chi ha costruito il portale. Chi lo costruisce dovrà cedere la città, in cui è presente il portale, ai Mercurian.[PARAGRAPH:1]I Mercurian sono angeli, con un solo scopo, distruggere le legioni dell'inferno. Si preoccupano poco dei mezzi necessari a raggiungere tale fine, e combatteranno fedelmente al fianco dei crudeli Calabim come dei compassionevoli Elohim, almeno fino a quando gli Infernali rimangono il loro nemico comune.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il giocatore che costruisce questa meraviglia potrà perdere il controllo della sua civiltà iniziale e prendere il controllo dei Mercurian. Non può esere costruita in una città capitale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El Portal Mercurian sólo puede ser construido una vez que los Infernales hayan entrado en el mundo.  Una vez completado, los Mercurians entraran en el mundo y se unirán al bando del que construyó el portal.  El constructor tendrá que entregar la ciudad donde fue construido el portal a los Mercurians.[PARAGRAPH:1]Los Mercurians son ángeles, pero ángeles con un solo propósito: destruir a las legiones del infierno.  Les importa bien poco los métodos utilizados para alcanzar ese fin, y combatirán, tanto como si son leales a los crueles Calabim o a los compasivos Elohimand, siempre y cuando los Infernales sean su común enemigo.[PARAGRAPH:1]El jugador que construya esta maravilla tendrá la opción de abandonar el control de su civilización y tomar el control de los Mercurians. No puede ser construida en una capital.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MERCURIAN_GATE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Building this will spawn the Mercurian civilization. They will take control of the city the gate is built in, but they will join your team.</English>
		<French>Construire ceci génèrera la civilisation Mercurienne. Ils prendront le contrôle de la ville où le portail est construit, mais il rejoindront votre équipe.</French>
		<German>Dieses Gebäude entlässt die Mercurian Zivilisation in unsere Welt. Sie werden zwar die Kontrolle über die Stadt mit dem Tor der Mercurians übernehmen, aber sie werden auch zu deinem Verbundeten.</German>
		<Italian>Costruire il Portale creerà la civiltà Mercurian. Prenderanno il controllo della città in cui il Portale viene costruito, ma si uniranno alla squadra di chi lo ha costruito.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Construir esto hará aparecer a la civilización Mercurian.  Tomarán el control de la ciudad en la que se ha construido el portal, pero se unirán al equipo del jugador que lo haga.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MERCURIAN_GATE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Building this will spawn the Mercurian civilization. They will take control of the city the gate is built in, but they will join your team.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Construire ceci génèrera la civilisation Mercurienne. Ils prendront le contrôle de la ville où le portail est construit, mais il rejoindront votre équipe.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Dieses Gebäude entlässt die Mercurian Zivilisation in unsere Welt. Sie werden zwar die Kontrolle über die Stadt mit dem Tor der Mercurians übernehmen, aber sie werden auch zu deinem Verbundeten.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Costruire il Portale creerà la civiltà Mercurian. Prenderanno il controllo della città in cui il Portale viene costruito, ma si uniranno alla squadra di chi lo ha costruito.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Construir esto hará aparecer a la civilización Mercurian.  Tomarán el control de la ciudad en la que se ha construido el portal, pero se unirán al equipo del jugador que lo haga.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MINES_OF_GALDUR</Tag>
		<English>Mines of Gal-Dur</English>
		<French>Mines de Gal-Dur</French>
		<German>Minen von Gal-Dur</German>
		<Italian>Miniere di Gal-Dur</Italian>
		<Spanish>Minas de Gal-Dur</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOKKAS_CAULDRON</Tag>
		<English>Mokka's Cauldron</English>
		<French>Chaudron de Mokka</French>
		<German>Mokkas Kessel der Untoten</German>
		<Italian>Calderone di Mokka</Italian>
		<Spanish>Caldero de Mokka</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOKKAS_CAULDRON_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Raises units that die in the city as demons</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Raises units that die in the city as demons</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Belebt Einheiten, die in der Stadt sterben, als Humunkuli wieder.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Rianima le unità morte in città come demoni</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Raises units that die in the city as demons</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOKKAS_CAULDRON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Frostlings were horrid creatures, all avarice and teeth, but weak unless they came in large numbers. Unable to survive the warmth of the Age of Rebirth they have disappeared from Erebus, and exist only in stories.[PARAGRAPH:1]One of those stories is about an unusually intelligent frostling named Mokka. He was said to carry a bag where he collected the breath of dying men and have a cauldron that would resurrect anyone who was placed in it. [PARAGRAPH:1]Legends are often incomplete and this cauldron is no different. Bodies placed in it do come back to life, but that life is unnatural.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Frostlings were horrid creatures, all avarice and teeth, but weak unless they came in large numbers. Unable to survive the warmth of the Age of Rebirth they have disappeared from Erebus, and exist only in stories.[PARAGRAPH:1]One of those stories is about an unusually intelligent frostling named Mokka. He was said to carry a bag where he collected the breath of dying men and have a cauldron that would resurrect anyone who was placed in it. [PARAGRAPH:1]Legends are often incomplete and this cauldron is no different. Bodies placed in it do come back to life, but that life is unnatural.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Frostlings were horrid creatures, all avarice and teeth, but weak unless they came in large numbers. Unable to survive the warmth of the Age of Rebirth they have disappeared from Erebus, and exist only in stories.[PARAGRAPH:1]One of those stories is about an unusually intelligent frostling named Mokka. He was said to carry a bag where he collected the breath of dying men and have a cauldron that would resurrect anyone who was placed in it. [PARAGRAPH:1]Legends are often incomplete and this cauldron is no different. Bodies placed in it do come back to life, but that life is unnatural.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]I Frostlings erano odiose creature, solo avidità e denti, ma deboli se non in gran numero. Incapaci di sopravvivere al caldo dell'Era della Rinascita sono scomparsi da Erebus, e esistono solo nelle storie.[PARAGRAPH:1]Una di queste storie riguarda un frostling insolitamente intelligente chiamato Mokka. Si racconta che portava con se una borsa dove raccoglieva il respiro degli uomini morenti e che aveva un calderone che avrebbe resuscitato chiunque ci veniva messo dentro. [PARAGRAPH:1]Le leggende sono spesso incomplete e questo calderone non fa differenza. I corpi messi dentro tornano in vita, ma con una vita innaturale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Frostlings were horrid creatures, all avarice and teeth, but weak unless they came in large numbers. Unable to survive the warmth of the Age of Rebirth they have disappeared from Erebus, and exist only in stories.[PARAGRAPH:1]One of those stories is about an unusually intelligent frostling named Mokka. He was said to carry a bag where he collected the breath of dying men and have a cauldron that would resurrect anyone who was placed in it. [PARAGRAPH:1]Legends are often incomplete and this cauldron is no different. Bodies placed in it do come back to life, but that life is unnatural.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOKKAS_CAULDRON_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Raises units that die in the city as demons.</English>
		<French>Raises units that die in the city as demons.</French>
		<German>Raises units that die in the city as demons.</German>
		<Italian>Rianima le unità morte in città come demoni</Italian>
		<Spanish>Raises units that die in the city as demons.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_EPIC</Tag><!-- overwrites vanilla tag because of French typos -->
		<English>National Epic</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Épop&#233;e nationale</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Nationalepos</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Poema patriottico</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>la Epopeya nacional:las Epopeyas nacionales</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_EPIC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]An "epic" is a heroic poem celebrating the life and achievements of a heroic individual or group. A "national epic" celebrates the exploits of an entire country.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Une "épopée" est un poème héroïque célébrant la vie et les exploits d'un individu ou d'un groupe.  Une "épopée nationale" célèbre les exploits d'un pays entier.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Ein Epos ist ein Gedicht, dass das Leben und die Taten eines Helden, oder gleich einer ganzen Gruppe, beschreibt. Ein National-Epos beschreibt die Heldentaten einer ganzen Nation.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Un Poema celebrà la vita e i successi di un eroico individuo o di un gruppo di eroi. Un Poema Patriottico celebra le gesta di un'intera nazione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Una "epopeya" es un poema heróico que cuanta la vida y los logros de un héroe o un grupo de héroes.  Una "epopeya nacional" cuenta los logros de una nación entera.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_EPIC_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]National Epic[COLOR_REVERT] greatly increases the rate at which its city produces [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Great People[COLOR_REVERT], particularly [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Great Commanders[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<French>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]L'Épopée Nationale[COLOR_REVERT] augmente grandement la vitesse à laquelle la ville produit des [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Personnages Illustres[COLOR_REVERT], particulièrement des [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Commandants Illustres[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Das [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Nationalepos[COLOR_REVERT]steigert die Chance enorm, dass die Stadt [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Grosse Persönlichkeiten[COLOR_REVERT], insbesondere [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Geniale Feldherren[COLOR_REVERT]hervorbringt.</German>
		<Italian>Il [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Poema Patriottico[COLOR_REVERT] aumenta notevolmente il tasso a cui la città produce [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Grandi Personaggi[COLOR_REVERT], particolarmente [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Grandi Comandanti[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>La [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Epopeya Nacional[COLOR_REVERT] incrementa enormemente el índice en que la ciudad produce [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Grandes Personajes[COLOR_REVERT], en particular [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Grandes Comandantes[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NOX_NOCTIS</Tag>
		<English>Nox Noctis</English>
		<French>Nox Noctis</French>
		<German>Die Nacht der Nächte</German>
		<Italian>Nox Noctis</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nox Noctis</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NOX_NOCTIS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Nox Noctis makes all of your units invisible as long as they are in your lands and not in a city. Invisible units never defend but can attack enemy stacks.</English>
		<French>Nox Noctis makes all of your units invisible as long as they are in your lands and not in a city. Invisible units never defend but can attack enemy stacks.</French>
		<German>Die Nacht der Nächte macht alle deine Einheiten unsichtbar, solange sie sich in eurem Land bewegen und nicht in einer Stadt. Unsichtbare Einheiten können sich nicht verteidigen, aber feindliche Truppenverbände angreifen.</German>
		<Italian>Il Nox Noctis rende tutte le tue unità invisibili fino a quando rimangono nei tuoi territori e non dentro una città. Le unità invisibili non si difendono quando un unità nemica si sposta nella stessa casella, ma possono attaccare i gruppi nemici.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nox Noctis makes all of your units invisible as long as they are in your lands and not in a city. Invisible units never defend but can attack enemy stacks.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PACT_OF_THE_NILHORN</Tag>
		<English>Pact of the Nilhorn</English>
		<French>Pacte de Nilhorn</French>
		<German>Pakt mit den Nilhorn</German>
		<Italian>Patto dei Nilhorn</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pacto de los Nilhorn</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PACT_OF_THE_NILHORN_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Three allied [LINK=UNIT_HILL_GIANT]Hill Giants[\LINK] will appear in the building civilization's city</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Trois [LINK=UNIT_HILL_GIANT]Géants des Collines[\LINK] alliés apparaîtront dans la ville de la civilisation construisant cette merveille.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Drei verbündete [LINK=UNIT_HILL_GIANT]Hügelriesen[\LINK] erscheinen in der Stadt.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Tre [LINK=UNIT_HILL_GIANT]Giganti delle Colline[\LINK] alleati appariranno nella città dell'edificio</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Tres [LINK=UNIT_HILL_GIANT]gigantes de las colinas[\LINK] aliados aparecerán en la ciudad de la civilización que lo construya.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PACT_OF_THE_NILHORN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Early explorers found it was best to avoid the massive giants that roamed the land.  A bard, named Antonis of Oriel, wandered too close and was captured by a group called the Nilhorn.  He offered the only gift he could for his life, he played a song.  The wild giants were so entranced by his song that, when it ended, they sat unmoving and Antonis could have simply walked out of the makeshift camp they had dragged him back to.  Fascinated by finding his new audience so appreciative, Antonis continued to play, and his performances became a part of the giants' nightly rituals.[PARAGRAPH:1]Antonis stayed with the Nilhorn for 3 years, until one of them reported seeing a Sheaim army approaching his homeland.  The giants avoided any settled land and tried to convince Antonis not to return, but he left the giants and returned to defend Oriel.  Although a talented musician, Antonis was an incompetent warrior and he was killed defending Oriel.  When he fell, the Nilhorn came out of the forests and approached the besieged village.  Both armies froze, unaccustomed to seeing giants willing to enter civilized lands.  Searching the battlefield, the giants found Antonis's body, and, enraged, they set upon the Sheaim.  The village defenders cheered at their new-found allies and joined in the assault.[PARAGRAPH:1]The battle was quick and the Sheaim were turned back.  After it was over, the giants picked up the body of Antonis and carried it with them into the forests.  The village raised a monument to their large rescuers and swore never to forget the aid they were given.  The Sheaim never forgot the failed battle either, and forever avoided Oriel in their attacks.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Les premiers explorateurs savaient bien qu'il vaut mieux éviter les massifs géants qui errent dans les terres sauvages. Un barde, appelé Antonis d'Oriel, erra trop près et fut capturé par un groupe appelé le Nilhorn. Il offrit le seul présent qu'il put pour sa vie : il joua une chanson. Les sauvages géants furent si enchantés par cette chanson, que lorsqu'elle prit fin, ils restèrent assis et Antonis put simplement sortir du campement de fortune où ils l'eurent traîné. Fasciné de voir son nouveau public si appréciatif, Antonis continua de jouer, et ses prestations devinrent une partie des rituel nocturnes des géants.[PARAGRAPH:1]Antonis resta avec le Nilhorn durant trois ans, jusqu'à ce que l'un d'eux lui rapporta qu'une armée sheaïm approchait sa terre natale. Les géants évitaient les terres colonisées et tentèrent de le convaincre de ne pas s'en retourner, mais il laissa les géants et retourna défendre Oriel. Bien que musicien talentueux, Antonis était un guerrier incompétent et il fut tué en défendant Oriel. Lorsqu'il chut, le Nilhorn sortit des bois et approcha le village assiégé. Les deux armées se figèrent, inaccoutumées de voir des géants voulant entrer en des lieux civilisés. Cherchant sur le champ de bataille, les géants trouvèrent la dépouille d'Antonis, et, enragé, assaillirent les Sheaïms. Les défenseurs du village acclamèrent leur nouveaux alliés et se joignirent à l'assaut.[PARAGRAPH:1]La bataille fut brève et les Sheaïms s'en retournèrent. Après cela, les géants ramassèrent le corps d'Antonis et le portèrent avec eux dans la forêt. Le village érigea un monument en l'honneur de le grand sauveurs et jurèrent de ne jamais oublier l'aide qu'ils leur portèrent. Les Sheaïms n'oublièrent jamais leur défaite, et depuis évite Oriel dans leurs attaques.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Reisende aus früherer Zeit fanden schnell heraus, dass es das Beste war, den riesigen Giganten, die die Lande durchstreiften, aus dem Wege zu gehen.. Ein Barde, mit Namen Antonis von Oriel, kam ihnen auf seinen Wanderungen zu nahe und wurde von einer Gruppe gefangen genommen, die sich die Nilhorn nannten. Er bot ihnen als Gegenleistung für sein Leben das einzige Geschenk an, das er zu bieten hatte: er spielte ein Lied. Die wilden Riesen waren so hingerissen durch sein Lied, dass sie, als es geendet hatte, nur bewegungslos da saßen, so dass Antonis einfach aus dem Behelfscamp hätte hinauslaufen können, in das sie in gebracht hatten. Erfreut, dass seine neuen Zuhörer seine Weisen so zu schätzen wussten, spielte Antonis weiter und seine Darbietungen wurden zum Bestandteil der nächtlichen Rituale der Riesen. [PARAGRAPH:1]Antonis blieb 3 weitere Jahre bei den Nilhorn, bis einer von ihnen eines Tages eine Armee der Sheaïm entdeckte, die sich seiner Heimat näherte. Da die Riesen jedes besiedelte Land mieden, versuchten sie, auch Antonis zum Bleiben zu überreden, aber er verließ die Giganten und kehrte nach Oriel zurück um es zu verteidigen. Aber auch wenn er ein talentierter Musiker gewesen war, so war er doch kein guter Krieger und er wurde vor Oriel getötet. Als er fiel kamen die Nilhorn aus ihren Wäldern und näherten sich dem Dorf. Beide Armeen erstarrten angesichts dieses ungewohnten Anblicks, Riesen, die sich zivilisiertem Land näherten. Die Riesen suchten das Schlachtfeld ab, fanden Antonins Körper und gerieten darüber in Raserei. Sie griffen die Sheaïm an. Die Verteidiger des Dorfes waren angesichts der neuen Freunde überglücklich und unterstützten den Überfall.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Schlacht war schnell geschlagen und die Sheaim wurden zurückgeworfen. Nachdem alles vorbei war, nahmen die Riesen Antonins Körper mit sich, zurück in die Wälder. Das Dorf errichtete ein Monument zu Ehren seiner Retter und schwor, die Hilfe, die ihm zuteil geworden war, nie zu vergessen. Auch die Sheaïm vergaßen diese verlorene Schlacht niemals und vermieden ab da jeden Angriff auf Oriel. </German>
		<Italian>[TAB]I primi esploratori scoprirono che era meglio evitare gli enormi giganti che vagavano in giro. Un bardo, chiamato Antonis da Oriel, si avvicino troppo e fu catturato da un gruppo chiamato i Nilhorn. Lui offrì l'unico dono che poteva per la sua vita, cantando una canzone. I giganti selvaggi rimasero cosi estasiati dalla canzone che, quando finì, rimaserò seduti immobili e Antonis avrebbe potuto tranquillamente uscire dal campo improvvisato in cui era stato trascinato. Affascinato nel trovare il suo nuovo pubblico cosi riconoscente, Antonis continuò a cantare, e il suo spettacolo divenne parte dei rituali notturni del giganti.[PARAGRAPH:1]Antonis stette con i Nilhorn per 3 anni, fino a quando uno di loro riferì di aver visto un'esercito Sheaim dirigersi verso la sua terra natia. I giganti evitavano le terre colonizzate e cercarono di convincere Antonis a non tornare a casa, ma lui li lasciò e tornò ad Oriel per difenderla. Sebbene un musicista di talento, Antonis era un guerriero incapace e fu ucciso mentre difendeva Oriel. Quando morì, i Nilhorn uscirono dalle foreste e si  avvicinarono al villaggio assediato. Entrambe gli eserciti si bloccarono, non abituati a vedere dei giganti all'interno di terre civilizzate. Cercando sul campo di battaglia, i giganti trovarono il cadavere di Antonis, e, arrabbiati, attaccarono gli Sheaim. I difensori del villaggio incoraggiarono i loro nuovi alleati e si unirono all'assalto.[PARAGRAPH:1]La battaglia fu rapida e gli Sheaim furono respinti. Quanto tutto finì, i giganti preserò il corpo di Antonis e lo portarono con loro nelle foreste. Il villaggio fece un monumento ai loro grandi soccorritori e giurarono di non dimenticare mai l'aiuto ricevuto. Neppure gli Sheaim dimenticarono mai la sconfitta subita, ed evitarono sempre Oriel nei loro attacchi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Los primeros exploradores se encontraron con que lo mejor era eludir a los gigantes que recorrían la tierra.  Un bardo, llamado Antonis de Oriel, se acerco demasiado y fue capturado por un grupo llamado los Nilhorn.  Él ofreció el único regalo que podía ofrecer a cambio de su vida, cantar una canción.  Los gigantes salvajes estaban tan encantados por la canción que, cuando terminó, se sentaron inmóviles y Antonis pudo simplemente caminar e irse del campamento al que le habían soltado.  Fascinado por encontrarse con su nueva audiencia tan apreciativa, Antonis siguió tocando, y sus canciones se convirtieron en parte de los rituales nocturnos de los gigantes.[PARAGRAPH:1]Antonis se quedó con los Nilhorn durante 3 años, hasta que uno de ellos le informó de que un ejército Sheaim se aproximaba hacia su tierra natal.  Los gigantes evitaban cualquier tierra colonizada e intentaron convencer a Antonis de que no volviera, pero dejó a los gigantes y volvió para defender Oriel.  Aunque era un músico con talento, Antonis era un guerrero inexperto y murió mientras defendía Orel.  Cuando cayó, los Nilhorn salieron de los bosques y se aproximaron a la villa asediada.  Ambos ejércitos se paralizaron, pues no estaban acostumbrados a ver gigantes entrar gritando en tierras civilizadas.  Buscando por el campo de batalla, los gigantes encontraron el cuerpo de Antonis, y entonces, se enfurecieron, y fueron a por los Sheaim.  Los defensores de la aldea aclamaron a sus nuevos aliados y se unieron en el asalto.[PARAGRAPH:1]La batalla fue rápida y los Sheaim se retiraron.  Después de acabar, los gigantes recogieron el cuerpo de Antonis y se lo llevaron hacia los bosques.  La villa levantó un monumento en honor a sus grandes rescatadores y juraron que nunca olvidarían la ayuda que les fue dada.  Por el otro lado los Sheaim nunca olvidaron su derrota, y siempre evitaron Oriel en sus ataques.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PILLAR_OF_CHAINS</Tag>
		<English>Pillar of Chains</English>
		<French>Pillier de Chaînes</French>
		<German>Säule der Qualen</German>
		<Italian>Pilastro delle Catene</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pilar de las Cadenas</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PILLAR_OF_CHAINS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The citizens marched into the city plaza picketing and demanding the liberties their neighbors possessed. They chanted and screamed at the palace as Flauros watched from his balcony. For hours they demonstrated, becoming bolder as the day went on, and more citizens joined.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Moroi stood their posts, they didn't threaten or seem aware of the horde of violent protestors before them. The citizens toppled statues in the plaza, destroyed benches and shook the palace gates and still Flauros waited.[PARAGRAPH:1]A wave of euphoria struck the crowd, they had risen up and Flauros hadn't responded. They were not powerless, they weren't afraid, Flauros was afraid of them. This thought intoxicated them, generations of the Calabim have suffered without complaint or voice, complacent in their fear. But their fear was gone now, they were a new people united against their cruel aristocracy.[PARAGRAPH:1]The sun dipped into the horizon, bathing the protestors in the reds and oranges of early night. It lengthened the shadows of the buildings until they reached out across the plaza like dark teeth on the worn granite cobblestones. For a heartbeat the angry wild cries of the protestors stopped as the shadows covered them, there was silence in the plaza. Then came the screams.[PARAGRAPH:1]In the morning, where there once was graceful statues and benches there was now a giant pillar of granite, iron and blood. Hundreds of barbed chains were woven around the tower and held fast by those chains were all those that protested the day before. Most were torn bodies ripped to pieces and hung on the chains, but a few still lived and writhed within its grasp.[PARAGRAPH:1]Flauros would often stand on his balcony and admire what he called the Rose of Prespur. With its thorns and blood stained top it almost seemed as such. Regardless of its artistic merits the people of Prespur never protested again.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Les citoyens envahissaient la place de la ville, réclamant les libertés accordées à leurs voisins. Ils scandaient et criaient vers le palais tandis que Flauros observait depuis son balcon. Ils manifestèrent pendant des heures, devenant plus intrépides à mesure que la journée avançait, et de plus en plus de civils les rejoignaient. Les Moroi maintenaient leurs positions, sans menacer ni sembler préoccupés par le horde de rebelles violents qui s'en prenait à eux. Les civils firent basculer les statues de la place, détruisirent les gradins, et secouèrent les portes du palais mais Flauros restait impassible.[PARAGRAPH:1]Une vague d'euphorie s'empara de la foule. Ils s'étaient levé et Flauros ne réagissait pas. Ils n'étaient pas impuissants, n'avaient peur de rien; Flauros avait peur d'eux. Cette pensée les grisa, des générations de Calabim avaient souffert en silence, complaisants dans leur terreur. Mais leur peur était évanouie maintenant, ils formaient un nouveau peuple uni face à son aristocratie cruelle.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le soleil baissait à l'horison, baignant les protestataires dans la lueur rouge orangée du crepuscule, allongeant les ombres des bâtiments jusqu'à ce qu'elles s'étendent au-delà de la place, telles les dents noires des pavés de granit. Le temps d'un battement de c&#156;ur, les cri sauvages des manifestants en colère s'estompèrent comme couverts par les ombres, le silence régnait sur la place. Puis les hurlements commencèrent.[PARAGRAPH:1]Au matin, un pilier de granit, de fer et de sang se tenait en lieu et place des statues et des gradins. Des centaines de barbelés encerclaient la tour et emprisonnaient ceux qui hier protestaient. La plupart n'étaient plus que des cadavres taillés en pièces et accrochés aux chaines, mais quelques uns vivaient encore et se débattaient dans ces filets.[PARAGRAPH:1]Flauros se posterait souvent au balcon pour admirer ce qu'il appelait la Rose de Prespur. Avec ses épines et ses tâches de sang au sommet, ça y ressemblait presque. En dépit de ses mérites artistiques, le peuple de Prespur de révolta jamais plus.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Bürger marschierten bis vor den Palast, während sie lautstark nach den Freiheiten verlangten, die das Volk anderer Länder genossen. Unter den Blicken von Flauros, der das Geschehen von seinem Balkon aus beobachtete, schrieen und grölten sie. Stundenlang demonstrierten sie, und mit jeder Minute wurden sie kühner und zahlreicher.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Moroi verharrten auf ihren Plätzen, sie schienen die Massen von Demonstranten nicht wahrzunehmen. Flauros rührte keinen Finger, als der wütende Mob die Statuen zu Boden warf, die Bänke zertrümmerte und die Gärten zertrampelte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Euphorie ergriff die Bürger, sie hatten sich gegen Flauros aufgelehnt, und Flauros’ Rache blieb aus. Sie waren nicht Machtlos. Sie mussteten sich nicht vor Flauros fürchten, denn Flauros fürchtete sie. Generationen von Calabim hatten stumm gelitten, ohne sich zu wehren oder zu fliehen, gefangen in ihrer Angst. Doch jetzt war ihre Angst verschwunden, jetzt waren sie vereint und würden die grausame Herrschaft stürzen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Schließlich versank die Sonne am Horizont, und die Demonstranten wurden in das sanfte Rot der beginnenden Nacht getaucht. Die Schatten der Gebäude wuchsen, lagen quer über dem Platz, wie dunkle Zähne auf den Pflastersteinen. Im Schatten stoppten die Menschen einen Herzschlag lang, Stille legte sich über die Stadt. Dann erschallten Schreie.[PARAGRAPH:1]Am nächsten Morgen hatte eine Säule aus Granit, Eisen und Blut den Platz von Statuen und Gärten eingenommen. Die Säule war umschlungen von hunderten von Ketten, und all jene, die am Vortag protestiert hatten, waren von den nackten Ketten an die Säule gefesselt. Die meisten waren auseinander- und zerrissen und hingen als blutige Fetzen an den Ketten, aber einige waren noch am Leben und bei Bewusstsein, sie drehten und windeten sich zwischen den Ketten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Flauros sollte noch oft auf seinem Balkon stehen und das bewundern, was er die Rose von Prespur nannte. Mit den Stacheln und der Blutroten Spitze wirkte die Säule wahrhaftig wie eine solche. Gleich, wie Kunstvoll sie war, die Bewohner von Prespur wagten es nie wieder, sich aufzulehnen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]I cittadini marciarono nella piazza della città protestando ed esigendo le libertà che i loro vicini avevano. Cantavano e urlavano al palazzo mentre Flauros li guardava dal suo balcone. Manifestarono per ore, diventando sempre più audaci col passare del tempo, e sempre più cittadini si univano.[PARAGRAPH:1]I Moroi restavano ai loro posti, non minacciavano o sembravano consapevoli dell'orda di manifestanti violenti davanti a loro. I cittadini rovesciarono le statue della piazza, distrussero panchine e scossero i cancelli del palazzo e Flauros rimaneva ad aspettare.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un'ondata di euforia colpi la folla, erano insorti e Flauros non aveva reagito. Non erano impotenti, non erano spaventati, Flauros aveva paura di loro. Questo pensieri li galvanizzò, generazioni di Calabim hanno sofferto senza lamentarsi, compiacenti nella loro paura. Ma le loro paure erano svanite ora, erano un nuovo popolo unito contro la loro crudele aristocrazia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il sole raggiunse l'orizzonte, colorando i manifestanti con il rosso e l'arancione dell'inizio della notte. Le ombre degli edifici si allungarono fino a raggiungere la piazza, come oscuri denti sui ciottoli di granito consumato. Per un battito cardiaco le urla selvaggie di rabbia dei manifestanti cessarono mentre le ombre li coprirono, c'era silenzio nella piazza. Poi arrivarono le urla.[PARAGRAPH:1]Al mattino, dove c'erano state graziose statue e panchine, ora c'era un gigante pilastro di granito, ferro e sangue. Centinaia di catene spinate erano intrecciate attorno al pilastro e tenute da quelle catene c'erano tutte le persone che avevano protestato il giorno prima. La maggior parte erano pezzi di corpi fatti a pezzi e appesi alle catene, ma alcuni vivevano ancora e si contorcevano.[PARAGRAPH:1]Flauros sarebbe stato spesso sul suo balcone ad ammirare ciò che lui chiamava la Rosa di Prespur. Con le sue spine e le macchie di sangue in cima quasi lo sembrava. Non curanti dei loro meriti artistici la popolazione di Prespur non protestò mai più.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Los ciudadanos marcharon hacia la plaza de la ciudad con piquetes y demandando las libertades que sus conciudadanos tuvieron.  Protestaron y gritaron hacia el palacio mientras Flauros observaba desde su alcoba.  Manifestaron durante horas, volviéndose cada vez más atrevidos según el día pasaba, y más ciudadanos se unieron.[PARAGRAPH:1]Los Moroi se mantuvieron en sus puestos, no se sentían amenazados ni parecían conscientes de la horda de protestantes violentos ante ellos.  Los ciudadanos derribaron estatuas en la plaza, destrozaron bancos y sacudieron las puertas del palacio, mientras Flauros seguía esperando.[PARAGRAPH:1]Una ola de euforia envolvió a la multitud, se rebelaron y Flauros seguía sin responder.  No estaban indefensos, no estaban asustados, Flauros les temía.  Este pensamiento les intoxicó, generaciones han sufrido sin voz ni opinión por los Calabim, complacidos en su miedo.  Paro su miedo ahora se había ido, ellos eran una nueva gente unida sontra su cruel aristocracia.[PARAGRAPH:1]El sol se adentró en el horizonte, bañando a los protestantes con los rojos y naranjas de la tarde.  Alargando las sombras de los edificios hasta que salieron de la plaza como dientes oscuros sobre los gastados adoquines de granito.  En un latido los gritos de odio salvaje de los protestantes pararon mientras las sombras los cubrían, había silencio en la plaza.  Y entonces vinieron los gritos de terror.[PARAGRAPH:1]Por la mañana, donde una vez hubo preciosas estatuas y bancos, ahora había un pilar gigantesco de granito, hierro y... sangre.  Cientos de cadenas con púas colgaban alrededor de la torre y atados a ellas estaban aquellos que protestaron el día anterior.  La mayoría eran cuerpos desmembrados que colgaban de las cadenas, pero algunos aún vivían y mientras se retorcían sus cuellos.[PARAGRAPH:1]Flauros se mantendría en pie a admirar desde su alcoba lo que acabaría llamando la Rosa de Prespur.  Con sus espinas y su sangre en lo alto casi es eso lo que parecía.  Sin tener en cuenta su mérito artístico la gente de Prespur nunca más volvió a protestar.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PROPHECY_OF_RAGNAROK</Tag>
		<English>Prophecy of Ragnarok</English>
		<French>Prophétie de Ragnarok</French>
		<German>Prophezeihung des Ragnarok</German>
		<Italian>Profezia del Ragnarok</Italian>
		<Spanish>Profecía del Ragnarok</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PROPHECY_OF_RAGNAROK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]This wonder increases the Armageddon Counter by 1 when a living unit is built. If that unit is killed the Armageddon Counter is reduced by 1.[PARAGRAPH:1]Once his world was that of the plow and the oxen, of caring for his crops and his family. That was before the vision. He fell amidst his rows of wheat, screaming and wailing. By the time his laborers found him, his clothes were rent and he was shivering in a fetal position. He let them lead him home, but all he could think of was the vision. This land would be consumed with fire and water, darkness would rule the land. Those alone who would know joy would be those who died, fighting the inevitable with honor. The next hour found him at the marketplace, crying out to passers-by of the end of days, of the last chance of redemption. He would not leave his post in the city, nor the others theirs. In every city in the land, the same cry can be heard-"The end is at hand! Ragnarok approaches!"</English>
		<French>[TAB]Cette merveille augmente le compteur Armageddon de 1  lorsqu'une unité vivante est construite. Si celle-ci est tuée , le compteur Armageddon diminue de 1.[PARAGRAPH:1]Son monde avait été celui de la charrue et des troupeaux, lorsqu'il s'occupait de ses récoltes et de sa famille. Mais cela était avant la vision. Il tomba parmi ses champs de blé, hurlant et gémissant. Au bout de quelque temps , ses employés le découvrirent, ses habits déchirés et recroquevillé dans la position foetale. Il les laissa le ramener chez lui, mais il ne pouvait penser à autre chose qu'à la vision. Cette terre serait ravagée par le feu et l'eau, les ténèbres dirigeraient le pays. Les seuls à connaître la joie seraient ceux qui mourraient, combattant l'inévitable avec honneur. Dès l'heure suivante, il fut sur la place du marché, annonçant aux passants la fin des temps, leur dernière chance de rédemption. Il ne quitterait pas son poste dans la ville, ni les autres le leur. Mais dans toutes les villes du pays, le même cri se faisait entendre : « La fin est en vue ! Ragnarok approche ! »  </French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Prophezeihung des Ragnarok lässt den Armageddonzähler jede Runde um einen Punkt wachsen, bis er 40 Punkte erreicht hat.[PARAGRAPH:1]Einst bestand sein Leben aus Pflug und Ochse, und aus der Sorge um die Früchte des Feldes und um seine Familie. Aber dann kam die Vision. Er kippte in die Reihen der Weizenpflanzen, schreiend und klagend. Nach einer Weile fanden ihn seine Hilfsarbeiter, seine Kleider waren zerrissen, er lag da wie ein Baby im Mutterleib mit angezogenen Beinen und schlotterte erbärmlich. Er ließ sich nach Hause führen, aber seine Gedanken drehten sich nur um die Vision. Wasser und Feuer würden dieses Land überkommen, und Dunkelheit würde es regieren. Einzig die, die Freude kennen, würden diejenigen sein, die in Ehren gegen das Unausweichliche kämpfend sterben. Eine Stunde später stand er auf dem Marktplatz und brüllte in die Menge der Vorbeilaufenden, dass das Ende der Tage nahe sei, der letzten Möglichkeit der Erlösung. Er würde seinen Platz in der Stadt nicht mehr verlassen, genauso wenig wie die anderen. In jeder Stadt des Landes ertönt nun der Ruf - "Das Ende ist nah! Ragnarok kommt!"</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Questa meraviglia aumenta il contatore dell'Armageddon di 1 quando un'unità vivente viene create nella città. Se quell'unità viene uccisa il contatore dell'Armageddon viene ridotto di 1[PARAGRAPH:1]Una volta il suo mondo era quello dell'aratro e dei buoi, del curare i suoi raccolti e la sua famiglia. Quello era prima della visione. Tutto iniziò quando cadde tra i filari di grano, urlando e piangendo. Quando i suoi operai lo trovarono, i suoi vestiti erano strappati e lui stava tremando in posizione fetale. Lasciò che lo portarono a casa, ma tutto ciò a cui riusciva a pensare era la visione. Questa terra consumata dal fuoco e dall'acqua, l'oscurità avrebbe regnato su queste terre. Gli unici che sarebbero stati felici sarebbero stati coloro che morivano, combattendo l'inevitabile con onore. Un'ora dopo si trovava al mercato, gridando ai passanti, della fine dei giorni, dell'ultima possibilità di redenzione. Non lascerebbe il suo posto in città, ne gli altri il loro. In ogni città in ogni terra, lo stesso urlo poteva essere sentito, "La fine è vicina! Il Ragnarok sta arrivando!"</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Esta maravilla incrementa el Contador del Armagedón en uno cuando una unidad viva es construida.  Si esa unidad es eliminada el Contador del Armagedón se reduce en 1[PARAGRAPH:1]Una vez su mundo era aquél del arado y los bueyes, el de preocuparse por sus cosechas y su familia. Eso era entes de la visión. Cayó sobre sus filas de trigo, gritando de terror y gimiendo. Con el tiempo sus labradores le encontraron, sus ropajes estaban rajados y se encontraba temblando en posición fetal. Dejó que se lo llevaran a casa, pero lo único en lo que pudo pensar era en la visión. Esta tierra sería consumida con fuego y agua, la oscuridad dominaría la tierra. Aquellos solitarios que conocerían la alegría serían aquellos que murieron, luchando contra lo inevitable con honor. A la hora siguiente lo encontraron en el mercado, gritándoles a los paseantes acerca del fin de los días, de la última oportunidar de redención. No dejaría su puesto en la ciudad, ni los otros. En cada ciudad de esta tierra, el mismo grito de advertencia puede ser oído: "¡El final está de la mano!¡El Ragnarok se acerca!"</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PROPHECY_OF_RAGNAROK_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>This wonder increases the Armageddon Counter by 1 when a living unit is built. If that unit is killed the Armageddon Counter is reduced by 1.</English>
		<French>Cette merveille augmente le compteur Armageddon de 1  lorsqu'une unité vivante est construite. Si celle-ci est tuée , le compteur Armageddon diminue de 1.</French>
		<German>Diese Prophezeihung über das Ende der Zeiten erhöht den Armageddonzähler um 1 wenn eine lebende Einheit aufgestllt wird und reduziert ihn wieder um 1 wenn die Einheit stirbt.</German>
		<Italian>Questa meraviglia aumenta il Contatore dell'Armageddon di 1 quando un unità vivente viene prodotta. Se quell'unità viene uccisa il Contatore dell'Armageddon diminuisce di 1.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Esta maravilla incrementa el Contador del Armagedón en 1 cuando una unidad viva es construida.  Si esa unidad es destruida el Contador del Armagedón se reduce en 1.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RIDE_OF_THE_NINE_KINGS</Tag>
		<English>Ride of the Nine Kings</English>
		<French>Chevauchée des Neuf Rois</French>
		<German>Ritt der Neun Könige</German>
		<Italian>Cavalcata dei Nove Re</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cabalgata de los Nueve Reyes</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHRINE_OF_SIRONA</Tag>
		<English>Shrine of Sirona</English>
		<French>Sanctuaire de Sirona</French>
		<German>Der Schrein von Sirona</German>
		<Italian>Santuario di Sirona</Italian>
		<Spanish>Santuario de Sirona</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHRINE_OF_SIRONA_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to heal one of your units per turn.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Vous permet de soigner une unité par tour.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt dir eine Einheit pro Runde zu Heilen.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Permette di curare una delle tue unità a turno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows you to heal one of your units per turn.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHRINE_OF_SIRONA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Text must be written</English>
		<French>Text must be written</French>
		<German>Text must be written</German>
		<Italian>Deve essere ancora scritta</Italian>
		<Spanish>Text must be written</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHRINE_OF_SIRONA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Shrine of Sirona allows you to heal one of your living units per turn by a small amount. If your unit is damaged it will gain the Sirona's Touch spell. If that spell is used on any unit it will become unavailable for all of your units until the next turn.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le Sanctuaire de Sirona vous permet à chaque tour de soigner légèrement une de vos unités vivantes. Si votre unité est endommagée, elle gagnera le sort Effleurement de Sirona. Si le sort est utilisé par n'importe quelle unité, il deviendra indisponible pour toutes les autres jusqu'au prochain tour.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Der Schrein von Sirona kann eine Einheit pro Runde um 15% heilen. Eine verletzte Einheit erhält den Zauber Sironas Berührung. Wenn dieser Zauber für eine Einheit angewendet wird, dann ist er für andere Einheiten erst in der nächsten Runde wieder verfügbar.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il Santuario di Sirona ti permette di curare, di un una piccola quantita, una delle tue unità viventi a turno. Se la tua unità è ferita otterrà la magia Tocco di Sirona. Se quella magia viene usata da una qualsiasi unità non sarà disponibile per tutte le altre unità fino al tuo prossimo turno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El Santuario de Sirona permite curar a una unidad viva una pequeña cantidad cada turno.  Si la unidad está dañada ganará el conjuro Toque de Sirona.  Si ese conjuro se usa en una unidad, no estará disponible para el resto de unidades hasta el siguiente turno.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHRINE_OF_THE_CHAMPION</Tag>
		<English>Shrine of the Champion</English>
		<French>Autel du Champion</French>
		<German>Schrein des Champions</German>
		<Italian>Mausoleo del Campione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tumba del Campeón</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHRINE_OF_THE_CHAMPION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB][COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Shrine of the Champion[COLOR_REVERT] can only be built after the civilization's hero has been killed.[PARAGRAPH:2]They passed solemnly by the body. The priests had done their best to hide the hideous state of the deceased, but it was clear that his death had been very painful. Women sobbed, and even hardened warriors swallowed hard and had to look away. The invasion had been stopped, and just in time. The only walls surrounding the city now were the piles of corpses, every enemy slain, but the cost... The best of them lay defeated.[PARAGRAPH:1]The priest spoke movingly of honor, of valor, of sacrifice. He collected donations for a monument, planned a meeting to decide on the form. Then the people turned to rebuild their city and their lives.[PARAGRAPH:1]A rider appeared. He spoke quickly to the priest, then yelled to the crowd. "A second wave approaches! The enemy will be here in hours!"[PARAGRAPH:1]A cry of despair arose. "Then it was for naught!" one old woman said. "We are doomed after all..." "We must flee the city with our lives!" called out another.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the townspeople began to do just that, one lone man shouted out, "No!" He strode up next to the body of their hero. "Is this why he died? So we could run, and live like beaten dogs? What is it you said, priest? 'His courage is an example to us all; his valor shall be as a scale against us; his sacrifice allows us to carry on in his stead...' Carry on crying? NO! To carry on fighting! You asked for a memorial, my friends?" The man unsheathed his sword. "This is all the 'memorial' my savior needs-a strong arm and a sharp blade to carry on his work, to carry on to completion! Let us fight or die as he did-this is the Shrine to the Champion!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Another blade was raised with his, in defiance of their oncoming foe. Then another, then a score, then a hundred, then a thousand.</English>
		<French>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]L'autel du Champion[COLOR_REVERT] ne peut être construit qu'après  que le héros de la civilisation ait été tué.[PARAGRAPH:2]Ils passèrent solennellement près du corps. Les prêtres avaient fait de leur mieux pour cacher l'état hideux du mort, mais il était clair que sa mort avait été très douloureuse. Les femmes sanglotèrent et même les guerriers les plus endurcis respiraient difficilement et durent tourner les yeux. L'invasion avait été stoppée, juste à temps. Mais le coût ... Le meilleur d'entre eux était étendu, vaincu.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le prêtre parla de manière émouvant d'honneur, de valeur, de sacrifice. Il collecta les dons pour un monument, prévit une réunion pour décider de la forme. Puis le peuple s'en retourna reconstruire la ville et leurs vies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un cavalier apparut. Il parla rapidement au prêtre puis cria à la foule. « Une deuxième vague approche ! L'ennemi sera là dans quelques heures ! »[PARAGRAPH:1]Un cri de désespoir s'éleva. « Tout cela pour rien » dit une vieille femme. « Nous sommes vaincus après tout... » « Nous devons fuir la ville pour nos vies » cria un autre.[PARAGRAPH:1]Alors que les citoyens commençaient à faire cela, Un homme seul lança, « NON !» il s'approcha du corps de leur héros. « Est-ce pour cela qu'il est mort ? Pour que vous puissiez fuir, et vivre tels comme des chiens battus ? Est-ce cela que tu as dit, prêtre ? Son courage est un exemple pour nous tous ; Sa valeur devrait être une référence pour nous ; son sacrifice nous permet de continuer sur ses traces... Continuer à pleurer ? NON ! Continuer à combattre ! Vous demandiez un mémorial, mes amis ? » L'homme sortit et leva son épée. « Voici le seul 'mémorial' dont a besoin mon sauveur ; un bras fort et une épée aiguisée pour continuer son &#339;œuvre, pour l'achever ! Combattons ou mourrons comme il l'a fait ; Cela est l'Autel du Champion ! » [PARAGRAPH:1]Une autre épée se leva avec la sienne, défiant l'ennemi qui approchait. Puis une autre, puis une vingtaine, puis une centaine, puis un millier.</French>
		<German>[TAB][COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Altar der Champions[COLOR_REVERT]Kann nur gebaut werden, nachdem der Held der Zivilisation getötet wurde.[PARAGRAPH:2]Sie schritten ernst an der Leiche vorbei. Die Priester haben ihr bestes getan, um den grausamen Zustand der Verwesung zu verstecken, aber es war nicht zu übersehen, dass er qualvoll gestorben ist. Die Frauen weinten und schluchzten und selbst hart gesottene Krieger schluckten hart und mussten weg schauen. Die Invasion wurde gestoppt gerade rechtzeitig. Die einzigen Mauern welche die Stadt jetzt umgeben sind die Berge von Leichen, jeder Feind wurde vernichtet, aber für welchen Preis... Die besten fielen im Kampf.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Priester sprach bewegend von Ehre, Mut und Opfer. Er sammelte Spenden für ein Denkmal und plante ein Treffen um die Bauform festzulegen. Dann kehrten die Leute zurück um Ihre Stadt und Ihre Leben wieder aufzubauen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Reiter erschien. Er redete schnell zum Priester und dann rief er zur Menge: "Eine zweite Welle erscheint! Der Feind wird in einigen Stunden hier sein!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Eine Stimme der Verzweiflung wurde laut. "Dann war es nichts Wert!" rief eine alte Frau. "Dann sind wir alle verdammt..." "Wir müssen die Stadt verlassen um unsere Leben zu retten." Rief eine andere.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als die Stadtbewohner begannen, um genau das zu tun rief ein einzelner Mann, "Niemals!" Er schritt dicht zu der Leiche des Helden. "Ist es das, wofür er gestorben ist? Das wir weglaufen und wie geschlagene Köter leben? Was hast du gesagt Priester? Sein Mut ist ein Beispiel für uns alle; Seine Tapferkeit sollte ein Vorbild für uns sein, seine Opfer erlauben uns in seine Fußstapfen zu wandern... um weiter zu jammern? Niemals! Um weiter zu kämpfen sage Ich! Ihr fragt nach einem Denkmal meine Freunde?" Der Mann zog sein Schwert "Das ist alles an Erinnerungen welche mein Retter braucht. Einen starken Arm und eine scharfe Klinge um seine Arbeit zu vollenden. Lasst uns kämpfen oder sterben so wie Er... das ist der Altar zum Champion!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Eine weitere Klinge wurde gezogen zusammen mit seiner, in Erwartung des kommenden Kampfes. Dann eine weitere, dann ein Dutzend , dann Hunderte und dann Tausende.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Mausoleo del Campione[COLOR_REVERT] può essere costruito solo dopo che l'eroe della civiltà è stato ucciso.[PARAGRAPH:2]Passarono solennemente al fianco del corpo. I preti hanno fatto del loro meglio per nascondere l'orribile stato del defunto, ma era palese che la sua morte doveva essere stata molto dolorosa. Le donne piangevano, e persino guerrieri veterani deglutivano pesantemente e distoglievano lo sguardo. L'invasione era stata fermata, e giusto in tempo. Le uniche mura che circondavano la città ora erano i mucchi di cadaveri, tutti i nemici uccisi, ma a quale prezzo... I migliori tra loro erano morti.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il prete parlo in modo commovente dell'onore, del valore e del sacrificio. Raccolse le donazioni per un monumento, e organizzo una riunione per deciderne la forma. Poi le persone iniziarono a ricostruire la loro città e le loro vite.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un cavaliere apparve. Parlò rapidamente con il prete, poi urlò alla folla. "Una seconda ondata si avvicina! Il nemico sarà qui fra qualche ora!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Un urlo di disperazione si levò. "Quindi è stato tutto per nulla!" una vecchia donna disse. "Siamo finiti dopo tutto..." "Dobbiamo abbandonare la città con le nostre vite!" disse un'altro.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mentre la gente si preparava a fare proprio quello, un singolo uomo urlò "No!" Raggiunse il corpo del loro eroe. "È per questo che è morto? Cosi che noi potessimo scappare, e vivere come cani bastonati? Prete, che cos'è che avete detto? 'Il suo coraggio è un esempio per noi tutti; il suo valore sarà una scala su cui noi ci misuriamo; il suo sacrificio ci ha permesso di proseguire in sua vece...' Continuare a piangere? NO! Continuare a combattere! Avete chiesto un monumento, amici miei?" L'uomo sguaino la sua spada. "Questa è l'unico 'monumento' che il mio salvatore necessita, un forte braccio e una lama affilata per continuare il suo lavoro, per portarlo a compimento! Combattiamo o  moriamo come ha fatto lui, questo è il Mausoleo del Campione!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Un'altra lama si levò, sfidando il nemico in arrivo. Poi un'altra, poi decine, poi centinaia, poi migliaia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]La [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Tumba del Campeón[COLOR_REVERT] sólo puede ser construida después de que el héroe de la civilización haya muerto.[PARAGRAPH:2]Pasaron solemnemente por el cuerpo. Los sacerdotes lo hicieron lo mejor que pudieron para ocultar el horripilante estado del fallecido, pero estaba claro que su muerte había sido muy dolorosa. Las mujeres lloraron, e incluso los más curtidos guerreros y guerreras lo pasaron mal y tuvieron que mirar a otro lado. La invasión había sido detenida, y justo a tiempo. Los únicos muros que rodeaban la ciudad ahora eran pilas de cadáveres, cada enemigo abatido, pero el coste... El mejor de todos ellos yace derrotado.[PARAGRAPH:1]El sacerdote habló sobretodo de honor, valor y sacrificio. Colectó donaciones para un monumento, y planeó un encuentro para decidir su forma. Entonces la gente volvió para reconstruir su ciudad y sus vidas.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un jinete apareció. Habló con rapidez al sacerdote, y entonces se dirigió a la multitud. "¡Una segunda oleada se aproxima!¡El enemigo estará aquí en cuestión de horas!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Un grito de desesperación apareció. "¡Entonces ha sido para nada!" dijo una anciana. "Después de todo estamos perdidos..." "¡Debemos huir de la ciudad por nuestras vidas!" gritó otro.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mientras los ciudadanos empezaron a hacerlo, un hombre solitario gritó en lo alto. "¡No!" Dio zancadas hasta el cuerpo de su héroe. "¿Es por esto por lo que hemos muerto?¿Entonces debemos correr, y vivir como perros apaleados?¿Es eso lo que decís, sacerdote? 'Su corage es un ejemplo para todos nosotros; su valor será como una escama contra nosotros; su sacrificio nos permite seguir en su lugar...' ¿Seguir llorando? ¡NO! ¡Seguir luchando! ¿Pedísteis un memorial, amigos míos?" El hombre desemvainó su espada. "¡Este es todo el 'memorial' que me salvador necesita: un brazo fuerte y una hoja afilada para seguir con su trabajo, seguir hasta terminarlo por completo! Lucharemos o moriremos como él... ¡esta es la Tumba del Campeón!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Otra espada se levantó como la suya, en desafío de su enemigo que se acerca. Entonces otra, y otras más, después cien, después mil.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHRINE_OF_THE_CHAMPION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Gives a bonus promotion to all units produced in the city.</English>
		<French>Donne une promotion gratuite à toutes les unités entraînées dans la ville.</French>
		<German>Verleiht allen in der Stadt produzierten Einheiten eine Bonus Beförderung.</German>
		<Italian>Fornisce una promozione gratuita a scelta a tutte le unità prodotte dalla città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Da un ascenso adicional a todas las unidades producidas en la ciudad.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SONG_OF_AUTUMN</Tag>
		<English>Song of Autumn</English>
		<French>Chanson de l'Automne</French>
		<German>Herbstlied</German>
		<Italian>Canzone dell'Autunno</Italian>
		<Spanish>Canción de Otoño</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SOUL_FORGE</Tag>
		<English>Soul Forge</English>
		<French>Forge des Âmes</French>
		<German>Seelenschmiede</German>
		<Italian>Fucina delle Anime</Italian>
		<Spanish>Forja de Almas</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SOUL_FORGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Text must be written</English>
		<French>Text must be written</French>
		<German>Text must be written</German>
		<Italian>Deve essere ancora scritta</Italian>
		<Spanish>Text must be written</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SOUL_FORGE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Soul Forge provides a Death mana to the civilization that builds it. More importantly, it converts the soul of any living unit, allied or enemy, that dies within a tile of the forge into production. Players will get the most benefit by building it in cities prone to attack, but will also incur the most risk of losing it by doing so.</English>
		<French>La Forge des Âmes fournit un Mana de Mort à la civilisation l'ayant construite. Plus important, elle transforme l'âme de toute créature vivante mourrant une case alentour en production, allié comme ennemi. Les joueurs tireront le maximum de bénéfice en la construisant dans une ville ayant des chances de se faire attaquer, bien qu'en faisant cela ils prennent le risque de la perdre.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Seelenschmiede stellt der erbauenden Zivilisation Mana des Todes zur Verfügung. Aber wichtiger ist noch, dass sie die Seelen der Einheiten, egal ob freundlich oder feindlich, die innerhalb eines Geländefeldes sterben, in Produktion umwandelt. Den meisten Nutzen bringt es, die Seelenschmiede in einer Stadt zu bauen, die anfällig für Angriffe ist. Das wiederum maximiert natürlich das Risiko, sie zu verlieren.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La Fucina delle Anime fornisce un Mana della Morte alla civiltà che la costruisce. Ma ancora più importante, converte l'anima di ogni unità vivente, amica o nemica, che muore nelle caselle adiacenti alla città, in martelli. I giocatori ottengono il massimo del beneficio costruendola in città attaccate spesso, naturalmente ciò aumenta anche il rischio di perdere questa meraviglia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]La Forja de Almas provee de Maná de Muerte a la civilización que la construya.  Lo que es más importante, convierte el alma de cualquier unidad viva, aliada o enemiga, que muera a una casilla de distancia de la forja para su producción.  Los jugadores obtendrán un mayor beneficio construyendola en ciudades con riesgo de ataques, pero también supone un mayor riesgo de perderla al hacerlo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SOUL_FORGE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Living units killed within 1 tile add to this city's production</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Les unités vivantes tuées sur une case voisine (distance 1) accroissent la production de cette ville.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Lebende Einheiten die innerhalb eines Geländefeldes Entfernung zur Stadt sterben werden in Produktion umgewandelt.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Le unità viventi uccise nelle casele adiacenti alla città verranno aggiunte alla produzione della città</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Living units killed within 1 tile add to this city's production</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STIGMATA_ON_THE_UNBORN</Tag>
		<English>Stigmata on the Unborn</English>
		<French>Stigmate du Non-Né</French>
		<German>Stigmata des Ungeborenen</German>
		<Italian>Stimmate del Non Nato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Estigma de los No Nacidos</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STIGMATA_ON_THE_UNBORN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The profane nailed the prophet to the stone,[NEWLINE]and had him opened to the sky.[NEWLINE]The sheet torn from their covered eyes,[NEWLINE]they gazed upon the unveiled world as true.[NEWLINE]The unborn saw and screamed and wriggled in the womb,[NEWLINE]and came unto the world dark, tainted and corrupt.</English>
		<French>The profane nailed the prophet to the stone,[NEWLINE]and had him opened to the sky.[NEWLINE]The sheet torn from their covered eyes,[NEWLINE]they gazed upon the unveiled world as true.[NEWLINE]The unborn saw and screamed and wriggled in the womb,[NEWLINE]and came unto the world dark, tainted and corrupt.</French>
		<German>Der Prophet, von Gottlosen geketten an den Stein,[NEWLINE]sein innerstes geöffnet dem himmlischen Schein,[NEWLINE]war erst ihr Blick noch stark verhüllt,[NEWLINE]erkennen sie jetzt die wahre Welt.[NEWLINE]Das Ungeborene schrie und wand sich Mutters Bauch,[NEWLINE]geboren mit dunklem, verderbendem Dämonenhauch.</German>
		<Italian>I profani inchiodarono il profeta alla pietra,[NEWLINE]e lo aprirono rivolto verso il cielo.[NEWLINE]Le palpebre degli occhi strappate,[NEWLINE]guardava il mondo rivelato come era realmente.[NEWLINE]Il Non Nato vide e urlò e si contorceva nel grembo,[NEWLINE]e venne al mondo oscuro, contaminato e corrotto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The profane nailed the prophet to the stone,[NEWLINE]and had him opened to the sky.[NEWLINE]The sheet torn from their covered eyes,[NEWLINE]they gazed upon the unveiled world as true.[NEWLINE]The unborn saw and screamed and wriggled in the womb,[NEWLINE]and came unto the world dark, tainted and corrupt.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TABLETS_OF_BAMBUR</Tag>
		<English>Tablets of Bambur</English>
		<French>Tablettes de Bambur</French>
		<German>Tafeln von Bambur</German>
		<Italian>Tavolette di Bambur</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tablillas de Bambur</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLE_OF_TEMPORENCE</Tag>
		<English>Temple of Temporance</English>
		<French>Temple de la Tempérance</French>
		<German>Kathedrale der Zeit</German>
		<Italian>Tempio della Temperanza</Italian>
		<Spanish>Templo de la Templanza</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLE_OF_TEMPORENCE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Temple of Temporance is a mighty cathedral standing on the "Ile de la Sheol," said to have been the first point of creation. Built on the site of an older church, which was in turn built on the site of a temple to Junil, it is a magnificent example of gothic architecture and one of the greatest buildings standing. The temple is a massive stone building of square towers, flying buttresses, and tall spires. The exterior of the building is decorated with delicate ribbons of arches and statues of saints and kings. The roofline of the building is festooned with gargoyles. The interior of the temple is a long, narrow space with columns lining each side, supporting two beautiful raised galleries. Brilliant stained glass windows shine gently down on the main altar.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Le Temple de la Tempérance est une majestueuse cathédrale se tenant sur l'Île de la Shéol, prétendument le premier point de la création. Construite sur le site d'une église plus ancienne, qui fut à son tour construite sur le site d'un temple de Junil, c'est un magnifique exemple d'architecture gothique et l'un des plus grand édifice. Le temple est une massive construction en pierre de tours carrées, de contreforts et de hautes flèches. L'extérieur du bâtiment est décodé avec de délicates ribambelles d'arches et des statues de saint et de rois. Le rebord du toit est festonné avec des gargouilles. L'intérieur du temple est un long espace étroit bordé de colonnes supportant deux belles galeries surélevées. De brillants vitraux luisent doucement sur l'autel principal/</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Kathedrale der Zeit ist eine mächtige Kirche, stehend auf der "Insel de la Sheol", sagt man von dem ersten Punkt der Erstellung. Gebaut auf den Grundmauern einer älteren Kirche, welche Stück für Stück auf dem Platz eines Tempels von Junil erbaut wurde, es ist ein großartiges Beispiel von gothischer Architektur und eines der größten existierenden Gebäude. Der Kathedrale ist ein massiges Steingebäude, bestehend aus quadratischen Türmen fliehenden Stützpfeilern und großen Turmspitzen. Die Außenseite des Gebäudes ist mit schönen Farbbändern und Gewölben sowie Skulpturen von Heiligen und Königen dekoriert. Das Dachgebilde des Bauwerks ist mit Gargoyles verziert. Das Innere der Kirche ist ein knapper , länglicher Raum mit Auswölbungen auf jeder Seite, welche zwei erhöhte Galerien hervorheben. Brillante Buntglasfenster scheinen sanft auf den Hauptaltar nieder.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il Tempio della Temperanza è un'imponente cattedrale che sta sulla "Ile de la Sheol", si dice che sia stato il primo punto della creazione. Costruita su una chiesa più vecchia, che a sua volta era stata costruita su un tempio di Junil, è un maginifico esempio di archittetura gotica e una delle più grandi strutture esistenti. Il tempio è un'enorme edificio in pietra composto da torri quadrate, contrafforti volanti, e alte guglie. L'esterno dell'edificio è decorato con file di archi e statue di santi e re. I cornicioni sono ornati da gargoyle. L'interno del tempio è lungo e stretto, con colonne su ambo i lati che supportano due bellissime balconate. Brillanti vetrate colorate illuminano gentilmente l'altare principale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]El Templo de la Templanza es una imponente catedral que se eleva sobre la "Ile de la Sheol", donde se dice que fue el primer punto de la creación.  Construida en el lugar de una antigua iglesia, que a su vez fue construida en el lugar de un Templo de Junil, es un magnífico ejemplo de arquitectura gótica y uno de los más grandes edificios jamás construidos. El templo es una construcción masiva de piedra en un cuadrado de torres, contrafuertes en lo alto, y espirales talladas. El exterior del edificio está decorado con cintas delicadas de arcos y estatuas de santos y reyes. La cornisa del edificio está adornada con gárgolas. El interior del templo es un largo y estrecho espacio con columnas alineando cada lado, que soportan dos preciosas galerías elevadas. Vistosas ventanas de cristales pintados brillan gentilmente al altar principal de debajo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_THE_NECRONOMICON</Tag>
		<English>The Necronomicon</English>
		<French>Necronomicon</French>
		<German>Das Nekronomicon</German>
		<Italian>Il Necronomicon</Italian>
		<Spanish>El Necronomicón</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_THE_NECRONOMICON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As the sun set into the ocean, its colors multiplied and shone across the sedated waters. Dying light in grapefruit and blood-orange shades pierced the temple's windows and comingled with the blues and greens, never mixing. The lights shimmered across the town's rooftops, glowing like the tolling of church bells as worshippers walked to the ocean and temple. For some, worship was to admire the ocean, to be present at its show. Others preferred immersion, giving their bodies to the water (metaphorically) as a way of saying "I owe you everything." Inside the temple the faithful bathed in the flowing water, letting the incense riding in the thick air penetrate their skin. Their minds flowed with the water and gave way to visions and serenity. A Priest of Whispers watched over as the din of the chamber filled with echoes of mumblings, humming, and short cries of ecstasy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Farther within the temple, Captain Grey-Eye of the Jury Rig raised his head after bowing to High Speaker The Bones of Its Mother Are Luminous Eyes.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"What have you brought us, Captain?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Grey-Eye was as faithful to the priests as any successful sea captain should be. He prayed regularly, both on the waves and on shore, and always gave a portion of his gold spoils back to the sea. Such spoils were what brought him before the Speaker in his hometown temple.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Rumors from the Calabim lands speak of rich bounties for a treasure they've apparently misplaced."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know. The ebb and flow of water brings me news from around the world."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Then y'know better than I the significance of the Book of Sable; I know none more than what they've offered to pay."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Speaker stared through unblinking, sunken eyes. He was hairless, pale, and skeletal but his voice was like the creaking of the Jury Rig's mast. He was Speaker when Grey-Eye worshipped here as a child and hadn't changed appearance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I will pay anything you ask. However, when the bargaining is done I have a favor to ask of you."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"You're too generous, Your Resonance. If you're paying in Lanun coins, I'll take the Calabim's price. I accept the favor-what is it?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I'm sending a priestess with you on your ship. She has a mission and you will find her abilities useful. Leave the book on the altar. Your service has been invaluable as always, Captain." Grey-Eye bowed his head and was escorted away. The Speaker regarded the book in front of him. The cover was a lightly colored and flimsy leather, dirty and weathered. The pages were becoming brittle. Human flesh no doubt; a product of the Catacomb Libralus, whose books were well guarded by the golems. No books ever left that city, making the Book of Sable especially rare. The High Speaker knew it was not chance, but the will of the unseen that brought the book to this temple.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He carried the book to the chamber of dreamers beneath the temple, where pools and pillars formed from mineral and organic deposits. The blessed seawater flowed throughout as dreamers lay in small pools. He approached a dreamer, a female in her teenage years, whose hair undulated like living tendrils in the water beneath her. A clay jar by her head had the words "the book of dead names sees beyond the depths" etched into it. The Speaker gave the book to one of the dreamers' attendants and ordered that it be placed in an empty pool.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Speaker, do books dream?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"It is the ocean that dreams. We are blessed to be a part of it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A voice from one of the pools spoke, "the dreams of the unseen permeate all creation." Everyone awake in the room chanted in response, "the dreams of the unseen permeate all creation."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"And thus shall you be called," intoned the Speaker, his voice penetrating the sleep of the dreamer who spoke. He watched the attendant lay the book in the water. The attendant punctured a needle into the front cover, as he would into a vein, and lit the wick in the needle's tube. He did this out of habit; the book lacked the biology to carry the smoldering wax's substance throughout the bloodstream, but this was how the dreaming was induced.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It was two hours before any change was noted. The Speaker still stood over the dreamers, patient, faithful, and curious. The teenage girl stirred and minds melded in the stream. Her limbs twitched as the lingering consciousness from the book felt forgotten corporeality.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Speak," commanded the Speaker. The girl remained silent and made small splashes as she moved. The Speaker said, "I seek the source of whispers."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He continued his commands until the girl settled down. Finally she spoke in her young voice, "I refuse."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"You are powerless to refuse. You will navigate the sea of dreams and find for me the source."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I can't move."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Tell me what you see."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I see everything. The dreams of everything. All at once, every one a shadow, fluid."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Look beyond them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"There is only darkness beyond the dreams."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Go there. I compel you." His voice reverberated in the chamber. He had not chosen to pursue this. He didn't consider it a choice. He was following the will of his masters, as spoken through the dreamers.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Whispers... I feel them... Pressure... I can't understand them, but every syllable crushes me..."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Move toward it. I will speak to it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"There's a being-shapeless, immense... there's... an eye-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At that moment the temple erupted with shrieks and wails of terror and pain. The Speaker fell forward and moaned, devoid of any thought or function. The young dreamer convulsed and died. At the temple's entrance worshippers ran into the town, possessed of nightmarish panic. They dashed themselves into walls and gouged at their throats with any tool available, trying to wake themselves from the nightmare they were in fact not in. Others remained in the temple, writhing and gurgling in the blessed water. Either they were stronger than the others, or perhaps more susceptible to the climactic vision, but they survived nonetheless. Of that moment, all could remember nothing more than the color yellow.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The temple was soon reopened for public worship. The surviving worshippers who rose to prominence joined the remaining priests. They became the caretakers of the temple that housed the Book of Sable, on whose pages appeared the names of the faithful who died for the Lord of Nightmares on that day.</English>
		<French>As the sun set into the ocean, its colors multiplied and shone across the sedated waters. Dying light in grapefruit and blood-orange shades pierced the temple's windows and comingled with the blues and greens, never mixing. The lights shimmered across the town's rooftops, glowing like the tolling of church bells as worshippers walked to the ocean and temple. For some, worship was to admire the ocean, to be present at its show. Others preferred immersion, giving their bodies to the water (metaphorically) as a way of saying "I owe you everything." Inside the temple the faithful bathed in the flowing water, letting the incense riding in the thick air penetrate their skin. Their minds flowed with the water and gave way to visions and serenity. A Priest of Whispers watched over as the din of the chamber filled with echoes of mumblings, humming, and short cries of ecstasy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Farther within the temple, Captain Grey-Eye of the Jury Rig raised his head after bowing to High Speaker The Bones of Its Mother Are Luminous Eyes.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"What have you brought us, Captain?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Grey-Eye was as faithful to the priests as any successful sea captain should be. He prayed regularly, both on the waves and on shore, and always gave a portion of his gold spoils back to the sea. Such spoils were what brought him before the Speaker in his hometown temple.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Rumors from the Calabim lands speak of rich bounties for a treasure they've apparently misplaced."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know. The ebb and flow of water brings me news from around the world."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Then y'know better than I the significance of the Book of Sable; I know none more than what they've offered to pay."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Speaker stared through unblinking, sunken eyes. He was hairless, pale, and skeletal but his voice was like the creaking of the Jury Rig's mast. He was Speaker when Grey-Eye worshipped here as a child and hadn't changed appearance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I will pay anything you ask. However, when the bargaining is done I have a favor to ask of you."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"You're too generous, Your Resonance. If you're paying in Lanun coins, I'll take the Calabim's price. I accept the favor-what is it?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I'm sending a priestess with you on your ship. She has a mission and you will find her abilities useful. Leave the book on the altar. Your service has been invaluable as always, Captain." Grey-Eye bowed his head and was escorted away. The Speaker regarded the book in front of him. The cover was a lightly colored and flimsy leather, dirty and weathered. The pages were becoming brittle. Human flesh no doubt; a product of the Catacomb Libralus, whose books were well guarded by the golems. No books ever left that city, making the Book of Sable especially rare. The High Speaker knew it was not chance, but the will of the unseen that brought the book to this temple.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He carried the book to the chamber of dreamers beneath the temple, where pools and pillars formed from mineral and organic deposits. The blessed seawater flowed throughout as dreamers lay in small pools. He approached a dreamer, a female in her teenage years, whose hair undulated like living tendrils in the water beneath her. A clay jar by her head had the words "the book of dead names sees beyond the depths" etched into it. The Speaker gave the book to one of the dreamers' attendants and ordered that it be placed in an empty pool.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Speaker, do books dream?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"It is the ocean that dreams. We are blessed to be a part of it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A voice from one of the pools spoke, "the dreams of the unseen permeate all creation." Everyone awake in the room chanted in response, "the dreams of the unseen permeate all creation."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"And thus shall you be called," intoned the Speaker, his voice penetrating the sleep of the dreamer who spoke. He watched the attendant lay the book in the water. The attendant punctured a needle into the front cover, as he would into a vein, and lit the wick in the needle's tube. He did this out of habit; the book lacked the biology to carry the smoldering wax's substance throughout the bloodstream, but this was how the dreaming was induced.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It was two hours before any change was noted. The Speaker still stood over the dreamers, patient, faithful, and curious. The teenage girl stirred and minds melded in the stream. Her limbs twitched as the lingering consciousness from the book felt forgotten corporeality.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Speak," commanded the Speaker. The girl remained silent and made small splashes as she moved. The Speaker said, "I seek the source of whispers."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He continued his commands until the girl settled down. Finally she spoke in her young voice, "I refuse."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"You are powerless to refuse. You will navigate the sea of dreams and find for me the source."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I can't move."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Tell me what you see."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I see everything. The dreams of everything. All at once, every one a shadow, fluid."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Look beyond them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"There is only darkness beyond the dreams."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Go there. I compel you." His voice reverberated in the chamber. He had not chosen to pursue this. He didn't consider it a choice. He was following the will of his masters, as spoken through the dreamers.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Whispers... I feel them... Pressure... I can't understand them, but every syllable crushes me..."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Move toward it. I will speak to it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"There's a being-shapeless, immense... there's... an eye-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At that moment the temple erupted with shrieks and wails of terror and pain. The Speaker fell forward and moaned, devoid of any thought or function. The young dreamer convulsed and died. At the temple's entrance worshippers ran into the town, possessed of nightmarish panic. They dashed themselves into walls and gouged at their throats with any tool available, trying to wake themselves from the nightmare they were in fact not in. Others remained in the temple, writhing and gurgling in the blessed water. Either they were stronger than the others, or perhaps more susceptible to the climactic vision, but they survived nonetheless. Of that moment, all could remember nothing more than the color yellow.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The temple was soon reopened for public worship. The surviving worshippers who rose to prominence joined the remaining priests. They became the caretakers of the temple that housed the Book of Sable, on whose pages appeared the names of the faithful who died for the Lord of Nightmares on that day.</French>
		<German>As the sun set into the ocean, its colors multiplied and shone across the sedated waters. Dying light in grapefruit and blood-orange shades pierced the temple's windows and comingled with the blues and greens, never mixing. The lights shimmered across the town's rooftops, glowing like the tolling of church bells as worshippers walked to the ocean and temple. For some, worship was to admire the ocean, to be present at its show. Others preferred immersion, giving their bodies to the water (metaphorically) as a way of saying "I owe you everything." Inside the temple the faithful bathed in the flowing water, letting the incense riding in the thick air penetrate their skin. Their minds flowed with the water and gave way to visions and serenity. A Priest of Whispers watched over as the din of the chamber filled with echoes of mumblings, humming, and short cries of ecstasy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Farther within the temple, Captain Grey-Eye of the Jury Rig raised his head after bowing to High Speaker The Bones of Its Mother Are Luminous Eyes.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"What have you brought us, Captain?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Grey-Eye was as faithful to the priests as any successful sea captain should be. He prayed regularly, both on the waves and on shore, and always gave a portion of his gold spoils back to the sea. Such spoils were what brought him before the Speaker in his hometown temple.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Rumors from the Calabim lands speak of rich bounties for a treasure they've apparently misplaced."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know. The ebb and flow of water brings me news from around the world."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Then y'know better than I the significance of the Book of Sable; I know none more than what they've offered to pay."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Speaker stared through unblinking, sunken eyes. He was hairless, pale, and skeletal but his voice was like the creaking of the Jury Rig's mast. He was Speaker when Grey-Eye worshipped here as a child and hadn't changed appearance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I will pay anything you ask. However, when the bargaining is done I have a favor to ask of you."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"You're too generous, Your Resonance. If you're paying in Lanun coins, I'll take the Calabim's price. I accept the favor-what is it?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I'm sending a priestess with you on your ship. She has a mission and you will find her abilities useful. Leave the book on the altar. Your service has been invaluable as always, Captain." Grey-Eye bowed his head and was escorted away. The Speaker regarded the book in front of him. The cover was a lightly colored and flimsy leather, dirty and weathered. The pages were becoming brittle. Human flesh no doubt; a product of the Catacomb Libralus, whose books were well guarded by the golems. No books ever left that city, making the Book of Sable especially rare. The High Speaker knew it was not chance, but the will of the unseen that brought the book to this temple.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He carried the book to the chamber of dreamers beneath the temple, where pools and pillars formed from mineral and organic deposits. The blessed seawater flowed throughout as dreamers lay in small pools. He approached a dreamer, a female in her teenage years, whose hair undulated like living tendrils in the water beneath her. A clay jar by her head had the words "the book of dead names sees beyond the depths" etched into it. The Speaker gave the book to one of the dreamers' attendants and ordered that it be placed in an empty pool.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Speaker, do books dream?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"It is the ocean that dreams. We are blessed to be a part of it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A voice from one of the pools spoke, "the dreams of the unseen permeate all creation." Everyone awake in the room chanted in response, "the dreams of the unseen permeate all creation."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"And thus shall you be called," intoned the Speaker, his voice penetrating the sleep of the dreamer who spoke. He watched the attendant lay the book in the water. The attendant punctured a needle into the front cover, as he would into a vein, and lit the wick in the needle's tube. He did this out of habit; the book lacked the biology to carry the smoldering wax's substance throughout the bloodstream, but this was how the dreaming was induced.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It was two hours before any change was noted. The Speaker still stood over the dreamers, patient, faithful, and curious. The teenage girl stirred and minds melded in the stream. Her limbs twitched as the lingering consciousness from the book felt forgotten corporeality.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Speak," commanded the Speaker. The girl remained silent and made small splashes as she moved. The Speaker said, "I seek the source of whispers."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He continued his commands until the girl settled down. Finally she spoke in her young voice, "I refuse."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"You are powerless to refuse. You will navigate the sea of dreams and find for me the source."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I can't move."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Tell me what you see."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I see everything. The dreams of everything. All at once, every one a shadow, fluid."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Look beyond them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"There is only darkness beyond the dreams."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Go there. I compel you." His voice reverberated in the chamber. He had not chosen to pursue this. He didn't consider it a choice. He was following the will of his masters, as spoken through the dreamers.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Whispers... I feel them... Pressure... I can't understand them, but every syllable crushes me..."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Move toward it. I will speak to it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"There's a being-shapeless, immense... there's... an eye-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At that moment the temple erupted with shrieks and wails of terror and pain. The Speaker fell forward and moaned, devoid of any thought or function. The young dreamer convulsed and died. At the temple's entrance worshippers ran into the town, possessed of nightmarish panic. They dashed themselves into walls and gouged at their throats with any tool available, trying to wake themselves from the nightmare they were in fact not in. Others remained in the temple, writhing and gurgling in the blessed water. Either they were stronger than the others, or perhaps more susceptible to the climactic vision, but they survived nonetheless. Of that moment, all could remember nothing more than the color yellow.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The temple was soon reopened for public worship. The surviving worshippers who rose to prominence joined the remaining priests. They became the caretakers of the temple that housed the Book of Sable, on whose pages appeared the names of the faithful who died for the Lord of Nightmares on that day.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre il sole finiva nell'oceano, i suoi colori si moltiplicarono e si riflettevano sulle acque. Le luci morenti color giallo e arancione sanguigno incontravano le finestre del tempio e si mescolavano ai blu e i verdi delle vetrate, senza mai mischiarsi. La luce brillava sui tetti della città, pulsando in sintonia con il rintocco delle campane della chiesa mentre i fedeli camminavano verso il tempio e l'oceano. Per alcuni, la venerazione era l'ammirare l'oceano, di assistere al suo spettaccolo. Altri preferivano immergersi, consegnando i loro corpi all'acqua (metaforicamente) come un modo di dire "Ti devo tutto". Dentro il tempio i fedeli si immergevano nell'acqua corrente, permettendo all'incenso, presente nell'aria, di penetrare la loro pelle. Le loro menti fluivano con l'acqua e lasciarono posto a visioni e serenità. Un Prete dei Sussurri guardava mentre l'aria iniziava a riempirsi degli echi di borbottii, ronzii, e brevi urla di estasi.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Più all'interno del tempio, Capitan Grey-Eye del Jury Rig alzò la testa dopo averla chinata al Alto Oratore The Bones of Its Mother Are Luminous Eyes.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Che cosa ci hai portato, Capitano?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Grey-Eye era un fedele dei preti come ogni capitano di successo dovrebbe essere. Pregava regolarmente, sia sul mare che sulla terra, e dava sempre una porzione dell'oro saccheggiato al mare. Quelle razzie erano ciò che lo portarono davanti all'Oratore del tempio della sua città natale.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Voci dalle terre Calabim di grandi ricompense per un tesoro che sembra abbiano perduto."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Lo so. Le acque mi portano notizie da tutto il mondo."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Quindi sapete meglio di me l'importanza del Libro di Sebill; Non so se qualcuno abbia promesso di pagare più di loro."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]L'Alto Oratore guardava attraverso profondi occhi che non si chiudevano mai. Era pelato, pallido, e scheletrico ma la sua voce era come lo scricchiolio dell'abero maestro del Jury Rig. Era un normale Oratore quando Grey-Eye pregava qui da bambino e il suo aspetto non era cambiato.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Ti paghero qualsiasi cifra. Però, quando l'affare è concluso ho un favore da chiederti."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Siete troppo generoso, Vostra Sonorità. Se pagate in monete Lanun, chiederò lo stesso tanto che offrono i Calabim. E accetto di farvi il favore, di che si tratta?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Sto mandando una sacerdotessa con voi sulla vostra nave. Lei ha una missione e voi troverete utili le sue abilità. Lasciate il Libro sull'altare. I vostri servigi sono impagabili come sempre, Capitano." Grey-Eye chinò la testa e fu accompagnato via. L'Oratore osservava il libro davanti a lui. La copertina era di pelle leggermente colorata, fragile, sporca e logora. Le pagine stavano iniziando a diventare fragili. Pelle umana senza dubbio; un prodotto della Catacomba Libralus, i cui libri erano tutti ben custoditi dai golem. Nessun libro aveva mai lasciato quella città, rendendo il Libro di Sebill particolarmente raro. L'Alto Oratore sapeva che non era stato il caso, ma volontà invisibili, a portare il libro a questo tempio.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Portò il libro alle camere dei sognatori sotto il tempio, dove piscine e pilastri erano formati da depositi minerali e organici. L'acqua di mare benedetta fluiva costantemente mentre i sognatori erano distesi in piccole piscine. Si avvicinò a un sognatore, una ragazzina, i cui capelli ondulavano come viticci viventi nell'acqua sottostante. Un barattolo di argilla vicino alla sua testa aveva la scritta "il libro dei nomi dei morti vede oltre le profondità" inscritta. L'Oratore diede il libro a uno degli assistenti dei sognatori e ordinò che venisse messo in una piscina vuota.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Oratore, il libri sognano?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"È l'oceano che sogna. Siamo benedetti per essere parte di ciò."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Una voce da una delle piscine parlò, "i sogni degli invisibili permeano tutta la creazione." Tutte le persone sveglie nella stanza recitarono in risposta, "i sogni degli invisibili permeano tutta la creazione."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"E cosi tu sarai chiamato," intonò l'Oratore, la sua voce si inserì nel sonno del sognatore che aveva parlato. Guardo l'assistente depositare il libro nell'acqua. L'assisente infilò uno ago nella copertina frontale, come avrebbe fatto con una vena, e accese lo stoppino nel tubo dell'ago. Lo fece solo per abitudine; il libro non aveva un metabolismo che avrebbe portato la sostanza simil cera attraverso il flusso sanguigno, ma era cosi che si inducevano i sogni.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Passarono due ora prima di notare qualsiasi cambiamento. L'Oratore rimaneva sopra i sognatori, paziente, fiducioso, e curioso. La ragazzina si agitò e le menti si fusero nella corrente. I suoi arti si contrasserò mentre la coscienza presente nel libro percepiva una corporeità dimenticata.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Parla," ordinò l'Oratore. La ragazzina rimase silente e fece dei piccoli spruzzi mentre si muoveva. L'Oratore disse, "Cerco l'origine dei sussurri."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Continuò ad impartire ordini fino a quando la ragazza non si calmò. Infine parlò con la sua giovane voce, "Mi rifiuto."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Non puoi rifiutarti. Navigherai il mare dei sogni e troverai per me l'origine."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Non posso muovermi."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Dimmi cosa vedi."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Vedo tutto. I sogni di ogni cosa. Tutti insieme, ognuno un'ombra, liquidi."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Guarda oltre."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"C'è solo oscurità oltre i sogni."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Vai li. Ti obbligo." La sua voce riverberò nella stanza. Non aveva scelto di perseguire questo. Non la considerava una scelta. Stava seguendo le volonta dei suoi padroni, come esposte attraverso i sognatori.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Sussurri... Li sento... Pressione... Non li capisco, ma ogni sillaba mi schiaccia..."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Vagli incontro. ci parlerò io."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"C'è un essere, senza forma, immenso... c'è... un'occhio"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In quel momento il tempio si riempi di urla di terrore e dolore. L'Oratore caddè in avanti e gemette, privo di qualsiasi pensiero o funzione. La giovane sognatrice fu presa da convulsioni e morì. All'entrata del tempio i fedeli corserò in città, presi da un attacco di panico indescrivibile. Si buttavano contro le pareti e si aprivano le gole con qualsiasi cosa trovavano, cercando di svegliarsi da incubi in cui però non erano. Altri rimaserò nel tempio, contorcendosi e gorgogliando nell'acqua benedetta. Che fosserò più forti, o magari più suscettibili alla visione, ma sopravvisserò. Di quel momento, tutti ricordavano solo il colore giallo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Il tempio fu riaperto al pubblico dopo pochi giorni. I fedeli sopravissuti salirono d'importanza e si unirono ai preti rimanenti. Loro divennerò i custodi del tempio che ospitava il Libro di Sebill, sulle cui pagine apparirono i nomi dei fedeli del Signore degli Incubi che morirono quel giorno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>As the sun set into the ocean, its colors multiplied and shone across the sedated waters. Dying light in grapefruit and blood-orange shades pierced the temple's windows and comingled with the blues and greens, never mixing. The lights shimmered across the town's rooftops, glowing like the tolling of church bells as worshippers walked to the ocean and temple. For some, worship was to admire the ocean, to be present at its show. Others preferred immersion, giving their bodies to the water (metaphorically) as a way of saying "I owe you everything." Inside the temple the faithful bathed in the flowing water, letting the incense riding in the thick air penetrate their skin. Their minds flowed with the water and gave way to visions and serenity. A Priest of Whispers watched over as the din of the chamber filled with echoes of mumblings, humming, and short cries of ecstasy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Farther within the temple, Captain Grey-Eye of the Jury Rig raised his head after bowing to High Speaker The Bones of Its Mother Are Luminous Eyes.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"What have you brought us, Captain?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Grey-Eye was as faithful to the priests as any successful sea captain should be. He prayed regularly, both on the waves and on shore, and always gave a portion of his gold spoils back to the sea. Such spoils were what brought him before the Speaker in his hometown temple.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Rumors from the Calabim lands speak of rich bounties for a treasure they've apparently misplaced."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I know. The ebb and flow of water brings me news from around the world."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Then y'know better than I the significance of the Book of Sable; I know none more than what they've offered to pay."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Speaker stared through unblinking, sunken eyes. He was hairless, pale, and skeletal but his voice was like the creaking of the Jury Rig's mast. He was Speaker when Grey-Eye worshipped here as a child and hadn't changed appearance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I will pay anything you ask. However, when the bargaining is done I have a favor to ask of you."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"You're too generous, Your Resonance. If you're paying in Lanun coins, I'll take the Calabim's price. I accept the favor-what is it?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I'm sending a priestess with you on your ship. She has a mission and you will find her abilities useful. Leave the book on the altar. Your service has been invaluable as always, Captain." Grey-Eye bowed his head and was escorted away. The Speaker regarded the book in front of him. The cover was a lightly colored and flimsy leather, dirty and weathered. The pages were becoming brittle. Human flesh no doubt; a product of the Catacomb Libralus, whose books were well guarded by the golems. No books ever left that city, making the Book of Sable especially rare. The High Speaker knew it was not chance, but the will of the unseen that brought the book to this temple.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He carried the book to the chamber of dreamers beneath the temple, where pools and pillars formed from mineral and organic deposits. The blessed seawater flowed throughout as dreamers lay in small pools. He approached a dreamer, a female in her teenage years, whose hair undulated like living tendrils in the water beneath her. A clay jar by her head had the words "the book of dead names sees beyond the depths" etched into it. The Speaker gave the book to one of the dreamers' attendants and ordered that it be placed in an empty pool.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Speaker, do books dream?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"It is the ocean that dreams. We are blessed to be a part of it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A voice from one of the pools spoke, "the dreams of the unseen permeate all creation." Everyone awake in the room chanted in response, "the dreams of the unseen permeate all creation."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"And thus shall you be called," intoned the Speaker, his voice penetrating the sleep of the dreamer who spoke. He watched the attendant lay the book in the water. The attendant punctured a needle into the front cover, as he would into a vein, and lit the wick in the needle's tube. He did this out of habit; the book lacked the biology to carry the smoldering wax's substance throughout the bloodstream, but this was how the dreaming was induced.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It was two hours before any change was noted. The Speaker still stood over the dreamers, patient, faithful, and curious. The teenage girl stirred and minds melded in the stream. Her limbs twitched as the lingering consciousness from the book felt forgotten corporeality.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Speak," commanded the Speaker. The girl remained silent and made small splashes as she moved. The Speaker said, "I seek the source of whispers."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He continued his commands until the girl settled down. Finally she spoke in her young voice, "I refuse."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"You are powerless to refuse. You will navigate the sea of dreams and find for me the source."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I can't move."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Tell me what you see."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"I see everything. The dreams of everything. All at once, every one a shadow, fluid."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Look beyond them."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"There is only darkness beyond the dreams."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Go there. I compel you." His voice reverberated in the chamber. He had not chosen to pursue this. He didn't consider it a choice. He was following the will of his masters, as spoken through the dreamers.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Whispers... I feel them... Pressure... I can't understand them, but every syllable crushes me..."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Move toward it. I will speak to it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"There's a being-shapeless, immense... there's... an eye-"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At that moment the temple erupted with shrieks and wails of terror and pain. The Speaker fell forward and moaned, devoid of any thought or function. The young dreamer convulsed and died. At the temple's entrance worshippers ran into the town, possessed of nightmarish panic. They dashed themselves into walls and gouged at their throats with any tool available, trying to wake themselves from the nightmare they were in fact not in. Others remained in the temple, writhing and gurgling in the blessed water. Either they were stronger than the others, or perhaps more susceptible to the climactic vision, but they survived nonetheless. Of that moment, all could remember nothing more than the color yellow.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The temple was soon reopened for public worship. The surviving worshippers who rose to prominence joined the remaining priests. They became the caretakers of the temple that housed the Book of Sable, on whose pages appeared the names of the faithful who died for the Lord of Nightmares on that day.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_THE_NEXUS</Tag>
		<English>The Nexus</English>
		<French>Nexus</French>
		<German>Der Nexus</German>
		<Italian>Il Nexus</Italian>
		<Spanish>El Nexo</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_THEATRE_OF_DREAMS</Tag>
		<English>Theatre of Dreams</English>
		<French>Théâtre des Rêves</French>
		<German>Theater der Träume</German>
		<Italian>Teatro dei Sogni</Italian>
		<Spanish>Teatro de los Sueños</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_ALTERATION</Tag>
		<English>Tower of Alteration</English>
		<French>Tour d'Altération</French>
		<German>Turm der Alteration</German>
		<Italian>Torre dell'Alterazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Torre de la Alteración</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_ALTERATION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>This tower both increases your own units' resistance to spells and reduces your enemies' resistance to your spells.</English>
		<French>Cette tour augmente la résistance de vos unités face aux sorts hostiles, et réduit les chances de l'ennemi de résister aux vôtres.</French>
		<German>Reduziert die Chancen des Gegners, Zaubern zu widerstehen um 10%.</German>
		<Italian>Questa torre aumenta la resistenza alle magie delle tue unità e riduce quella delle unità nemiche alle tue magie.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Reduce la probabilidad de que el enemigo sea capaz de resistir conjuros en un 10%.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_COMPLACENCY</Tag>
		<English>Tower of Complacency</English>
		<French>Tour de Complaisance</French>
		<German>Turm der Selbstzufriedenheit</German>
		<Italian>Torre della Compiacenza</Italian>
		<Spanish>Torre de la Complacencia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_COMPLACENCY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Text must be written</English>
		<French>Text must be written</French>
		<German>Text must be written</German>
		<Italian>Deve essere ancora scritta</Italian>
		<Spanish>Text must be written</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_COMPLACENCY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Tower of Complacency exerts a powerful mental influence over the citizens of the city that builds it. The people become little more than drones, mindlessly following their overlords' commands. All unhappiness is removed, but the productivity of the city suffers.</English>
		<French>La Tour de Complaisance exerce une puissante influence mentale sur les citoyens de la ville qui la construit. Le peuple devient à peine plus que des drones, suivant les ordres de leur suzerain sans réfléchir. Le mécontentement est supprimé, mais la productivité de la ville en souffre.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Der Turm der Selbstzufriedenheit übt einen starken mentalen Einfluss auf die Bewohner der Stadt aus, in der er errichtet wurde. Die Menschen werden wie Drohnen, folgen willenlos den Befehlen ihres Herrschers. Dadurch gibt es keine Unzufriedenheit in der Stadt, aber die Produktivität leidet auch.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La Torre della Compiacenza esercità una forte influenza mentale sui cittadini della città in cui viene costruita. Le persone diventano poco più che automi, seguendo i comandi impartitigli dai loro sovrani senza pensare. Non vi è più malcontento, ma la produttività della città ne risente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]La Torre de la Complacencia ejerce una potente influencia mental sobre los habitantes de la ciudad donde es construida.  La gente se vuelve poco más que autómatas que siguen las órdenes de sus comandantes supremos inconscientemente.  Toda la infelicidad es eliminada, pero la porductividad de la ciudad se ve afectada.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_DIVINATION</Tag>
		<English>Tower of Divination</English>
		<French>Tour de Divination</French>
		<German>Turm der Weissagung</German>
		<Italian>Torre della Divinazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Torre de la Adivinación</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_MASTERY</Tag>
		<English>Tower of Mastery</English>
		<French>Tour de Maîtrise</French>
		<German>Turm der Macht</German>
		<Italian>Torre della Maestria</Italian>
		<Spanish>Torre de la Maestría</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_MASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Text must be written</English>
		<French>Text must be written</French>
		<German>Text must be written</German>
		<Italian>Deve essere ancora scritta</Italian>
		<Spanish>Text must be written</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_MASTERY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A civilization that completes the Tower of Mastery wins the game.</English>
		<French>Une civilisation qui termine la Tour de Maîtrise gagne la partie.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Der Erbauer des Turms der Macht gewinnt das Spiel.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La civilità che costruisce la Torre della Maestria vince la partita (se attiva questa modalità di vittoria).</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]La civilización que complete la Torre de la Maestría gana la partida.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_NECROMANCY</Tag>
		<English>Tower of Necromancy</English>
		<French>Tour de Nécromancie</French>
		<German>Turm der Nekromantie</German>
		<Italian>Torre della Necromanzia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Torre de la Nigromancia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_NECROMANCY_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the amount of skeletons its empire can summon by 5[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Your Undead start with the [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG]Strong[\LINK] promotion</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Augmente de 5 le nombre de Squelettes qu'un empire peut évoquer[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Vos morts-vivants entrent en jeu avec la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG]Fort[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erhöht die Anzahl der Skelette, die das Reich beschwören kann um 5[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Euer Untoter beginnt mit der [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG]Strong[\LINK] Beförderung.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Aumenta la quantità di scheletri evocabili dalla civiltà che la costruisce di 5[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Le tue unità non morte iniziano con la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG]Forte[\LINK]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Increases the amount of skeletons its empire can summon by 5[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Your Undead start with the [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG]Strong[\LINK] promotion</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_NECROMANCY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases the amount of skeletons its empire can summon by 5.</English>
		<French>Augmente de 5 le nombre de Squelettes qu'un empire peut évoquer</French>
		<German>Erhöht die Anzahl der Skelette, die das Reich beschwören kann um 5</German>
		<Italian>Aumenta la quantità di scheletri evocabili dalla civiltà che la costruisce di 5.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aumenta la cantidad de esqueletos que puede tener el imperio en 5.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_THE_ELEMENTS</Tag>
		<English>Tower of the Elements</English>
		<French>Tour des Éléments</French>
		<German>Turm der Elemente</German>
		<Italian>Torre degli Elementi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Torre de los Elementos</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Your Elementals start with the [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG]Strong[\LINK] promotion[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Summons a permanent elemental guardian.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Vos élémentaires entrent en jeu avec la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG]Fort[\LINK].[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Un gardien élémentaire permanent est évoqué.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Eure Elementare beginnen mit der [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG]Strong[\LINK] Beförderung[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Beschwört einen permanenten elementaren Wächter.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]I tuoi Elementali iniziano con la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG]Forte[\LINK][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Evoca un guardiano elementale permanente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Your Elementals start with the [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG]Strong[\LINK] promotion[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Summons a permanent elemental guardian.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOWER_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases the strength of all your Air, Earth, Fire, Nature and Water summons by 1.</English>
		<French>Augmente de 1 la force de toutes vos évocations d'Air, d'Eau, de Feu, de Nature et de Terre.</French>
		<German>Erhöht die Stärke all Eurer Luft-, Erd-, Feuer-, Natur- und Wasserbeschwörungen um 1.</German>
		<Italian>Aumentà di 1 la forza di tutte le unità evocate di Aria, Terra, Fuoco, Natura e Acqua.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aumenta en 1 la fuerza de todas las invocaciones de Aire, Tierra, Fuego, Naturaleza y Agua.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WINTER_PALACE</Tag>
		<English>Winter Palace</English>
		<French>Palais d'Hiver</French>
		<German>Sommerresidenz</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo Invernale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio de Invierno</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CITADEL_OF_THE_HAND</Tag>
		<English>Citadel of the Hand</English>
		<French>Citadelle de la Main</French>
		<German>Zitadelle der Hand</German>
		<Italian>Cittadella della Mano</Italian>
		<Spanish>Citadel of the Hand</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>