<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - Misc -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ELOHIM_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Elohim</English>
		<French>élohion:élohionne:élohions:élohionnes</French>
		<German>Elohimisch</German>
		<Italian>Elohim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Elohim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ELOHIM_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Elohim</English>
		<French>Elohim</French>
		<German>Reich der Elohim</German>
		<Italian>Elohim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Elohim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ELOHIM_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Elohim</English>
		<French>Élohions</French>
		<German>Elohim</German>
		<Italian>Elohim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Elohim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ELOHIM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In the Age of Dragons the gods waged war through proxies, fierce Dragons, wild Krakens, and armies of lesser angels and demons and, rarely, face to face. In either case, the destruction caused was cataclysmic.[PARAGRAPH:1]Immanuel Logos was a follower of Sirona, Goddess of Wisdom. He ruled a small tribe in her name, dispensing wisdom and providing shelter for her followers. Until one day he observed her army, a phalanx of titans, marching upon a stronghold of Aeron. The armies met in a field worked by a group of subsistence farmers. When the battle ended, the armies were tattered, but the bystanders were worse, broken in body, fields destroyed, and despondent of spirit. It was a scene played out countless times, as dragons crushed struggling settlements when they clashed or holy fire rained down upon those caught in the middle. Immanuel believed in his goddess, but he could no longer stand on the sidelines, nor confine his care to his own people.[PARAGRAPH:1]Off came his regal symbols, and he tossed aside his sacred spear for the last time. He gathered orphaned children in his arms, and doled comfort to the dying. Sirona watched this noble leader leave her service but did not forbid him leaving. She knew that for humanity to survive, they needed more than someone fighting on their behalf. They needed care and shelter through the days of heavenly warfare.[PARAGRAPH:1]Thus was born an order of monks. Before the compact, they had no permanent home. They traveled the world, tending to the battered and broken under the guidance of Immanuel and his successors, who took his name to show their spiritual heritage and authority. Their service attracted other kind-hearted souls to their numbers, and they became one of the most trusted groups in the eyes of men and angels. Thus, when the compact was forged, they were the only mortals who witnessed the handing of the Godslayer to the legend Finner. The agreement of the gods to withdraw from direct combat in mortal realms was met by the world Erebus herself with great joy, and at that spot seven fir trees were born to stand witness. Before departing, Sucellus tasked the order of the Elohim with tending to this and other sacred sites, some symbols of great importance, some fonts of power.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the kingdoms of men arose in the Age of Magic, the Elohim continued this mission, peacefully when possible, with force when necessary. Warlords who searched for clues to the location of Finner's tomb, wizards who coveted an angel's tears for his magics, and others sought the Elohim's knowledge, secrets that they often died to protect. The warrior monk tradition was begun in these trying times, men who carried no weapon, so anathema was warfare to them, but could subdue marauders within the blink of an eye. The monk's purity was a ward against the more vile forces that sought to harm their charges.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then came Bhall's fall and Mulcarn's breach of the Compact. The Elohim lost contact with many of their sacred sites, abandoning them to the elements and wild men. But they returned to their original mission, and traveled to desperate communities, tending to disease and enshrining dying knowledge in chants and stories so when rebirth came, it would be swift and complete. As in the Age of Dragons, their numbers swelled with those inspired by their example, and they became not just an order, but a nation.[PARAGRAPH:1]Today that nation has emerged into the sunlight of rebirth. Einion Logos is the head of the ancient order of Elohim, a position of unequaled respect. He is ancient himself, but wishes to live however long enough to see his followers reclaim their shrines. Gariel the Strong was the King of the Elohim nation which shelters the order. He led his people out of the Age of Ice, but his reign was cut short by illness and passed to Ethne the White, his daughter who must now withstand the trials of the Age of Rebirth.</English>
		<French>In the Age of Dragons the gods waged war through proxies, fierce Dragons, wild Krakens, and armies of lesser angels and demons and, rarely, face to face. In either case, the destruction caused was cataclysmic.[PARAGRAPH:1]Immanuel Logos was a follower of Sirona, Goddess of Wisdom. He ruled a small tribe in her name, dispensing wisdom and providing shelter for her followers. Until one day he observed her army, a phalanx of titans, marching upon a stronghold of Aeron. The armies met in a field worked by a group of subsistence farmers. When the battle ended, the armies were tattered, but the bystanders were worse, broken in body, fields destroyed, and despondent of spirit. It was a scene played out countless times, as dragons crushed struggling settlements when they clashed or holy fire rained down upon those caught in the middle. Immanuel believed in his goddess, but he could no longer stand on the sidelines, nor confine his care to his own people.[PARAGRAPH:1]Off came his regal symbols, and he tossed aside his sacred spear for the last time. He gathered orphaned children in his arms, and doled comfort to the dying. Sirona watched this noble leader leave her service but did not forbid him leaving. She knew that for humanity to survive, they needed more than someone fighting on their behalf. They needed care and shelter through the days of heavenly warfare.[PARAGRAPH:1]Thus was born an order of monks. Before the compact, they had no permanent home. They traveled the world, tending to the battered and broken under the guidance of Immanuel and his successors, who took his name to show their spiritual heritage and authority. Their service attracted other kind-hearted souls to their numbers, and they became one of the most trusted groups in the eyes of men and angels. Thus, when the compact was forged, they were the only mortals who witnessed the handing of the Godslayer to the legend Finner. The agreement of the gods to withdraw from direct combat in mortal realms was met by the world Erebus herself with great joy, and at that spot seven fir trees were born to stand witness. Before departing, Sucellus tasked the order of the Elohim with tending to this and other sacred sites, some symbols of great importance, some fonts of power.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the kingdoms of men arose in the Age of Magic, the Elohim continued this mission, peacefully when possible, with force when necessary. Warlords who searched for clues to the location of Finner's tomb, wizards who coveted an angel's tears for his magics, and others sought the Elohim's knowledge, secrets that they often died to protect. The warrior monk tradition was begun in these trying times, men who carried no weapon, so anathema was warfare to them, but could subdue marauders within the blink of an eye. The monk's purity was a ward against the more vile forces that sought to harm their charges.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then came Bhall's fall and Mulcarn's breach of the Compact. The Elohim lost contact with many of their sacred sites, abandoning them to the elements and wild men. But they returned to their original mission, and traveled to desperate communities, tending to disease and enshrining dying knowledge in chants and stories so when rebirth came, it would be swift and complete. As in the Age of Dragons, their numbers swelled with those inspired by their example, and they became not just an order, but a nation.[PARAGRAPH:1]Today that nation has emerged into the sunlight of rebirth. Einion Logos is the head of the ancient order of Elohim, a position of unequaled respect. He is ancient himself, but wishes to live however long enough to see his followers reclaim their shrines. Gariel the Strong was the King of the Elohim nation which shelters the order. He led his people out of the Age of Ice, but his reign was cut short by illness and passed to Ethne the White, his daughter who must now withstand the trials of the Age of Rebirth.</French>
		<German>Im Zeitalter der Drachen führten die Götter ihre Kriege mit Hilfe von Stellvertretern, grimmigen Drachen, wilden Kraken, Armeen von niederen Engeln und Dämonen und, in seltenen Fällen, auch von Angesicht zu Angesicht. In jedem Fall war die angerichtete Zerstörung verhängnisvoll.[PARAGRAPH:1]Immanuel Logos war ein Anhänger von Sirona, der Göttin der Weisheit. Er regierte einen kleinen Stamm in ihrem Namen, verbreitete sein Wissen und bot ihren Anhängern Schutz. Bis er eines Tages sah, wie ihre Armee, eine Phalanx von Titanen, auf eine Festung von Aeron vorrückte. Die Armeen trafen sich auf einem Feld, das von einigen Bauern bestellt wurde. Als der Lärm der Schlacht sich legte, waren die stolzen Armeen dezimiert und versprengt, aber die unfreiwilligen Zuschauer hatte es noch härter getroffen: jeder Knochen im Körper gebrochen, ihre Felder zerstört und Mutlosigkeit machte sich in ihren Seelen breit. Diese Szene wiederholte sich unzählige Male, so zerschmetterten aufeinander prallende Drachen ums Überleben kämpfende Siedlungen oder heiliges Feuer ergoss sich über jene, die zwischen den Fronten gefangen waren. Immanuel glaubte an seine Göttin, aber er konnte nicht länger abseits stehen und seine Fürsorge nur seinen eigenen Leuten zukommen lassen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er legte seine königlichen Symbole ab und warf seinen heiligen Speer ein letztes Mal beiseite. Er schloss Waisenkinder in seine Arme und leistete den Sterbenden Beistand. Sirona sah, dass dieser edle Anführer ihre Dienste verließ, jedoch hielt sie ihn nicht zurück. Sie wusste, damit die Menschheit überleben konnte, war mehr nötig als jemand, der in ihrem Namen kämpfte. Die Menschen brauchten Schutz und Fürsorge während der Zeit des himmlischen Krieges.[PARAGRAPH:1]So wurde ein Orden von Mönchen geboren. Vor dem Pakt hatten sie keine feste Heimstatt. Sie zogen durch die Welt und sorgten für die Geschundenen und Gebrochenen unter der Führung von Immanuel und seinen Nachfolgern, die seinen Namen als Zeichen ihrer spirituellen Herkunft und Autorität annahmen. Ihre Aufopferung zog weitere mildtätige Seelen an und sie wurden in den Augen von Menschen und Engeln zu einer der vertrauenswürdigsten Gruppen. So kam es, dass sie, als der Pakt geschmiedet wurde, die einzigen Sterblichen waren, die die Übergabe des Gottesschlächters an den legendären Finner beiwohnten. Die Übereinkunft der Götter, sich aus dem direkten Kampf in der Welt der Sterblichen zurückzuziehen, wurde von der Welt Erebus mit großer Freude aufgenommen und an jener Stelle wurden sieben Tannen als Zeugen des Augenblicks gepflanzt. Bevor er diese Welt verließ, beauftrage Sucellus den Orden der Elohim damit, für diese und andere heilige Stätten zu sorgen, einige davon Symbole von großer Bedeutung, andere Zeichen großer Macht.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als die Königreiche der Menschen im Zeitalter der Magie erblühten, setzten die Elohim diese Mission fort, friedlich, wenn möglich, mit Gewalt, falls nötig. Kriegsherren, die nach Hinweisen auf den Ort von Finners Grab suchten, Zauberer, die eine Engelsträne für ihre Magie begehrten, und andere versuchten, das Wissen der Elohim in ihre Gewalt zu bringen, Geheimnisse, für deren Schutz diese oft ihr Leben ließen. Die Tradition der Krieger-Mönche wurde in jenen schweren Zeiten begründet, Männer, die keine Waffen trugen, da ihnen der Krieg ein Gräuel war, die jedoch jeden Straßenräuber innerhalb eines Augenblicks bezwingen konnten. Die Reinheit der Mönche bildete einen Schutz gegen die bösartigen Kräfte, die ihrer Mission schaden wollten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dann ereignete sich Bhalls Sturz und Mulcarns Bruch des Paktes. Die Elohim verloren den Kontakt zu vielen ihrer heiligen Stätten und überließen sie den Elementen und den Wilden. Aber sie kehrten zu ihrer ursprünglichen Mission zurück, besuchten verzweifelte Gemeinden, behandelten Krankheiten und bewahrten aussterbendes Wissen in Liedern und Geschichten, so dass es bei der Wiedergeburt der Welt schnell und vollständig wiederhergestellt werden könnte. Wie im Zeitalter der Drachen füllten sich ihre Ränge mit jenen, die von ihrem Vorbild inspiriert wurden, und aus dem Orden der Elohim erwuchs eine eigene Nation.[PARAGRAPH:1]Heute ist diese Nation in das Licht der Wiedergeburt getretten. Einon Logos ist das Oberhaupt des altehrwürdigen Ordens der Elohim, eine Stellung, die beispiellosen Respekt gebietet. Er ist selbst ein alter Mann, aber sein Wunsch ist es, lange genug zu leben, um zu sehen, wie seine Anhänger ihre heiligen Stätten zurückgewinnen. Gariel der Starke war der König des Volkes der Elohim, das den Orden schützt. Er führte sein Volk aus dem Zeitalter des Eises hinaus, aber Krankheit setzte seiner Herrschaft ein jähes Ende. Die Krone ging an Ethne die Weiße, seine Tochter, die nun die Prüfungen des Zeitalters der Wiedergeburt meistern muss.</German>
		<Italian>Durante l'Era dei Draghi gli dei combattevano tra loro principalmente attraverso dei loro rappresentanti: Draghi feroci, Kraken selvaggi, ed eserciti di angeli e demoni minori e solo raramente di persona. In ogni caso la distruzione causata era cataclismatica.[PARAGRAPH:1]Immanuel Logos era un seguace di Sirona, Dea della Saggezza. Guidava una piccola tribù in suo nome, distribuendo saggezza e fornendo riparo ai seguaci della dea. Fino a quando, un giorno, guardò una delle sue armate, una falange di titani, in marcia verso una roccaforte di Aeron. Gli eserciti si scontrarono sui campi lavorati da un gruppo di agricoltori di sussistenza. Quando la battaglia finì, gli eserciti erano malconci, ma gli astanti erano messi peggio, distrutti nel corpo, con i campi distrutti, e abbattuti nello spirito. Era una scena che si era ripetuta innumerevoli volte, quando i draghi schiacciavano insediamenti durante i loro duelli o quando il fuoco sacro cadeva su quelli presi nel mezzo. Immanuel riponeva la sua fiducia nella sua dea, ma non poteva più stare da parte, ne limitare le sue cure solo alla sua gente.[PARAGRAPH:1]Gettò via i suoi simboli regali, e mise da parte la sua lancia sacra per l'ultima volta. Raccolse tra le sue braccia gli orfani, e confortò i morenti. Sirona vide questo nobile leader abbandonare il suo servizio, ma non gli impedì di andarsene. Sapeva che, perché gli uomini potessero sopravvivere, avevano bisogno di qualcuno che faceva altro oltre a combattere in loro vece. Avevano bisogno di cure e di un riparo durante i giorni di guerra divina.[PARAGRAPH:1]E cosi nacque un ordine di monaci. Prima del patto non avevano una casa permanente. Giravano per il mondo, prendendosi cura dei malati e dei feriti sotto la guida di Immanuel e dei suoi sucessori, che presero il suo cognome come dimostrazione della loro eredita spirituale e autorità. Le loro azioni attirarono altre anime dal cuore gentile crescendo di numero, e divennerò uno dei gruppi più fidati agli occhi degli uomini e degli angeli. E cosi, quando il patto fu siglato, loro furono gli unici mortali che assistetterò alla consegna della Sterminatrice di Dei alla leggenda Finner. L'accordo tra gli dei di non combattere direttamente nel reame dei mortali fu accolto dal mondo di Erebus con grande gioia, e in quel punto sette pini nacquero per fare da testimoni. Prima di andare via, Sucellus incaricò l'ordine degli Elohim di prendersi cura di questo e degli altri siti sacri, alcuni in quanto simboli di grande importanza, altri in quanto fonti di potere.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quando i regni degli uomini si svilupparono durante l'Era della Magia, gli Elohim continuarono la loro missione, pacificamente quando possibile, con la forza quando necessario. Signori della guerra che cercavano indizi sulla locazione della tomba di Finner, incantatori che bramavano le lacrime di angelo per la loro magia e molti altri cercavano la conoscenza degli Elohim, segreti che spesso proteggevano sino alla morte. La tradizione dei monaci guerrieri iniziò in quei tempi difficili, uomini che non portavano armi, il cui anatema era la guerra, ma che potevano neutralizzare dei predoni in un battito di ciglia. La purezza del monaco faceva da scudo contro le forze più malvage che miravano a ferire i loro protetti.[PARAGRAPH:1]Poi Bhall cadde e Mulcarn infranse il Patto. Gli Elohim persero i contatti con molti dei loro luoghi sacri, abbandonandoli agli elementi e agli uomini selvaggi. Ma tornarono alla loro missione originale, e viaggiarono tra le comunità disperate, occupandosi dei malati e salvando la conoscenza in canti e storie cosi che quando la rinascità sarebbe arrivata essa sarebbe stata rapida e completa. Come durante l'Era dei Draghi, il loro numero aumentò con coloro che seguivano il loro esempio, divenendo non un semplice ordine ma una nazione.[PARAGRAPH:1]Oggi quella nazione è emersa nella luce della rinascita. Einion Logos è a capo dell'antico ordine degli Elohim, una posizione di ineguagliato rispetto. Lui stesso è anziano, ma desidera vivere abbastanza a lungo da vedere i suoi seguaci reclamare i loro santuari. Gariel il Forte era il Re della nazione che offrì riparo all'ordine Elohim. Guidò il suo popolo fuori dall'Era del Ghiaccio, ma il suo regno fu interrotto presto dalla malattia ed ora è Ethne la Bianca, sua figlia, a dover superare le prove dell'Era della Rinascita.</Italian>
		<Spanish>In the Age of Dragons the gods waged war through proxies, fierce Dragons, wild Krakens, and armies of lesser angels and demons and, rarely, face to face. In either case, the destruction caused was cataclysmic.[PARAGRAPH:1]Immanuel Logos was a follower of Sirona, Goddess of Wisdom. He ruled a small tribe in her name, dispensing wisdom and providing shelter for her followers. Until one day he observed her army, a phalanx of titans, marching upon a stronghold of Aeron. The armies met in a field worked by a group of subsistence farmers. When the battle ended, the armies were tattered, but the bystanders were worse, broken in body, fields destroyed, and despondent of spirit. It was a scene played out countless times, as dragons crushed struggling settlements when they clashed or holy fire rained down upon those caught in the middle. Immanuel believed in his goddess, but he could no longer stand on the sidelines, nor confine his care to his own people.[PARAGRAPH:1]Off came his regal symbols, and he tossed aside his sacred spear for the last time. He gathered orphaned children in his arms, and doled comfort to the dying. Sirona watched this noble leader leave her service but did not forbid him leaving. She knew that for humanity to survive, they needed more than someone fighting on their behalf. They needed care and shelter through the days of heavenly warfare.[PARAGRAPH:1]Thus was born an order of monks. Before the compact, they had no permanent home. They traveled the world, tending to the battered and broken under the guidance of Immanuel and his successors, who took his name to show their spiritual heritage and authority. Their service attracted other kind-hearted souls to their numbers, and they became one of the most trusted groups in the eyes of men and angels. Thus, when the compact was forged, they were the only mortals who witnessed the handing of the Godslayer to the legend Finner. The agreement of the gods to withdraw from direct combat in mortal realms was met by the world Erebus herself with great joy, and at that spot seven fir trees were born to stand witness. Before departing, Sucellus tasked the order of the Elohim with tending to this and other sacred sites, some symbols of great importance, some fonts of power.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the kingdoms of men arose in the Age of Magic, the Elohim continued this mission, peacefully when possible, with force when necessary. Warlords who searched for clues to the location of Finner's tomb, wizards who coveted an angel's tears for his magics, and others sought the Elohim's knowledge, secrets that they often died to protect. The warrior monk tradition was begun in these trying times, men who carried no weapon, so anathema was warfare to them, but could subdue marauders within the blink of an eye. The monk's purity was a ward against the more vile forces that sought to harm their charges.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then came Bhall's fall and Mulcarn's breach of the Compact. The Elohim lost contact with many of their sacred sites, abandoning them to the elements and wild men. But they returned to their original mission, and traveled to desperate communities, tending to disease and enshrining dying knowledge in chants and stories so when rebirth came, it would be swift and complete. As in the Age of Dragons, their numbers swelled with those inspired by their example, and they became not just an order, but a nation.[PARAGRAPH:1]Today that nation has emerged into the sunlight of rebirth. Einion Logos is the head of the ancient order of Elohim, a position of unequaled respect. He is ancient himself, but wishes to live however long enough to see his followers reclaim their shrines. Gariel the Strong was the King of the Elohim nation which shelters the order. He led his people out of the Age of Ice, but his reign was cut short by illness and passed to Ethne the White, his daughter who must now withstand the trials of the Age of Rebirth.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ELOHIM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Elohim have a couple of ways to stay safe in the dangerous world of Erebus, their hero and world spell.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategy: Einion and Thessalonica's Defender trait helps a Builder style of play as repelling invasions gets easier. Monks are decent units fighters and healers regardless of your religion, and by building reliquary buildings your units will pass on their experience. Their hero and World Spell can both save your empire from an unexpected declaration of war. Once the Elohim start claiming cities from other leaders, Thessalonica's Tolerant trait starts to shine, allowing them to build those civilizations' unique units and unique buildings. Captured cities with the Tolerant trait do not allow you to build Elohim unique buildings and units, although any [LINK=BUILDING_PAGAN_TEMPLE]Pagan Temple[\LINK] replacement will still satisfy the requirement of building an [LINK=BUILDING_ABBEY]Abbey[\LINK]. All Elohim units will have -1 Attack Strength outside of their own borders, so conquest will prove more difficult, but Thessalonica may be able to offset that somewhat depending on what new units she is able to produce from her captured cities. Ethne, meanwhile, will give all Disciple Units mobility and increase their experience gain rate, which is useful for the Elohim Monk unique units. Eionin, being Philosophical, is a good choice if you want to go for an Altar of Luonnotar victory. Several of the Elohim unique buildings provide additional priest slots, which will make this victory condition easier for all of the Elohim leaders.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Elohim are the Keepers of Sacred Places. As such, for each of the unique features they have within their borders, they get a different blessing. To assist them with this endeavor, they will start the game by knowing the location of all unique features on the map. The Elohim palace begins with water and nature mana, helping you improve the sometimes less than ideal lands that you'll sometimes settle to pick up these unique features. You may want to pick up sun mana for the [LINK=SPELL_SCORCH]Scorch[\LINK] spell if you end up settling near the tundra unique features. Visit the [LINK=CONCEPT_ELOHIM_KEEPERS_OF_SACRED_PLACES]Elohim - Keepers of Sacred Places[\LINK] Concept Pedia page for a listing of what each unique feature provides.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The Elohim have a couple of ways to stay safe in the dangerous world of Erebus, their hero and world spell.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategy: Einion and Thessalonica's Defender trait helps a Builder style of play as repelling invasions gets easier. Monks are decent units fighters and healers regardless of your religion, and by building reliquary buildings your units will pass on their experience. Their hero and World Spell can both save your empire from an unexpected declaration of war. Once the Elohim start claiming cities from other leaders, Thessalonica's Tolerant trait starts to shine, allowing them to build those civilizations' unique units and unique buildings. Captured cities with the Tolerant trait do not allow you to build Elohim unique buildings and units, although any [LINK=BUILDING_PAGAN_TEMPLE]Pagan Temple[\LINK] replacement will still satisfy the requirement of building an [LINK=BUILDING_ABBEY]Abbey[\LINK]. All Elohim units will have -1 Attack Strength outside of their own borders, so conquest will prove more difficult, but Thessalonica may be able to offset that somewhat depending on what new units she is able to produce from her captured cities. Ethne, meanwhile, will give all Disciple Units mobility and increase their experience gain rate, which is useful for the Elohim Monk unique units. Eionin, being Philosophical, is a good choice if you want to go for an Altar of Luonnotar victory. Several of the Elohim unique buildings provide additional priest slots, which will make this victory condition easier for all of the Elohim leaders.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Elohim are the Keepers of Sacred Places. As such, for each of the unique features they have within their borders, they get a different blessing. To assist them with this endeavor, they will start the game by knowing the location of all unique features on the map. The Elohim palace begins with water and nature mana, helping you improve the sometimes less than ideal lands that you'll sometimes settle to pick up these unique features. You may want to pick up sun mana for the [LINK=SPELL_SCORCH]Scorch[\LINK] spell if you end up settling near the tundra unique features. Visit the [LINK=CONCEPT_ELOHIM_KEEPERS_OF_SACRED_PLACES]Elohim - Keepers of Sacred Places[\LINK] Concept Pedia page for a listing of what each unique feature provides.</French>
		<German>[TAB]The Elohim have a couple of ways to stay safe in the dangerous world of Erebus, their hero and world spell.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategy: Einion and Thessalonica's Defender trait helps a Builder style of play as repelling invasions gets easier. Monks are decent units fighters and healers regardless of your religion, and by building reliquary buildings your units will pass on their experience. Their hero and World Spell can both save your empire from an unexpected declaration of war. Once the Elohim start claiming cities from other leaders, Thessalonica's Tolerant trait starts to shine, allowing them to build those civilizations' unique units and unique buildings. Captured cities with the Tolerant trait do not allow you to build Elohim unique buildings and units, although any [LINK=BUILDING_PAGAN_TEMPLE]Pagan Temple[\LINK] replacement will still satisfy the requirement of building an [LINK=BUILDING_ABBEY]Abbey[\LINK]. All Elohim units will have -1 Attack Strength outside of their own borders, so conquest will prove more difficult, but Thessalonica may be able to offset that somewhat depending on what new units she is able to produce from her captured cities. Ethne, meanwhile, will give all Disciple Units mobility and increase their experience gain rate, which is useful for the Elohim Monk unique units. Eionin, being Philosophical, is a good choice if you want to go for an Altar of Luonnotar victory. Several of the Elohim unique buildings provide additional priest slots, which will make this victory condition easier for all of the Elohim leaders.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Elohim are the Keepers of Sacred Places. As such, for each of the unique features they have within their borders, they get a different blessing. To assist them with this endeavor, they will start the game by knowing the location of all unique features on the map. The Elohim palace begins with water and nature mana, helping you improve the sometimes less than ideal lands that you'll sometimes settle to pick up these unique features. You may want to pick up sun mana for the [LINK=SPELL_SCORCH]Scorch[\LINK] spell if you end up settling near the tundra unique features. Visit the [LINK=CONCEPT_ELOHIM_KEEPERS_OF_SACRED_PLACES]Elohim - Keepers of Sacred Places[\LINK] Concept Pedia page for a listing of what each unique feature provides.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Gli Elohim hanno un paio di modi per stare al sicuro nel pericoloso mondo di Erebus, il loro eroe e la loro magia globale.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategia: Il tratto Difensore di Einion e Thessalonica aiuta uno stile di gioco da Costruttore in quanto respingere le invasioni diviene più semplice. I Monaci sono dei decenti combattenti e guaritori indipendentemente dalla tua religione e costruendo l'edificio Reliquiario le tue unità passeranno ad altre la loro esperienza quando muoiono. Il loro eroe e magia globale possono entrambe salvare il tuo impero da una dichiarazione di guerra inaspettata. Quando gli Elohim iniziano a prendere città da altri leader il tratto Tollerante di Thessalonica inizia a dare i suoi frutti, permettendogli di costruire le unità e gli edifici unici della civiltà conquistata. Il tratto però non permette alle città conquistate di costruire unità o edifici unici degli Elohim, ma qualsiasi [LINK=BUILDING_PAGAN_TEMPLE]Tempio Pagano[\LINK] o sostituto soddisfa comunque i requisiti per l'[LINK=BUILDING_ABBEY]Abbazia[\LINK]. Tutte le unità Elohim subiscono un -1 alla Forza d'Attacco quando sono fuori dai loro confini, pertanto conquistare diviene un pò più difficile del normale, ma Thessalonica, a seconda di quali unità può costruire da città già conquistate, può ovviare a questo malus. Ethne, invece, fornisce a tutte le unità di Discepoli maggiore movimento e aumenta l'esperienza che ottengono automaticamente, cosa molto utile per l'unità unica Monaco degli Elohim. Eionin, essendo Filosofico, è una buona scelta se si vuole conseguire una vittoria Altare dei Luonnotar. Diversi edifici unici Elohim forniscono slot aggiuntivi per i preti nelle città, rendendo la vittoria Altare dei Luonnotar la più semplice per tutti i leader Elohim.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Gli Elohim sono i Custodi dei Luoghi Sacri. Perciò, per ogni caratteristica unica presente all'interno dei loro confini, ottengono un diverso beneficio. Per aiutarli in questa impresa loro iniziano conoscendo la posizione di tutte le caratteristiche uniche. Il palazzo degli Elohim (chiamato Giardini dello Splendore) fornisce il mana della natura e dell'acqua, permettendoti di migliorare le terre, a volte, non esattamente ideali che dovresti colonizzare per avere queste caratteristiche uniche. Potresti voler avere accesso pure al mana del sole per la magia [LINK=SPELL_SCORCH]Bruciatura[\LINK] se colonizzi caratteristiche uniche vicine alla tundra. Vai alla pagina [LINK=CONCEPT_ELOHIM_KEEPERS_OF_SACRED_PLACES]Elohim - Custodi dei Luoghi Sacri[\LINK] dei Concetti nella Civilopedia per una lista dei bonus che ogni caratteristica unica fornisce.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Elohim have a couple of ways to stay safe in the dangerous world of Erebus, their hero and world spell.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategy: Einion and Thessalonica's Defender trait helps a Builder style of play as repelling invasions gets easier. Monks are decent units fighters and healers regardless of your religion, and by building reliquary buildings your units will pass on their experience. Their hero and World Spell can both save your empire from an unexpected declaration of war. Once the Elohim start claiming cities from other leaders, Thessalonica's Tolerant trait starts to shine, allowing them to build those civilizations' unique units and unique buildings. Captured cities with the Tolerant trait do not allow you to build Elohim unique buildings and units, although any [LINK=BUILDING_PAGAN_TEMPLE]Pagan Temple[\LINK] replacement will still satisfy the requirement of building an [LINK=BUILDING_ABBEY]Abbey[\LINK]. All Elohim units will have -1 Attack Strength outside of their own borders, so conquest will prove more difficult, but Thessalonica may be able to offset that somewhat depending on what new units she is able to produce from her captured cities. Ethne, meanwhile, will give all Disciple Units mobility and increase their experience gain rate, which is useful for the Elohim Monk unique units. Eionin, being Philosophical, is a good choice if you want to go for an Altar of Luonnotar victory. Several of the Elohim unique buildings provide additional priest slots, which will make this victory condition easier for all of the Elohim leaders.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Elohim are the Keepers of Sacred Places. As such, for each of the unique features they have within their borders, they get a different blessing. To assist them with this endeavor, they will start the game by knowing the location of all unique features on the map. The Elohim palace begins with water and nature mana, helping you improve the sometimes less than ideal lands that you'll sometimes settle to pick up these unique features. You may want to pick up sun mana for the [LINK=SPELL_SCORCH]Scorch[\LINK] spell if you end up settling near the tundra unique features. Visit the [LINK=CONCEPT_ELOHIM_KEEPERS_OF_SACRED_PLACES]Elohim - Keepers of Sacred Places[\LINK] Concept Pedia page for a listing of what each unique feature provides.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_EINION</Tag>
		<English>Einion Logos</English>
		<French>Einion Logos</French>
		<German>Einion Logos</German>
		<Italian>Einion Logos</Italian>
		<Spanish>Einion Logos</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_EINION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Culva.[PARAGRAPH:1]He always began with "culva", the Lanun word for love. He went through his list, intoned each word and its meaning. At the beginning they were all recited from memory, but each week he added a few more, and he had to read from the journal he kept for the task when he neared the end of the list. [PARAGRAPH:1]She died 2 years ago. He had promised that he would take her to the Aegean Isles, always postponing it. During times of war he was needed for battle, in other times he was needed to maintain the peace. Threatening armies retreated from cities once they found out he was in them, enemies unwilling to negotiate were eager to offer peace when he carried the treaty to their capitals' gates. [PARAGRAPH:1]But there is no good deal that can be made with demons. He had just returned from negotiations with the Infernals, a deep blue demon with a goat's head and shattered bones had agreed to the peace treaty but with several demands. He had lost most of them and that infuriated the demon. He threatened, Einion ignored the threats and demanded complete surrender. The demon had no choice. [PARAGRAPH:1]The treaty was signed, it agreed to end hostilities between the Elohim and the Infernals. That all crimes previous to the signing of that treaty would be forgiven. The demon signed, and smiled.[PARAGRAPH:1]The smile haunted Einion for the 3 days it took to return home. While the others celebrated his success, the end of the war, a dark cloud hung over Einion. When he opened the door to his secluded manor-house he understood why.[PARAGRAPH:1]The stench slammed into him but he had been on enough battlefields to realize immediately what had happened. The curse of knowledge is that it kills hope, you know what has happened, what is happening, what will happen regardless of your desire to remain ignorant. [PARAGRAPH:1]Einion walked through his house, wanting to run to his wife but unwilling to move any faster than a walk through the horrors around him. Blood was everywhere. An elegant glass cabinet in the foyer had had her faced pressed up against it. You could still see the prints of her face and hands in the dried blood, and the fragile shells she had painted herself were inside undamaged. No one had pushed her against the glass, she had been possessed and rubbed and held her face just enough to leave the mark.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was like this in every room. She had climbed unto the rafters in their sitting room and tied her long hair to the rope braces. Then she had leapt off, her hair and patches of flesh from her head still dangled there. The paintings that hung in the hallway to their bedroom had been painted over with cruel messages to him, all in her handwriting. Einion tried to ignore them.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was a grey light coming from their bedroom. It made odd jumping shadows in the hallway, like a tattered flag being waved in front of a lantern. Einion expected to find her dead, but she was unable to die.[PARAGRAPH:1]Her skin was gone, she had carved it off herself, she had torn and pulled most of her joints out of their sockets, and they now hung and flopped at odd angles. The light was from a grey symbol on her chest. A mark that wouldn't allow her to die, but wouldn't relieve her of any of the pain she was experiencing. Her soul was trapped in a tortured body. Her body writhed in pain, her soul could be seen stretching out of it, trying to escape, but held fast by the symbol's power. She had been driven mad by the pain and screamed soundlessly. [PARAGRAPH:1]Einion wept as he knelt by the bed. He cast the spell to dispel the symbol and once it was gone, once he killed her, he collapsed by the bed and prayed for her forgiveness. [PARAGRAPH:1]His Rue-de-guar (shield bearer) found him there that evening when Einion failed to show up to the celebration banquet they had planned for him. The city suffered with their favorite son and his tears were shared by the youngest child to the most veteran warriors. When the city called out for blood, that they must break the truce, only Einion said no. He addressed the Council of Ayes: [PARAGRAPH:1]"If you grieve for me, lay down your arms; if you love me, do not march to the battlefield but return to your wives and children. Let your ships be those of trade and exploration, your dreams be of children playing in the yard and long years spent among friends. I go to bury my wife, with whom I had too little time; do not allow your time to so easily slip by."</English>
		<French>[TAB]Culva.[PARAGRAPH:1]He always began with "culva", the Lanun word for love. He went through his list, intoned each word and its meaning. At the beginning they were all recited from memory, but each week he added a few more, and he had to read from the journal he kept for the task when he neared the end of the list. [PARAGRAPH:1]She died 2 years ago. He had promised that he would take her to the Aegean Isles, always postponing it. During times of war he was needed for battle, in other times he was needed to maintain the peace. Threatening armies retreated from cities once they found out he was in them, enemies unwilling to negotiate were eager to offer peace when he carried the treaty to their capitals' gates. [PARAGRAPH:1]But there is no good deal that can be made with demons. He had just returned from negotiations with the Infernals, a deep blue demon with a goat's head and shattered bones had agreed to the peace treaty but with several demands. He had lost most of them and that infuriated the demon. He threatened, Einion ignored the threats and demanded complete surrender. The demon had no choice. [PARAGRAPH:1]The treaty was signed, it agreed to end hostilities between the Elohim and the Infernals. That all crimes previous to the signing of that treaty would be forgiven. The demon signed, and smiled.[PARAGRAPH:1]The smile haunted Einion for the 3 days it took to return home. While the others celebrated his success, the end of the war, a dark cloud hung over Einion. When he opened the door to his secluded manor-house he understood why.[PARAGRAPH:1]The stench slammed into him but he had been on enough battlefields to realize immediately what had happened. The curse of knowledge is that it kills hope, you know what has happened, what is happening, what will happen regardless of your desire to remain ignorant. [PARAGRAPH:1]Einion walked through his house, wanting to run to his wife but unwilling to move any faster than a walk through the horrors around him. Blood was everywhere. An elegant glass cabinet in the foyer had had her faced pressed up against it. You could still see the prints of her face and hands in the dried blood, and the fragile shells she had painted herself were inside undamaged. No one had pushed her against the glass, she had been possessed and rubbed and held her face just enough to leave the mark.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was like this in every room. She had climbed unto the rafters in their sitting room and tied her long hair to the rope braces. Then she had leapt off, her hair and patches of flesh from her head still dangled there. The paintings that hung in the hallway to their bedroom had been painted over with cruel messages to him, all in her handwriting. Einion tried to ignore them.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was a grey light coming from their bedroom. It made odd jumping shadows in the hallway, like a tattered flag being waved in front of a lantern. Einion expected to find her dead, but she was unable to die.[PARAGRAPH:1]Her skin was gone, she had carved it off herself, she had torn and pulled most of her joints out of their sockets, and they now hung and flopped at odd angles. The light was from a grey symbol on her chest. A mark that wouldn't allow her to die, but wouldn't relieve her of any of the pain she was experiencing. Her soul was trapped in a tortured body. Her body writhed in pain, her soul could be seen stretching out of it, trying to escape, but held fast by the symbol's power. She had been driven mad by the pain and screamed soundlessly. [PARAGRAPH:1]Einion wept as he knelt by the bed. He cast the spell to dispel the symbol and once it was gone, once he killed her, he collapsed by the bed and prayed for her forgiveness. [PARAGRAPH:1]His Rue-de-guar (shield bearer) found him there that evening when Einion failed to show up to the celebration banquet they had planned for him. The city suffered with their favorite son and his tears were shared by the youngest child to the most veteran warriors. When the city called out for blood, that they must break the truce, only Einion said no. He addressed the Council of Ayes: [PARAGRAPH:1]"If you grieve for me, lay down your arms; if you love me, do not march to the battlefield but return to your wives and children. Let your ships be those of trade and exploration, your dreams be of children playing in the yard and long years spent among friends. I go to bury my wife, with whom I had too little time; do not allow your time to so easily slip by."</French>
		<German>[TAB]Culva.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er begann jedes mal mit "culva", dem lanunischen Wort für Liebe. Viele Worte finden sich in seiner Liste und jedem davon sann er in Klang und Bedeutung nach. Anfangs vermochte er sie aus dem Gedächtnis zu rezitieren, aber jede Woche fügte er neue hinzu, so dass er begann, sie in seinem Tagebuch aufzuzeichnen und daraus zu lesen, eh er es beendete.[PARAGRAPH:1]2 Jahre ist es nun her. Er hatte ihr versprochen, mit ihr zu den Ägeischen Inseln zu reisen, doch nie bot sich die Gelegenheit, ihr diesen Traum zu erfüllen. In Zeiten des Krieges war er auf dem Feld unabdingbar und in Zeiten des Friedens oblag ihm die Verantwortung, diesen zu festigen und zu bewahren. Denn seiner Person gegenwärtig, gaben drohende Armeen Belagerungen auf und zogen ab. Feinde, die sich nie zuvor zu Verhandlung bewegen liessen, brannten mit einem mal darauf, Frieden zu schliessen, wenn er ihnen den Vertrag bis vor ihre Stadttore brachte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Doch mit Dämonen können keine wirklich guten und sicheren Verträge ausgehandelt werden. Er kehrte gerade von den Verhandlungen mit den Infernalen zurück; der dunkelblaue Abgesandte der Dämonen mit Ziegenkopf und geborstenen Knochen hatte in ein Friedensabkommen eingewilligt, doch nicht ohne Forderungen, in seinem rasendem Zorn über die verlorene Schlacht. Er drohte, doch Einion ignorierte seine Drohungen und erzwang die vollständige Kapitulation. Der Dämon hatte keine Wahl.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Vertrag, der die Feindschaft zwischen den Elohim und den Infernal beenden sollte, wurde unterzeichnet, auf das jegliche Verbrechen der Vergangenheit vergeben sein. Und mit einem Grinsen unterzeichnete der Dämon.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dieses Grinsen verfolgte Einion Tag für Tag seiner Heimreise. Während die Elohim seinen Erfolg und das Ende des Krieges feierten, lag ihm ein dunkler Schatten auf der Seele. Und als er die Tür zu seinem entlegenen Landsitz öffnete, da wusste er warum.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Gestank. Er kannte ihn vom Schlachtfeld her. Und eine Gewissheit kroch ihm zum Herz hinab und zerquetschte all seine Hoffnung. Eine Gewissheit über das was geschehen war, eine Gewissheit über das, was geschehen sollte, als er ungeachtet seiner mahnenden Stimme den Frieden mit dem Dämon erzwang.[PARAGRAPH:1]So betrat Einion das Haus. Um seiner Frau Willen wollte er rennen, doch zu schwer zerrte der Schrecken an ihm... Blut überall. Die Vitrine im Foyer trug den Abdruck ihres Gesichts und ihrer Hände im getrockneten Blut. Niemand hatte sie gegen die gläserne Tür gestoßen, vielmehr war sie wie besessen gewesen und hatte ihr Gesicht, einen Abdruck hinterlassend, dagegen gedrückt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ein ähnliches Bild zeigte sich ihm in jedem Raum. Im Wohnzimmer war sie unter die Dachsparren geklettert und hatte ihr Haar an der Aufhängung des Vorhangs befestigt. So hat sie sich fallen lassen, ihr Haar und Skalp hingen immer noch dort oben. Die Gemälde, welche entlang des Flures zu ihrem Schlafzimmer hingen, waren übersät mit grausamen, an ihn gerichteten Schriften. Einion versuchte, sie nicht zu beachten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er fand sie ohne Haut; sie hatte sie sich eigens abgeschabt und die meisten ihrer Knochen aus den Gelenken gerissen, so dass sie nun mehr an ihr herunter hingen oder in skurrilen Winkeln vom Körper ab standen. Ein graues Licht strahlte aus einem Mal auf ihrer Brust, welches ihr nicht erlaubte zu sterben noch ihr die Schmerzen nahm. Ihre Seele war gefangen in dieser zerstörten Hülle. Ihr Körper wand sich unter Schmerzen, ihre Seele schien sichtbar, einen Fluchtweg suchend und festgehalten von jenem Mal auf ihrer Brust. Der Schmerz liess sie wahnsinnig werden, fortwährend schreiend, ohne Laut.[PARAGRAPH:1]Einion wimmerte als er an ihrem Bett niedersank. Mit ihrem Tod erlöste er sie von diesem grausamen Fluch, und brach um Vergebung flehend zusammen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sein Rue-de-gar (Knappe) fand ihn dort liegend an jenem Abend, denn er war zu seinem Ehrenbankett nicht erschienen. Sein Reich fühlte mit ihrem großen Helden, vom jüngsten Kind bis zum erfahrensten Krieger wurden Tränen des Leides vergossen. Als sein Volk Blutrache schwor und die Waffenruhe brechen wollte, entschloss Einion sich dagegen. Er sprach zum Rat der Ayes.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Wenn ihr für mich trauert, legt eure Waffen nieder; wenn ihr mich liebt, kehret nicht in die Schlacht, denn zu euren Frauen und Kindern zurück. Lasst eure Schiffe für Handel und Entdeckertum segeln und eure Träume die von spielenden Kindern und Freundschaft sein. Ich werde nun meine Frau, mit der ich zuwenig Zeit teilen durfte, zu Grabe tragen; lasst es nicht zu, dass euch dasselbe Schicksal ereilt."</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Culva.[PARAGRAPH:1]Iniziava sempre con "culva", la parola Lanun per amore. Aveva esaminato la sua lista, intonando ogni parola e il suo significato. All'inizio erano tutte recitate a memoria, ma ogni settimana ne aggiungeva qualcheduna, e doveva leggerle dal diario che teneva quando si avvicinava alla fine della lista. [PARAGRAPH:1]Lei era morta 2 anni fa. Gli aveva promesso che l'avrebbe portata alle Isole Aegean, ma aveva sempre procastinato. Durante le guerre lui era richesto per le battaglie, mentre durante gli altri periodi era chiamato per mantenere la pace. Le armate assedianti si ritiravano quando sapevano che dentro la città vi era lui, i nemici che non volevano negoziare offrivano rapidamente la pace quando era lui a portare l'accordo alle porte della loro capitale. [PARAGRAPH:1]Ma non vi è alcun possibile buon accordo che può essere fatto con i demoni. Era appena tornato dalle nogoziazioni con gli Infernali, un demone color blu scuro con la testa da capra e ossa spezzate aveva accettato l'accordo di pace, ma con parecchie richieste. Ne aveva perse la maggior parte, e ciò faceva infuriare il demone. Lo minacciò, ma Einion ignorò le minaccie e chiese la resa totale. Il demone non aveva scelta. [PARAGRAPH:1]Il trattato fu siglato, esso consisteva nel cessare le ostilità tra gli Elohim e gli Infernali. Che tutti i crimini commessi prima della firma del trattato sarebberò stati perdonati. Il demone firmò, e sorrise.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quel sorriso perseguitò Einion per i 3 giorni del ritorno a casa. Mentre gli altri celebravano il suo successo, la fine della guerra, un malumore rimaneva su Einion. Quando aprì la porta del suo isolato maniero capì il perché.[PARAGRAPH:1]La puzza lo colpì, ma era stato su abbastanza campi di battaglia da capire immediatamente cosa era successo. La maledizione della conoscenza è ciò che uccide la speranza, tu sai cosa è successo, cosa sta succedendo e cosa succedera indiferrentemente dal tuo desiderio di rimanere ignorante. [PARAGRAPH:1]Einion camminò per casa sua, volendo tornare di corsa dalla moglie, ma non volendo andare più veloce del semplice camminare attraverso gli orrori attorno a lui. C'era sangue dappertutto. In una vetrina elegante nell'atrio trovò l'impronta della faccia di lei impressa. Si potevano ancora vedere le impronte del suo volto e delle sue mani nel sangue secco, e le fragili conchiglie che lei stessa aveva colorato erano integre. Nessuno l'aveva spinta contro il vetro, era stata posseduta e il suo volto era stato strofinato abbastanza a lungo da lasciare il segno.[PARAGRAPH:1]In ogni stanza era la stessa scena. Si era arrampicata sino alle travi del salotto e aveva legato i suoi lunghi capelli agli agganci per le corde. Poi era saltata giu; i suoi capelli, e pezzi di scalpo, erano ancora appesi. I dipinti che erano appesi nel corridoio che portava alla loro camera da letto erano stati imbrattati con dei messaggi crudeli diretti a lui, tutti nella scrittura di lei. Einion provò ad ignorarli.[PARAGRAPH:1]Vi era una luce grigia proveniente dalla loro camera da letto. Creava delle strane ombre nel corridoio, come se una bandiera sbrindellata fosse stata messa davanti a una lanterna. Einion si aspettava di trovarla morta, ma lei non poteva morire.[PARAGRAPH:1]La sua pelle era stata rimossa, se l'era tolta lei, si era tolta anche la maggior parte delle articolazioni dalle loro sedi, che ora rimanevano appese ad angoli anormali. La luce proveniva da un simbolo grigio sul suo petto. Un marchio che non gli permetteva di morire, ma che non alleviava minimamente il dolore che lei stava provando. La sua anima era intrappolata in un corpo torturato. Il suo corpo si contorceva dal dolore, e si poteva vedere la sua anima che cercava di staccarsi da esso, ma veniva trattenuta saldamente dal potere del simbolo. Il dolore l'aveva fatta impazzire e urlava senza emettere suono. [PARAGRAPH:1]Einion pianse mentre si inginocchiava vicino al letto. Lui lanciò la magia che avrebbe dissolto il simbolo e dopo che esso sparì, dopo averla uccisa, collassò vicino al letto e pregò per il perdono da parte di lei. [PARAGRAPH:1]Il suo Rue-de-guar (protatore di scudo) lo trovò li, di sera, quando Einion non si presentò al banchetto celebrativo che era stato organizzato in suo onore. La città condivise la sofferenza del suo figlio preferito e le sue lacrime furono condivise dal bambino più giovane sino al guerriero più veterano. Quando la città chiese di aver vendetta e di spezzare la tregua solo Einion disse no. Disse al Consiglio di Ayes: [PARAGRAPH:1]"Se siete tristi per me, deponete le armi; se mi amate non andate sul campo di battaglia, ma tornate dalle vostre mogli e figli. Usate le vostre navi per commerciare ed esplorare, e i vostri sogni siano di bambini che giocano in giardino e di anni passati tra amici. Io vado a seppellire mia moglie, con cui ho passato poco tempo; non permettete al vostro di tempo di passare cosi facilmente."</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Culva.[PARAGRAPH:1]He always began with "culva", the Lanun word for love. He went through his list, intoned each word and its meaning. At the beginning they were all recited from memory, but each week he added a few more, and he had to read from the journal he kept for the task when he neared the end of the list. [PARAGRAPH:1]She died 2 years ago. He had promised that he would take her to the Aegean Isles, always postponing it. During times of war he was needed for battle, in other times he was needed to maintain the peace. Threatening armies retreated from cities once they found out he was in them, enemies unwilling to negotiate were eager to offer peace when he carried the treaty to their capitals' gates. [PARAGRAPH:1]But there is no good deal that can be made with demons. He had just returned from negotiations with the Infernals, a deep blue demon with a goat's head and shattered bones had agreed to the peace treaty but with several demands. He had lost most of them and that infuriated the demon. He threatened, Einion ignored the threats and demanded complete surrender. The demon had no choice. [PARAGRAPH:1]The treaty was signed, it agreed to end hostilities between the Elohim and the Infernals. That all crimes previous to the signing of that treaty would be forgiven. The demon signed, and smiled.[PARAGRAPH:1]The smile haunted Einion for the 3 days it took to return home. While the others celebrated his success, the end of the war, a dark cloud hung over Einion. When he opened the door to his secluded manor-house he understood why.[PARAGRAPH:1]The stench slammed into him but he had been on enough battlefields to realize immediately what had happened. The curse of knowledge is that it kills hope, you know what has happened, what is happening, what will happen regardless of your desire to remain ignorant. [PARAGRAPH:1]Einion walked through his house, wanting to run to his wife but unwilling to move any faster than a walk through the horrors around him. Blood was everywhere. An elegant glass cabinet in the foyer had had her faced pressed up against it. You could still see the prints of her face and hands in the dried blood, and the fragile shells she had painted herself were inside undamaged. No one had pushed her against the glass, she had been possessed and rubbed and held her face just enough to leave the mark.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was like this in every room. She had climbed unto the rafters in their sitting room and tied her long hair to the rope braces. Then she had leapt off, her hair and patches of flesh from her head still dangled there. The paintings that hung in the hallway to their bedroom had been painted over with cruel messages to him, all in her handwriting. Einion tried to ignore them.[PARAGRAPH:1]There was a grey light coming from their bedroom. It made odd jumping shadows in the hallway, like a tattered flag being waved in front of a lantern. Einion expected to find her dead, but she was unable to die.[PARAGRAPH:1]Her skin was gone, she had carved it off herself, she had torn and pulled most of her joints out of their sockets, and they now hung and flopped at odd angles. The light was from a grey symbol on her chest. A mark that wouldn't allow her to die, but wouldn't relieve her of any of the pain she was experiencing. Her soul was trapped in a tortured body. Her body writhed in pain, her soul could be seen stretching out of it, trying to escape, but held fast by the symbol's power. She had been driven mad by the pain and screamed soundlessly. [PARAGRAPH:1]Einion wept as he knelt by the bed. He cast the spell to dispel the symbol and once it was gone, once he killed her, he collapsed by the bed and prayed for her forgiveness. [PARAGRAPH:1]His Rue-de-guar (shield bearer) found him there that evening when Einion failed to show up to the celebration banquet they had planned for him. The city suffered with their favorite son and his tears were shared by the youngest child to the most veteran warriors. When the city called out for blood, that they must break the truce, only Einion said no. He addressed the Council of Ayes: [PARAGRAPH:1]"If you grieve for me, lay down your arms; if you love me, do not march to the battlefield but return to your wives and children. Let your ships be those of trade and exploration, your dreams be of children playing in the yard and long years spent among friends. I go to bury my wife, with whom I had too little time; do not allow your time to so easily slip by."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ETHNE</Tag>
		<English>Ethne the White</English>
		<French>Ethne la Blanche</French>
		<German>Ethne die Weisse</German>
		<Italian>Ethne la Bianca</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ethne the White</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ETHNE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]On the day of her birth, the king decreed that his daughter would never witness the suffering of the world. So Ethne grew up in luxury, tended to by an obedient staff, and she never saw the world past the lavish gardens that surrounded the palace. She grew into a gentle-spirited girl, not expectant or demanding as one might expect of a child in her situation, but kind, without malice of any sort. [PARAGRAPH:1]Her world remained tiny until the day she saw Splendor, a brightly colored blue and yellow parrot that came gliding over the palace hedges. Ethne was 14 and she expected the bird to come to her call, as all of the palace animals had been trained to do so, but he merely sat looking down at her from the branches of the Tulip Poplar tree. [PARAGRAPH:1]Confused but fascinated by the strange bird she brought him fruit and nuts and after she backed away he flew down to the plate she had laid out for him. He landed beside the plate and hopped up to it on one leg, holding the other close to his body. Ethne realized he had been hurt, one of his claws was missing, and she cried for the first time she could remember as she watched him eat and hobble on the edge of the plate. [PARAGRAPH:1]Unable to stand it, Ethne got up and came toward Splendor, wanting to somehow fix him but she only scared him away. His wings were uninjured and in a few seconds he was airborne and he flew out of the palace grounds. Ethne chased after him, overwhelmed with grief for the poor bird. She ran by the marble fountains, the topiary gardens, ponds full of sparkling fish, all without blemish, to the sculpted hedges that marked the borders of her world. And without thinking, she pushed through them and dropped onto the city street beyond into a world unlike anything she had imagined. [PARAGRAPH:1]People pushed and shoved through crowded streets, tired horses dragged wagons through the mud, diseased beggars yelled for charity and were ignored by everyone. People argued over scraps in front of decaying buildings. [PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne wandered the streets for hours, unable to comprehend the suffering that existed outside of the palace gates. Well past nightfall, she was stopped by a man with golden blond hair dressed in blue robes. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Child, do you know that many search and worry for you?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I know. " She answered, too confused to say more. [PARAGRAPH:1]"You have been able to see the world as one outside of it, to know something of perfection and how we fall short of it. It is a rare experience for the mortal mind. "[PARAGRAPH:1]"There is so much evil," Ethne struggled to communicate her thoughts, she didn't have words for most of what she was feeling. "Everything is broken, even the palace life is wrong, when there is so much need outside of it. I haven't seen anything that is good. "[PARAGRAPH:1]The stranger knelt down beside Ethne, his grey eyes locked on her watery blue as he told the following story:[PARAGRAPH:1]A farmer's horse jumped the fence and fled his field. The following day his neighbor came to console him for his loss, saying, 'I am sorry for the evil luck that has befallen you. '[PARAGRAPH:1]The farmer only replied, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]The next day the horse returned and it brought a wild horse with it. The neighbor came back and congratulated the farmer on his good fortune. [PARAGRAPH:1]The farmer only replied, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]A week later the farmer's son was trying to tame the new horse when he was thrown from it and broke his leg. Again the neighbor came back to curse the farmers bad fortune. [PARAGRAPH:1]The farmer only replied, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]On the following day the captain came to the town to recruit men for the war and passed by the farmers son because of his broken leg. Once again the farmer said to the neighbor, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne considered the story before replying, "If this is not evil, then what is?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Good, or evil, isn't what happens to you. It isn't creation. It is what you do about it. When you return to your palace after seeing this, how you have changed will be for good or for evil. "[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne returned to the palace that night, and she took to her studies with a new fervor. She had the hedges removed and looked daily out into the country she was the princess of, determined to take the lesson to heart. [PARAGRAPH:3]Ethne is the last reincarnation of Eve, the Queen of Patria and frequent Wife of Kylorin. [PARAGRAPH:1]After having an affair with Eridanus, Ceridwen enchanted Eve so that she would be reborn every time she dies. She maintains no memory of her past lives. She has lived hundreds of lives many of which Kylorin has shared with her. She led a slave uprising when born into the Calabim, she was a Grigori student of Cassiel and a Lanun pirate queen among many more roles. She is always female, always human and as an adult, she looks very similar to her original form. [PARAGRAPH:1]Eve's great affinity for Fire and Spirit is still largely untrained and uncontrolled. She inspires those that follow her. Her effect can be felt for miles as a feeling of courage, faith and peace. She can inspire entire armies or cities. Her power only remains as long as her own faith is steadfast. During the Age of Magic it was this power (even untrained and before Cerdiwen taught Kylorin how to focus magic) that gave humanity the trust to come together and form a nation. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Magic Eve opposed the Imprimatur Council. This happened across multiple lives and in one Kylorin killed her for trying to raise up a revolution against him. After this he found a copy of Soren Cassamer's "Prison of Reason" among her items and reading it made him question the empire he had created. In her next life (as Erichai) Kylorin let her grow and she founded the Sanctus Inquisition. Kylorin joined the rebellion, which led to the fall of Patria. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Ice she was born as Epona. Again her power was used to unite the Amurites and lead them against Mulcarn. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Rebirth Ethne the White was killed with the Nether Blade, which trapped her soul, delivered it to Laroth in the Otherworld, and disrupted her cycle of rebirth. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Invention, Laroth uses Eve's power to gather a host of dead spirits to his cause. And when Kylorin enters the Otherworld to stop Auric from becoming the god of the dead, it is Eve who stops him. And once Laroth realizes the Ending Stone has been stolen from the Otherworld, Eve and Arak the Erkling lead the Gossamer Legion (an army of ghosts that have followed Eve in ages past) out into creation to recover it from Morrigan and the Matronae. </English>
		<French>[TAB]On the day of her birth, the king decreed that his daughter would never witness the suffering of the world. So Ethne grew up in luxury, tended to by an obedient staff, and she never saw the world past the lavish gardens that surrounded the palace. She grew into a gentle-spirited girl, not expectant or demanding as one might expect of a child in her situation, but kind, without malice of any sort. [PARAGRAPH:1]Her world remained tiny until the day she saw Splendor, a brightly colored blue and yellow parrot that came gliding over the palace hedges. Ethne was 14 and she expected the bird to come to her call, as all of the palace animals had been trained to do so, but he merely sat looking down at her from the branches of the Tulip Poplar tree. [PARAGRAPH:1]Confused but fascinated by the strange bird she brought him fruit and nuts and after she backed away he flew down to the plate she had laid out for him. He landed beside the plate and hopped up to it on one leg, holding the other close to his body. Ethne realized he had been hurt, one of his claws was missing, and she cried for the first time she could remember as she watched him eat and hobble on the edge of the plate. [PARAGRAPH:1]Unable to stand it, Ethne got up and came toward Splendor, wanting to somehow fix him but she only scared him away. His wings were uninjured and in a few seconds he was airborne and he flew out of the palace grounds. Ethne chased after him, overwhelmed with grief for the poor bird. She ran by the marble fountains, the topiary gardens, ponds full of sparkling fish, all without blemish, to the sculpted hedges that marked the borders of her world. And without thinking, she pushed through them and dropped onto the city street beyond into a world unlike anything she had imagined. [PARAGRAPH:1]People pushed and shoved through crowded streets, tired horses dragged wagons through the mud, diseased beggars yelled for charity and were ignored by everyone. People argued over scraps in front of decaying buildings. [PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne wandered the streets for hours, unable to comprehend the suffering that existed outside of the palace gates. Well past nightfall, she was stopped by a man with golden blond hair dressed in blue robes. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Child, do you know that many search and worry for you?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I know. " She answered, too confused to say more. [PARAGRAPH:1]"You have been able to see the world as one outside of it, to know something of perfection and how we fall short of it. It is a rare experience for the mortal mind. "[PARAGRAPH:1]"There is so much evil," Ethne struggled to communicate her thoughts, she didn't have words for most of what she was feeling. "Everything is broken, even the palace life is wrong, when there is so much need outside of it. I haven't seen anything that is good. "[PARAGRAPH:1]The stranger knelt down beside Ethne, his grey eyes locked on her watery blue as he told the following story:[PARAGRAPH:1]A farmer's horse jumped the fence and fled his field. The following day his neighbor came to console him for his loss, saying, 'I am sorry for the evil luck that has befallen you. '[PARAGRAPH:1]The farmer only replied, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]The next day the horse returned and it brought a wild horse with it. The neighbor came back and congratulated the farmer on his good fortune. [PARAGRAPH:1]The farmer only replied, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]A week later the farmer's son was trying to tame the new horse when he was thrown from it and broke his leg. Again the neighbor came back to curse the farmers bad fortune. [PARAGRAPH:1]The farmer only replied, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]On the following day the captain came to the town to recruit men for the war and passed by the farmers son because of his broken leg. Once again the farmer said to the neighbor, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne considered the story before replying, "If this is not evil, then what is?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Good, or evil, isn't what happens to you. It isn't creation. It is what you do about it. When you return to your palace after seeing this, how you have changed will be for good or for evil. "[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne returned to the palace that night, and she took to her studies with a new fervor. She had the hedges removed and looked daily out into the country she was the princess of, determined to take the lesson to heart. [PARAGRAPH:3]Ethne is the last reincarnation of Eve, the Queen of Patria and frequent Wife of Kylorin. [PARAGRAPH:1]After having an affair with Eridanus, Ceridwen enchanted Eve so that she would be reborn every time she dies. She maintains no memory of her past lives. She has lived hundreds of lives many of which Kylorin has shared with her. She led a slave uprising when born into the Calabim, she was a Grigori student of Cassiel and a Lanun pirate queen among many more roles. She is always female, always human and as an adult, she looks very similar to her original form. [PARAGRAPH:1]Eve's great affinity for Fire and Spirit is still largely untrained and uncontrolled. She inspires those that follow her. Her effect can be felt for miles as a feeling of courage, faith and peace. She can inspire entire armies or cities. Her power only remains as long as her own faith is steadfast. During the Age of Magic it was this power (even untrained and before Cerdiwen taught Kylorin how to focus magic) that gave humanity the trust to come together and form a nation. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Magic Eve opposed the Imprimatur Council. This happened across multiple lives and in one Kylorin killed her for trying to raise up a revolution against him. After this he found a copy of Soren Cassamer's "Prison of Reason" among her items and reading it made him question the empire he had created. In her next life (as Erichai) Kylorin let her grow and she founded the Sanctus Inquisition. Kylorin joined the rebellion, which led to the fall of Patria. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Ice she was born as Epona. Again her power was used to unite the Amurites and lead them against Mulcarn. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Rebirth Ethne the White was killed with the Nether Blade, which trapped her soul, delivered it to Laroth in the Otherworld, and disrupted her cycle of rebirth. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Invention, Laroth uses Eve's power to gather a host of dead spirits to his cause. And when Kylorin enters the Otherworld to stop Auric from becoming the god of the dead, it is Eve who stops him. And once Laroth realizes the Ending Stone has been stolen from the Otherworld, Eve and Arak the Erkling lead the Gossamer Legion (an army of ghosts that have followed Eve in ages past) out into creation to recover it from Morrigan and the Matronae. </French>
		<German>[TAB]An dem Tag ihrer Geburt, befahl der König, dass seine Tochter niemals die Leiden der Welt erfahren sollte. So wuchs Ethne in Luxus auf, umsorgt von einer gehorsamen Dienerschaft, und sah nie die Welt hinter den üppigen Gärten, die den Palast umgaben. Sie wuchs zu einem sanften Mädchen auf, nicht erwartungsvoll oder verlangend wie man es von einem Kind in ihrer Situation erwarten hätte können, sondern höflich, ohne jegliche Bosheit. [PARAGRAPH:1]Ihre Welt blieb winzig, bis zu dem Tag, an dem sie Splendor erblickte, einen hellfärbigen, blau-gelben Papagei, der über die Palasthecken geflogen kam. Ethne war 14, und sie erwartete, dass der Vogel auf ihren Ruf zu ihr kommen würde, da alle Tiere des Palastes so abgerichtet waren, doch alles was er tat, war auf den Zweigen der Tulpenpappel zu sitzen, und auf sie herab zu schauen. [PARAGRAPH:1]Verwirrt, aber auch fasziniert von dem fremden Vogel, brachte sie ihm Früchte und Nüsse, und nachdem sie zurück gewichen war, flog er zur Platte, die sie für ihn bereitgelegt hatte, hinunter. Er landete neben der Platte, und hüpfte auf sie auf einem Fuß, und hielt den anderen nahe an seinem Körper. Ethne begriff, dass er verletzt worden war, eine seiner Krallen fehlte, und sie weinte das erste Mal seit sie sich erinnern konnte, während sie ihm beim Essen zusah, und dabei, wie er am Rand der Platte umher hüpfte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie konnte es unmöglich aushalten, und sie stand auf, und näherte sich Splendor, da sie ihn irgendwie heilen wollte, aber sie erschreckte ihn nur. Seine Flügel waren unverletzt, und in ein paar Sekunden war er in der Luft, und flog aus den Palastgründen. Ethne lief ihm nach, überwältigt von Trauer wegen des armen Vogels. Sie rannte vorbei, an den marmornen Brunnen, den Figurengärten, den Teichen, voll von glitzernden Fischen, alle ohne Makel, zu den Hecken mit ihren Figuren, die die Grenzen ihrer Welt bedeuteten. Und ohne nachzudenken, drängte sie sich hindurch, und stürzte in die Stadtstraße dahinter, in eine Welt, die keiner ähnelte, die sie sich hatte vorstellen können.[PARAGRAPH:1]Menschen drängelten und drückten sich durch bevölkerte Straßen, müde Pferde zogen Wägen durch den Schlamm, aussätzige Bettler riefen nach Mitleid, und wurden von jedem ignoriert. Menschen stritten um Abfall vor verfallenden Gebäuden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne wanderte stundenlang in den Straßen, unfähig, das Leiden zu verstehen, das außerhalb ihrer Palasttore existierte. Lang nach Einbruch der Nacht, wurde sie von einem Mann mit goldenem, blondem Haar aufgehalten, der blaue Kleider trug.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kind, weißt du nicht, dass viele nach dir suchen, und sich um dich sorgen?" [PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich weiß." Sie war zu verwirrt, um mehr zu antworten. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Du hattest die Möglichkeit, die Welt als jemand von außerhalb zu betrachten, Perfektion zu wissen, und wie wenig wir davon haben. Das ist eine seltene Erfahrung für einen sterblichen Geist."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Es gibt so viel Schlechtes." Ethne hatte Mühe, ihre Gedanken zu vermitteln, sie kannte keine Wörter für die meisten ihrer Gefühle. "Alles ist zerbrochen, sogar das Leben im Palast ist falsch, wenn es soviel Not hier draußen gibt. Ich habe nichts gesehen, das gut ist."[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Fremde kniete sich neben Ethne, seine grauen sahen in ihre wässrigen blauen Augen, als er ihr die folgende Geschichte erzählte: [PARAGRAPH:1]Das Pferd eines Bauern sprang einst über den Zaun, und floh von seiner Weide. Am nächsten Tag kam sein Nachbar, um ihn für seinen Verlust zu trösten, und sprach: 'Es tut mir Leid, dass dieses Pech dir zugestoßen ist.' [PARAGRAPH:1]Doch der Bauer antwortete nur: 'Wer kann schon sagen, was gut und was schlecht ist?' [PARAGRAPH:1] Am nächsten Tag kam das Pferd zurück, und brachte ein Wildpferd mit sich. Der Nachbar kam wieder, und gratulierte dem Bauern zu seinem Glück.[PARAGRAPH:1]Doch der Bauer antwortete nur: 'Wer kann schon sagen, was gut und was schlecht ist?'[PARAGRAPH:1]Eine Woche später versuchte der Sohn des Bauern, das neue Pferd zu zähmen, doch er wurde abgeworfen, und brach sein Bein. Wieder kam der Nachbar, um das Pech des Bauern zu verfluchen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Doch der Bauer antwortete nur: 'Wer kann schon sagen, was gut und was schlecht ist?'[PARAGRAPH:1]Am nächsten Tag kam der Hauptmann in die Stadt, um Männer für den Krieg zu rekrutieren, und ließ den Sohn des Bauern aus, wegen dessen gebrochenen Beines. Wieder sagte der Bauer zu dem Nachbar: 'Wer kann schon sagen, was gut und was schlecht ist?' [PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne dachte über die Geschichte nach, bevor sie antwortete: "Wenn das nicht schlecht ist, was ist es dann?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Gut oder schlecht, das ist nichts, was dir passiert. Es ist nicht die Schöpfung, sondern was du damit anfängst. Wenn du zu deinem Palast zurückkehrst, nachdem du das alles gesehen hast, wird die Art, in der du dich geändert hast, gut oder schlecht sein." [PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne kehrte in dieser Nacht zum Palast zurück, und sie nahm ihre Studien mit neuer Begeisterung wieder auf. Sie ließ die Hecken entfernen, und betrachtete täglich das Land, dessen Prinzessin sie war, fest entschlossen, sich diese Lektion zu Herzen zu nehmen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Nel giorno della sua nascita il re decretò che sua figlia non avrebbe mai visto la sofferenza del mondo. E cosi, Ethne, crebbe nel lusso, con servitori obbedienti che se ne prendevano cura e non vedendo mai il mondo oltre i sontuosi giardini che circondavano il palazzo. Divenne una ragazza dal cuore gentile, non viziata o esigente come uno potrebbe aspettarsi da un bambina nella sua posizione, ma gentile, senza alcuna malizia di alcun tipo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il suo mondo rimase piccolo sino al giorno in cui vide Splendore, un pappagallo color blu e giallo accesi, che era arrivato planando sopra le siepi del palazzo. Ethne aveva 14 anni e si aspettava che il pappagallo avrebbe risposto al suo richiamo, come facevano tutti gli animali del palazzo in quanto addestrati, invece lui stava li, fissandola tranquillamente dai rami di un Pioppo Tulipano.[PARAGRAPH:1]Confusa ma affascinata dallo strano uccellino lei gli portò frutta e noccioline, e dopo che si fu allontanata lui scese sino al piatto che lei gli aveva lasciato. Atterrò affianco al piatto e vi salì rimanendo su solo una zampa, tenendo l'altra vicina al corpo. Ethne capì che era stato ferito, uno dei suoi artigli era assente, e pianse per la prima volta, almeno per quello che lei ricorda, mentre lo vedeva mangiare e saltellare sul bordo del piatto.[PARAGRAPH:1]Incapace di rimanere immobile, Ethne si alzò e andò verso Splendore, volendo curarlo in qualche modo ma riuscendo solo a farlo allontanare. Le sue ali non erano ferite e in qualche secondo era in aria e volò fuori dal terreno del palazzo. Ethne lo rincorse, soprafatta dalla tristezza per il povero uccellino. Corse vicino alle fontane di marmo, ai giardini topiari, agli stagni pieni di pesci scintillanti, tutti senza imperfezioni, sino alle siepi scolpite che segnavano i confini del suo mondo. E senza pensare le attraversò, finendo nelle strade della città che vi era dietro di esse, entrando in un mondo diverso da qualsiasi cosa avesse mai immaginato.[PARAGRAPH:1]Le persone si facevano largo a spinte in strade affollate, dei cavalli stanchi trainavano carri nel fango, dei mendicanti malati chiedevano la carità e venivano ignorati da tutti. Persone discutevano per degli scarti davanti a degli edifici in rovina.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne girò tra le strade per ore, incapace di comprendere la sofferenza che esisteva al di fuori delle porte del palazzo. Dopo il calar della notte Ethne fu fermata da un'uomo dai capelli dorati vestito di una veste blu.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Piccoletta, sai che molti sono preoccupati per te e ti stanno cercando?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Lo so." Lei rispose, troppo confusa per poter dire altro.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tu hai potuto vedere il mondo come un estraneo, potendo conoscere qualcosa di perfetto e di come noi non ci siamo riusciti. È un'esperienza rara per una mente mortale."[PARAGRAPH:1]"C'è così tanto male." Ethne aveva difficolta a comunicare i suoi pensieri, non conosceva le parole per la maggior parte dei sentimenti che stava provando. "Tutto è sbagliato, anche la vita di palazzo è sbagliata, quando vi è cosi tanto bisogno qua fuori. Non ho visto niente di buono."[PARAGRAPH:1]Lo straniero si inginocchiò affianco a Ethne, i suoi occhi griggi fissi su quelli blu acqua di lei, mentre gli raccontava la seguente storia:[PARAGRAPH:1]Il cavallo di un contadino saltò il suo recinto e scappò. Il giorno seguente il suo vicino andò a consolare il contadino per la sua perdita, dicendogli, 'Mi dispiace per la sfortuna che ti ha colpito.'[PARAGRAPH:1]Il contadino rispose solamente: 'Chi può dire cosa è bene e cosa è male?'[PARAGRAPH:1]Il giorno seguente il cavallo ritornò portando con se un cavallo selvatico. Il vicino tornò di nuovo per congratularsi della sua fortuna.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il contadino rispose solamente: 'Chi può dire cosa è bene e cosa è male?'[PARAGRAPH:1]Una settimana dopo il figlio del contadino cadde dal cavallo selvatico mentre cercava di addomesticarlo rompendosi una gamba. Di nuovo il vicino venne a maledire la sfortuna del contadino.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il contadino rispose solamente: 'Chi può dire cosa è bene e cosa è male?'[PARAGRAPH:1]Nei giorni seguenti un capitano arrivò nel paese per reclutare uomini per la guerra ma lasciò il figlio del contadino per via della gamba rotta. Ancora una volta il contadino disse al vicino: 'Chi può dire cosa è bene e cosa è male?'[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne riflettè sulla storia prima di rispondere, "Se questo non è male, allora che cosa lo è?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Il bene o il male non è qualcosa che ti accade. Non è la creazione. È ciò che tu fai al suo riguardo. Quando tornerai al tuo palazzo dopo aver visto questo, sarai cambiata per il bene o per il male."[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne tornò al palazzo quella notte, e affrontò i suoi studi con una nuova determinazione. Fece anche rimuovere le siepi e guardava ogni giorno la nazione di cui era principessa, decisa a mantenere la lezione appresa nel suo cuore.  [PARAGRAPH:3]Ethne is the last reincarnation of Eve, the Queen of Patria and frequent Wife of Kylorin. [PARAGRAPH:1]After having an affair with Eridanus, Ceridwen enchanted Eve so that she would be reborn every time she dies. She maintains no memory of her past lives. She has lived hundreds of lives many of which Kylorin has shared with her. She led a slave uprising when born into the Calabim, she was a Grigori student of Cassiel and a Lanun pirate queen among many more roles. She is always female, always human and as an adult, she looks very similar to her original form. [PARAGRAPH:1]Eve's great affinity for Fire and Spirit is still largely untrained and uncontrolled. She inspires those that follow her. Her effect can be felt for miles as a feeling of courage, faith and peace. She can inspire entire armies or cities. Her power only remains as long as her own faith is steadfast. During the Age of Magic it was this power (even untrained and before Cerdiwen taught Kylorin how to focus magic) that gave humanity the trust to come together and form a nation. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Magic Eve opposed the Imprimatur Council. This happened across multiple lives and in one Kylorin killed her for trying to raise up a revolution against him. After this he found a copy of Soren Cassamer's "Prison of Reason" among her items and reading it made him question the empire he had created. In her next life (as Erichai) Kylorin let her grow and she founded the Sanctus Inquisition. Kylorin joined the rebellion, which led to the fall of Patria. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Ice she was born as Epona. Again her power was used to unite the Amurites and lead them against Mulcarn. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Rebirth Ethne the White was killed with the Nether Blade, which trapped her soul, delivered it to Laroth in the Otherworld, and disrupted her cycle of rebirth. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Invention, Laroth uses Eve's power to gather a host of dead spirits to his cause. And when Kylorin enters the Otherworld to stop Auric from becoming the god of the dead, it is Eve who stops him. And once Laroth realizes the Ending Stone has been stolen from the Otherworld, Eve and Arak the Erkling lead the Gossamer Legion (an army of ghosts that have followed Eve in ages past) out into creation to recover it from Morrigan and the Matronae. </Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]On the day of her birth, the king decreed that his daughter would never witness the suffering of the world. So Ethne grew up in luxury, tended to by an obedient staff, and she never saw the world past the lavish gardens that surrounded the palace. She grew into a gentle-spirited girl, not expectant or demanding as one might expect of a child in her situation, but kind, without malice of any sort. [PARAGRAPH:1]Her world remained tiny until the day she saw Splendor, a brightly colored blue and yellow parrot that came gliding over the palace hedges. Ethne was 14 and she expected the bird to come to her call, as all of the palace animals had been trained to do so, but he merely sat looking down at her from the branches of the Tulip Poplar tree. [PARAGRAPH:1]Confused but fascinated by the strange bird she brought him fruit and nuts and after she backed away he flew down to the plate she had laid out for him. He landed beside the plate and hopped up to it on one leg, holding the other close to his body. Ethne realized he had been hurt, one of his claws was missing, and she cried for the first time she could remember as she watched him eat and hobble on the edge of the plate. [PARAGRAPH:1]Unable to stand it, Ethne got up and came toward Splendor, wanting to somehow fix him but she only scared him away. His wings were uninjured and in a few seconds he was airborne and he flew out of the palace grounds. Ethne chased after him, overwhelmed with grief for the poor bird. She ran by the marble fountains, the topiary gardens, ponds full of sparkling fish, all without blemish, to the sculpted hedges that marked the borders of her world. And without thinking, she pushed through them and dropped onto the city street beyond into a world unlike anything she had imagined. [PARAGRAPH:1]People pushed and shoved through crowded streets, tired horses dragged wagons through the mud, diseased beggars yelled for charity and were ignored by everyone. People argued over scraps in front of decaying buildings. [PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne wandered the streets for hours, unable to comprehend the suffering that existed outside of the palace gates. Well past nightfall, she was stopped by a man with golden blond hair dressed in blue robes. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Child, do you know that many search and worry for you?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"I know. " She answered, too confused to say more. [PARAGRAPH:1]"You have been able to see the world as one outside of it, to know something of perfection and how we fall short of it. It is a rare experience for the mortal mind. "[PARAGRAPH:1]"There is so much evil," Ethne struggled to communicate her thoughts, she didn't have words for most of what she was feeling. "Everything is broken, even the palace life is wrong, when there is so much need outside of it. I haven't seen anything that is good. "[PARAGRAPH:1]The stranger knelt down beside Ethne, his grey eyes locked on her watery blue as he told the following story:[PARAGRAPH:1]A farmer's horse jumped the fence and fled his field. The following day his neighbor came to console him for his loss, saying, 'I am sorry for the evil luck that has befallen you. '[PARAGRAPH:1]The farmer only replied, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]The next day the horse returned and it brought a wild horse with it. The neighbor came back and congratulated the farmer on his good fortune. [PARAGRAPH:1]The farmer only replied, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]A week later the farmer's son was trying to tame the new horse when he was thrown from it and broke his leg. Again the neighbor came back to curse the farmers bad fortune. [PARAGRAPH:1]The farmer only replied, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]On the following day the captain came to the town to recruit men for the war and passed by the farmers son because of his broken leg. Once again the farmer said to the neighbor, 'Who is to say what is good and what is evil?'[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne considered the story before replying, "If this is not evil, then what is?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Good, or evil, isn't what happens to you. It isn't creation. It is what you do about it. When you return to your palace after seeing this, how you have changed will be for good or for evil. "[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethne returned to the palace that night, and she took to her studies with a new fervor. She had the hedges removed and looked daily out into the country she was the princess of, determined to take the lesson to heart. [PARAGRAPH:3]Ethne is the last reincarnation of Eve, the Queen of Patria and frequent Wife of Kylorin. [PARAGRAPH:1]After having an affair with Eridanus, Ceridwen enchanted Eve so that she would be reborn every time she dies. She maintains no memory of her past lives. She has lived hundreds of lives many of which Kylorin has shared with her. She led a slave uprising when born into the Calabim, she was a Grigori student of Cassiel and a Lanun pirate queen among many more roles. She is always female, always human and as an adult, she looks very similar to her original form. [PARAGRAPH:1]Eve's great affinity for Fire and Spirit is still largely untrained and uncontrolled. She inspires those that follow her. Her effect can be felt for miles as a feeling of courage, faith and peace. She can inspire entire armies or cities. Her power only remains as long as her own faith is steadfast. During the Age of Magic it was this power (even untrained and before Cerdiwen taught Kylorin how to focus magic) that gave humanity the trust to come together and form a nation. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Magic Eve opposed the Imprimatur Council. This happened across multiple lives and in one Kylorin killed her for trying to raise up a revolution against him. After this he found a copy of Soren Cassamer's "Prison of Reason" among her items and reading it made him question the empire he had created. In her next life (as Erichai) Kylorin let her grow and she founded the Sanctus Inquisition. Kylorin joined the rebellion, which led to the fall of Patria. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Ice she was born as Epona. Again her power was used to unite the Amurites and lead them against Mulcarn. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Rebirth Ethne the White was killed with the Nether Blade, which trapped her soul, delivered it to Laroth in the Otherworld, and disrupted her cycle of rebirth. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Age of Invention, Laroth uses Eve's power to gather a host of dead spirits to his cause. And when Kylorin enters the Otherworld to stop Auric from becoming the god of the dead, it is Eve who stops him. And once Laroth realizes the Ending Stone has been stolen from the Otherworld, Eve and Arak the Erkling lead the Gossamer Legion (an army of ghosts that have followed Eve in ages past) out into creation to recover it from Morrigan and the Matronae. </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_THESSALONICA</Tag>
		<English>Thessalonica</English>
		<French>Thessalonica</French>
		<German>Thessalonica</German>
		<Italian>Thessalonica</Italian>
		<Spanish>Thessalonica</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SANCTUARY</Tag>
		<English>Sanctuary</English>
		<French>Sanctuaire</French>
		<German>Heilige Stätte</German>
		<Italian>Santuario</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sanctuary</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_SANCTUARY_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Removes all non-Elohim units from your lands and keeps them from entering for 30 turns</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Repousse toutes les unités non-Elohim de vos terres et les empeche d'entrer pendant 30 tours</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Entfernt alle nicht-Elohim Einheiten aus eurem Land und macht die Grenzübertretung für 30 Runden unmöglich</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Rimuove tutte le unità non Elohim dai tuoi terreni e gli impedisce di entrarvi per 30 turni</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Removes all non-Elohim units from your lands and keeps them from entering for 30 turns</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ABBEY</Tag>
		<English>Abbey</English>
		<French>Abbaye</French>
		<German>Abtei</German>
		<Italian>Abbazia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Abbey</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ABBEY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Bow down my soul in worship very low[NEWLINE]And in the holy silences be lost.[NEWLINE]Bow down before the marble man of woe,[NEWLINE]Bow down before the singing angel host.[NEWLINE]What jewelled glory fills my spirit's eye,[NEWLINE]What golden grandeur moves the depths of me![NEWLINE]The soaring arches lift me up on high[NEWLINE]Taking my breath with their rare symmetry.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Bow down my soul and let the wondrous light[NEWLINE]Of beauty bathe thee from her lofty throne,[NEWLINE]Bow down before the wonder of man's might.[NEWLINE]Bow down in worship, humble and alone;[NEWLINE]Bow lowly down before the sacred sight[NEWLINE]Of man's divinity alive in stone. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]    -- Claude McKay </English>
		<French>Bow down my soul in worship very low[NEWLINE]And in the holy silences be lost.[NEWLINE]Bow down before the marble man of woe,[NEWLINE]Bow down before the singing angel host.[NEWLINE]What jewelled glory fills my spirit's eye,[NEWLINE]What golden grandeur moves the depths of me![NEWLINE]The soaring arches lift me up on high[NEWLINE]Taking my breath with their rare symmetry.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Bow down my soul and let the wondrous light[NEWLINE]Of beauty bathe thee from her lofty throne,[NEWLINE]Bow down before the wonder of man's might.[NEWLINE]Bow down in worship, humble and alone;[NEWLINE]Bow lowly down before the sacred sight[NEWLINE]Of man's divinity alive in stone. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]    -- Claude McKay</French>
		<German>Bow down my soul in worship very low[NEWLINE]And in the holy silences be lost.[NEWLINE]Bow down before the marble man of woe,[NEWLINE]Bow down before the singing angel host.[NEWLINE]What jewelled glory fills my spirit's eye,[NEWLINE]What golden grandeur moves the depths of me![NEWLINE]The soaring arches lift me up on high[NEWLINE]Taking my breath with their rare symmetry.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Bow down my soul and let the wondrous light[NEWLINE]Of beauty bathe thee from her lofty throne,[NEWLINE]Bow down before the wonder of man's might.[NEWLINE]Bow down in worship, humble and alone;[NEWLINE]Bow lowly down before the sacred sight[NEWLINE]Of man's divinity alive in stone. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]    -- Claude McKay</German>
		<Italian>Bow down my soul in worship very low[NEWLINE]And in the holy silences be lost.[NEWLINE]Bow down before the marble man of woe,[NEWLINE]Bow down before the singing angel host.[NEWLINE]What jewelled glory fills my spirit's eye,[NEWLINE]What golden grandeur moves the depths of me![NEWLINE]The soaring arches lift me up on high[NEWLINE]Taking my breath with their rare symmetry.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Bow down my soul and let the wondrous light[NEWLINE]Of beauty bathe thee from her lofty throne,[NEWLINE]Bow down before the wonder of man's might.[NEWLINE]Bow down in worship, humble and alone;[NEWLINE]Bow lowly down before the sacred sight[NEWLINE]Of man's divinity alive in stone. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]    -- Claude McKay</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bow down my soul in worship very low[NEWLINE]And in the holy silences be lost.[NEWLINE]Bow down before the marble man of woe,[NEWLINE]Bow down before the singing angel host.[NEWLINE]What jewelled glory fills my spirit's eye,[NEWLINE]What golden grandeur moves the depths of me![NEWLINE]The soaring arches lift me up on high[NEWLINE]Taking my breath with their rare symmetry.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Bow down my soul and let the wondrous light[NEWLINE]Of beauty bathe thee from her lofty throne,[NEWLINE]Bow down before the wonder of man's might.[NEWLINE]Bow down in worship, humble and alone;[NEWLINE]Bow lowly down before the sacred sight[NEWLINE]Of man's divinity alive in stone. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]    -- Claude McKay</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ABBEY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Construction of an Abbey cannot be started before a number of Monasteries are completed. Once this requirement is met however, the Abbey allows considerable upgrades to your more experienced Monk units.</English>
		<French>Construction of an Abbey cannot be started before a number of Monasteries are completed. Once this requirement is met however, the Abbey allows considerable upgrades to your more experienced Monk units.</French>
		<German>Die Errichtung einer Abtei kann nicht ohne die vorherige Fertigstellung einer gewissen Zahl von Klostern begonnen werden. Ist diese Voraussetzung jedoch einmal erfüllt, erlaubt die Abtei beachtliche Aufwertungen Eurer erfahrenen Mönche.</German>
		<Italian>La costruzione di un'Abbazia non può inizare prima di aver completato un certo numero di Monasteri. Però una volta soddisfatto tale requisito l'Abbazia rende disponibili dei considerevoli miglioramenti per i tuoi monaci più esperti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Construction of an Abbey cannot be started before a number of Monasteries are completed. Once this requirement is met however, the Abbey allows considerable upgrades to your more experienced Monk units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ABBEY_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows visiting monks to achieve [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_PURITY]Purity[\LINK] and [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_FOCUS]Focus[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Allows visiting monks to achieve [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_PURITY]Purity[\LINK] and [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_FOCUS]Focus[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Ermöglicht Mönchen den Erhalt von [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_PURITY]Reinheit[\LINK] und [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_FOCUS]Fokus[\LINK]</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Permette ai monaci che la visitano di ottenere la [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_PURITY]Purezza[\LINK] e [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_FOCUS]Concentrazione[\LINK]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows visiting monks to achieve [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_PURITY]Purity[\LINK] and [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_FOCUS]Focus[\LINK]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARCHIVES</Tag>
		<English>Archives</English>
		<French>Archives</French>
		<German>Archiv</German>
		<Italian>Archivi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Archives</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARCHIVES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"They say that knowledge is power. This is true.", he paused for a moment, allowing the fact to weigh on the minds of the initiates. [PARAGRAPH:1]"That is not all that knowledge is however - it is our history and our heritage, our past and our future. Within the walls of this archive are records dating back before the Ice, transcripts and accounts of the bloodiest of battles, the musings of the greatest minds and the tales of the most legendary bards. You will spend a lifetime within these walls and see yet a fraction of the wonders they contain. Yet the fraction you do see will shape the person you are to become..." [PARAGRAPH:1]     -- Einon Logos, addressing initiates in the Archive of Cahir Abbey</English>
		<French>"They say that knowledge is power. This is true.", he paused for a moment, allowing the fact to weigh on the minds of the initiates. [PARAGRAPH:1]"That is not all that knowledge is however - it is our history and our heritage, our past and our future. Within the walls of this archive are records dating back before the Ice, transcripts and accounts of the bloodiest of battles, the musings of the greatest minds and the tales of the most legendary bards. You will spend a lifetime within these walls and see yet a fraction of the wonders they contain. Yet the fraction you do see will shape the person you are to become..." [PARAGRAPH:1]     -- Einon Logos, addressing initiates in the Archive of Cahir Abbey</French>
		<German>"They say that knowledge is power. This is true.", he paused for a moment, allowing the fact to weigh on the minds of the initiates. [PARAGRAPH:1]"That is not all that knowledge is however - it is our history and our heritage, our past and our future. Within the walls of this archive are records dating back before the Ice, transcripts and accounts of the bloodiest of battles, the musings of the greatest minds and the tales of the most legendary bards. You will spend a lifetime within these walls and see yet a fraction of the wonders they contain. Yet the fraction you do see will shape the person you are to become..." [PARAGRAPH:1]     -- Einon Logos, addressing initiates in the Archive of Cahir Abbey</German>
		<Italian>"Dicono che la conoscenza sia potere. È vero.", si fermò per un momento per permettere all'affermazione di pesare sulla mente degli iniziati. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Però la conoscenza non è solo quello, è la nostra storia e la nostra eredità, il nostro passato e il nostro futuro. Dentro le mura di questi archivi ci sono documenti risalenti a prima del Ghiaccio, trascrizioni e resoconti delle più sanguinose battaglie, le riflessioni delle più grandi menti e i racconti dei più leggendari bardi. Passerete la vita all'interno di queste mura eppure riuscirete a vedere solo una frazione delle meraviglie che contengono. Nonostante ciò la frazione che vedrete plasmerà la persona che diventerete..." [PARAGRAPH:1]     -- Einon Logos, rivolgendosi agli iniziati degli Archivi di Cahir Abbey</Italian>
		<Spanish>"They say that knowledge is power. This is true.", he paused for a moment, allowing the fact to weigh on the minds of the initiates. [PARAGRAPH:1]"That is not all that knowledge is however - it is our history and our heritage, our past and our future. Within the walls of this archive are records dating back before the Ice, transcripts and accounts of the bloodiest of battles, the musings of the greatest minds and the tales of the most legendary bards. You will spend a lifetime within these walls and see yet a fraction of the wonders they contain. Yet the fraction you do see will shape the person you are to become..." [PARAGRAPH:1]     -- Einon Logos, addressing initiates in the Archive of Cahir Abbey</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHANCEL_OF_GUARDIANS</Tag>
		<English>Chancel of Guardians</English>
		<French>Ch&#156;ur des Gardiens</French>
		<German>Altar der Wächter</German>
		<Italian>Presbiterio dei Guardiani</Italian>
		<Spanish>Antealtar de los Guardianes</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHANCEL_OF_GUARDIANS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Increases the defense of the city and has a 20% chance of bestowing the Defensive promotion on any unit produced in the city.</English>
		<French>Augmente la défense de la ville et a 20% de chance d'accorder la promotion Défensif aux unités crées dans la ville.</French>
		<German>Verstärkt die Verteidigung der Stadt, und gewährt eine Chance von 20% darauf, das neue Einheiten mit der Beförderung "Verteidiger" aufgestellt werden.</German>
		<Italian>Aumenta la difesa della città e ha il 20% di probabilità di fornire la promozione Difensivo a qualsiasi unità creata dalla città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Incrementa la defensa de la ciudad y hay un 20% de probabilidades de otorgar el ascenso Defensiva a cualquier unidad producida en la ciudad.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHANCEL_OF_GUARDIANS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]20% chance of bestowing the [LINK=PROMOTION_DEFENSIVE]Defensive[\LINK] promotion on any unit trained in the city</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]20% de chance d'offrir la promotion Défenseur aux unités créées dans la ville</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]20% chance of bestowing the Defensive promotion on any unit trained in the city</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Probabilità del 20% di fornire la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_DEFENSIVE]Difensivo[\LINK] a qualsiasi unità creata dalla città</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]20% chance of bestowing the Defensive promotion on any unit trained in the city</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GARDENS_OF_SPLENDOR</Tag>
		<English>Gardens of Splendor</English>
		<French>Jardins de la Splendeur</French>
		<German>Gärten von Splendor</German>
		<Italian>Giardini dello Splendore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gardens of Splendor</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GARDENS_OF_SPLENDOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The sunlight on the garden[NEWLINE]Hardens and grows cold,[NEWLINE]We cannot cage the minute[NEWLINE]Within its nets of gold;[NEWLINE]When all is told[NEWLINE]We cannot beg for pardon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Our freedom as free lances[NEWLINE]Advances towards its end;[NEWLINE]The earth compels, upon it[NEWLINE]Sonnets and birds descend;[NEWLINE]And soon, my friend,[NEWLINE]We shall have no time for dances.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The sky was good for flying[NEWLINE]Defying the church bells[NEWLINE]And every evil iron[NEWLINE]Siren and what it tells:[NEWLINE]The earth compels,[NEWLINE]We are dying, friends, dying[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And not expecting pardon,[NEWLINE]Hardened in heart anew,[NEWLINE]But glad to have sat under[NEWLINE]Thunder and rain with you,[NEWLINE]And grateful too[NEWLINE]For sunlight on the garden.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] -- Sunlight on the Garden, Louis MacNeice</English>
		<French>The sunlight on the garden[NEWLINE]Hardens and grows cold,[NEWLINE]We cannot cage the minute[NEWLINE]Within its nets of gold;[NEWLINE]When all is told[NEWLINE]We cannot beg for pardon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Our freedom as free lances[NEWLINE]Advances towards its end;[NEWLINE]The earth compels, upon it[NEWLINE]Sonnets and birds descend;[NEWLINE]And soon, my friend,[NEWLINE]We shall have no time for dances.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The sky was good for flying[NEWLINE]Defying the church bells[NEWLINE]And every evil iron[NEWLINE]Siren and what it tells:[NEWLINE]The earth compels,[NEWLINE]We are dying, friends, dying[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And not expecting pardon,[NEWLINE]Hardened in heart anew,[NEWLINE]But glad to have sat under[NEWLINE]Thunder and rain with you,[NEWLINE]And grateful too[NEWLINE]For sunlight on the garden.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] -- Sunlight on the Garden, Louis MacNeice</French>
		<German>The sunlight on the garden[NEWLINE]Hardens and grows cold,[NEWLINE]We cannot cage the minute[NEWLINE]Within its nets of gold;[NEWLINE]When all is told[NEWLINE]We cannot beg for pardon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Our freedom as free lances[NEWLINE]Advances towards its end;[NEWLINE]The earth compels, upon it[NEWLINE]Sonnets and birds descend;[NEWLINE]And soon, my friend,[NEWLINE]We shall have no time for dances.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The sky was good for flying[NEWLINE]Defying the church bells[NEWLINE]And every evil iron[NEWLINE]Siren and what it tells:[NEWLINE]The earth compels,[NEWLINE]We are dying, friends, dying[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And not expecting pardon,[NEWLINE]Hardened in heart anew,[NEWLINE]But glad to have sat under[NEWLINE]Thunder and rain with you,[NEWLINE]And grateful too[NEWLINE]For sunlight on the garden.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] -- Sunlight on the Garden, Louis MacNeice</German>
		<Italian>The sunlight on the garden[NEWLINE]Hardens and grows cold,[NEWLINE]We cannot cage the minute[NEWLINE]Within its nets of gold;[NEWLINE]When all is told[NEWLINE]We cannot beg for pardon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Our freedom as free lances[NEWLINE]Advances towards its end;[NEWLINE]The earth compels, upon it[NEWLINE]Sonnets and birds descend;[NEWLINE]And soon, my friend,[NEWLINE]We shall have no time for dances.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The sky was good for flying[NEWLINE]Defying the church bells[NEWLINE]And every evil iron[NEWLINE]Siren and what it tells:[NEWLINE]The earth compels,[NEWLINE]We are dying, friends, dying[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And not expecting pardon,[NEWLINE]Hardened in heart anew,[NEWLINE]But glad to have sat under[NEWLINE]Thunder and rain with you,[NEWLINE]And grateful too[NEWLINE]For sunlight on the garden.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] -- Sunlight on the Garden, Louis MacNeice</Italian>
		<Spanish>The sunlight on the garden[NEWLINE]Hardens and grows cold,[NEWLINE]We cannot cage the minute[NEWLINE]Within its nets of gold;[NEWLINE]When all is told[NEWLINE]We cannot beg for pardon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Our freedom as free lances[NEWLINE]Advances towards its end;[NEWLINE]The earth compels, upon it[NEWLINE]Sonnets and birds descend;[NEWLINE]And soon, my friend,[NEWLINE]We shall have no time for dances.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The sky was good for flying[NEWLINE]Defying the church bells[NEWLINE]And every evil iron[NEWLINE]Siren and what it tells:[NEWLINE]The earth compels,[NEWLINE]We are dying, friends, dying[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]And not expecting pardon,[NEWLINE]Hardened in heart anew,[NEWLINE]But glad to have sat under[NEWLINE]Thunder and rain with you,[NEWLINE]And grateful too[NEWLINE]For sunlight on the garden.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] -- Sunlight on the Garden, Louis MacNeice</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MINSTER</Tag>
		<English>Minster</English>
		<French>Ministère</French>
		<German>Münster</German>
		<Italian>Cattedrale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Minster</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MINSTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English> Before the Altar, bowed, he stands[NEWLINE]With empty hands;[NEWLINE]Upon it perfumed offerings burn[NEWLINE]Wreathing with smoke the sacrificial urn.[NEWLINE]Not one of all these has he given,[NEWLINE]No flame of his has leapt to Heaven[NEWLINE]Firesouled, vermilion-hearted,[NEWLINE]Forked, and darted,[NEWLINE]Consuming what a few spare pence[NEWLINE]Have cheaply bought, to fling from hence[NEWLINE]In idly-asked petition.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]His sole condition[NEWLINE]Love and poverty.[NEWLINE]And while the moon[NEWLINE]Swings slow across the sky,[NEWLINE]Athwart a waving pine tree,[NEWLINE]And soon[NEWLINE]Tips all the needles there[NEWLINE]With silver sparkles, bitterly[NEWLINE]He gazes, while his soul[NEWLINE]Grows hard with thinking of the poorness of his dole.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Shining and distant Goddess, hear my prayer[NEWLINE]Where you swim in the high air![NEWLINE]With charity look down on me,[NEWLINE]Under this tree,[NEWLINE]Tending the gifts I have not brought,[NEWLINE]The rare and goodly things[NEWLINE]I have not sought.[NEWLINE]Instead, take from me all my life![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Upon the wings[NEWLINE]Of shimmering moonbeams[NEWLINE]I pack my poet's dreams[NEWLINE]For you.[NEWLINE]My wearying strife,[NEWLINE]My courage, my loss,[NEWLINE]Into the night I toss[NEWLINE]For you.[NEWLINE]Golden Divinity,[NEWLINE]Deign to look down on me[NEWLINE]Who so unworthily[NEWLINE]Offers to you:[NEWLINE]All life has known,[NEWLINE]Seeds withered unsown,[NEWLINE]Hopes turning quick to fears,[NEWLINE]Laughter which dies in tears.[NEWLINE]The shredded remnant of a man[NEWLINE]Is all the span[NEWLINE]And compass of my offering to you.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Empty and silent, I[NEWLINE]Kneel before your pure, calm majesty.[NEWLINE]On this stone, in this urn[NEWLINE]I pour my heart and watch it burn,[NEWLINE]Myself the sacrifice; but be[NEWLINE]Still unmoved:  Divinity."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]From the altar, bathed in moonlight,[NEWLINE]The smoke rose straight in the quiet night.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]   -- Amy Lowell, Before the Altar</English>
		<French> Before the Altar, bowed, he stands[NEWLINE]With empty hands;[NEWLINE]Upon it perfumed offerings burn[NEWLINE]Wreathing with smoke the sacrificial urn.[NEWLINE]Not one of all these has he given,[NEWLINE]No flame of his has leapt to Heaven[NEWLINE]Firesouled, vermilion-hearted,[NEWLINE]Forked, and darted,[NEWLINE]Consuming what a few spare pence[NEWLINE]Have cheaply bought, to fling from hence[NEWLINE]In idly-asked petition.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]His sole condition[NEWLINE]Love and poverty.[NEWLINE]And while the moon[NEWLINE]Swings slow across the sky,[NEWLINE]Athwart a waving pine tree,[NEWLINE]And soon[NEWLINE]Tips all the needles there[NEWLINE]With silver sparkles, bitterly[NEWLINE]He gazes, while his soul[NEWLINE]Grows hard with thinking of the poorness of his dole.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Shining and distant Goddess, hear my prayer[NEWLINE]Where you swim in the high air![NEWLINE]With charity look down on me,[NEWLINE]Under this tree,[NEWLINE]Tending the gifts I have not brought,[NEWLINE]The rare and goodly things[NEWLINE]I have not sought.[NEWLINE]Instead, take from me all my life![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Upon the wings[NEWLINE]Of shimmering moonbeams[NEWLINE]I pack my poet's dreams[NEWLINE]For you.[NEWLINE]My wearying strife,[NEWLINE]My courage, my loss,[NEWLINE]Into the night I toss[NEWLINE]For you.[NEWLINE]Golden Divinity,[NEWLINE]Deign to look down on me[NEWLINE]Who so unworthily[NEWLINE]Offers to you:[NEWLINE]All life has known,[NEWLINE]Seeds withered unsown,[NEWLINE]Hopes turning quick to fears,[NEWLINE]Laughter which dies in tears.[NEWLINE]The shredded remnant of a man[NEWLINE]Is all the span[NEWLINE]And compass of my offering to you.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Empty and silent, I[NEWLINE]Kneel before your pure, calm majesty.[NEWLINE]On this stone, in this urn[NEWLINE]I pour my heart and watch it burn,[NEWLINE]Myself the sacrifice; but be[NEWLINE]Still unmoved:  Divinity."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]From the altar, bathed in moonlight,[NEWLINE]The smoke rose straight in the quiet night.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]   -- Amy Lowell, Before the Altar</French>
		<German> Before the Altar, bowed, he stands[NEWLINE]With empty hands;[NEWLINE]Upon it perfumed offerings burn[NEWLINE]Wreathing with smoke the sacrificial urn.[NEWLINE]Not one of all these has he given,[NEWLINE]No flame of his has leapt to Heaven[NEWLINE]Firesouled, vermilion-hearted,[NEWLINE]Forked, and darted,[NEWLINE]Consuming what a few spare pence[NEWLINE]Have cheaply bought, to fling from hence[NEWLINE]In idly-asked petition.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]His sole condition[NEWLINE]Love and poverty.[NEWLINE]And while the moon[NEWLINE]Swings slow across the sky,[NEWLINE]Athwart a waving pine tree,[NEWLINE]And soon[NEWLINE]Tips all the needles there[NEWLINE]With silver sparkles, bitterly[NEWLINE]He gazes, while his soul[NEWLINE]Grows hard with thinking of the poorness of his dole.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Shining and distant Goddess, hear my prayer[NEWLINE]Where you swim in the high air![NEWLINE]With charity look down on me,[NEWLINE]Under this tree,[NEWLINE]Tending the gifts I have not brought,[NEWLINE]The rare and goodly things[NEWLINE]I have not sought.[NEWLINE]Instead, take from me all my life![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Upon the wings[NEWLINE]Of shimmering moonbeams[NEWLINE]I pack my poet's dreams[NEWLINE]For you.[NEWLINE]My wearying strife,[NEWLINE]My courage, my loss,[NEWLINE]Into the night I toss[NEWLINE]For you.[NEWLINE]Golden Divinity,[NEWLINE]Deign to look down on me[NEWLINE]Who so unworthily[NEWLINE]Offers to you:[NEWLINE]All life has known,[NEWLINE]Seeds withered unsown,[NEWLINE]Hopes turning quick to fears,[NEWLINE]Laughter which dies in tears.[NEWLINE]The shredded remnant of a man[NEWLINE]Is all the span[NEWLINE]And compass of my offering to you.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Empty and silent, I[NEWLINE]Kneel before your pure, calm majesty.[NEWLINE]On this stone, in this urn[NEWLINE]I pour my heart and watch it burn,[NEWLINE]Myself the sacrifice; but be[NEWLINE]Still unmoved:  Divinity."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]From the altar, bathed in moonlight,[NEWLINE]The smoke rose straight in the quiet night.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]   -- Amy Lowell, Before the Altar</German>
		<Italian> Before the Altar, bowed, he stands[NEWLINE]With empty hands;[NEWLINE]Upon it perfumed offerings burn[NEWLINE]Wreathing with smoke the sacrificial urn.[NEWLINE]Not one of all these has he given,[NEWLINE]No flame of his has leapt to Heaven[NEWLINE]Firesouled, vermilion-hearted,[NEWLINE]Forked, and darted,[NEWLINE]Consuming what a few spare pence[NEWLINE]Have cheaply bought, to fling from hence[NEWLINE]In idly-asked petition.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]His sole condition[NEWLINE]Love and poverty.[NEWLINE]And while the moon[NEWLINE]Swings slow across the sky,[NEWLINE]Athwart a waving pine tree,[NEWLINE]And soon[NEWLINE]Tips all the needles there[NEWLINE]With silver sparkles, bitterly[NEWLINE]He gazes, while his soul[NEWLINE]Grows hard with thinking of the poorness of his dole.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Shining and distant Goddess, hear my prayer[NEWLINE]Where you swim in the high air![NEWLINE]With charity look down on me,[NEWLINE]Under this tree,[NEWLINE]Tending the gifts I have not brought,[NEWLINE]The rare and goodly things[NEWLINE]I have not sought.[NEWLINE]Instead, take from me all my life![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Upon the wings[NEWLINE]Of shimmering moonbeams[NEWLINE]I pack my poet's dreams[NEWLINE]For you.[NEWLINE]My wearying strife,[NEWLINE]My courage, my loss,[NEWLINE]Into the night I toss[NEWLINE]For you.[NEWLINE]Golden Divinity,[NEWLINE]Deign to look down on me[NEWLINE]Who so unworthily[NEWLINE]Offers to you:[NEWLINE]All life has known,[NEWLINE]Seeds withered unsown,[NEWLINE]Hopes turning quick to fears,[NEWLINE]Laughter which dies in tears.[NEWLINE]The shredded remnant of a man[NEWLINE]Is all the span[NEWLINE]And compass of my offering to you.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Empty and silent, I[NEWLINE]Kneel before your pure, calm majesty.[NEWLINE]On this stone, in this urn[NEWLINE]I pour my heart and watch it burn,[NEWLINE]Myself the sacrifice; but be[NEWLINE]Still unmoved:  Divinity."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]From the altar, bathed in moonlight,[NEWLINE]The smoke rose straight in the quiet night.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]   -- Amy Lowell, Before the Altar</Italian>
		<Spanish> Before the Altar, bowed, he stands[NEWLINE]With empty hands;[NEWLINE]Upon it perfumed offerings burn[NEWLINE]Wreathing with smoke the sacrificial urn.[NEWLINE]Not one of all these has he given,[NEWLINE]No flame of his has leapt to Heaven[NEWLINE]Firesouled, vermilion-hearted,[NEWLINE]Forked, and darted,[NEWLINE]Consuming what a few spare pence[NEWLINE]Have cheaply bought, to fling from hence[NEWLINE]In idly-asked petition.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]His sole condition[NEWLINE]Love and poverty.[NEWLINE]And while the moon[NEWLINE]Swings slow across the sky,[NEWLINE]Athwart a waving pine tree,[NEWLINE]And soon[NEWLINE]Tips all the needles there[NEWLINE]With silver sparkles, bitterly[NEWLINE]He gazes, while his soul[NEWLINE]Grows hard with thinking of the poorness of his dole.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Shining and distant Goddess, hear my prayer[NEWLINE]Where you swim in the high air![NEWLINE]With charity look down on me,[NEWLINE]Under this tree,[NEWLINE]Tending the gifts I have not brought,[NEWLINE]The rare and goodly things[NEWLINE]I have not sought.[NEWLINE]Instead, take from me all my life![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Upon the wings[NEWLINE]Of shimmering moonbeams[NEWLINE]I pack my poet's dreams[NEWLINE]For you.[NEWLINE]My wearying strife,[NEWLINE]My courage, my loss,[NEWLINE]Into the night I toss[NEWLINE]For you.[NEWLINE]Golden Divinity,[NEWLINE]Deign to look down on me[NEWLINE]Who so unworthily[NEWLINE]Offers to you:[NEWLINE]All life has known,[NEWLINE]Seeds withered unsown,[NEWLINE]Hopes turning quick to fears,[NEWLINE]Laughter which dies in tears.[NEWLINE]The shredded remnant of a man[NEWLINE]Is all the span[NEWLINE]And compass of my offering to you.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Empty and silent, I[NEWLINE]Kneel before your pure, calm majesty.[NEWLINE]On this stone, in this urn[NEWLINE]I pour my heart and watch it burn,[NEWLINE]Myself the sacrifice; but be[NEWLINE]Still unmoved:  Divinity."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]From the altar, bathed in moonlight,[NEWLINE]The smoke rose straight in the quiet night.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]   -- Amy Lowell, Before the Altar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MINSTER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Minster of the Elohim is a major project to complete, with significant rewards both to the city and civilization-wide. It also allows your high level Monk units to gain significant bonuses.</English>
		<French>The Minster of the Elohim is a major project to complete, with significant rewards both to the city and civilization-wide. It also allows your high level Monk units to gain significant bonuses.</French>
		<German>Das Münster der Elohim ist ein großes Projekt, mit deutlichen Belohnungen sowohl für die Stadt als auch die gesamte Bevölkerung. Es erlaubt Euren hochstufigen Mönchen den Erhalt signifikanter Boni.</German>
		<Italian>La Cattedrale degli Elohim è un grande progetto da completare, con significative ricompense sia per la città che per tutta la civiltà. Permette inoltre ai tuoi monaci di alto livello di ottenere significativi bonus.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Minster of the Elohim is a major project to complete, with significant rewards both to the city and civilization-wide. It also allows your high level Monk units to gain significant bonuses.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MINSTER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows visiting monks to achieve [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_ENLIGHTENMENT]Enlightenment[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Allows visiting monks to achieve [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_ENLIGHTENMENT]Enlightenment[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Ermöglicht Mönchen den Erhalt von [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_ENLIGHTENMENT]Erleuchtung[\LINK]</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Permette ai monaci che la visitano di raggiungere l'[LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_ENLIGHTENMENT]Illuminazione[\LINK]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows visiting monks to achieve [LINK=PROMOTION_MONK_ENLIGHTENMENT]Enlightenment[\LINK]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MONASTERY</Tag>
		<English>Monastery</English>
		<French>Monastère</French>
		<German>Kloster</German>
		<Italian>Monastero</Italian>
		<Spanish>Monastery</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>foggy blue mountain range[NEWLINE]sun setting in purple[NEWLINE]like in a painting[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]pointed rooftops[NEWLINE]light meals[NEWLINE]quiet gardening[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]in the sky ravens[NEWLINE]wind chimes within reach[NEWLINE]of my hand[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]where depression is no[NEWLINE]depression[NEWLINE]but philosophy[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]and sadness[NEWLINE]no sadness[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]But what if[NEWLINE]the gardens[NEWLINE]were taken over[NEWLINE]by noisy memories[NEWLINE]and sadness[NEWLINE]were just different[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]   -- Ela Zawrat, Evening in a Monastery</English>
		<French>foggy blue mountain range[NEWLINE]sun setting in purple[NEWLINE]like in a painting[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]pointed rooftops[NEWLINE]light meals[NEWLINE]quiet gardening[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]in the sky ravens[NEWLINE]wind chimes within reach[NEWLINE]of my hand[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]where depression is no[NEWLINE]depression[NEWLINE]but philosophy[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]and sadness[NEWLINE]no sadness[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]But what if[NEWLINE]the gardens[NEWLINE]were taken over[NEWLINE]by noisy memories[NEWLINE]and sadness[NEWLINE]were just different[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]   -- Ela Zawrat, Evening in a Monastery</French>
		<German>foggy blue mountain range[NEWLINE]sun setting in purple[NEWLINE]like in a painting[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]pointed rooftops[NEWLINE]light meals[NEWLINE]quiet gardening[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]in the sky ravens[NEWLINE]wind chimes within reach[NEWLINE]of my hand[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]where depression is no[NEWLINE]depression[NEWLINE]but philosophy[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]and sadness[NEWLINE]no sadness[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]But what if[NEWLINE]the gardens[NEWLINE]were taken over[NEWLINE]by noisy memories[NEWLINE]and sadness[NEWLINE]were just different[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]   -- Ela Zawrat, Evening in a Monastery</German>
		<Italian>foggy blue mountain range[NEWLINE]sun setting in purple[NEWLINE]like in a painting[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]pointed rooftops[NEWLINE]light meals[NEWLINE]quiet gardening[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]in the sky ravens[NEWLINE]wind chimes within reach[NEWLINE]of my hand[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]where depression is no[NEWLINE]depression[NEWLINE]but philosophy[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]and sadness[NEWLINE]no sadness[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]But what if[NEWLINE]the gardens[NEWLINE]were taken over[NEWLINE]by noisy memories[NEWLINE]and sadness[NEWLINE]were just different[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]   -- Ela Zawrat, Evening in a Monastery'</Italian>
		<Spanish>foggy blue mountain range[NEWLINE]sun setting in purple[NEWLINE]like in a painting[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]pointed rooftops[NEWLINE]light meals[NEWLINE]quiet gardening[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]in the sky ravens[NEWLINE]wind chimes within reach[NEWLINE]of my hand[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]where depression is no[NEWLINE]depression[NEWLINE]but philosophy[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]and sadness[NEWLINE]no sadness[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]But what if[NEWLINE]the gardens[NEWLINE]were taken over[NEWLINE]by noisy memories[NEWLINE]and sadness[NEWLINE]were just different[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]   -- Ela Zawrat, Evening in a Monastery</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RELIQUARY</Tag>
		<English>Reliquary</English>
		<French>Reliquaire</French>
		<German>Reliquienschrein</German>
		<Italian>Reliquiario</Italian>
		<Spanish>Relicario</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RELIQUARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Elohim are a spiritually-attuned people, and many who have passed on leave behind relics in order to teach future generations lessons from the past. Despite the health hazard of exhibiting the remains of the dead to the public, the Elohim preserve these artifacts in Reliquaries. From ordinary labourers to their soldiers, every citizen of the Elohim finds the guarded treasures of their Reliquaries a window to enlightenment.[NEWLINE]In turn, when their time comes, they too will pass on their lessons in life to those who walk in the halls of the Reliquary. Thus, enlightenment has come full circle.</English>
		<French>The Elohim are a spiritually-attuned people, and many who have passed on leave behind relics in order to teach future generations lessons from the past. Despite the health hazard of exhibiting the remains of the dead to the public, the Elohim preserve these artifacts in Reliquaries. From ordinary labourers to their soldiers, every citizen of the Elohim finds the guarded treasures of their Reliquaries a window to enlightenment.[NEWLINE]In turn, when their time comes, they too will pass on their lessons in life to those who walk in the halls of the Reliquary. Thus, enlightenment has come full circle.</French>
		<German>The Elohim are a spiritually-attuned people, and many who have passed on leave behind relics in order to teach future generations lessons from the past. Despite the health hazard of exhibiting the remains of the dead to the public, the Elohim preserve these artifacts in Reliquaries. From ordinary labourers to their soldiers, every citizen of the Elohim finds the guarded treasures of their Reliquaries a window to enlightenment.[NEWLINE]In turn, when their time comes, they too will pass on their lessons in life to those who walk in the halls of the Reliquary. Thus, enlightenment has come full circle.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Elohim sono un popolo spiritualmente in sintonia, e molti di quelli che lasciano questo mondo lasciano dietro di se delle reliquie in modo da insegnare alle nuove generazioni le lezioni del passato. Nonostante il pericolo per l'igiene di esibire i resti dei morti al pubblico, gli Elohim conservano questi artefatti nei Reliquiari. Dai semplici lavoratori sino ai soldati, ogni cittadino Elohim trova nei tesori custoditi all'interno dei Reliquiari una finestra sull'illuminazione.[NEWLINE]In cambio, quando verrà la loro ora, loro stessi passeranno ciò che hanno appreso in vita a coloro che camminano nelle sale del Reliquiario. Facendo cosi tornare l'illuminaziona al punto d'origine.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Elohim are a spiritually-attuned people, and many who have passed on leave behind relics in order to teach future generations lessons from the past. Despite the health hazard of exhibiting the remains of the dead to the public, the Elohim preserve these artifacts in Reliquaries. From ordinary labourers to their soldiers, every citizen of the Elohim finds the guarded treasures of their Reliquaries a window to enlightenment.[NEWLINE]In turn, when their time comes, they too will pass on their lessons in life to those who walk in the halls of the Reliquary. Thus, enlightenment has come full circle.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RELIQUARY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>All units created in the city start with the Spirit guide promotion.</English>
		<French>Toutes les unités construites dans cette ville commencent avec la promotion Guide Spirituel.</French>
		<German>Alle in der Stadt geschaffenen Einheiten starten mit der Beförderung Guru.</German>
		<Italian>Tutte le unità create nella città iniziano con la promozione Spirito Guida.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Todas las unidades creadas en la ciudad empiezan con el ascenso Guía Espiritual.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CORLINDALE</Tag>
		<English>Corlindale</English>
		<French>Corlindale</French>
		<German>Corlindale</German>
		<Italian>Corlindale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Corlindale</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CORLINDALE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As Corlindale walked towards the overgrown walls, his heart was filled up with equal portions of excitement and fear. His first battle! This was what he had been training for, during the long and hard years of being locked in the Amurite citadels, forced to study moldy old tomes and practice vocalization for unbearably long stretches at a time, listening to the Elder mages droning on and on about ancient runestones and vagaries of magic while secretly wishing them to oblivion. [PARAGRAPH:1]His fellow mages marched beside him, all in a strictly ordered formation, all with equally expressionless faces. He realized that he must look a fool in all his excitement, and made a partly-successful attempt at emulating their indifferent expressions. [PARAGRAPH:1]Moments later: chaos. Everyone was gone, the ordered formations falling into disarray as the Ljosalfar sentries that had been hiding in the treetops unleashed a hail of arrows at the unprotected mages. He had managed to evade it by quickly evoking a protective spell, in a more instinctual than rational reaction. Then he had started to run. Now he was all alone, in the streets of an enemy city. Thankfully, most of the enemy forces seemed to be concentrated at the outer walls, but he still felt very exposed as he walked around the empty streets, marveling at the mighty oak trees. He almost felt as if he were walking in a dream, so eerie was the beauty around him, and so distant the sounds of the battlefield. He found it hard to recall what the cause for the present conflict had been-perhaps a dispute over borders? Perhaps the elves had been overly protective of a source of mana? It all seemed so distant and insignificant now. [PARAGRAPH:1]Suddenly he stumbled upon an elvish patrol, coming towards him from a side-street. As one of them saw him, he called out in the melodic elven language. The vigilant sentry and the other soldiers started approaching Corlindale, though somewhat warily. They had probably been warned about the skill of Amurite mages. [PARAGRAPH:1]It did not do them much good, however. He held out his palm, and drew heat from the surrounding air to create an enormous fireball, glad of the recent rainfall that would minimize the risk of a forest fire. He flung the fiery ball at the patrol, and closed his eyes at the searing explosion of light and heat which ensued. 'Naught but ashes remained of the leading elves, while the ones who had evaded the blast threw their weapons and fled. The cowards. [PARAGRAPH:1]Feeling strangely exhilarated, he walked on. His first victory-as is so often the case with the young upstarts in military life-had made him feel all but invincible, and he almost wished more elves would come. [PARAGRAPH:1]Moments later, a wish fulfilled. He heard the rustles of leaves behind him, and immediately invoked another ball of fire. Remembering the rain of arrows with dread, he elected not to take any chances, and in one whirling motion he turned around and flung the ball in the general direction of the sound. Time stopped. [PARAGRAPH:1]Before him stood a female elf, her hair long and silvery, her eyes almond shaped and beautiful, but her face marred by the expression of pure terror on her face. Worse still, at her feet stood two younger children, a boy and a girl, clinging to their mothers dress, the older girl mirroring her mother's expression of terror, the young boy just seeming curious about the fiery object travelling towards him at a rapid pace. Corlindale had time to take all this in, in a moment which seemed to linger for centuries. He reached out his hand, and desperately and fervently willed the ball to stop, to cease its flight towards destruction, even to turn around and consume him. Anything but this. At last, as it became evident that nothing could be done, that no force in this world could reverse his magic, he closed his eyes, and his howl of misery almost served to drown the shrieks of pain. [PARAGRAPH:1]One evening in the late autumn, a stranger approached the city of Cahir Abbey, in the lands of the Elohim. He was clad in a brown cloak, with no symbols or markings of any kind, and seemed very fatigued, so the sentries on the wall took him in, and gave him food and shelter. Some were curious about his origin, but one look at his eyes was enough to convince them that not all stories were fit for human ears. This was a broken man, in spirit more so than in body, and their hearts ached with pity for his cruel fate.</English>
		<French>As Corlindale walked towards the overgrown walls, his heart was filled up with equal portions of excitement and fear. His first battle! This was what he had been training for, during the long and hard years of being locked in the Amurite citadels, forced to study moldy old tomes and practice vocalization for unbearably long stretches at a time, listening to the Elder mages droning on and on about ancient runestones and vagaries of magic while secretly wishing them to oblivion. [PARAGRAPH:1]His fellow mages marched beside him, all in a strictly ordered formation, all with equally expressionless faces. He realized that he must look a fool in all his excitement, and made a partly-successful attempt at emulating their indifferent expressions. [PARAGRAPH:1]Moments later: chaos. Everyone was gone, the ordered formations falling into disarray as the Ljosalfar sentries that had been hiding in the treetops unleashed a hail of arrows at the unprotected mages. He had managed to evade it by quickly evoking a protective spell, in a more instinctual than rational reaction. Then he had started to run. Now he was all alone, in the streets of an enemy city. Thankfully, most of the enemy forces seemed to be concentrated at the outer walls, but he still felt very exposed as he walked around the empty streets, marveling at the mighty oak trees. He almost felt as if he were walking in a dream, so eerie was the beauty around him, and so distant the sounds of the battlefield. He found it hard to recall what the cause for the present conflict had been-perhaps a dispute over borders? Perhaps the elves had been overly protective of a source of mana? It all seemed so distant and insignificant now. [PARAGRAPH:1]Suddenly he stumbled upon an elvish patrol, coming towards him from a side-street. As one of them saw him, he called out in the melodic elven language. The vigilant sentry and the other soldiers started approaching Corlindale, though somewhat warily. They had probably been warned about the skill of Amurite mages. [PARAGRAPH:1]It did not do them much good, however. He held out his palm, and drew heat from the surrounding air to create an enormous fireball, glad of the recent rainfall that would minimize the risk of a forest fire. He flung the fiery ball at the patrol, and closed his eyes at the searing explosion of light and heat which ensued. 'Naught but ashes remained of the leading elves, while the ones who had evaded the blast threw their weapons and fled. The cowards. [PARAGRAPH:1]Feeling strangely exhilarated, he walked on. His first victory-as is so often the case with the young upstarts in military life-had made him feel all but invincible, and he almost wished more elves would come. [PARAGRAPH:1]Moments later, a wish fulfilled. He heard the rustles of leaves behind him, and immediately invoked another ball of fire. Remembering the rain of arrows with dread, he elected not to take any chances, and in one whirling motion he turned around and flung the ball in the general direction of the sound. Time stopped. [PARAGRAPH:1]Before him stood a female elf, her hair long and silvery, her eyes almond shaped and beautiful, but her face marred by the expression of pure terror on her face. Worse still, at her feet stood two younger children, a boy and a girl, clinging to their mothers dress, the older girl mirroring her mother's expression of terror, the young boy just seeming curious about the fiery object travelling towards him at a rapid pace. Corlindale had time to take all this in, in a moment which seemed to linger for centuries. He reached out his hand, and desperately and fervently willed the ball to stop, to cease its flight towards destruction, even to turn around and consume him. Anything but this. At last, as it became evident that nothing could be done, that no force in this world could reverse his magic, he closed his eyes, and his howl of misery almost served to drown the shrieks of pain. [PARAGRAPH:1]One evening in the late autumn, a stranger approached the city of Cahir Abbey, in the lands of the Elohim. He was clad in a brown cloak, with no symbols or markings of any kind, and seemed very fatigued, so the sentries on the wall took him in, and gave him food and shelter. Some were curious about his origin, but one look at his eyes was enough to convince them that not all stories were fit for human ears. This was a broken man, in spirit more so than in body, and their hearts ached with pity for his cruel fate.</French>
		<German>Das Herz von Corlindale war zu gleichen Teilen mit Aufregung und Angst gefüllt, als er auf die bewachsene Mauern zuschritt. Sein erster Kampf! Dies war es, wofür er ausgebildet worden war, während der langen und harten Jahre, die er in den Zitadellen der Amuriter eingesperrt gewesen war, dazu gezwungen, alte staubige Wälzer zu studieren, für unertragbar lange Zeitspannen Aussprache zu üben, und den älteren Magiern dabei zuzuhören, während sie weiter und weiter über alte Runensteine und die Launen der Magie schwafelten, während er insgeheim wünschte, sie mögen der Vergessenheit anheim fallen. [PARAGRAPH:1]Seine Magierkameraden marschierten an seiner Seite, alle in einer strengen Formation geordnet, alle mit den gleichen ausdruckslosen Gesichtern. Ihm ging auf, dass er in seiner Aufregung wie ein Narr aussehen musste, und machte einen nur teilweise erfolgreichen Versuch, ihren gleichgültigen Ausdruck nachzuahmen. [PARAGRAPH:]Nur Augenblicke später: Chaos. Alle waren weg, die geordneten Formationen hatten sich aufgelöst, als die Posten der Ljosalfar, die sich in den Baumwipfeln versteckt hatten, einen Hagel von Pfeilen auf die ungeschützten Magier niedergehen hatten lassen. Er hatte es geschafft, dem zu entgehen, indem er schnell einen Schutzzauber gewirkt hatte, mehr aus einem Instinkt heraus als aus einer gesteuerten Reaktion. Dann war er gelaufen. Jetzt war er auf sich gestellt, in den Straßen einer feindlichen Stadt. Zum Glück waren die meisten Truppen des Feindes anscheinend an den äußeren Wällen beschäftigt, aber er fühlte sich dennoch äußerst ungeschützt, als er durch die leeren Straßen wanderte, und die mächtigen Eichen bewunderte. Ihm war es fast, als befände er sich in einem Traum, so unwirklich war die Schönheit, die ihn umgab, und so fern die Geräusche der Schlacht. Es fiel ihm schwer, sich an den Grund für diesen Konflikt zu erinnern, vielleicht eine Grenzstreitigkeit? Waren die Elfen zu sehr auf eine Mana-Ressource bedacht gewesen? Dies kam ihm nun alles weit entfernt und unwesentlich vor. [PARAGRAPH:1]Plötzlich stieß er auf eine Elfische Patrouille, die sich ihm aus einer Seitenstraße näherte. Als der erste ihn sah, rief er etwas in der melodischen Elfensprache. Die aufmerksame Wache und die anderen Soldaten bewegten sich auf Corlindale zu, wenn auch etwas vorsichtig. Wahrscheinlich waren sie vor den Fähigkeiten der Magier der Armuriter gewarnt worden. [PARAGRAPH:1]Das nützte ihnen jedoch nichts. Er streckte seine Handfläche aus und zog Hitze aus der Luft die ihn umgab, um einen gewaltigen Feuerball zu erschaffen, dabei war er froh über den letzten Regen, der die Gefahr eines Waldbrandes verringern würde. Er schleuderte die feurige Kugel gegen die Patrouille, und schloss seine Augen vor der darauf folgenden alles verbrennenden Explosion von Licht und Hitze. Nichts als Asche blieb von den ersten der Elfen zurück, und die, die der Explosion entgangen waren, ließen ihre Waffen fallen und flohen. Feiglinge. [PARAGRAPH:1]Sich auf eine seltsame Art beflügelt fühlend, schritt er weiter. Sein erster Sieg, wie so oft bei jungen Aufstrebenden im Militär, gab ihm das Gefühl, unbesiegbar zu sein, und fast wünschte er, dass mehr Elfen kommen sollten. [PARAGRAPH:1]Kurz darauf ging sein Wunsch in Erfüllung. Er hörte das Rascheln von Laub hinter ihm, und rief sofort einen weiteren Ball aus Feuer hervor. Da er sich mit Grauen an den Pfeilregen erinnerte, entschied er sich, kein Risiko einzugehen, und mit einer einzigen Bewegung drehte er sich um und schleuderte den Ball in die Richtung des Geräusches. Die Zeit hielt an. [PARAGRAPH:1]Vor ihm stand eine Elfenfrau, ihr Haar lang und silbern, ihre Augen mandelförmig und schön, aber ihr Gesicht von purem Schrecken gezeichnet. Schlimmer noch, an ihren Beinen lehnten zwei kleine Kinder, ein Junge und ein Mädchen, die sich am Rock ihrer Mutter festhielten, das ältere Mädchen widerspiegelte den Ausdruck von Schrecken ihrer Mutter, der kleinere Junge schien nur Neugierig gegenüber dem feurigen Ding zu sein, das sich ihm mit gewaltiger Geschwindigkeit näherte. Corlindal hatte genug Zeit, all dies zu bemerken, in einem Augenblick der Jahrhunderte zu dauern schien. Verzweifelt streckte er seine Hand aus und wünschte insbrünstig der Ball möge halten, seinen Flug in die Zerstörung abbrechen, oder sogar umkehren und ihn selbst verzehren. Alles bis auf das. Endlich wurde ihm klar, dass er nichts tun konnte, das keine Macht der Welt seine Magie ungeschehen machen konnte, er schloss seine Augen, und das Aufheulen in seinem Jammer übertönte fast um die Schmerzensschreie zu überdecken. [PARAGRAPH:1]Eines Abends im Spätherbst näherte sich ein Fremder der Stadt Cahir Abbey, in den Ländern der Elohim. Er war in einen braunen Mantel gehüllt, ohne Symbole oder Zeichen irgendeiner Art, und schien sehr ermüdet zu sein, und so ließen ihn die Wachen auf der Mauer ein und gaben ihm zu Essen und eine Wohnstatt. Einige waren neugierig nach seiner Herkunft, aber ein Blick in seine Augen reichte aus um sie zu überzeugen, dass nicht alle Geschichten für die Ohren der Menschen bestimmt sind. Dies war ein gebrochener Mann, sein Geist mehr noch als sein Körper, und in ihren Herzen regte sich Mitleid für sein grausames Schicksal.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre Corlindale camminava verso le giganti mura il suo cuore si riempì in egual misura di eccitazione e paura. Era la sua prima battaglia! Questo era ciò per cui si era allenato durante i lunghi e difficili anni in cui era chiuso dentro le cittadelle degli Amurite, costretto a studiare vecchi tomi ammuffiti e a praticare la pronuncia per tempi insopportabilmente lunghi a volte, ascoltando i maghi anziani parlare incostantemente di antiche pietre runiche e dei capricci della magia mentre segretamente gli augurava l'oblio. [PARAGRAPH:1]I suoi compagni maghi marciavano al suo fianco, tutti in una formazione ordinata, tutti con la stessa faccia inespressiva. Capì che doveva sembrare un'idiota nella sua eccitazione, e fece un tentativo quasi riuscito ad emulare la loro espressione indifferente. [PARAGRAPH:1]Qualche momento dopo: caos. Tutti erano spariti, la formazione composta si scompose quando le sentinelle Ljosalfar che si erano nascoste sulle cime degli alberi fecero piovere un sacco di frecce sui maghi senza protezione. Era riuscito a evitarle grazie a una rapida magia protettiva che aveva lanciato in una maniera più instintiva che razionale. Poi aveva iniziato a correre. Ora era completamente da solo nelle strade di una città nemica. Fortunatamente la maggior parte delle forze nemiche sembravano concentrate sulle mura esterne, ma si sentiva ancora esposto mentre camminava per le strade deserte, ammirando le imponenti quercie. Gli sembrava quasi di star camminando in un sogno, così misteriosa era la bellezza che lo circondava, e cosi distante era il suono della battaglia. Trovò difficile ricordare quale fosse la causa dell'attuale conflitto, forse una disputa sui confini? Forse gli efli erano stati iperprotettivi per una fonte di mana? Sembrava tutto cosi distante e insignificante ora. [PARAGRAPH:1]All'improvviso incontrò una pattuglia elfica, diretta verso di lui da una strada laterale. Quando uno di loro lo vide avviso gli altri nella melodica lingua elfica. La vigile sentinella e gli altri soldati iniziarono ad avvicinarsi a Corlindale, anche se un po diffidenti. Probabilmtente erano stati avvisati delle capacita dei maghi Amurite. [PARAGRAPH:1]Non che gli giovò qualcosa comunque. Tese il palmo della mano, e attinse il calore dell'aria circostante per creare un'enorme palla di fuoco, felice della recente pioggia che avrebbe minimizzato il rischio di un'incendio boschivo. Scagliò la palla verso la pattuglia, e chiuse gli occhi in seguito all'esplosione di luce e calore che ne seguì. Non rimaneva altro che cenere dell'elfo alla guida, mentre gli altri, che avevano evitato l'esplosione, fecero cadere le armi e scapparono. Codardi. [PARAGRAPH:1]Sentendosi stranamente euforico, continuò a camminare. La sua prima vittoria, come succedeva spesso ai giovani appena entrati nella vita militare, lo aveva fatto sentire invincibile, e quasi sperò che altri elfi giungesserò. [PARAGRAPH:1]Qualche momento dopo il desiderio si avverò. Sentì il rumore di foglie dietro di lui, e immediatamente invocò un'altra palla di fuoco. Ricordandosi della pioggia di frecce con terrore decise di non lasciare nulla al caso, e in un rapido movimento si voltò e scagliò la palla nella direzione del suono. Il tempo si fermò. [PARAGRAPH:1]Davanti a lui c'era un'elfa, i suoi capelli lunghi e argentati, i suoi occhi a forma di mandorla e bellissimi, ma il suo volto era segnato da un'espressione di puro terrore. Peggio ancora, ai suoi piedi stavano due bambini elfici, un maschio e una femmina, aggrappati al vestito della madre, la bambina aveva la stessa espressione di terrore della madre, mentre il bambino sembrava semplicemente incuriosito dall'oggetto che gli si stava avvicinando rapidamente. Corlindale ebbe il tempo di vedere tutto questo in un momento che sembrò durare secoli. Lui allungò la mano e cercò disperatamente di fermare la palla mentalmente, di fermarla nel viaggio di distruzione, persino di farla tornare indietro e di farsi consumare da essa. Tutto tranne quello che stava per accadere. Alla fine, quando divenne evidente che non si poteva fare nulla, che nessuna forza al mondo avrebbe potuto invertire la sua magia, chiuse gli occhi, e il suo urlo di sofferenza riusci quasi a coprire le urla di dolore. [PARAGRAPH:1]Una sera nel tardo autunno, uno straniero si avvicinò alla città di Cahir Abbey, nelle terre Elohim. Era vestito con un mantello marrone, senza simboli di alcun tipo e sembrava molto stanco, perciò le sentinelle del muro lo fecero entrare e gli diedero del cibo e gli offrirono riparo. Alcuni erano curiosi di sapere le sue origini, ma uno sguardo ai suoi occhi era sufficente a convincerli che non tutte le storie erano adatte alle orecchie umane. Questo era un uomo distrutto, più nello spirito che nel corpo, ed i loro cuori dolevano per la sua crudele sorte.</Italian>
		<Spanish>As Corlindale walked towards the overgrown walls, his heart was filled up with equal portions of excitement and fear. His first battle! This was what he had been training for, during the long and hard years of being locked in the Amurite citadels, forced to study moldy old tomes and practice vocalization for unbearably long stretches at a time, listening to the Elder mages droning on and on about ancient runestones and vagaries of magic while secretly wishing them to oblivion. [PARAGRAPH:1]His fellow mages marched beside him, all in a strictly ordered formation, all with equally expressionless faces. He realized that he must look a fool in all his excitement, and made a partly-successful attempt at emulating their indifferent expressions. [PARAGRAPH:1]Moments later: chaos. Everyone was gone, the ordered formations falling into disarray as the Ljosalfar sentries that had been hiding in the treetops unleashed a hail of arrows at the unprotected mages. He had managed to evade it by quickly evoking a protective spell, in a more instinctual than rational reaction. Then he had started to run. Now he was all alone, in the streets of an enemy city. Thankfully, most of the enemy forces seemed to be concentrated at the outer walls, but he still felt very exposed as he walked around the empty streets, marveling at the mighty oak trees. He almost felt as if he were walking in a dream, so eerie was the beauty around him, and so distant the sounds of the battlefield. He found it hard to recall what the cause for the present conflict had been-perhaps a dispute over borders? Perhaps the elves had been overly protective of a source of mana? It all seemed so distant and insignificant now. [PARAGRAPH:1]Suddenly he stumbled upon an elvish patrol, coming towards him from a side-street. As one of them saw him, he called out in the melodic elven language. The vigilant sentry and the other soldiers started approaching Corlindale, though somewhat warily. They had probably been warned about the skill of Amurite mages. [PARAGRAPH:1]It did not do them much good, however. He held out his palm, and drew heat from the surrounding air to create an enormous fireball, glad of the recent rainfall that would minimize the risk of a forest fire. He flung the fiery ball at the patrol, and closed his eyes at the searing explosion of light and heat which ensued. 'Naught but ashes remained of the leading elves, while the ones who had evaded the blast threw their weapons and fled. The cowards. [PARAGRAPH:1]Feeling strangely exhilarated, he walked on. His first victory-as is so often the case with the young upstarts in military life-had made him feel all but invincible, and he almost wished more elves would come. [PARAGRAPH:1]Moments later, a wish fulfilled. He heard the rustles of leaves behind him, and immediately invoked another ball of fire. Remembering the rain of arrows with dread, he elected not to take any chances, and in one whirling motion he turned around and flung the ball in the general direction of the sound. Time stopped. [PARAGRAPH:1]Before him stood a female elf, her hair long and silvery, her eyes almond shaped and beautiful, but her face marred by the expression of pure terror on her face. Worse still, at her feet stood two younger children, a boy and a girl, clinging to their mothers dress, the older girl mirroring her mother's expression of terror, the young boy just seeming curious about the fiery object travelling towards him at a rapid pace. Corlindale had time to take all this in, in a moment which seemed to linger for centuries. He reached out his hand, and desperately and fervently willed the ball to stop, to cease its flight towards destruction, even to turn around and consume him. Anything but this. At last, as it became evident that nothing could be done, that no force in this world could reverse his magic, he closed his eyes, and his howl of misery almost served to drown the shrieks of pain. [PARAGRAPH:1]One evening in the late autumn, a stranger approached the city of Cahir Abbey, in the lands of the Elohim. He was clad in a brown cloak, with no symbols or markings of any kind, and seemed very fatigued, so the sentries on the wall took him in, and gave him food and shelter. Some were curious about his origin, but one look at his eyes was enough to convince them that not all stories were fit for human ears. This was a broken man, in spirit more so than in body, and their hearts ached with pity for his cruel fate.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CORLINDALE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Corlindale makes a superb mage, though if his magic can't protect you, his diplomacy will. He can be sacrificed to make peace between your civ and all current enemies, pushing their troops outside your borders. Beware of enemy assassins, because he will be simple to eliminate should one pierce your defenses.</English>
		<French>Corlindale makes a superb mage, though if his magic can't protect you, his diplomacy will. He can be sacrificed to make peace between your civ and all current enemies, pushing their troops outside your borders. Beware of enemy assassins, because he will be simple to eliminate should one pierce your defenses.</French>
		<German>Corlindale ist ein herausragender Magier, der, wenn er Euch nicht durch Magie schützen kann, es durch Diplomatie vermag. Seine Opferung besiegelt den Frieden zwischen Euch und Euren Feinden und versetzt deren Truppen ausserhalb Eurer Landesgrenzen.</German>
		<Italian>Corlindale è un mago fenomenale, e se la sua magia non riesce a proteggerti lo farà la sua diplomazia. Puo venir sacrificato per fare la pace tra la tua civiltà e tutti i nemici attuali, spingendo cosi le loro truppe fuori dai tuoi confini. Fai attenzione agli assassini nemici, perché può facilmente essere eliminato se uno di loro supera le tue difese.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Corlindale makes a superb mage, though if his magic can't protect you, his diplomacy will. He can be sacrificed to make peace between your civ and all current enemies, pushing their troops outside your borders. Beware of enemy assassins, because he will be simple to eliminate should one pierce your defenses.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DEVOUT</Tag>
		<English>Devout</English>
		<French>Dévot</French>
		<German>Vollstrecker Sironas</German>
		<Italian>Devoto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Devout</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DEVOUT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Devouts are respected far and wide, and allowed entry without question into any land. They tend the sick and dying left behind from brutal conquests of the more bellicose nations, preventing restless spirits from gathering.</English>
		<French>Devouts are respected far and wide, and allowed entry without question into any land. They tend the sick and dying left behind from brutal conquests of the more bellicose nations, preventing restless spirits from gathering.</French>
		<German>Vollstrecker Sironas werden weit und breit respektiert und erhalten überall fraglos Einlass. Sie pflegen die Kranken und Sterbenden, die die brutalen Feldzüge der kriegerischeren Reiche hinterlassen, und verhindern so die Ansammlung rastloser Seelen.</German>
		<Italian>I Devoti sono rispettati in lungo e in largo e possono entrare in qualsiasi paese senza che gli vengano poste domande. Loro si occupano dei malati e dei morenti lasciati indietro in seguito a brutali conquiste da parte di nazioni più bellicose, prevenendo cosi la presenza di spiriti irrequieti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Devouts are respected far and wide, and allowed entry without question into any land. They tend the sick and dying left behind from brutal conquests of the more bellicose nations, preventing restless spirits from gathering.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DEVOUT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Devouts can travel through rival territory without open borders and start with [LINK=SPELL_SANCTIFY]sanctify[\LINK], so they are useful to keep the Armageddon counter low despite foreign wars by sanctifying city ruins. The do not have the [LINK=PROMOTION_MARKSMAN]marksman[\LINK] promotion, however.</English>
		<French>Devouts can travel through rival territory without open borders and start with sanctify, so they are useful to keep the Armageddon counter low despite foreign wars by sanctifying city ruins. The do not have the marksman promotion, however.</French>
		<German>Vollstrecker Sironas können sich auch ohne offene Grenzen durch fremdes Territorium bewegen und beherrschen den "Heiligen"-Zauberspruch. Damit sind sie nützlich um den Amargeddonzähler trotz Kriegen zwischen anderen niedrig zu halten, indem sie den Spruch auf Stadtruinen sprechen. Jedoch verfügen sie nicht über die "Scharfschützen"-Beförderung.</German>
		<Italian>I Devoti possono attraversare i territori rivali anche senza avere il diritto di passaggio e iniziano con [LINK=SPELL_SANCTIFY]santificare[\LINK], il che li rende molto utili nel mantenere basso il contatore dell'Armaggeddon, nonostante le guerre straniere, attraverso la santificazione delle rovine delle città. Tuttavia non possiedono la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_MARKSMAN]Tiratore Scelto[\LINK].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Devouts can travel through rival territory without open borders and start with sanctify, so they are useful to keep the Armageddon counter low despite foreign wars by sanctifying city ruins. The do not have the marksman promotion, however.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MONK</Tag>
		<English>Monk</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Moine:Moines</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Mönch</German>
		<Italian>Monaco</Italian>
		<Spanish>Monk</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MONK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Day 6. Encountered the remnants of a company of Macemen. Theyve seen my foe. If I make haste, I am but a day away from ridding the world of his evil. I must prepare.-Extract from the diary of Brother Kideran, Demon Hunter.[PARAGRAPH:1]Only the smartest, most evil of prey is worthy of the Monk's attention. These men have given their lives over to the intense focus and meditation required to leave behind the frail constraints of their bodies and become something more than mortal. Free from the laws of physics, Monks are equipped with the mental tools needed to take up the fight with the Demons themselves-and win.</English>
		<French>Day 6. Encountered the remnants of a company of Macemen. Theyve seen my foe. If I make haste, I am but a day away from ridding the world of his evil. I must prepare.-Extract from the diary of Brother Kideran, Demon Hunter.[PARAGRAPH:1]Only the smartest, most evil of prey is worthy of the Monk's attention. These men have given their lives over to the intense focus and meditation required to leave behind the frail constraints of their bodies and become something more than mortal. Free from the laws of physics, Monks are equipped with the mental tools needed to take up the fight with the Demons themselves-and win.</French>
		<German>Mönche beginnen mit einer freien Beförderung aus dem Geweihten Beförderungszirkel.[PARAGRAPH:2]Tag 6. Die Überreste einer Einheit von Morgensternkämpfern getroffen. Sie haben meinen Feind gesehen. Wenn ich mich beeile, bin ich nur noch einen Tag davon entfernt, die Welt von diesem Übel zu befreien. Ich muss mich vorbereiten. - Auszug aus dem Tagebuch von Bruder Kideran, Dämonenjäger.[PARAGRAPH:1]Nur die gerissensten und bösesten sind es Wert, die Aufmerksamkeit eines Mönches zu erlangen. Diese Männer haben ihr Leben dafür gegeben, starke Konzentration und Meditation, die benötigt werden, um die gebrechlichen Hemmnisse ihrer Körper zu überwinden und mehr zu werden als ein einfacher Sterblicher. Sie sind unabhängig von den Gesetzen der Physik und verfügen über die notwendige Geisteskraft, um den Kampf mit Dämonen aufnehmen zu können und zu gewinnen.</German>
		<Italian>6° giorno. Incontrati i superstiti di una compagnia di guerrieri con mazza. Hanno visto il mio bersaglio. Se mi sbrigo sarò ad un giorno di distanza dal rimuovere dal mondo questo male. Devo prepararmi.-Estratto dal diario di Fratello Kideran, Cacciatore di Demoni.[PARAGRAPH:1]Solo le prede più scaltre e malvagie sono degne dell'attenzione di un Monaco. Questi uomini hanno votato le loro vite alla concentrazione e alla meditazione richeste per lasciarsi indietro le deboli costrizioni dei loro corpi diventando qualcosa di superiore a un mortale. Liberi dalle leggi della fisica i Monaci possiedono gli strumenti mentali necessari per combattere contro i Demoni stessi, e vincere.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Day 6. Encountered the remnants of a company of Macemen. Theyve seen my foe. If I make haste, I am but a day away from ridding the world of his evil. I must prepare.-Extract from the diary of Brother Kideran, Demon Hunter.[PARAGRAPH:1]Only the smartest, most evil of prey is worthy of the Monk's attention. These men have given their lives over to the intense focus and meditation required to leave behind the frail constraints of their bodies and become something more than mortal. Free from the laws of physics, Monks are equipped with the mental tools needed to take up the fight with the Demons themselves-and win.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MONK_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Monks are great for fighting demonic units. They also have the Medic promotion, making them decent healers. They don't need a building to train so they can be created in any city.</English>
		<French>Les Moines sont bien pour combattre les unités démoniaques. Ils possèdent aussi la promotion Médecin I, en faisant des guérisseurs décents. Ils n'ont besoin d'aucun bâtiment pour être entraînés et peuvent donc être créé dans n'importe quelle ville.</French>
		<German>Mönche sind exzellent für den Kampf gegen Dämonen geeignet, zumal sie mit der Heilung I-Beförderung starten, also auch zum Heilen zu gebrauchen sind. Sie benötigen zur Errichtung keine Speziellen Gebäude und können so in jeder Stadt ausgebildet werden.</German>
		<Italian>I Monaci sono ottimi per combattere le unità demoniache. Possiedono anche la promozione Medico, rendendoli dei decenti guaritori. Non richedono inoltre alcun edificio per essere creati.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Monks are great for fighting demonic units. They also have the Medic promotion, making them decent healers. They don't need a building to train so they can be created in any city.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MONK_FOCUS</Tag>
		<English>Focus</English>
		<French>Focus</French>
		<German>Fokus</German>
		<Italian>Concentrazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Focus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MONK_PURITY</Tag>
		<English>Purity</English>
		<French>Pureté</French>
		<German>Reinheit</German>
		<Italian>Purezza</Italian>
		<Spanish>Purity</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MONK_ENLIGHTENMENT</Tag>
		<English>Enlightenment</English>
		<French>Illumination</French>
		<German>Erleuchtung</German>
		<Italian>Illuminazione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Enlightenment</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_NEWNAME_SOHEI</Tag>
		<English>Sohei</English>
		<French>Sohei</French>
		<German>Sohei</German>
		<Italian>Sohei</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sohei</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_POOL_OF_TEARS</Tag>
		<English>"These sacred waters hold the power to cure the sick."</English>
		<French>"These sacred waters hold the power to cure the sick."</French>
		<German>"Dieses geheiligte Wasser enthält die Macht, die Kranken zu heilen."</German>
		<Italian>"Queste acque sacre hanno il potere di curare i malati."</Italian>
		<Spanish>"These sacred waters hold the power to cure the sick."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_POOL_OF_TEARS_ELOHIM</Tag>
		<English>Your unit has arrived at the Pool of Tears</English>
		<French>Votre unité atteint le bassin des Larmes</French>
		<German>Eure Einheit ist am See der Tränen angekommen</German>
		<Italian>La tua unità è arrivata alla Pozza delle Lacrime</Italian>
		<Spanish>Your unit has arrived at the Pool of Tears</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_POOL_OF_TEARS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Gain the Expansive Trait</English>
		<French>Obtenir le trait Accessible</French>
		<German>Erhalte das Merkmal Expansiv</German>
		<Italian>Ottieni il tratto Espansivo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gain the Expansive Trait</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SIRONAS_BEACON</Tag>
		<English>"The light of Sirona's wisdom shines brightly. Let none who see it ever forget that she guides us."</English>
		<French>"The light of Sirona's wisdom shines brightly. Let none who see it ever forget that she guides us."</French>
		<German>"Das Licht von Sironas Weisheit leuchtet hell. Lasst keinen, der es jemals sieht, vergessen, dass sie es ist, die uns führt."</German>
		<Italian>"La luce della saggezza di Sirona brilla intensamente. Che nessuno che la veda si dimentichi che lei ci guida."</Italian>
		<Spanish>"The light of Sirona's wisdom shines brightly. Let none who see it ever forget that she guides us."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SIRONAS_BEACON_ELOHIM</Tag>
		<English>Your unit arrives at Sirona's Beacon</English>
		<French>Votre unité atteint le sanctuaire de Sirona</French>
		<German>Eure Einheit ist bei Sironas Leuchtfeuer angekommen</German>
		<Italian>La tua unità è arrivata al Faro di Sirona</Italian>
		<Spanish>Your unit arrives at Sirona's Beacon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SIRONAS_BEACON_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Gain the Spiritual Trait</English>
		<French>Obtenir le trait Spirituel</French>
		<German>Erhalte das Merkmal Spirituell</German>
		<Italian>Ottieni il tratto Spirituale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gain the Spiritual Trait</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REMNANTS_OF_PATRIA</Tag>
		<English>"These wonders have endured the ages and stand proudly to this day. Let our legacy be as great"</English>
		<French>"These wonders have endured the ages and stand proudly to this day. Let our legacy be as great"</French>
		<German>"Diese Stillen Zeugen haben die Zeiten überdauert, stolz stehen sie bis zum heutigen Tag. Lasst unser Vermächtnis ebenso groß sein."</German>
		<Italian>"Queste meraviglie hanno attraversato i secoli e si ergono fiere ancor oggi. Possa la nostra eredità essere altrettanto grande"</Italian>
		<Spanish>"These wonders have endured the ages and stand proudly to this day. Let our legacy be as great"</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REMNANTS_OF_PATRIA_ELOHIM</Tag>
		<English>Your unit arrives at the Remnants of Patria</English>
		<French>Your unit arrives at the Remnants of Patria</French>
		<German>Eure Einheit erreicht die "Stillen Zeugen von Patria"</German>
		<Italian>La tua unità è arrivata ai Resti di Patria</Italian>
		<Spanish>Your unit arrives at the Remnants of Patria</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REMNANTS_OF_PATRIA_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Gain the Industrious Trait</English>
		<French>Obtenir le trait Travailleur</French>
		<German>Erhalte das Merkmal Industriell</German>
		<Italian>Ottieni il tratto Industrioso</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gain the Industrious Trait</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MIRROR_OF_HEAVEN</Tag>
		<English>"Even in this desert there shines the light of life."</English>
		<French>"Even in this desert there shines the light of life."</French>
		<German>"Sogar in der Wüste scheint das Licht des Lebens."</German>
		<Italian>"Persino in questo deserto la luce della vita brilla."</Italian>
		<Spanish>"Even in this desert there shines the light of life."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MIRROR_OF_HEAVEN_ELOHIM</Tag>
		<English>Your unit arrives at the Mirror of Heaven</English>
		<French>Your unit arrives at the Mirror of Heaven</French>
		<German>Eure Einheit ist am Himmelsspiegel angekommen</German>
		<Italian>La tua unità è arrivata allo Specchio del Cielo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Your unit arrives at the Mirror of Heaven</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ODIOS_PRISON</Tag>
		<English>"Look upon the folly of unchecked aggression - let us never make such a mistake..."</English>
		<French>"Look upon the folly of unchecked aggression - let us never make such a mistake..."</French>
		<German>"Seht diesen Wahnwitz ungehemmter Aggression - lasst uns niemals solch einen Fehler begehen..."</German>
		<Italian>"Osservate la follia di un'aggressività incontrollata, non commettiamo lo stesso errore..."</Italian>
		<Spanish>"Look upon the folly of unchecked aggression - let us never make such a mistake..."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ODIOS_PRISON_ELOHIM</Tag>
		<English>Your unit arrives at Odio's Prison</English>
		<French>Your unit arrives at Odio's Prison</French>
		<German>Eure Einheit ist an Odios Gefängnis angekommen</German>
		<Italian>La tua unità è arrivata alla Prigione di Odio</Italian>
		<Spanish>Your unit arrives at Odio's Prison</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ODIOS_PRISON_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Will reset your worldspell if it has been used</English>
		<French>Will reset your worldspell if it has been used</French>
		<German>Erlaubt es Euch, Euren Weltzauber ein zweites Mal zu wirken, sofern Ihr ihn bereits gewirkt habt.</German>
		<Italian>Ripristina la tua magia globale se è stata già usata</Italian>
		<Spanish>Will reset your worldspell if it has been used</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BRADELINES_WELL</Tag>
		<English>"This site is corrupted - let us repair the damage that has been wrought"</English>
		<French>"This site is corrupted - let us repair the damage that has been wrought"</French>
		<German>"Dieser Ort ist verdorben - lasst uns den verursachten Schaden beseitigen"</German>
		<Italian>"Questo luogo è corrotto, ripariamo il danno che è stato causato"</Italian>
		<Spanish>"This site is corrupted - let us repair the damage that has been wrought"</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BRADELINES_WELL_ELOHIM</Tag>
		<English>Your unit has arrived at Bradeline's Well</English>
		<French>Your unit has arrived at Bradeline's Well</French>
		<German>Eure Einheit ist an Bradelines Brunnen angelangt</German>
		<Italian>La tua unità è arrivata al Pozzo di Bradeline</Italian>
		<Spanish>Your unit has arrived at Bradeline's Well</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BRADELINES_WELL_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Destroys the mana source, decreases the Armagedon counter and prevents units being called through the portal</English>
		<French>Destroys the mana source, decreases the Armagedon counter and prevents units being called through the portal</French>
		<German>Zerstört den Manaknoten, reduziert den Armageddonzähler und verhindert das Rufen von Einheiten durch das Portal</German>
		<Italian>Distrugge la fonte di mana, diminuisce il contatore dellArmagedon e impedisce di richiamare unità attraverso il portale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Destroys the mana source, decreases the Armagedon counter and prevents units being called through the portal</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_PACIFIST</Tag>
		<English>Pacifist</English>
		<French>Pacifist</French>
		<German>Pazifist</German>
		<Italian>Pacifista</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pacifist</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SOFT_SPOKEN</Tag>
		<English>Soft Spoken</English>
		<French>Soft Spoken</French>
		<German>Flüsternd</German>
		<Italian>Affabile</Italian>
		<Spanish>Soft Spoken</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_ELOHIM</Tag>
		<English>Elohim Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Elohim</French>
		<German>Palast der Elohim</German>
		<Italian>Elohim Palace</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Elohim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>