<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - Units -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHISLEV_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Chislev</English>
		<French>chislevite:chislevite:chislevites:chislevites</French>
		<German>Chislev'sch:Chislev'schen:Chislev'sche</German>
		<Italian>Chislev</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chislev</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHISLEV_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Chislev</English>
		<French>Chislev</French>
		<German>Reich der Chislev</German>
		<Italian>Chislev</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chislev</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHISLEV_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Chislev</English>
		<French>Chislevites</French>
		<German>Chislev</German>
		<Italian>Chislev</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chislev</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHISLEV_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Chislev people have long lived in small tribes of one or two villages each, though consider themselves to be one tribe bound by their culture and language. The nature of this fractured nation was altered forever when Jonas Endain led the orcs from Braduk the Burning in war against the Bannor. The Chislev had always been a peaceful people, but the march of the orcs swept through their jungle home and whole villages were slaughtered and burnt to the ground. Many of the Chislev fled from the onslaught and fell back to the plains, but the losses suffered were intolerable. [PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]The grieving tribes banded together to perform the funeral rites of their people. It was during these rites that the young Absaroke came to unite a number of the tribesmen in a resolution for vengeance and war on the orcs. Absaroke was not a rash man however, despite his youth. He knew that a war so soon after their terrible losses would be futile. Instead, he led a group of the bravest tribesmen into the flank of the orc army, hoping to cause distraction sufficient to allow other villages still caught up in the advance to fall back and join them. The tactic succeeded and after a night of fierce battle, Absaroke led his party home before Jonas could turn his attention to the tribe. The orcs continued the march toward the Bannor and the previously stranded Chislev fell back to the plains with their kin. Absorke dubbed those who joined him that night as his "warchiefs" and sent them out to re-establish villages and rebuild the strength of the tribe. When the time came, every warchief vowed to be ready. Years have passed, and that time is now approaching.</English>
		<French>Les Chislevites ont vécu longtemps en petites tribus composées d'un ou deux villages chacune, plutôt que comme une grande tribu unie par sa culture et sa langue. La nature de cette nation morcelée fut changée à jamais quand Jonas Endain guida les orcs de Braduk l'Enflammé à la guerre conte les Bannors. Les Chislevites ont toujours été un peuple pacifique, mais la marche des orcs au travers de leurs jungles natales les balaya et de nombreux villages furent rasés et réduits en cendres. De nombreux Chislevites fuirent l'assaut et émigrèrent dans les plaines, mais leurs pertes leur étaient intolérables.[PARAGRAPH:2]Les tribus meurtries se réunirent afin de célébrer les rites funéraires pour leurs gens. Ce fut pendant ces rites funéraires que le jeune Absaroke vint unifier certains membres de la tribu dans une volonté de vengeance et de guerre face aux orcs. Absaroke n'était cependant pas un homme irréfléchi, malgré sa jeunesse. Il savait qu'une guerre avec leurs pertes terribles était futile. Au lieu de cela, il guida un groupe de membres de la tribu les plus braves sur le flanc de l'armée orc, espérant les distraire suffisamment pour permettre aux autres villages toujours coincés de s'échapper et les rejoindre. Le plan marcha, et après une dure nuit de combats acharnés, Absaroke replia son groupe dans les plaines avant que Jonas puisse se concentrer sur la tribu. Les orcs continuèrent leur avancée contre les Bannors et les Chislevites bloqués purent rejoindre leurs proches dans les plaines. Absorke nomma ceux qui l'avaient rejoint cette nuit "chefs de guerre" et les envoya refonder les villages et reconstruire le force de la tribu. Chaque chef de guerre fit le serment d'être prêt lorsque le temps viendrait. Des années ont passé et ce temps approche.</French>
		<German>The Chislev people have long lived in small tribes of one or two villages each, though consider themselves to be one tribe bound by their culture and language. The nature of this fractured nation was altered forever when Jonas Endain led the orcs from Braduk the Burning in war against the Bannor. The Chislev had always been a peaceful people, but the march of the orcs swept through their jungle home and whole villages were slaughtered and burnt to the ground. Many of the Chislev fled from the onslaught and fell back to the plains, but the losses suffered were intolerable. [PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]The grieving tribes banded together to perform the funeral rites of their people. It was during these rites that the young Absaroke came to unite a number of the tribesmen in a resolution for vengeance and war on the orcs. Absaroke was not a rash man however, despite his youth. He knew that a war so soon after their terrible losses would be futile. Instead, he led a group of the bravest tribesmen into the flank of the orc army, hoping to cause distraction sufficient to allow other villages still caught up in the advance to fall back and join them. The tactic succeeded and after a night of fierce battle, Absaroke led his party home before Jonas could turn his attention to the tribe. The orcs continued the march toward the Bannor and the previously stranded Chislev fell back to the plains with their kin. Absorke dubbed those who joined him that night as his "warchiefs" and sent them out to re-establish villages and rebuild the strength of the tribe. When the time came, every warchief vowed to be ready. Years have passed, and that time is now approaching.</German>
		<Italian>Il popolo Chislev visse per molto tempo diviso in piccole tribù da uno o due villaggi ciascuna, anche se loro si considerano una sola tribù per via della cultura e dalla lingua condivisa. L'indole di questa frammentata nazione cambiò per sempre quando Jonas Endain guidò gli orchi da Braduk l'Ardente in guerra contro i Bannor. I Chislev sono sempre stati un popolo pacifico, ma, nella loro marcia, gli orchi attraversarono la giungla in cui abitavano massacrando interi villaggi per poi bruciarli sino alle fondamenta. Molti Chislev riuscirono a sfuggire al massacro e si rifugiarono nelle pianure, ma le perdite subite erano insopportabili. [PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Le tribù in lutto si riunirono per celebrare i riti funebri per i loro morti. Fu durante questi riti che un giovane Absaroke riuscì ad ottenere il supporto di altri membri della tribù per decidere di vendicarsi e dichiarare guerra agli orchi. Absaroke però non era avventato nonostante la sua giovinezza. Sapeva che iniziare una guerra dopo aver perso cosi tanti uomini sarebbe stato inutile. Invece guidò un gruppo composta dai membri della tribù più coraggiosi sul fianco dell'esercito orchesco, sperando di creare una distrazione sufficente per permettere ai villaggi che si trovavano sulla strada degli orchi di ripiegare e unirsi a loro. Questa tattica ebbe successo e dopo una notte di duri combattimenti Absaroke guidò il suo gruppo verso casa, prima che Jonas potesse concentrare la sua attenzione sulla sua tribù. Gli orchi continuarono la loro marcia verso i Bannor e i Chislev che prima erano intrappolati si rifugiarono anche loro nelle pianure con i loro parenti. Absorke soprannominò coloro che avevano combattuto con lui quella notte come i suoi "capiguerra" e li mandò a stabilire nuovi villagi e ricostruire la forza della tribù. I capiguerra giurarono che, quando sarebbe arrivato il momento, sarebbero stati pronti. Sono passati anni, e quel momento si sta avvicinando.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Chislev people have long lived in small tribes of one or two villages each, though consider themselves to be one tribe bound by their culture and language. The nature of this fractured nation was altered forever when Jonas Endain led the orcs from Braduk the Burning in war against the Bannor. The Chislev had always been a peaceful people, but the march of the orcs swept through their jungle home and whole villages were slaughtered and burnt to the ground. Many of the Chislev fled from the onslaught and fell back to the plains, but the losses suffered were intolerable. [PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]The grieving tribes banded together to perform the funeral rites of their people. It was during these rites that the young Absaroke came to unite a number of the tribesmen in a resolution for vengeance and war on the orcs. Absaroke was not a rash man however, despite his youth. He knew that a war so soon after their terrible losses would be futile. Instead, he led a group of the bravest tribesmen into the flank of the orc army, hoping to cause distraction sufficient to allow other villages still caught up in the advance to fall back and join them. The tactic succeeded and after a night of fierce battle, Absaroke led his party home before Jonas could turn his attention to the tribe. The orcs continued the march toward the Bannor and the previously stranded Chislev fell back to the plains with their kin. Absorke dubbed those who joined him that night as his "warchiefs" and sent them out to re-establish villages and rebuild the strength of the tribe. When the time came, every warchief vowed to be ready. Years have passed, and that time is now approaching.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABSAROKE</Tag>
		<English>Absaroke</English>
		<French>Absaroke</French>
		<German>Absaroke</German>
		<Italian>Absaroke</Italian>
		<Spanish>Absaroke</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABSAROKE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Chahta approached the fire as dawn broke behind the distant mountains and light fell across the plain. Absaroke was sat, deep in thought. The smell of the funeral pyres drifted from the edge of the village and stirred Chahta's anger and his pain.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We must strike again at them", he stated. "The attack of last night saved many but now our warriors hunger for vengeance. The blood of the tribe has been spilled and calls out for blood in return".[NEWLINE]  "It is not time."[NEWLINE]"But has the tribe not always lived as the hunter-bird?" Chahta argued, gesturing to the first rock-raven to circle the plain. It swooped suddenly to pluck some small creature from the ground before carrying it aloft. "The orcs did not expect our retaliation, we should act switftly". Absaroke shook his head and continued to stare into the fire. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"It is true that our tribe has always drawn strength and wisdom from the way of the hunter-birds, hunting early will provide the greatest spoils. But it is not time to live that way anymore. I do not wish to be the first raven to claim a prize, great or small. I wish to fly at the head of a flock of mighty birds, descending upon the field such that the sun is blotted from the sky. Then I shall attack with beak and claw and wing. When I return to the sky, I want to know that nothing remains on the ground for me to attack. I want them dead as much as you, dear friend. But I want them all."</English>
		<French>Chahta s'approcha du feu à l'aube, tandis que le soleil apparaissait derrière les montagnes distantes et que la lumière inondait peu à peu les plaines. Absaroke était assis, plongé profondément dans ses pensées. L'odeur des bûchers funéraires provenait du village et aiguisaient la colère et la peine de Chahta.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Nous devons leur répliquer", décida-t-il."L'attaque de la veille a sauvé beaucoup d'entre nous, mais nos guerriers ont maintenant soif de vengeance. Le sang de la tribu a été versé et appelle au sang en retour."[NEWLINE]"L'heure n'est pas venue."[NEWLINE]"Mais la tribu n'a-t-elle pas toujours vécu comme l'oiseau de proie?" répondit Chahta en montrant le premier corbeau de pierre survolant en cercle la plaine. Il piqua soudain pour cueillir une petite créature au sol avant de l'emmener au loin. "Les orcs ne s'attendaient pas à ce que nous répliquions. Nous devrions agir vite." Absaroke secoua la tête et continua de fixer le feu.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Il est vrai que noter tribu a toujours tiré force et sagesse de la voie de l'oiseau de proie, et que les chasser tôt provoquera les plus grandes blessures. Mais le temps n'est plus à ce mode de vie. Je ne veux pas être le premier corbeau à réclamer mon dû, petit ou grand. Je voudrais voler à la tête d'un foule de puissants oiseaux, cachant le soleil lorsqu'ils descendent sur le champ de bataille. Alors j'attaquerai avec mon bec, mes serres et mes ailes. Quand je m'envolerai, je veux être sûr qu'il ne restera rien à attaquer. Je les veux morts autant que toi, mon cher ami. Mais je les veux tous."</French>
		<German>Chahta approached the fire as dawn broke behind the distant mountains and light fell across the plain. Absaroke was sat, deep in thought. The smell of the funeral pyres drifted from the edge of the village and stirred Chahta's anger and his pain.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We must strike again at them", he stated. "The attack of last night saved many but now our warriors hunger for vengeance. The blood of the tribe has been spilled and calls out for blood in return".[NEWLINE]  "It is not time."[NEWLINE]"But has the tribe not always lived as the hunter-bird?" Chahta argued, gesturing to the first rock-raven to circle the plain. It swooped suddenly to pluck some small creature from the ground before carrying it aloft. "The orcs did not expect our retaliation, we should act switftly". Absaroke shook his head and continued to stare into the fire. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"It is true that our tribe has always drawn strength and wisdom from the way of the hunter-birds, hunting early will provide the greatest spoils. But it is not time to live that way anymore. I do not wish to be the first raven to claim a prize, great or small. I wish to fly at the head of a flock of mighty birds, descending upon the field such that the sun is blotted from the sky. Then I shall attack with beak and claw and wing. When I return to the sky, I want to know that nothing remains on the ground for me to attack. I want them dead as much as you, dear friend. But I want them all."</German>
		<Italian>Chahta si avvicinò al fuoco mentre il sole sorgeva da dietro le montagne distanti e illuminava leggermente la pianura. Absaroke era seduto assorto nei suoi pensieri. L'odore delle pire funerarie che proveniva dal bordo del villaggio risvegliò la rabbia e il dolore di Chahta.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Dobbiamo attaccarli di nuovo", disse. "L'attacco della notte scorsa ha salvato molte persone, ma ora i nostri guerrieri desiderano vendicarsi. Il sangue della tribù è stato versato e ciò richiede sangue in cambio".[NEWLINE]"Non è il momento."[NEWLINE]"La tribù non ha forse sempre vissuto come i rapaci?" Chahta sostennè mentre indicava il primo corvo delle rocce che sorvolava in cerchio la pianura. Il corvo poi scese rapidamente in picchiata per afferrare qualche piccolo animale da terra prima di tornare in cielo. "Gli orchi non si aspettano una nostra rappresaglia, dovremmo agire rapidamente". Absaroke scosse la testa e continuò a fissare il fuoco. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"È vero che la nostra tribù ha sempre tratto forza e saggezza dalla natura dei rapaci, essere i primi a cacciare permette di ottenere i migliori risultati. Ma non è più il momento di vivere in quel modo. Io non desidero essere il primo corvo a catturare la preda, grade o piccola che sia. Io desidero volare alla testa di uno stormo di uccelli possenti che quando calano sulla terra oscurano il sole in cielo. Poi attaccherò con il becco, l'artiglio e l'ala. Quando tornerò in cielo voglio essere sicuro che non rimanga null'altro per terra per me da attaccare. Li voglio morti quanto te, amico mio. Ma io li voglio tutti."</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chahta approached the fire as dawn broke behind the distant mountains and light fell across the plain. Absaroke was sat, deep in thought. The smell of the funeral pyres drifted from the edge of the village and stirred Chahta's anger and his pain.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"We must strike again at them", he stated. "The attack of last night saved many but now our warriors hunger for vengeance. The blood of the tribe has been spilled and calls out for blood in return".[NEWLINE]  "It is not time."[NEWLINE]"But has the tribe not always lived as the hunter-bird?" Chahta argued, gesturing to the first rock-raven to circle the plain. It swooped suddenly to pluck some small creature from the ground before carrying it aloft. "The orcs did not expect our retaliation, we should act switftly". Absaroke shook his head and continued to stare into the fire. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"It is true that our tribe has always drawn strength and wisdom from the way of the hunter-birds, hunting early will provide the greatest spoils. But it is not time to live that way anymore. I do not wish to be the first raven to claim a prize, great or small. I wish to fly at the head of a flock of mighty birds, descending upon the field such that the sun is blotted from the sky. Then I shall attack with beak and claw and wing. When I return to the sky, I want to know that nothing remains on the ground for me to attack. I want them dead as much as you, dear friend. But I want them all."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_NATANE</Tag>
		<English>Natane</English>
		<French>Natane</French>
		<German>Natane</German>
		<Italian>Natane</Italian>
		<Spanish>Natane</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_NATANE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>She entered the spirit hut. Absaroke sat facing a small fire, smoke spiralling through the hole in the roof. He was preparing for the conflict. In the morning he would lead the best warriors of four villages against the orcs. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]So many orcs. When the scouts had first reported their numbers, she could not believe their words. The orcs had always been scattered and fragmented - these ones marched behind a mighty leader and banner, their numbers swelling as each tribe fell in line. Absaroke understood this. In order to defeat his foe he had emulated them, uniting the Chislev tribes against those of the orcs. He would never say as much and she knew better than to suggest it - his temper was poor these days - but it was plain to see. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He rose from his meditation, seeing her for the first time. "My daughter, what troubles you?"[NEWLINE]  "Our people go to war, Father. Our farmers take up spears instad of tending their crop, our spirit healers tend the wounded instead of the sick. The warpath is well prepared - but I fear those of us who do not tread it will suffer the loss of those who do." As she spoke, her voice had risen and her tone became angry.[NEWLINE]"Your words are true, Natane. This time will be hard for the Chislev - equally for those at war and those at home. You understand this well, so it falls to you to guide our people that remain here."</English>
		<French>Elle pénétra dans la tente des esprits. Absaroke était assis face à un petit feu, la fumée montant en petites spirales vers le trou dans le toit. Il se préparait au combat. À l'aube il mènerait les meilleurs guerriers de quatre villages conte les orcs.[PARAGRAPH:2]Tant d'orcs. Quand les éclaireurs rapportèrent leur nombre pour la première fois, elle n'avait pas pu les croire. Les orcs avaient toujours été dispersés et fragmentés, et ceux-là marchaient derrière une bannière et un leader puissants, leurs rangs se gonflant à chaque tribu se ralliant. Absaroke l'aavit compris. Pour vaincre son ennemi il avait uni les tribus Chislevites contre les orcs. Il ne dirait combien ils étaient, et elle le connaissait assez bien pour ne pas lui demander (il n'était pas pas patient ces jours ci) mais c'était facile à voir.[PARAGRAPH:2]Il sortit de sa méditation, la voyant pour la première fois. "Ma fille, qu'est-ce qui te trouble?"[NEWLINE]"Notre peuple part en guerre, Père. Nos fermiers attrapent des lances au lieu de leurs récoltes, nos soigneurs spirituels s'occupent des blessés au lieu des malades. Le sentier de la guerre est clair, mais je crains que ceux qui ne le suivent pas subissent les pertes de ceux qui le suivent."Tandis qu'elle s'exprimait, savoix devenait plus forte et son ton faisait place à la colère.[NEWLINE]"Tu dis vrai, Natane. Ça va être une période difficile, autant pour ceux à la guerre que ceux à l'arrière. Tu l'as bien compris, il te revient donc le devoir de guider ceux qui restent ici."</French>
		<German>She entered the spirit hut. Absaroke sat facing a small fire, smoke spiralling through the hole in the roof. He was preparing for the conflict. In the morning he would lead the best warriors of four villages against the orcs. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]So many orcs. When the scouts had first reported their numbers, she could not believe their words. The orcs had always been scattered and fragmented - these ones marched behind a mighty leader and banner, their numbers swelling as each tribe fell in line. Absaroke understood this. In order to defeat his foe he had emulated them, uniting the Chislev tribes against those of the orcs. He would never say as much and she knew better than to suggest it - his temper was poor these days - but it was plain to see. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He rose from his meditation, seeing her for the first time. "My daughter, what troubles you?"[NEWLINE]  "Our people go to war, Father. Our farmers take up spears instad of tending their crop, our spirit healers tend the wounded instead of the sick. The warpath is well prepared - but I fear those of us who do not tread it will suffer the loss of those who do." As she spoke, her voice had risen and her tone became angry.[NEWLINE]"Your words are true, Natane. This time will be hard for the Chislev - equally for those at war and those at home. You understand this well, so it falls to you to guide our people that remain here."</German>
		<Italian>Entrò nella capanna degli spiriti. Absaroke sedeva di fronte a un piccolo fuoco con il fumo che usciva dal buco nel tetto. Si stava preparando per lo scontro. Al mattino avrebbe guidato i migliori guerrieri di quattro villaggi contro gli orchi. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Tanti orchi. Quando gli scout avevano riferito il loro numero lei non gli credette. Gli orchi erano sempre stati divisi e frammentati - questi qui marciavano dietro un potente condottiero e uno stendardo, il loro numero aumentava con ogni tribù che si arrendeva. Absaroke lo capiva. Per sconfiggere il suo nemico lo aveva emulato, unendo le tribù Chislev contro quelle degli orchi. Lui non lo avrebbe mai detto e lei sapeva che non era caso di dirlo - il suo umore era pessimo in questi giorni - ma era una cosa palese. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Lui terminò la sua meditazione, vedendola solo ora. "Figlia mia, cosa ti turba?"[NEWLINE]"Il nostro popolo va in guerra, Padre. I nostri contadini impugnano delle lance invece che curarsi dei loro raccolti, i nostri guaritori spirituali curano i feriti invece dei malati. Il sentiero di guerra è ben preparato - ma temo che quelli di noi che non lo percorrono soffrano della perdita di coloro che invece lo fanno." Mentre parlava la sua voce era diventata più forte e il suo tono era diventato arrabbiato.[NEWLINE]"Le tue parole sono giuste, Natane. Questa volta sarà difficile per i Chislev - sia per coloro che vanno in guerra che per quelli che restano a casa. Tu lo comprendi bene, e per questo devi essere tu a guidare il nostro popolo che rimane qui."</Italian>
		<Spanish>She entered the spirit hut. Absaroke sat facing a small fire, smoke spiralling through the hole in the roof. He was preparing for the conflict. In the morning he would lead the best warriors of four villages against the orcs. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]So many orcs. When the scouts had first reported their numbers, she could not believe their words. The orcs had always been scattered and fragmented - these ones marched behind a mighty leader and banner, their numbers swelling as each tribe fell in line. Absaroke understood this. In order to defeat his foe he had emulated them, uniting the Chislev tribes against those of the orcs. He would never say as much and she knew better than to suggest it - his temper was poor these days - but it was plain to see. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He rose from his meditation, seeing her for the first time. "My daughter, what troubles you?"[NEWLINE]  "Our people go to war, Father. Our farmers take up spears instad of tending their crop, our spirit healers tend the wounded instead of the sick. The warpath is well prepared - but I fear those of us who do not tread it will suffer the loss of those who do." As she spoke, her voice had risen and her tone became angry.[NEWLINE]"Your words are true, Natane. This time will be hard for the Chislev - equally for those at war and those at home. You understand this well, so it falls to you to guide our people that remain here."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BEAR_TOTEM</Tag>
		<English>Bear Totem</English>
		<French>Totem Ours</French>
		<German>Bärentotem</German>
		<Italian>Totem dell'Orso</Italian>
		<Spanish>Oso Totem</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COUNCIL_OF_THE_SHAMAN</Tag>
		<English>Council of the Shaman</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Concile Chamanique:Conciles Chamaniques</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Rat der Schamanen</German>
		<Italian>Consiglio dello Sciamano</Italian>
		<Spanish>Council of the Shaman</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COUNCIL_OF_THE_SHAMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Some Shaman Councils consist of many practitioners, whilst others have few or a solitary member. What is certain however is that whatever debate and discussion takes place inside the council, it speaks with one united voice to the rest of the tribe.</English>
		<French>Certains Conciles Chamaniques sont constitués de nombreux practiciens, tandis que dautres ne comptent que peu voire un seul membre. Ce qui est cependant certain, c'est que quelsque soient les discussions et débats qu iont lieu en interne, le Concile parle d'une voix unie au reste de la tribu.</French>
		<German>Some Shaman Councils consist of many practitioners, whilst others have few or a solitary member. What is certain however is that whatever debate and discussion takes place inside the council, it speaks with one united voice to the rest of the tribe.</German>
		<Italian>Alcuni Consigli degli Sciamani sono composti da molti membri mentre altri ne hanno pochi o solo uno. Una cosa è certa però, non importa quale dibattito o discussione avviene all'interno del consiglio, esso parla al resto della tribù con una sola voce.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Some Shaman Councils consist of many practitioners, whilst others have few or a solitary member. What is certain however is that whatever debate and discussion takes place inside the council, it speaks with one united voice to the rest of the tribe.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COUNCIL_OF_THE_SHAMAN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Council of the Shaman provides a boost to Adept and Disciple units trained in the city. The Shaman's words also help to guide the previously peaceful Chislev into the era of war that awaits, reducing global War Weariness by a small amount.</English>
		<French>Le Concile Chamanique fournit un bonus aux unités de type Adepte et Disciple entrainées dan la ville. Les mots du Chaman aident également à guider le peuple Chislevite, initialement pacifique, dans la période de guerre qui arrive, réduisant un peu la Lassitude de la Guerre globale.</French>
		<German>The Council of the Shaman provides a boost to Adept and Disciple units trained in the city. The Shaman's words also help to guide the previously peaceful Chislev into the era of war that awaits, reducing global War Weariness by a small amount.</German>
		<Italian>Il Consiglio dello Sciamano fornisce dell'esperienza alle unità Arcane e alle unità Discepoli create nella città. Le parole dello Sciamano inoltre aiutano a guidare i prima pacifici Chislev verso il periodo di guerra che li aspetta, riducendo di un pò la stanchezza di guerra in tutte le loro città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Council of the Shaman provides a boost to Adept and Disciple units trained in the city. The Shaman's words also help to guide the previously peaceful Chislev into the era of war that awaits, reducing global War Weariness by a small amount.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COUNCIL_OF_THE_WARCHIEF</Tag>
		<English>Council of the Warchief</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Concile du Chef de Guerre:Conciles du Chef de Guerre</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Rat der Häuptlinge</German>
		<Italian>Consiglio del Capoguerra</Italian>
		<Spanish>Council of the Warchief</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COUNCIL_OF_THE_WARCHIEF_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Warchiefs vary dramatically in appearance and temperament but are united in their goal. Their council-tent will invariably contain personal totems and trophies of the old-enemy taken in the night-raid led by Absaroke.</English>
		<French>Les Chefs de Guerre sont très différents d'apparence comme de tempérament, mais sont unis par le même but. Leurs tentes-conciles contiennent toujours des totems personnels et des trophées pris au  vieil ennemi lors de la nuit de raid menée par Absaroke.</French>
		<German>The Warchiefs vary dramatically in appearance and temperament but are united in their goal. Their council-tent will invariably contain personal totems and trophies of the old-enemy taken in the night-raid led by Absaroke.</German>
		<Italian>I Capoguerra variano drasticamente in aspetto e temperamento ma sono uniti nel raggiungere il loro obiettivo. La loro tenda del consiglio conterrà senza dubbio i totem personali e i trofei presi dal vecchio nemico durante l'incursione notturna guidata da Absaroke.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Warchiefs vary dramatically in appearance and temperament but are united in their goal. Their council-tent will invariably contain personal totems and trophies of the old-enemy taken in the night-raid led by Absaroke.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COUNCIL_OF_THE_WARCHIEF_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Council of the Warchief represents one of the great leaders of the tribe. A warchief will initially only be concerned with his own village, but as the tribe spreads he may be responsible for two or three villages. The building acts as a centre of government, reducing maintenance costs for nearby cities. Additionally, it provides a boost to military unit production and a small global boost to defense as the tribe's warriors prepare for the battle ahead. When the worldspell is used, only cities containing a Council of the Warchief will produce units. Only one Council of the Warchief may be built for every three Tribal councils already in existance.</English>
		<French>Le Concile du Chef de Guerre représente un des grands chefs de la tribu. Un chef de guerre ne s'occupe initialement que d'un seul village, mais alors que la tribu s'étend il peut devenir responsable de deux ou trois villages. Le bâtiment agit comme un centre du gouvernement, réduisant le coût d'entretien des villes proches. Il fournit de plus un bonus à la production d'unités militaires et un petit bonus global à la défense tandis que les guerriers de la tribu se préparent pour la bataille à venir. Quand le Sort Mondial est lancé, seules les villes disposant d'un Concile du Chef de Guerre produiront des unités. Un seul Concile du Chef de Guerre peut être produit pour chaque groupe de trois Conseils Tribaux.</French>
		<German>The Council of the Warchief represents one of the great leaders of the tribe. A warchief will initially only be concerned with his own village, but as the tribe spreads he may be responsible for two or three villages. The building acts as a centre of government, reducing maintenance costs for nearby cities. Additionally, it provides a boost to military unit production and a small global boost to defense as the tribe's warriors prepare for the battle ahead. When the worldspell is used, only cities containing a Council of the Warchief will produce units. Only one Council of the Warchief may be built for every three Tribal councils already in existance.</German>
		<Italian>Il Consiglio del Capoguerra rappresenta uno dei grandi capi della tribù. Un capoguerra inizialmente si dovrà preoccupare solo del suo villaggio, ma con l'espandersi della tribù potrebbe divenire responsabile di due o tre villaggi. L'edificio funge da centro di governo, riducendo il mantenimento nelle città vicine. In più fornisce un bonus alla produzione per le unità militari e un piccolo bonus alla difesa in tutte le città ed infine tutte le unità terrestri create in città iniziano con 2 punti esperienza, essendo che i guerrieri della tribù si preparano per la battaglia. Quando la magia globale viene usata solo le città che contengono un Consiglio del Capoguerra produrranno unità. Per costruire un Consiglio del Capoguerra è richiesta la presenza di tre Consigli Tribali ciascuno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Council of the Warchief represents one of the great leaders of the tribe. A warchief will initially only be concerned with his own village, but as the tribe spreads he may be responsible for two or three villages. The building acts as a centre of government, reducing maintenance costs for nearby cities. Additionally, it provides a boost to military unit production and a small global boost to defense as the tribe's warriors prepare for the battle ahead. When the worldspell is used, only cities containing a Council of the Warchief will produce units. Only one Council of the Warchief may be built for every three Tribal councils already in existance.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEDICINE_HUT</Tag>
		<English>Medicine Hut</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Cabane de l'Homme-Médecine:Cabanes de l'Homme-Médecine</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Zelt der Heilung</German>
		<Italian>Capanna del Guaritore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Medicine Hut</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEDICINE_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Far from the campfire and the totems, surrounded by bones of obscure creatures and past enemies and fogged by a thick and frangrant smoke, the medicine hut is home to the village's Sprirt Healer.</English>
		<French>Loin des feux de camps et des totems, entourée d'os de créatures obscures et d'ennemis du passé et remplie d'une lourde fumée chargée d'odeurs, la Cabane de l'Homme Médecine est le foyer du Soigneur Spirituel.</French>
		<German>Far from the campfire and the totems, surrounded by bones of obscure creatures and past enemies and fogged by a thick and frangrant smoke, the medicine hut is home to the village's Sprirt Healer.</German>
		<Italian>Lontana dai fuochi da campo e dai totem, circondata da ossa di oscure creature e nemici sconfitti e avvolta da un fumo spesso e profumato, la capanna del guaritore è la casa del Guaritore Spirituale del villaggio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Far from the campfire and the totems, surrounded by bones of obscure creatures and past enemies and fogged by a thick and frangrant smoke, the medicine hut is home to the village's Sprirt Healer.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEDICINE_HUT_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Medicine hut provides additional healing to units in the city and also allows construction of the Spirit Healer unit, which offer healing support to warparties.</English>
		<French>La Cabane de l'Homme Médecine fournit un bonus de Soins aux unités dans la ville et permet également la construction de l'unité Soigneur Spirituel, qui fournit un support de soin aux groupes de combat.</French>
		<German>The Medicine hut provides additional healing to units in the city and also allows construction of the Spirit Healer unit, which offer healing support to warparties.</German>
		<Italian>La Capanna del Guaritore fornisce cure aggiuntive alle unità presenti in città e permette inoltre di creare l'unità Guaritore Spirituale, che fornisce un supporto curativo ai gruppi da guerra.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Medicine hut provides additional healing to units in the city and also allows construction of the Spirit Healer unit, which offer healing support to warparties.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_CHISLEV</Tag>
		<English>Chislev Capital</English>
		<French>Tente Capitale Chislevite</French>
		<German>Zeltpalast der Chislev</German>
		<Italian>Capitale dei Chislev</Italian>
		<Spanish>Chislev Capital</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOTEM_OF_OLD_ENEMY</Tag>
		<English>Totem of the Old Enemy</English>
		<French>Totem du Vieil Ennemi</French>
		<German>Totem des Alten Feindes</German>
		<Italian>Totem del Vecchio Nemico</Italian>
		<Spanish>Totem of the Old Enemy</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TOTEM_OF_OLD_ENEMY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Totem of the Old Enemy serves to remind the tribe of what has been lost and those responsible. It provides units produced here with the "Orc Slaying" promotion, which increases their power against any unit with the "Orcish" promotion by 30%.</English>
		<French>Le Totem du Vieil Ennemi permet à la tribu de se souvenir de ce qui a été perdu et qui en est responsable. Il confère aux unités produites dans la ville la promotion "Tueur d'Orc" , qui augmente leur puissance de 30% contre n'importe quelle unité avec la promotion "Orc".</French>
		<German>The Totem of the Old Enemy serves to remind the tribe of what has been lost and those responsible. It provides units produced here with the "Orc Slaying" promotion, which increases their power against any unit with the "Orcish" promotion by 30%.</German>
		<Italian>Il Totem del Vecchio Nemico serve a ricordare alla tribù cosa è stato perso e chi è il responsabile. Fornisce alle unità create nella città del totem la promozione "Sterminatore di Orchi", che aumenta la forza del 30% quando si affronta un unità che possiede la promozione "Orco".</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Totem of the Old Enemy serves to remind the tribe of what has been lost and those responsible. It provides units produced here with the "Orc Slaying" promotion, which increases their power against any unit with the "Orcish" promotion by 30%.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRIBAL_COUNCIL</Tag>
		<English>Tribal Council</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Conseil Tribal:Conseils Tribaux</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Rat des Stammes</German>
		<Italian>Consiglio Tribale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tribal Council</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRIBAL_COUNCIL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The tribal council replaces the Elder Council. Its members are responsible for the welfare of the village's development and cultural health, giving a small bonus to both Science and Culture output. It is more important however in the implementation of Absaroke's "larger plan" (at a tribal level rather than a village level) as each Warchief's council requires three Tribal Councils. More cities, with more Tribal Councils allows more Warchief Councils to be built. The Warchief's Council is important to Worldspell use.</English>
		<French>Le Conseil Tribal remplace le Conseil des Anciens. Ses membres sont responsables du bon développement du village et de sa culture, conférant un petit bonus à la Science et à la Culture. Il est cependant plus important pour le déroulement du "grand plan" d'Absaroke (au niveau de la tribu plus que celui du village) puisque chaque Concile de Chef de Guerre requiert trois Conseils Tribaux. Plus de villes, avec plus de Conseils Tribaux permettent plus du Conciles de Chef de Guerre qui sont important pour l'usage de leur Sort Mondial.</French>
		<German>The tribal council replaces the Elder Council. Its members are responsible for the welfare of the village's development and cultural health, giving a small bonus to both Science and Culture output. It is more important however in the implementation of Absaroke's "larger plan" (at a tribal level rather than a village level) as each Warchief's council requires three Tribal Councils. More cities, with more Tribal Councils allows more Warchief Councils to be built. The Warchief's Council is important to Worldspell use.</German>
		<Italian>Il Consiglio Tribale sostituisce il Consiglio degli Anziani. I suoi membri sono responsabili per il benessere del villagio e del suo sviluppo oltre che della preservazione della cultura, fornendo un piccolo bonus alla produzione di Ricerca e Cultura. Tuttavia la sua importanza maggiore è per la realizzazione del "Grande Piano" di Absaroke (al livello tribale più che al livello del villaggio) visto che ogni Consiglio del Capoguerra richede tre Consigli Tribali. Più città significa più Consigli Tribali che permettono di costruire più Consigli del Capoguerra. Il Consiglio del Capoguerra è importante per la magia globale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The tribal council replaces the Elder Council. Its members are responsible for the welfare of the village's development and cultural health, giving a small bonus to both Science and Culture output. It is more important however in the implementation of Absaroke's "larger plan" (at a tribal level rather than a village level) as each Warchief's council requires three Tribal Councils. More cities, with more Tribal Councils allows more Warchief Councils to be built. The Warchief's Council is important to Worldspell use.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRIBAL_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Tribal Shrine</English>
		<French>Autel Tribal</French>
		<German>Schrein des Stammes</German>
		<Italian>Santuario Tribale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tribal Shrine</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRIBAL_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The contents of a village shrine is personal to the villagers who lay the items there. A fire will always be present and tended, representing the enduring memory of those lost, surrounded by items of the lost as selected by their survivors. This is mistakenly believed by some scholars to be a form of fire-worship and linked to Bhall, though the truth is quite the opposite.</English>
		<French>Le contenu d'un autel dans un village est lié aux villageois qui ydéposent des objets. Un feu est toujours allumé et entretenu, en hommage à la mémoire persistante des défunts, et entouré des objets ayant appartenus aux défunts et sélectionnés par les survivants. Ce culte est souvent considéré à tort par certains érudits comme un culte de feu lié à Bhall, alors que la vérité ne peut en être plus éloignée.</French>
		<German>The contents of a village shrine is personal to the villagers who lay the items there. A fire will always be present and tended, representing the enduring memory of those lost, surrounded by items of the lost as selected by their survivors. This is mistakenly believed by some scholars to be a form of fire-worship and linked to Bhall, though the truth is quite the opposite.</German>
		<Italian>Il contenuto del santuario di un villaggio è proprietà degli abitanti del villagio avendo loro messo gli oggetti che sono presenti. Un fuoco è sempre presente e alimentato a rappresentare la continua memoria di coloro che sono morti, circondato da oggetti appartenuti ai defunti selezionati dai sopravvissuti. Tutto ciò viene scambiato erroneamente da alcuni studiosi come una forma di venerazione del fuoco e collegato a Bhall, sebbene la verita si più l'opposto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The contents of a village shrine is personal to the villagers who lay the items there. A fire will always be present and tended, representing the enduring memory of those lost, surrounded by items of the lost as selected by their survivors. This is mistakenly believed by some scholars to be a form of fire-worship and linked to Bhall, though the truth is quite the opposite.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRIBAL_SHRINE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>A shrine not to a pagan god but to the memory of the tribe. The tribal rituals that take place here do not require Incense to provide happiness. In addition, three Tribal Shrines are required for each "Council of the Shaman" building.</English>
		<French>Un autel non pas pour un dieu païen mais pour la mémoire de la tribu. Les rituels tribaux qui ont lieu ici n'ont pas besoin d'encens pour apporter du bonheur. De plus, trois autels tribaux sont à chaque fois requis pour construire un "Concile du Chaman".</French>
		<German>A shrine not to a pagan god but to the memory of the tribe. The tribal rituals that take place here do not require Incense to provide happiness. In addition, three Tribal Shrines are required for each "Council of the Shaman" building.</German>
		<Italian>Un santuario non per un dio pagano ma per la memoria della tribù. I rituali tribali che hanno luogo qui non richedono Incenso per fornire felicità. Inoltre sono richesti tre Santuari Tribali per ogni edificio "Consiglio dello Sciamano".</Italian>
		<Spanish>A shrine not to a pagan god but to the memory of the tribe. The tribal rituals that take place here do not require Incense to provide happiness. In addition, three Tribal Shrines are required for each "Council of the Shaman" building.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TRIBAL_LAW</Tag>
		<English>Tribal Law</English>
		<French>Loi Tribale</French>
		<German>Gesetz des Stammes</German>
		<Italian>Legge Tribale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tribal Law</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_INSPIRE_FURY</Tag>
		<English>Inspire Fury</English>
		<French>Inspirer la Furie</French>
		<German>Raserei entfachen</German>
		<Italian>Inspirare la Furia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Inspire Fury</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_INSPIRE_FURY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>By reminding the Chislev warriors of the wrongs done to their people, Meskwaki can inspire a fury in them that causes them to fall upon their foes with unchecked wrath. Thoughts of self-preservation are lost as the warriors simply wish to avenge themselves and their tribe. The warparty strikes fiercely, but takes heavy losses against any organized opponent's counter-attack.</English>
		<French>En rappelant aux guerriers Chislevites les torts causés à leur peuple, Meskwaki peut leur inspirer la furie le faisant attaquer l'ennemi avec une fureur non contenue. L'instinct de survie est oublié tandis que les guerriers cherchent simplement à se venger ainsi que leur tribu. Le groupe de combat attaque férocement, mais subit de lourdes pertes face à une contre-attaque organisée.</French>
		<German>By reminding the Chislev warriors of the wrongs done to their people, Meskwaki can inspire a fury in them that causes them to fall upon their foes with unchecked wrath. Thoughts of self-preservation are lost as the warriors simply wish to avenge themselves and their tribe. The warparty strikes fiercely, but takes heavy losses against any organized opponent's counter-attack.</German>
		<Italian>Ricordando ai guerrieri Chislev i torti subiti dal loro popolo Meskwaki può inspirare in loro una furia che li porta ad avventarsi contro i nemici con una rabbia incotrollata. L'istinto di autoconservazione viene perduto mentre i guerrieri desiderano semplicemente vendicare se stessi e la loro tribù. Il gruppo da guerra attacca con ferocia, ma subirà pesanti perdite da qualsiasi contrattacco da parte di un nemico organizzato.</Italian>
		<Spanish>By reminding the Chislev warriors of the wrongs done to their people, Meskwaki can inspire a fury in them that causes them to fall upon their foes with unchecked wrath. Thoughts of self-preservation are lost as the warriors simply wish to avenge themselves and their tribe. The warparty strikes fiercely, but takes heavy losses against any organized opponent's counter-attack.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WARPATH</Tag>
		<English>Warpath</English>
		<French>Sentier de la Guerre</French>
		<German>Kriegspfad</German>
		<Italian>Sentiero di Guerra</Italian>
		<Spanish>Warpath</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WARPATH_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Creates units in cities with "Council of the Warchief"[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires at least one "Council of the Warchief" to be completed.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Crée des unités dans les villes disposant d'un "Concile du Chef de Guerre"[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requiert au moins un "Concile du Chef de Guerre" pour être lancé.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erschafft Einheiten in Städten mit "Rat der Häuptlinge"[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Benötigt mindestens einen fertiggestellten "Rat der Häuptlinge"</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Crea delle unità nelle città che hanno un "Consiglio del Capoguerra"[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Richiede che almeno un "Consiglio del Capoguerra" sia costruito per essere usata.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Creates units in cities with "Council of the Warchief"[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires at least one "Council of the Warchief" to be completed.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_WARPATH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>This Chislev Worldspell calls the warriors of the tribe together. Every "Council of the Warchief" produces a number of units in it's city, based on city population and the current technologies available. The more prepared and developed the tribe is when the worldspell cast, the more warriors will answer the call to war and the more skilled they will be.</English>
		<French>Ce Sort Mondial Chislevite appelle les guerriers de la tribu à se réunir. Chaque "Concile du Chef de Guerre" produit un certain nombre d'unités dans la ville dans laquelle il est construit, dépendant de la population de la ville et des technologies actuellement développées. Plus la tribu est bien préparée et bien développée quand le Sort Mondial est lancé, plus il y aura de guerriers qui répondront à l'appel de la guerre et plus ils seront compétents.</French>
		<German>This Chislev Worldspell calls the warriors of the tribe together. Every "Council of the Warchief" produces a number of units in it's city, based on city population and the current technologies available. The more prepared and developed the tribe is when the worldspell cast, the more warriors will answer the call to war and the more skilled they will be.</German>
		<Italian>La magia globale dei Chislev richiama i guerrieri della tribù ad unirsi. Ogni "Consiglio del Capoguerra" produce un numero di unità nella città in cui è a seconda della popolazione della città e delle tecnologie possedute. Più la tribù è preparata e sviluppata, quando si lancia la magia globale, maggiore sarà il numero di guerrieri a rispondere alla chiamata alla guerra e maggiore sarà la loro esperienza.</Italian>
		<Spanish>This Chislev Worldspell calls the warriors of the tribe together. Every "Council of the Warchief" produces a number of units in it's city, based on city population and the current technologies available. The more prepared and developed the tribe is when the worldspell cast, the more warriors will answer the call to war and the more skilled they will be.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ROCK_RAVEN</Tag>
		<English>Rock Raven</English>
		<French>Corbeau de Pierre</French>
		<German>Felsrabe</German>
		<Italian>Corvo delle Rocce</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rock Raven</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ROCK_RAVEN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Rock Ravens are natural hunter birds and more aggressive than a hawk in that it will attempt to attack larger prey. The damage done is generally minor, but a flock of vicious birds can prove a problem to an advancing army.</English>
		<French>Les Corbeaux de Pierre sont des oiseaux de proie naturels plus aggressifs qu'un faucon car ils s'attaquent à de plus grosses proies. Les dégâts sont généralement légers, mais une nuée d'oiseaux vicieux peut poser un réel problème à une armée en marche.</French>
		<German>Rock Ravens are natural hunter birds and more aggressive than a hawk in that it will attempt to attack larger prey. The damage done is generally minor, but a flock of vicious birds can prove a problem to an advancing army.</German>
		<Italian>I Corvi delle Rocce sono degli uccelli cacciatori naturali e sono più aggressivi dei Falchi in quanto proveranno ad attaccare prede più grandi di loro. Il danno causato è minore di solito, ma uno stormo di questi feroci uccelli può essere un problema per un'esercito in marcia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Rock Ravens are natural hunter birds and more aggressive than a hawk in that it will attempt to attack larger prey. The damage done is generally minor, but a flock of vicious birds can prove a problem to an advancing army.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MESKWAKI</Tag>
		<English>Meskwaki</English>
		<French>Meshwaki</French>
		<German>Meshwaki</German>
		<Italian>Meshwaki</Italian>
		<Spanish>Meshwaki</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MESKWAKI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>There is a piece of sage advice that is passed to each new generation of the Chislev people - "Do not anger the shaman". This advice was never so sound as when it was applied to Meskwaki, the shaman of Skeros.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Meskwaki opened his eyes slowly. He was back in the pit. Spirit knows he wished to be anywhere else, but here he lay again. The guttural language of the jeering orcs above drifted down through the dim light as the campfires threw strange shadows across the walls above. He had been here as a child. His village all but wiped out by the orcs as they drove the Chislev from their jungle home. The greenskins had banded together behind a barbarian king and their aggression knew no bounds. His life with the tribe had been peaceful, but there was no peace here anymore. Laying in a earthen pit with only the sound of a whimpering child and the stench of the tribesmen decaying on the other side of the hole. It was sometime before he again realised that the crying child was him. Anger flashed in his heart and the sobbing stopped. He heard the sound of his tribes drums, no longer played in celebration of the spirits, but a menacing war-beat. He rose to his feet and flung himself at the walls of the pit. Clawing his way up the sheer surface, fingers bloodied as he pushed them deep into the earth. Anger drove him on. He reached the rim of the pit. The camp was in turmoil. The tribesmen of the next village - led by Absaroke - had been roused to war and were cutting a furious path into the heart of the camp as the orcs struggled to ready themselves. Meskwaki clambered free of his prison and threw himself into the fray, clubbing at the orcs with his fists and kicking out at any he could. His fists were ineffective weapons against the bulk of an orc warrior, but his sheer ferocity allowed him to drive several back as the other tribesmen moved to cut them down. Then it all stopped. The sound was gone and the images fading. The sensation of warm blood trickling from the back of his scalp. Falling to the floor, he didn't see the orc, but he did catch sight the bloodied mace that had laid him down. The vision faded to blackness.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Meskwaki opened his eyes again. He was back in his own time, the visions of the past fading from his eyes but still burning in his heart. He still felt that rage. He had called for it. Now he would visit it upon the old-enemy. Striding from his tent, cold rage burning in his eyes he took his place at the head of the warparty. Today the greenskins would pay."</English>
		<French>Il y a un sage conseil qui se passe de génération en génération chez les Chislevites : "Ne fâche pas le Chaman". Ce conseil n'a jamais été aussi vrai que lorsqu'il s'applique à Meskwaki, le chaman de Skeros[PARAGRAPH:2]Meskwaki ouvrit lentement les yeux. Il était de retour dans la fosse. Les esprits savent à quel point il aurait aimé être n'importe où aileurs, mais c'est à nouveau là qu'il gisait. Le langage guttural des orcs moqueurs au-dessus descendait à travers la chiche lumière, tandis que les feux de camps créaient des ombres étranges sur les murs alentours. Il était arrivé ici enfant. Son village fut rasé par les orcs tandis qu'ils chassaient les chislevites de leurs jungles natales. Les peaux-vertes s'étaient regroupées derrière un roi barbare et leurs attaques ne connaissaient aps de limites. Sa vie dans la tribu avait été tranquille, mais il n'y avait plus de paix. Il gisait dans une fosse de pierre avec seulement les geignements d'un enfant et la puanteur des corps en décomposition des membres de la tribu de l'aute côté du trou. Il se passa un certain temps avant qu'il réalise que l'enfant en pleurs n'était autre que lui. La colère déferla dans son c&#156;ur et les sanglots s'arrêtèrent. Il entendit les sons des tambours de sa tribu, ne jouant plus pour célébrer les eprits, mais jouant un hymne guerrier menaçant. Il se leva et se colla aux parois de la fosse. Se servant de ses mains comme des griffes, il escalada jusqu'à la surface, ses doigts ensanglantés tandis qu'il les enfonçait profondément dans la terre. La colère le guida. Il atteint le bord de la fosse. Le camp était en émoi. Les membres du village voisin, guidés par Absaroke, s'étaient mis en guerre et se taillaient un chemin furieux au c&#156;ur du camp tandis que les orcs se démenaient pour se préparer. Meskwaki s'échappa de sa prison et se lança dans la bataille, matraquant les orcs avec ses poings et donannt des coups de pieds à tout ce qui était à portée. Ses poings étaient inefficaces face à d'imposants guerriers orcs, mais sa férocité lui permit d'en repousser quelques uns tandis que les autres membres de la tribu arrivaient pour les abattre. Puis tout s'arrêta. Tout était assourdi et les images se brouillaient. Vintla sensation du sang chaud dégoulinant à l'arrière de son crâne. S'effondrant, il n'avait pas vu l'orc, mais avait bien aperçu la masse ensanglantée qui l'avait abattu. Sa vision laissa place aux ténèbres.[PARAGRAPH:2]Meskwaki ouvrit à nouveau ses yeux. Il était de retour au présent, les visions quittant son regard mais brûlant toujours dans son c&#156;ur. Il sentait toujours cette rage. Il l'avait appelée. Il allait rendre visite à ses vieux ennemis. Il sortit à grand pas de sa tente, une rage froide brûlant dans son regard tandis qu'il prenait la tête du goupe de combat. Aujourd'hui les peaux-vertes allaient payer.</French>
		<German>There is a piece of sage advice that is passed to each new generation of the Chislev people - "Do not anger the shaman". This advice was never so sound as when it was applied to Meskwaki, the shaman of Skeros.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Meskwaki opened his eyes slowly. He was back in the pit. Spirit knows he wished to be anywhere else, but here he lay again. The guttural language of the jeering orcs above drifted down through the dim light as the campfires threw strange shadows across the walls above. He had been here as a child. His village all but wiped out by the orcs as they drove the Chislev from their jungle home. The greenskins had banded together behind a barbarian king and their aggression knew no bounds. His life with the tribe had been peaceful, but there was no peace here anymore. Laying in a earthen pit with only the sound of a whimpering child and the stench of the tribesmen decaying on the other side of the hole. It was sometime before he again realised that the crying child was him. Anger flashed in his heart and the sobbing stopped. He heard the sound of his tribes drums, no longer played in celebration of the spirits, but a menacing war-beat. He rose to his feet and flung himself at the walls of the pit. Clawing his way up the sheer surface, fingers bloodied as he pushed them deep into the earth. Anger drove him on. He reached the rim of the pit. The camp was in turmoil. The tribesmen of the next village - led by Absaroke - had been roused to war and were cutting a furious path into the heart of the camp as the orcs struggled to ready themselves. Meskwaki clambered free of his prison and threw himself into the fray, clubbing at the orcs with his fists and kicking out at any he could. His fists were ineffective weapons against the bulk of an orc warrior, but his sheer ferocity allowed him to drive several back as the other tribesmen moved to cut them down. Then it all stopped. The sound was gone and the images fading. The sensation of warm blood trickling from the back of his scalp. Falling to the floor, he didn't see the orc, but he did catch sight the bloodied mace that had laid him down. The vision faded to blackness.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Meskwaki opened his eyes again. He was back in his own time, the visions of the past fading from his eyes but still burning in his heart. He still felt that rage. He had called for it. Now he would visit it upon the old-enemy. Striding from his tent, cold rage burning in his eyes he took his place at the head of the warparty. Today the greenskins would pay.</German>
		<Italian>Vi è un detto che viene passato ad ogni nuova generazione del popolo Chislev: "Non far arrabbiare lo sciamano". Questo detto non è mai risultato più vero di quando viene applicato a Meskwaki, lo sciamano di Skeros.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Meskwaki aprì i suoi occhi lentamente. Era tornato nella fossa. Gli spiriti sapevano quanto avrebbe desiderato essere da qualsiasi altra parte, ma eccolo qui di nuovo. La lingua gutturale degli orchi che lo schernivano da sopra si abbassava mentre la scarsa luce dei fuochi da campo creava delle strane ombre sui muri. Era stato qui da bambino. Il suo villaggio completamente distrutto dagli orchi mentre i Chislev venivano cacciati via dalla loro casa nella giungla. I pelleverde si erano uniti sotto un re barbaro e i loro attacchi non avevano limiti. La sua vita con la tribù era stata pacifica, ma non c'era più pace qui ormai. Giacendo in una fossa nella terra con solo il suono di un bambino che piagniucolava e il tanfo dei cadaveri in decomposizione dei membri della tribù sull'altro lato del buco. Passò un po di tempo prima che si accorgesse che il bambino che piangeva era lui. La rabbia scoppiò nel suo cuore e il singhiozzare cessò. Sentì il suono dei tamburi della sua tribù, non più suonati per celebrare gli spiriti, ma suonare un minaccioso ritmo di guerra. Si alzò in piedi e si lanciò sulle pareti della fossa. Artigliando la superficie per scalarla, ccon le dita insanguinate per via della dura terra in cui le infilava. La rabbia lo guidava. Raggiunse il bordo della fossa. Il campo era in tumulto. Gli uomini del prossimo villaggio, guidati da Absaroke, erano stati chiamati alla guerra e si stavano aprendo una strada con ferocia verso il centro del campo mentre gli orchi cercavano di prepararsi. Meskwaki si arrampicò fuori dalla sua prigione e si lanciò nella mischia, colpendo gli orchi con i suoi pugni e calciandone quanti più poteva. I suoi pugni erano delle armi inutili contro la stazza di un guerriero orchesco, ma la sua pura ferocia gli permise di farli indietreggiare mentre altri membri della tribù si avvicinavano per abbatterli. Poi tutto si fermò. I suoni erano spariti e le immagini svanirono. La sensazione del sangue caldo che scorreva da dietro la sua testa. Cadendo a terra non vide l'orco, ma vide di sfuggita la mazza insanguinata che lo aveva abbattuto. La sua vista si oscurò.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Meskwaki aprì i suoi occhi di nuovo. Era tornato nel presente, le visioni del passato svanivano dai suoi occhi ma continuavano a bruciare nel suo cuore. Sentiva ancora la rabbia. L'aveva chiamata lui. Ora l'avrebbe scatenata contro il Vecchio Nemico. Si allontanò dalla sua tenda con una fredda rabbia che bruciava nei suoi occhi per poi mettersi a capo di un gruppo da guerra. Oggi i pelleverde pagheranno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>There is a piece of sage advice that is passed to each new generation of the Chislev people - "Do not anger the shaman". This advice was never so sound as when it was applied to Meskwaki, the shaman of Skeros.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Meskwaki opened his eyes slowly. He was back in the pit. Spirit knows he wished to be anywhere else, but here he lay again. The guttural language of the jeering orcs above drifted down through the dim light as the campfires threw strange shadows across the walls above. He had been here as a child. His village all but wiped out by the orcs as they drove the Chislev from their jungle home. The greenskins had banded together behind a barbarian king and their aggression knew no bounds. His life with the tribe had been peaceful, but there was no peace here anymore. Laying in a earthen pit with only the sound of a whimpering child and the stench of the tribesmen decaying on the other side of the hole. It was sometime before he again realised that the crying child was him. Anger flashed in his heart and the sobbing stopped. He heard the sound of his tribes drums, no longer played in celebration of the spirits, but a menacing war-beat. He rose to his feet and flung himself at the walls of the pit. Clawing his way up the sheer surface, fingers bloodied as he pushed them deep into the earth. Anger drove him on. He reached the rim of the pit. The camp was in turmoil. The tribesmen of the next village - led by Absaroke - had been roused to war and were cutting a furious path into the heart of the camp as the orcs struggled to ready themselves. Meskwaki clambered free of his prison and threw himself into the fray, clubbing at the orcs with his fists and kicking out at any he could. His fists were ineffective weapons against the bulk of an orc warrior, but his sheer ferocity allowed him to drive several back as the other tribesmen moved to cut them down. Then it all stopped. The sound was gone and the images fading. The sensation of warm blood trickling from the back of his scalp. Falling to the floor, he didn't see the orc, but he did catch sight the bloodied mace that had laid him down. The vision faded to blackness.[PARAGRAPH:1][NEWLINE]Meskwaki opened his eyes again. He was back in his own time, the visions of the past fading from his eyes but still burning in his heart. He still felt that rage. He had called for it. Now he would visit it upon the old-enemy. Striding from his tent, cold rage burning in his eyes he took his place at the head of the warparty. Today the greenskins would pay.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MESKWAKI_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Meskwaki is a a potent support-mage for a warparty. His unique ability to inspire fury (grants the Furious promotion) in the warriors following him allow his frenzied attacks to succeed where prudence would suggest failure was inevitable.</English>
		<French>Meskwaki est un mage de support utile pour un groupe de combat. Sa capicité unique à inspirer la furie (confère la promotion Furieux) aux guerriers qui le suivent permettent à ses attaques folles de réussir là où la prudence suggérerait que l'échec est inévitable.</French>
		<German>Meskwaki is a a potent support-mage for a warparty. His unique ability to inspire fury (grants the Furious promotion)in the warriors following him allow his frenzied attacks to succeed where prudence would suggest failure was inevitable.</German>
		<Italian>Meskwaki è un potente mago da supporto per un gruppo da guerra. La sua abilità unica di Insipirare la Furia (che fornisce la promozione Furioso) nei guerrieri che lo seguono permette ai suoi attacchi furibondi di avere successo dove la prudenza dice che il fallimento è inevitabile.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Meskwaki is a a potent support-mage for a warparty. His unique ability to inspire fury (grants the Furious promotion)in the warriors following him allow his frenzied attacks to succeed where prudence would suggest failure was inevitable.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPIRIT_HEALER</Tag>
		<English>Spirit Healer</English>
		<French>Soigneur Spirituel</French>
		<German>Geistheiler</German>
		<Italian>Guaritore Spirituale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Spirit Healer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPIRIT_HEALER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Chislev are well aware of the science that exists in the world, which some of the other races hold in such high regard. They are also aware however that the others remain gladly ignorant of the world's own soul and the unique magic which the Spirit Healer calls upon to cure the children of the earth. Scholars of the other races have dismissed it as simple sorcery combined with superstition - the truth would seem to be a matter of perspective.</English>
		<French>Les Chislevites connaissent l'existence de la science dans le monde, que certaines nations tiennent en si haute estime. Mais ils sont également conscients de ce que les autres ignorent à propos de l'âme du monde lui-même et de la magie unique à laquelle font appel les Soigneurs Spirituels pour soigner les enfants de la terre. Les érudits l'ont simplement classé comme un mélange de sorcellerie basique et de superstition, mais la vérité est plus une histoire de perspective.</French>
		<German>The Chislev are well aware of the science that exists in the world, which some of the other races hold in such high regard. They are also aware however that the others remain gladly ignorant of the world's own soul and the unique magic which the Spirit Healer calls upon to cure the children of the earth. Scholars of the other races have dismissed it as simple sorcery combined with superstition - the truth would seem to be a matter of perspective.</German>
		<Italian>I Chislev sono pienamente consapevoli della scienza che esiste nel mondo, la quale viene tenuta in grande considerazione da alcune razze. Sono inoltre consapevoli che gli altri rimangono volontariamente ignoranti riguardo l'anima stessa del mondo e della magia unica che il Guaritore Spirituale chiama per guarire i figli della terra. Gli studiosi delle altre razze la considerano una semplice stregoneria mista a superstizione, la verità sembra essere una questione di prospettiva.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Chislev are well aware of the science that exists in the world, which some of the other races hold in such high regard. They are also aware however that the others remain gladly ignorant of the world's own soul and the unique magic which the Spirit Healer calls upon to cure the children of the earth. Scholars of the other races have dismissed it as simple sorcery combined with superstition - the truth would seem to be a matter of perspective.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SPIRIT_HEALER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Spirit Healer's act are a support unit for offensive stacks. They boost the heal rate of friendly units and can remove [LINK=PROMOTION_DISEASED]Disease[\LINK], [LINK=PROMOTION_PLAGUED]Plagued[\LINK] and [LINK=PROMOTION_WITHERED]Withered[\LINK] promotions. Additionally, they are able to cast Spirit Guide, ensuring that their wisdom is not completely lost upon their death.</English>
		<French>Le Soigneur Spirituel agit comme une unité de support pour les groupes offensifs. Ils améliorent la régénération des unités amies et éliminer les promotions Malade, Pestiféré et Atrophié. De plus, ils sont capables de lancer le sort Guide Spirituel, s'assurant que leur sagesse ne sera pas complètement perdue s'ils venaient à mourir.</French>
		<German>Spirit Healer's act are a support unit for offensive stacks. They boost the heal rate of friendly units and can remove Diseased, Plagued and Withered promotions. Additionally, they are able to cast Spirit Guide, ensuring that their wisdom is not completely lost upon their death.</German>
		<Italian>Il Guaritore Spirituale è un'unità di supporto per i gruppi d'attacco. Aumenta il tasso di cura delle unità alleate e può rimuovere le promozioni [LINK=PROMOTION_DISEASED]Malato[\LINK], [LINK=PROMOTION_PLAGUED]Appestato[\LINK] e [LINK=PROMOTION_WITHERED]Avvizzito[\LINK]. In più possono lanciare Spirito Guida, in modo da assicurarsi che la loro saggezza non viene perduta completamente alla loro morte.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Spirit Healer's act are a support unit for offensive stacks. They boost the heal rate of friendly units and can remove Diseased, Plagued and Withered promotions. Additionally, they are able to cast Spirit Guide, ensuring that their wisdom is not completely lost upon their death.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WINDTALKER</Tag>
		<English>Windtalker</English>
		<French>Messager du Vent</French>
		<German>Windsprecher</German>
		<Italian>Windtalker</Italian>
		<Spanish>Windtalker</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_COMMANDER_CHISLEV_WARCHIEF</Tag>
		<English>Warchief</English>
		<French>Chef de guerre</French>
		<German>Kriegshäuptling</German>
		<Italian>Capoguerra</Italian>
		<Spanish>Warchief</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
