<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GRIGORI_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Grigori</English>
		<French>grigori:grigorie:grigoris:grigories</French>
		<German>Grigorisch</German>
		<Italian>Grigori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grigori</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GRIGORI_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Grigori</English>
		<French>Grigor</French>
		<German>Reich der Grigorier</German>
		<Italian>Grigori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grigori</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GRIGORI_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Grigori</English>
		<French>Grigoris</French>
		<German>Grigori</German>
		<Italian>Grigori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grigori</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GRIGORI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Grigori are the only civilization that gains the powerful Adventurer unit. The Adventurer is a Great Person and Hero that can be upgraded into almost any human unit. The Grigori use these customizable heroes as elite warriors, and they can grow into some of the best units in the game. This is balanced with an inability to gain the benefits of a state religion. [PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel was an angel in the service of Dagda. He spent the Age of Dragons protecting the men who hid from the might of the warring gods around them. It was his counsel that led Dagda to create and sign the Compact, but Cassiel felt the Compact did not go far enough. He wanted the gods to retreat entirely, to let the men form their own world. When the Compact allowed the gods to battle through men, Cassiel abandoned Dagda's service and began his own crusade to lead men away from a war that has little to do with them. This action gained him few allies among the gods or the humans who serve them. A few brave souls were attracted to Cassiel's creed, though he refused to offer any divine boons or even direct leadership to them. His followers must adhere to his ideas and lead themselves. Throughout the ages the cities of the Grigori offered safe haven for those who wanted to lead their own lives. The wars of the Age of Magic and the scarcity of the Age of Ice took its toll on them like every other land, but they sought help not from the heavens but from themselves.[PARAGRAPH:1]In the Age of Rebirth, Cassiel still stands, offering others ideas and guidance but little more, and some brave few are still drawn to his ideas. Among those who seek asylum in his lands are the Luonnotar, who teach that none of the gods acting on Erebus is worthy of worship, but only one greater god who made them. Cassiel certainly agrees with the first part of this, though he isn't forthcoming on the second.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The Grigori are the only civilization that gains the powerful Adventurer unit. The Adventurer is a Great Person and Hero that can be upgraded into almost any human unit. The Grigori use these customizable heroes as elite warriors, and they can grow into some of the best units in the game. This is balanced with an inability to gain the benefits of a state religion. [PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel was an angel in the service of Dagda. He spent the Age of Dragons protecting the men who hid from the might of the warring gods around them. It was his counsel that led Dagda to create and sign the Compact, but Cassiel felt the Compact did not go far enough. He wanted the gods to retreat entirely, to let the men form their own world. When the Compact allowed the gods to battle through men, Cassiel abandoned Dagda's service and began his own crusade to lead men away from a war that has little to do with them. This action gained him few allies among the gods or the humans who serve them. A few brave souls were attracted to Cassiel's creed, though he refused to offer any divine boons or even direct leadership to them. His followers must adhere to his ideas and lead themselves. Throughout the ages the cities of the Grigori offered safe haven for those who wanted to lead their own lives. The wars of the Age of Magic and the scarcity of the Age of Ice took its toll on them like every other land, but they sought help not from the heavens but from themselves.[PARAGRAPH:1]In the Age of Rebirth, Cassiel still stands, offering others ideas and guidance but little more, and some brave few are still drawn to his ideas. Among those who seek asylum in his lands are the Luonnotar, who teach that none of the gods acting on Erebus is worthy of worship, but only one greater god who made them. Cassiel certainly agrees with the first part of this, though he isn't forthcoming on the second.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Grigori sind die einzige Zivilisation, die die mächtige Einheit "Abenteurer" aufstellen kann. Der Abenteurer ist eine Große Persönlichkeit und ein Held, der zu fast jeder menschlichen Einheit modernisiert werden kann. Die Grigori nutzen diese anpassbaren Helden als Elitekämpfer, die sich zu einigen der besten Einheiten des Spieles entwickeln können. Dies wird dadurch aufgewogen, dass die Grigori unfähig sind, die Vorteile einer Staatsreligion nutzen zu können.[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel war ein Engel im Dienste von Dagda. Während des Zeitalters der Drachen beschützte er die Menschen, die sich vor der Macht der kriegführenden Göttern versteckten. Auf seinen Rat hin entwarf und unterschrieb Dagda den Pakt, jedoch war Cassiel der Meinung, dass der Pakt nicht weit genug ging. Er wollte, dass sich die Götter gänzlich zurückzogen, damit sich die Menschen ihre eigene Welt aufbauen könnten. Als den Göttern durch den Pakt erlaubt wurde, ihre Kriege mit Hilfe der Menschen zu führen, verließ Cassiel Dagdas Dienste und begann seinen eigenen Kreuzzug, um die Menschen aus einem Krieg herauszuführen, mit dem sie kaum etwas zu tun hatten. Durch diese Tat gewann er nur wenige Verbündete unter den Göttern oder den Menschen, die ihnen dienten. Einige wenige tapfere Seelen teilten Cassiels Überzeugungen, obwohl er sich weigerte, göttliche Wohltaten anzubieten oder sogar direkte Führungsaufgaben wahrzunehmen. Seine Anhänger müssen sich seinen Idealen verpflichten und sich selbst regieren. Während aller Zeitalter boten die Städte der Grigori sichere Zuflucht für jene, die ihr Leben selbst bestimmen wollten. Die Kriege des Zeitalters der Magie und der Mangel des Zeitalters des Eises verlangten von ihnen denselben Tribut wie von anderen Völkern, aber sie vertrauten nicht auf die Hilfe des Himmels, sondern aufeinander.[PARAGRAPH:1]Im Zeitalter der Wiedergeburt steht Cassiel immer noch bereit, um seine Ideale und seien Rat anzubieten, aber wenig mehr, und einige wenige Tapfere werden immer noch von seinen Idealen angezogen. Unter denen, die in seinen Landen um Asyl bitten, befinden sich die Luonnotar, die lehren, dass keiner der auf Erebus aktiven Götter der Anbetung würdig ist, sondern nur der eine höchste Gott, der sie erschaffen hat. Cassiel stimmt dem ersten Teil dieser Aussage sicherlich zu, auch wenn er den zweiten Teil nicht gutheißen kann.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]I Grigori sono l'unica civiltà che ottiene la potente unità Avventuriero. L'Avventuriero è un Grande Personaggio e un'Eroe che può essere migliorato in quasi qualsiasi unità umana. I Grigori usano questi eroi personalizzabili come guerrieri d'elite, ed essi possono diventare alcune delle migliori unità del gioco. Tutto questo viene bilanciato dall'impossibilità di ottenere i benefici da un'eventuale religione di stato. [PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel era un'angelo al servizio di Dagda. Passò l'Era dei Draghi proteggendo gli uomini che si nascondevano dalla furia delle divinità che si scontravao attorno a loro. Furono i suoi consigli a spingere Dagda a creare e firmare il Patto, nonostante ciò Cassiel ritenne che il Patto non era sufficiente. Lui voleva che gli dei si ritraessero completamente dal mondo, cosi da permettere agli uomini di plasmarlo essendo il loro. Quando il Patto permise agli dei di combattere tra di loro attraverso gli uomini Cassiel smise di servire Dagda e inizio la sua crociata personale per guidare gli uomini lontano da una guerra che aveva poco a che fare con loro. Questa sua azione gli fece guadagnare ben pochi alleati tra gli dei o gli uomini che li servivano. Ma alcune anime coraggiose vennerò attratte dal credo di Cassiel, sebbene lui si rifiutò di offrire loro qualsivoglia tipo di favore divino o guida diretta. I suoi seguaci dovevano seguire le sue idee e scegliere da soli le loro strade. Nel corso delle ere le città dei Grigori offrirono un rifugio sicuro a coloro che volevano guidare da soli le loro vite. Le guerre dell'Era della Magia e la scarsità di risorse dell'Era del Ghiaccio li colpirono come tutti gli altri, ma loro non cercarono aiuto dal paradiso ma da se stessi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Nell'Era della Rinascita Cassiel è ancora presente, offrendo agli altri idee e indicazioni ma poco altro, e alcuni coraggiosi continuano ad essere attirati dalle sue idee. Tra coloro che cercano asilo nelle sue terre ci sono i Luonnotar, che sontengono che nessuno degli dei che agiscono su Erebus sia degno di essere venerato, al contrario di un'unico dio maggiore che li ha creati. Cassiel è di sicuro d'accordo sulla prima parte, ma non è dello stesso parere sulla seconda.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Grigori are the only civilization that gains the powerful Adventurer unit. The Adventurer is a Great Person and Hero that can be upgraded into almost any human unit. The Grigori use these customizable heroes as elite warriors, and they can grow into some of the best units in the game. This is balanced with an inability to gain the benefits of a state religion. [PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel was an angel in the service of Dagda. He spent the Age of Dragons protecting the men who hid from the might of the warring gods around them. It was his counsel that led Dagda to create and sign the Compact, but Cassiel felt the Compact did not go far enough. He wanted the gods to retreat entirely, to let the men form their own world. When the Compact allowed the gods to battle through men, Cassiel abandoned Dagda's service and began his own crusade to lead men away from a war that has little to do with them. This action gained him few allies among the gods or the humans who serve them. A few brave souls were attracted to Cassiel's creed, though he refused to offer any divine boons or even direct leadership to them. His followers must adhere to his ideas and lead themselves. Throughout the ages the cities of the Grigori offered safe haven for those who wanted to lead their own lives. The wars of the Age of Magic and the scarcity of the Age of Ice took its toll on them like every other land, but they sought help not from the heavens but from themselves.[PARAGRAPH:1]In the Age of Rebirth, Cassiel still stands, offering others ideas and guidance but little more, and some brave few are still drawn to his ideas. Among those who seek asylum in his lands are the Luonnotar, who teach that none of the gods acting on Erebus is worthy of worship, but only one greater god who made them. Cassiel certainly agrees with the first part of this, though he isn't forthcoming on the second.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GRIGORI_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Loosely speaking, the Grigori are the "Great Person" Civilisation. They sacrifice the ability to adopt a State Religion, but eventually obtain amazing power through using many Specialists in their cities, as well as physical power through a plethora of mini-hero units.[NEWLINE][H2]Adventurers[\H2][ICON_BULLET]As the Grigori gain Great Person points they also progress towards their next free Adventurer spawn. Adventurers are weak, but begin with the Hero promotion that lets them gain experience passively over time, and they can be upgraded into almost any type of human military unit. While not as powerful as full-on World Heroes, the Grigori have many more and each Adventurer is significantly stronger than the default unit of it's class due to their many promotions, and almost always stronger than unique unit replacements.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]As it becomes harder to create Great People, so does it become harder to create Adventurers.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Using Adventurers, even a Grigori army that has never been to war will likely be more than a match for any attacker, as a Grigori army can contain multiple Twin-Casting Archmages, alongside nearly maxed out Phalanxes and fully upgraded Arquebuses.[NEWLINE][H2]Refugees[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Once the Grigori have the Code of Laws tech, they can construct the Memorial of the Refugee, which causes Refugees to spawn in at random.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Refugees are similar to Adventurers in that they can be upgraded into almost any human military unit. However they do not passively gain experience, and can also be made into Settlers, or added to cities to increase their population.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]They can also build Dwellings in other cities which cause Refugees to spawn there as well.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Refugees can be used to bulk out the Grigori military, expand the civilisations borders, or boost the size of existing cities.[NEWLINE][H2]Statesmen[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Statesmen are a type of specialist that is unique to the Grigori. They do not contribute to the Great Person counter, but with the Grigori's unique Citizen's Forum building, Statesmen can affect Adventurer spawns.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]In this way, the Grigori can use Statesmen to create more adventurers without the associated Great People that make it harder to do so.[NEWLINE][H2]Sidequests[\H2][ICON_BULLET]When a Grigori military unit is at a Fort, it can choose to go on a Sidequest.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sidequests last 10 turns and cannot be cancelled. During this time the unit will make random moves in addition to its normal controllable ones, does not reveal Fog of War, and gains extra experience passively, up to a limit of 100 XP.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]If the unit wanders into the Fog of War, it will become uncontrollable until the side quest has finished, or you send another unit out to find it.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Used correctly, Sidequests ensure that all Grigori military units are of a good level, even the rank and file.[NEWLINE][H2]Bringing it all together![\H2][ICON_BULLET]Making the best use of all of the Grigori mechanics requires you to assign as many Specialists as you can afford to, but it also requires a strong economy as both Adventurers and Refugees cost a big chunk of commerce to upgrade all the way.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Consider Civics that boost your Great Person rate like Pacifism or Republic, as well as ones that provide additional specialists to even further increase the GP rate.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Grigori mechanics make a wide array of victory types possible. Played for war they will find they have a military that often both outnumbers the enemy and has more powerful units, allowing them to win a landslide military victory.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Played defensively the Grigori will find that their military is better prepared for defence, and that they need to invest much less than other Civs in the building forces to withstand attack. This frees up their production queues to focus on Arcane or Culture buildings.</English>
		<French>Loosely speaking, the Grigori are the "Great Person" Civilisation. They sacrifice the ability to adopt a State Religion, but eventually obtain amazing power through using many Specialists in their cities, as well as physical power through a plethora of mini-hero units.[NEWLINE][H2]Adventurers[\H2][ICON_BULLET]As the Grigori gain Great Person points they also progress towards their next free Adventurer spawn. Adventurers are weak, but begin with the Hero promotion that lets them gain experience passively over time, and they can be upgraded into almost any type of human military unit. While not as powerful as full-on World Heroes, the Grigori have many more and each Adventurer is significantly stronger than the default unit of it's class due to their many promotions, and almost always stronger than unique unit replacements.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]As it becomes harder to create Great People, so does it become harder to create Adventurers.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Using Adventurers, even a Grigori army that has never been to war will likely be more than a match for any attacker, as a Grigori army can contain multiple Twin-Casting Archmages, alongside nearly maxed out Phalanxes and fully upgraded Arquebuses.[NEWLINE][H2]Refugees[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Once the Grigori have the Code of Laws tech, they can construct the Memorial of the Refugee, which causes Refugees to spawn in at random.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Refugees are similar to Adventurers in that they can be upgraded into almost any human military unit. However they do not passively gain experience, and can also be made into Settlers, or added to cities to increase their population.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]They can also build Dwellings in other cities which cause Refugees to spawn there as well.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Refugees can be used to bulk out the Grigori military, expand the civilisations borders, or boost the size of existing cities.[NEWLINE][H2]Statesmen[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Statesmen are a type of specialist that is unique to the Grigori. They do not contribute to the Great Person counter, but with the Grigori's unique Citizen's Forum building, Statesmen can affect Adventurer spawns.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]In this way, the Grigori can use Statesmen to create more adventurers without the associated Great People that make it harder to do so.[NEWLINE][H2]Sidequests[\H2][ICON_BULLET]When a Grigori military unit is at a Fort, it can choose to go on a Sidequest.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sidequests last 10 turns and cannot be cancelled. During this time the unit will make random moves in addition to its normal controllable ones, does not reveal Fog of War, and gains extra experience passively, up to a limit of 100 XP.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]If the unit wanders into the Fog of War, it will become uncontrollable until the side quest has finished, or you send another unit out to find it.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Used correctly, Sidequests ensure that all Grigori military units are of a good level, even the rank and file.[NEWLINE][H2]Bringing it all together![\H2][ICON_BULLET]Making the best use of all of the Grigori mechanics requires you to assign as many Specialists as you can afford to, but it also requires a strong economy as both Adventurers and Refugees cost a big chunk of commerce to upgrade all the way.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Consider Civics that boost your Great Person rate like Pacifism or Republic, as well as ones that provide additional specialists to even further increase the GP rate.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Grigori mechanics make a wide array of victory types possible. Played for war they will find they have a military that often both outnumbers the enemy and has more powerful units, allowing them to win a landslide military victory.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Played defensively the Grigori will find that their military is better prepared for defence, and that they need to invest much less than other Civs in the building forces to withstand attack. This frees up their production queues to focus on Arcane or Culture buildings.</French>
		<German>Loosely speaking, the Grigori are the "Great Person" Civilisation. They sacrifice the ability to adopt a State Religion, but eventually obtain amazing power through using many Specialists in their cities, as well as physical power through a plethora of mini-hero units.[NEWLINE][H2]Adventurers[\H2][ICON_BULLET]As the Grigori gain Great Person points they also progress towards their next free Adventurer spawn. Adventurers are weak, but begin with the Hero promotion that lets them gain experience passively over time, and they can be upgraded into almost any type of human military unit. While not as powerful as full-on World Heroes, the Grigori have many more and each Adventurer is significantly stronger than the default unit of it's class due to their many promotions, and almost always stronger than unique unit replacements.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]As it becomes harder to create Great People, so does it become harder to create Adventurers.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Using Adventurers, even a Grigori army that has never been to war will likely be more than a match for any attacker, as a Grigori army can contain multiple Twin-Casting Archmages, alongside nearly maxed out Phalanxes and fully upgraded Arquebuses.[NEWLINE][H2]Refugees[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Once the Grigori have the Code of Laws tech, they can construct the Memorial of the Refugee, which causes Refugees to spawn in at random.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Refugees are similar to Adventurers in that they can be upgraded into almost any human military unit. However they do not passively gain experience, and can also be made into Settlers, or added to cities to increase their population.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]They can also build Dwellings in other cities which cause Refugees to spawn there as well.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Refugees can be used to bulk out the Grigori military, expand the civilisations borders, or boost the size of existing cities.[NEWLINE][H2]Statesmen[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Statesmen are a type of specialist that is unique to the Grigori. They do not contribute to the Great Person counter, but with the Grigori's unique Citizen's Forum building, Statesmen can affect Adventurer spawns.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]In this way, the Grigori can use Statesmen to create more adventurers without the associated Great People that make it harder to do so.[NEWLINE][H2]Sidequests[\H2][ICON_BULLET]When a Grigori military unit is at a Fort, it can choose to go on a Sidequest.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sidequests last 10 turns and cannot be cancelled. During this time the unit will make random moves in addition to its normal controllable ones, does not reveal Fog of War, and gains extra experience passively, up to a limit of 100 XP.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]If the unit wanders into the Fog of War, it will become uncontrollable until the side quest has finished, or you send another unit out to find it.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Used correctly, Sidequests ensure that all Grigori military units are of a good level, even the rank and file.[NEWLINE][H2]Bringing it all together![\H2][ICON_BULLET]Making the best use of all of the Grigori mechanics requires you to assign as many Specialists as you can afford to, but it also requires a strong economy as both Adventurers and Refugees cost a big chunk of commerce to upgrade all the way.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Consider Civics that boost your Great Person rate like Pacifism or Republic, as well as ones that provide additional specialists to even further increase the GP rate.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Grigori mechanics make a wide array of victory types possible. Played for war they will find they have a military that often both outnumbers the enemy and has more powerful units, allowing them to win a landslide military victory.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Played defensively the Grigori will find that their military is better prepared for defence, and that they need to invest much less than other Civs in the building forces to withstand attack. This frees up their production queues to focus on Arcane or Culture buildings.</German>
		<Italian>Generalmente parlando i Grigori sono la civiltà dei "Grandi Personaggi". Loro sacrificano l'abilità di adottare una religione di stato, ma possono ottenere un'incredibile potere attraverso l'uso di molti specialisti nelle loro città, oltre al potere ottenuto attraverso una sovrabbondanza di unità simil eroiche.[NEWLINE][H2]Avventurieri[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Quando i Grigori ottengono punti per i Grandi Personaggi progrediscono anche verso la generazione gratuita di un nuovo Avventuriero. Gli Avventurieri sono deboli, ma iniziano con la promozione Eroe, che gli consente di guadagnare esperienza nel tempo, e possono venir migliorati in quasi qualsiasi unità militare umana. Sebbene non siano forti quanto dei veri Eroi i Grigori ne hanno molti di più e ogni Avventuriero è significativamente più forte dell'unità base della sua classe per via delle sue molte promozioni, e quasi sempre più forte delle unità uniche di rimpiazzo.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Man mano che diventa più difficile creare Grandi Personaggi lo stesso avviene per gli Avventurieri.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Usando gli Avventurieri persino un'esercito Grigori che non ha mai combattuto può dare del filo da torcere a qualsiasi attaccante, in quanto un'esercito Grigori può contenere diversi Arcimaghi con lancio doppio, insieme a Falangi vicine all'apice della forza e Archibuggieri completamente potenziati.[NEWLINE][H2]Rifugiati[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Una volta che i Grigori ottengono la tecnologia Codice delle Leggi possono costruire il Memoriale del Rifugiato, che permette la generazione casuale in città di Rifugiati.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]I Rifugiati sono simili agli Avventurieri, in quanto anche loro possono essere migliorati in quasi qualsiasi unità militare umana. Tuttavia loro non ottengono esperienza nel tempo, e possono anche essere trasformati in Coloni, o uniti alle città per aumentare la loro popolazione.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Possono inoltre creare l'edificio Abitazioni dei Rifugiati nelle altre città permettendo cosi la generazione di Rifugiati anche li.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]I Rifugiati possono essere usati per ingrossare le forze armate Grigori, espandere i territori della civiltà, o aumentare la popolazione delle città già esistenti.[NEWLINE][H2]Statisti[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Gli Statisti sono un tipo di specialista unico disponibile solo ai Grigori. Di norma non contribuiscono al contatore dei Grandi Personaggi, ma con l'edificio unico dei Grigori, il Forum dei Cittadini, possono influenzare la generazione di Avventurieri.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]In questo modo i Grigori possono usare gli Statisti per creare più Avventurieri, senza associarli ai Grandi Personaggi che diventano più difficili da ottenere col tempo.[NEWLINE][H2]Missioni Secondarie[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Quando un'unità militare Grigori è in un Forte può decidere di intraprendere una Missione Secondaria.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Le Missioni Secondarie durano 10 turni e non possono essere interrotte. Durante questo periodo di tempo l'unità compirà movimenti casuali in aggiunta a quelli normali controllabili, non rivelerà la Nebbia di Guerra e otterrà esperienza extra passivamente, sino ad un massimo di 100 PE.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Se l'unità finisce all'interno della Nebbia di Guerra non sarà più controllabile sino a quando la missione secondaria non sarà conclusa, o mandi un'altra unità a cercarla.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Se usate correttamente le Missioni Secondarie permettono a tutte le unità militari Grigori di essere di alto livello, persino quelle base.[NEWLINE][H2]Unire il tutto![\H2][ICON_BULLET]Per ottenere il massimo dalle mecchaniche dei Grigori si deve assegnare quanti più Specialisti possibile, ma è anche necessario avere una forte economia in quanto sia gli Avventurieri che i Rifugiati richiedono ingenti quantita di soldi per essere migliorati.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Prendi in considerazione le Forme di Governo che aiutano la generazione di Grandi Personaggi, come Pacifismo o Repubblica, oltre a quelle che forniscono specialisti aggiuntivi.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Le mecchaniche dei Grigori rendono possibili diversi tipi di vittoria. Se usati per la guerra si ritroveranno con delle forze armate che spesso soverchiano numeramente il nemico e che possiedono delle unità più forti, permettendogli di vincere una vittoria di conquista.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Se giocati sulla difensiva i Grigori scopriranno che hanno bisogno di investire di meno rispetto alle altre civiltà per avere una buona forza difensiva capace di respingere le invasioni. Questo gli permette di investire maggiormente sugli edifici culturali o arcani.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Loosely speaking, the Grigori are the "Great Person" Civilisation. They sacrifice the ability to adopt a State Religion, but eventually obtain amazing power through using many Specialists in their cities, as well as physical power through a plethora of mini-hero units.[NEWLINE][H2]Adventurers[\H2][ICON_BULLET]As the Grigori gain Great Person points they also progress towards their next free Adventurer spawn. Adventurers are weak, but begin with the Hero promotion that lets them gain experience passively over time, and they can be upgraded into almost any type of human military unit. While not as powerful as full-on World Heroes, the Grigori have many more and each Adventurer is significantly stronger than the default unit of it's class due to their many promotions, and almost always stronger than unique unit replacements.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]As it becomes harder to create Great People, so does it become harder to create Adventurers.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Using Adventurers, even a Grigori army that has never been to war will likely be more than a match for any attacker, as a Grigori army can contain multiple Twin-Casting Archmages, alongside nearly maxed out Phalanxes and fully upgraded Arquebuses.[NEWLINE][H2]Refugees[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Once the Grigori have the Code of Laws tech, they can construct the Memorial of the Refugee, which causes Refugees to spawn in at random.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Refugees are similar to Adventurers in that they can be upgraded into almost any human military unit. However they do not passively gain experience, and can also be made into Settlers, or added to cities to increase their population.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]They can also build Dwellings in other cities which cause Refugees to spawn there as well.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Refugees can be used to bulk out the Grigori military, expand the civilisations borders, or boost the size of existing cities.[NEWLINE][H2]Statesmen[\H2][ICON_BULLET]Statesmen are a type of specialist that is unique to the Grigori. They do not contribute to the Great Person counter, but with the Grigori's unique Citizen's Forum building, Statesmen can affect Adventurer spawns.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]In this way, the Grigori can use Statesmen to create more adventurers without the associated Great People that make it harder to do so.[NEWLINE][H2]Sidequests[\H2][ICON_BULLET]When a Grigori military unit is at a Fort, it can choose to go on a Sidequest.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sidequests last 10 turns and cannot be cancelled. During this time the unit will make random moves in addition to its normal controllable ones, does not reveal Fog of War, and gains extra experience passively, up to a limit of 100 XP.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]If the unit wanders into the Fog of War, it will become uncontrollable until the side quest has finished, or you send another unit out to find it.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Used correctly, Sidequests ensure that all Grigori military units are of a good level, even the rank and file.[NEWLINE][H2]Bringing it all together![\H2][ICON_BULLET]Making the best use of all of the Grigori mechanics requires you to assign as many Specialists as you can afford to, but it also requires a strong economy as both Adventurers and Refugees cost a big chunk of commerce to upgrade all the way.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Consider Civics that boost your Great Person rate like Pacifism or Republic, as well as ones that provide additional specialists to even further increase the GP rate.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Grigori mechanics make a wide array of victory types possible. Played for war they will find they have a military that often both outnumbers the enemy and has more powerful units, allowing them to win a landslide military victory.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Played defensively the Grigori will find that their military is better prepared for defence, and that they need to invest much less than other Civs in the building forces to withstand attack. This frees up their production queues to focus on Arcane or Culture buildings.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CASSIEL</Tag>
		<English>Cassiel</English>
		<French>Cassiel</French>
		<German>Cassiel</German>
		<Italian>Cassiel</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cassiel</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CASSIEL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]My name is Elizabeth, and I was murdered on the first day of winter. My father was at the market. In the instant I died, he was buying ribbons for my hair. Later, he would put them on my corpse.[PARAGRAPH:1]My father knew the man who killed me, a neighbor that talked to him about trade and argued about religion. As a follower of the Order, my father was quick to advocate it to anyone who would listen. The neighbor looked at me the way some men look at teenage girls, but he had never spoken to me until that day.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hello Elizabeth."[PARAGRAPH:1]I was surprised he knew my name. I was removing the last of the vegetables from our small garden before the night's frost killed them. I stood and subconsciously straightened the worn dress I was wearing. I didn't answer him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do you know anything about cats?" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I had a cat, she disappeared a few weeks ago."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was she white?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, did you find her?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I was an only child, my mother died when I was born and my cat Abagail was the keeper of my secrets and playmate for as long as I could remember. I searched for her and had almost given up hope.[PARAGRAPH:1]"More like she found me, she's moved into my cellar. She's taken over a corner for herself and her kittens."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kittens?"[PARAGRAPH:1]He returned my smile. His hand had been resting on his knife-most men in the city carried them-but now he relaxed and took his hand off of it.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Would you like to see them? Maybe help me move them to your house. I want to make sure they get somewhere warm before tonight."[PARAGRAPH:1]I followed him to his house; we walked across my yard and through a small field that separated our homes. At the time I was too excited to wonder why we didn't walk on the road. The field opened to the back of his house, which is where the cellar entrance was. He unlocked the cellar and opened it for me. This was the first time I had a suspicion that something was wrong. If I was by myself I wouldn't have gone down there, but I had told him I would and I didn't want to seem like a scared girl so I went down the wooden stairs. He followed and closed the doors behind him.[PARAGRAPH:1]The cellar was a shrine to Agares, decorated in blood and jagged weapons. He attacked me as soon as I saw it. In time he would sacrifice me on the cellar's brown altar, but even worse was done to me before.[PARAGRAPH:1]I wandered in the grey. I saw my father search for me, my body was found in the woods outside the village a few days later, covered with cuts and ritual marks. My killer came to my house and offered his condolences with the rest of the neighborhood, pretended to be shocked and upset. I watched my father come and go, cry and then pretend to be okay when neighbors came over. Crushed by the thought that when his daughter really needed him, he wasn't there.[PARAGRAPH:1]In time I became aware of something else. Abagail came trotting through a wall, meowing in that way she reserved for when I forgot to feed her. I rushed to her, picked her up and squeezed her as she nuzzled my neck with her head.[PARAGRAPH:1]When I set her down she started walking, then looked back to see if I was following, which I did. We left the city, walked through forests, fields, mountains. I was never tired or hungry and only had a dim view of the world, as if I was viewing it through a haze. Some dark places we avoided and I could occasionally hear voices, usually angry or sad from those places.[PARAGRAPH:1]We walked until we entered a city much larger than mine. We went through it to a grand palace at its center, decorated in bronze and black. We walked through to the throne room and the haze was gone from the center of this room. A man with ivory skin sat on a throne, listening to an argument between two merchants. The man was tired and I somehow knew that he was once one of the greatest of angels, now bearing the burden of mortality and time.[PARAGRAPH:1]I had heard of an angel that had become human, the archangel Cassiel who had turned against the gods, who claimed that religion was servitude and wouldn't follow them. But after what I saw, felt, experienced... I couldn't accept that. There was an enemy, a religion that should be battled. I approached his throne, knowing he would see me even if no one else did.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Cassiel, the Veil killed me. You can do something about that, the Order is trying to fight them. You could help."[PARAGRAPH:1]He looked at me, I saw a great sadness in him. The same as in my father when he sat in my bedroom and cried. The arguing merchants quieted, realizing Cassiel's attention was somewhere else.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Open your eyes."[PARAGRAPH:1]He said it to me, he was pleading with me and commanding me at the same time. I tried to follow it, everything except Cassiel seemed distant. I could see Abagail at my feet, the rest was clouds of grey flowing into each other. I looked at these clouds, there were shapes in them, figures, faces. And I began to see other spirits in them. Men and women, orcs and elves, children and adults, all caught in their own grey worlds.[PARAGRAPH:1]I talked to the spirit of a man who had been killed by an order Confessor for lying, a boy who had starved because his family couldn't afford food and the teachings of Kilmorph don't emphasize charity, an elf who had used wood from a sacred tree to rebuild his home and had been killed by the Fellowship for it. And thousands who had died in wars they didn't believe in for gods they didn't trust and who didn't accept them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Later I went back to Cassiel, he was sitting alone on the roof of his palace.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are we forever doomed to this in-between place? I understand now that the gods are flawed, but if they hold the only way into heaven, what else can we do but follow them?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel smiled at me. "The places they have made are not heaven, the true heaven is closed to everyone, even them. One day the doors will open and we will be rejoined. Until then we wait and we try to improve what we have been given."[PARAGRAPH:1]After that I sat at the feet of his throne, played with Abagail and paid less and less attention to the occurrences of the mortal world. Until I heard a familiar voice in the throne room, that of my father.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Lord Cassiel, I have come from the Bannor empire, I have turned my back on my people and my god. The religion that once seemed so important to me, that I dedicated my life to, offered no comfort to me when I needed it. Only hollow words about faith and my own weakness. Now I come to you. Three years ago my daughter was killed, she was only a child and she was sacrificed in some unholy ceremony. Because of the manner of her death the priests say they cannot bury her in the cemetery, they burned her so that an evil spirit wouldn't inhabit her tiny corpse."[PARAGRAPH:1]My father fought to keep his composure. He took a deep breath before continuing.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Now I come to you." He repeated. "To offer my help, I'm only a simple merchant but if you would have me I wish to join the Grigori."[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel looked at him, requests like this weren't uncommon. They usually wouldn't even get to Cassiel himself unless the person was someone politically important.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You will stay in the palace tonight. Tomorrow you will awake a new man, put your old life behind you and start a new one here. Your name will be Goodreau. In the morning you will go into the city, find a job and earn your place among my people. But for tonight you are still Tamur the Merchant. My sergeant will show you a room and provide you with food and drink. Eat and sleep well."[PARAGRAPH:1]My father thanked him and followed the sergeant out of the throne room. I followed them and sat in the small bedroom they gave him. Traveling had been hard on him and he ate ravenously and fell asleep. I sat in the corner of the room just as I had in my bedroom when he cried after my death.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Elizabeth?"[PARAGRAPH:1]My father was awake, awake and staring at me.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, daddy."[PARAGRAPH:1]He jumped out of the bed, terrified, but only terrified that he was somehow imaging this and I would disappear before he could grab me. But his arms passed right through me and he fell on the floor sobbing. I knelt down beside him, he stared at me, trying to memorize every detail of my face.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh sweetie, I'm so sorry... please... I'm sorry... I'm sorry"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Daddy, I'm okay."[PARAGRAPH:1]We talked and I told him about the fake heavens and my life at the palace. How, if it had been three years, it seemed like only a few days to me. That I really didn't remember dying that well, but I remembered playing games with him and the walks we used to take. I lied and told him I didn't know who killed me, I didn't want him going back.[PARAGRAPH:1]We talked until dawn. As I began to fade from his sight he pleaded with me to stay, asked what he could do to stay with me. I repeated Cassiel's words.[PARAGRAPH:1]"One day the doors will open and we will be rejoined. Until then we wait and we try to improve what we have been given."[PARAGRAPH:1]He said he loved me, that he would see me again and when I was completely gone from his view he left the palace and started his new life among the Grigori.</English>
		<French>[TAB]My name is Elizabeth, and I was murdered on the first day of winter. My father was at the market. In the instant I died, he was buying ribbons for my hair. Later, he would put them on my corpse.[PARAGRAPH:1]My father knew the man who killed me, a neighbor that talked to him about trade and argued about religion. As a follower of the Order, my father was quick to advocate it to anyone who would listen. The neighbor looked at me the way some men look at teenage girls, but he had never spoken to me until that day.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hello Elizabeth."[PARAGRAPH:1]I was surprised he knew my name. I was removing the last of the vegetables from our small garden before the night's frost killed them. I stood and subconsciously straightened the worn dress I was wearing. I didn't answer him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do you know anything about cats?" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I had a cat, she disappeared a few weeks ago."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was she white?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, did you find her?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I was an only child, my mother died when I was born and my cat Abagail was the keeper of my secrets and playmate for as long as I could remember. I searched for her and had almost given up hope.[PARAGRAPH:1]"More like she found me, she's moved into my cellar. She's taken over a corner for herself and her kittens."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kittens?"[PARAGRAPH:1]He returned my smile. His hand had been resting on his knife-most men in the city carried them-but now he relaxed and took his hand off of it.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Would you like to see them? Maybe help me move them to your house. I want to make sure they get somewhere warm before tonight."[PARAGRAPH:1]I followed him to his house; we walked across my yard and through a small field that separated our homes. At the time I was too excited to wonder why we didn't walk on the road. The field opened to the back of his house, which is where the cellar entrance was. He unlocked the cellar and opened it for me. This was the first time I had a suspicion that something was wrong. If I was by myself I wouldn't have gone down there, but I had told him I would and I didn't want to seem like a scared girl so I went down the wooden stairs. He followed and closed the doors behind him.[PARAGRAPH:1]The cellar was a shrine to Agares, decorated in blood and jagged weapons. He attacked me as soon as I saw it. In time he would sacrifice me on the cellar's brown altar, but even worse was done to me before.[PARAGRAPH:1]I wandered in the grey. I saw my father search for me, my body was found in the woods outside the village a few days later, covered with cuts and ritual marks. My killer came to my house and offered his condolences with the rest of the neighborhood, pretended to be shocked and upset. I watched my father come and go, cry and then pretend to be okay when neighbors came over. Crushed by the thought that when his daughter really needed him, he wasn't there.[PARAGRAPH:1]In time I became aware of something else. Abagail came trotting through a wall, meowing in that way she reserved for when I forgot to feed her. I rushed to her, picked her up and squeezed her as she nuzzled my neck with her head.[PARAGRAPH:1]When I set her down she started walking, then looked back to see if I was following, which I did. We left the city, walked through forests, fields, mountains. I was never tired or hungry and only had a dim view of the world, as if I was viewing it through a haze. Some dark places we avoided and I could occasionally hear voices, usually angry or sad from those places.[PARAGRAPH:1]We walked until we entered a city much larger than mine. We went through it to a grand palace at its center, decorated in bronze and black. We walked through to the throne room and the haze was gone from the center of this room. A man with ivory skin sat on a throne, listening to an argument between two merchants. The man was tired and I somehow knew that he was once one of the greatest of angels, now bearing the burden of mortality and time.[PARAGRAPH:1]I had heard of an angel that had become human, the archangel Cassiel who had turned against the gods, who claimed that religion was servitude and wouldn't follow them. But after what I saw, felt, experienced... I couldn't accept that. There was an enemy, a religion that should be battled. I approached his throne, knowing he would see me even if no one else did.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Cassiel, the Veil killed me. You can do something about that, the Order is trying to fight them. You could help."[PARAGRAPH:1]He looked at me, I saw a great sadness in him. The same as in my father when he sat in my bedroom and cried. The arguing merchants quieted, realizing Cassiel's attention was somewhere else.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Open your eyes."[PARAGRAPH:1]He said it to me, he was pleading with me and commanding me at the same time. I tried to follow it, everything except Cassiel seemed distant. I could see Abagail at my feet, the rest was clouds of grey flowing into each other. I looked at these clouds, there were shapes in them, figures, faces. And I began to see other spirits in them. Men and women, orcs and elves, children and adults, all caught in their own grey worlds.[PARAGRAPH:1]I talked to the spirit of a man who had been killed by an order Confessor for lying, a boy who had starved because his family couldn't afford food and the teachings of Kilmorph don't emphasize charity, an elf who had used wood from a sacred tree to rebuild his home and had been killed by the Fellowship for it. And thousands who had died in wars they didn't believe in for gods they didn't trust and who didn't accept them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Later I went back to Cassiel, he was sitting alone on the roof of his palace.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are we forever doomed to this in-between place? I understand now that the gods are flawed, but if they hold the only way into heaven, what else can we do but follow them?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel smiled at me. "The places they have made are not heaven, the true heaven is closed to everyone, even them. One day the doors will open and we will be rejoined. Until then we wait and we try to improve what we have been given."[PARAGRAPH:1]After that I sat at the feet of his throne, played with Abagail and paid less and less attention to the occurrences of the mortal world. Until I heard a familiar voice in the throne room, that of my father.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Lord Cassiel, I have come from the Bannor empire, I have turned my back on my people and my god. The religion that once seemed so important to me, that I dedicated my life to, offered no comfort to me when I needed it. Only hollow words about faith and my own weakness. Now I come to you. Three years ago my daughter was killed, she was only a child and she was sacrificed in some unholy ceremony. Because of the manner of her death the priests say they cannot bury her in the cemetery, they burned her so that an evil spirit wouldn't inhabit her tiny corpse."[PARAGRAPH:1]My father fought to keep his composure. He took a deep breath before continuing.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Now I come to you." He repeated. "To offer my help, I'm only a simple merchant but if you would have me I wish to join the Grigori."[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel looked at him, requests like this weren't uncommon. They usually wouldn't even get to Cassiel himself unless the person was someone politically important.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You will stay in the palace tonight. Tomorrow you will awake a new man, put your old life behind you and start a new one here. Your name will be Goodreau. In the morning you will go into the city, find a job and earn your place among my people. But for tonight you are still Tamur the Merchant. My sergeant will show you a room and provide you with food and drink. Eat and sleep well."[PARAGRAPH:1]My father thanked him and followed the sergeant out of the throne room. I followed them and sat in the small bedroom they gave him. Traveling had been hard on him and he ate ravenously and fell asleep. I sat in the corner of the room just as I had in my bedroom when he cried after my death.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Elizabeth?"[PARAGRAPH:1]My father was awake, awake and staring at me.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, daddy."[PARAGRAPH:1]He jumped out of the bed, terrified, but only terrified that he was somehow imaging this and I would disappear before he could grab me. But his arms passed right through me and he fell on the floor sobbing. I knelt down beside him, he stared at me, trying to memorize every detail of my face.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh sweetie, I'm so sorry... please... I'm sorry... I'm sorry"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Daddy, I'm okay."[PARAGRAPH:1]We talked and I told him about the fake heavens and my life at the palace. How, if it had been three years, it seemed like only a few days to me. That I really didn't remember dying that well, but I remembered playing games with him and the walks we used to take. I lied and told him I didn't know who killed me, I didn't want him going back.[PARAGRAPH:1]We talked until dawn. As I began to fade from his sight he pleaded with me to stay, asked what he could do to stay with me. I repeated Cassiel's words.[PARAGRAPH:1]"One day the doors will open and we will be rejoined. Until then we wait and we try to improve what we have been given."[PARAGRAPH:1]He said he loved me, that he would see me again and when I was completely gone from his view he left the palace and started his new life among the Grigori.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Mein Name ist Elisabeth, und ich bin in den ersten Wintertagen ermordet worden. Mein Vater war auf dem Markt. In dem Moment, in dem ich starb, hatte er Bänder für meine Haare gekauft. Später hat er sie dann an meine Leiche gebunden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mein Vater kannte den Mann, der mich getötet hat, einen Nachbarn, der mit ihm über Handel geredet, und über Religion gestritten hat. Als ein Gläubiger der Weisung, war mein Vater schnell dabei, ihn bei jedem anzupreisen, der ihm zuhören würde. Der Nachbar hat mich angesehen, wie manche Männer jugendliche Mädchen anschauen, aber er hatte nie mit mir gesprochen, bis zu jenem Tag.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hallo, Elisabeth."[PARAGRAPH:1]Ich war überrascht, dass er meinen Namen kannte. Ich war dabei, das letzte Gemüse aus unserem kleinen Garten hinein zu bringen, bevor der nächtliche Frost es zerstören konnte. Ich stand auf, und strich unterbewusst das ausgetragene Kleid, das ich anhatte, glatt. Ich antwortete ihm nicht.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Weißt du etwas über Katzen?", fragte er.[PARAGRAPH:1] "Ich hatte eine Katze, die ist vor ein paar Wochen verschwunden."[PARAGRAPH:1]"War sie weiß?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ja, habt Ihr sie gefunden?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Ich war ein Einzelkind, meine Mutter starb bei meiner Geburt, und meine Katze Abagail war die Behüterin meiner Geheimnisse, und meine Spielkameradin solange ich mich erinnern konnte. Ich hatte nach ihr gesucht, und die Hoffnung schon fast aufgegeben.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Eher hat sie mich gefunden, sie wohnt in meinem Keller. Sie hat sich eine Ecke zurecht gemacht, für sich und ihre Kätzchen." [PARAGRAPH:1]"Kätzchen?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Er erwiderte mein Lächeln. Seine Hand war auf seinem Messer gelegen, die meisten Männer in der Stadt hatten eines, aber jetzt entspannte er sich, und nahm seine Hand herunter.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Möchtest du sie sehen? Vielleicht kannst du mir helfen, sie in euer Haus zu bringen. Ich möchte nur sicher sein, dass sie vor heute Nacht noch ins Warme kommen." [PARAGRAPH:1]Ich folgte ihm zu seinem Haus, wir gingen durch unseren Garten, und durch ein kleines Feld, das unsere Häuser trennte. Noch war ich zu aufgeregt, um mich zu fragen, warum wir nicht auf der Straße gingen. Das Feld führte zur Rückseite seines Hauses, an der der Eingang zum Keller lag. Er sperrte den Keller auf, und hielt mir die Tür offen. Das war das erste Mal, an dem mir etwas falsch vorkam. Wenn ich alleine gewesen wäre, wäre ich dort nicht hinunter gegangen, aber ich hatte ihm gesagt, dass ich es würde, und ich wollte nicht wie ein verängstigtes Mädchen wirken, und so stieg ich die hölzernen Stiegen hinunter. Er folgte mir, und schloss die Türen hinter ihm.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Keller war ein Schrein zu Ehren Agares', mit Blut und gebrauchten Waffen geschmückt. Sobald ich das sah, griff er mich an. Danach wollte er mich auf dem braunen Altar des Kellers opfern, doch noch schlimmeres tat er mir davor noch an.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ich wanderte im wabernden Grau. Ich sah meinen Vater, als er nach mir suchte, mein Körper wurde ein paar Tage später in den Wäldern außerhalb der Stadt gefunden, bedeckt mit Schnitten und rituellen Symbolen. Mein Mörder kam in mein Haus und stattete sein Beileid mit dem Rest der Nachbarschaft ab, und gab vor, schockiert und erzürnt zu sein. Ich sah meinen Vater kommen und gehen, weinen, und vorzugeben, dass alles gut wäre, wenn die Nachbarn vorbei kamen. Erdrückt von dem Gedanken, dass er, als seine Tochter ihn wirklich gebraucht hätte, nicht da war.[PARAGRAPH:1]Nach einiger Zeit, fiel mir noch weiteres auf. Abagail kam durch eine Mauer getrottet, und miaute in einer Art, in der sie immer miaute, wenn ich sie zu füttern vergessen hatte. Ich lief zu ihr, nahm sie auf, und drückte sie, als sie meinen Nacken mit ihrem Kopf rieb.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als ich sie absetzte, begann sie zu gehen, und sah zurück, um zu sehen, ob ich ihr folgte, und das tat ich. Wir verließen die Stadt, und wanderten durch Wälder, Felder, und Berge. Ich war nie hungrig oder müde, und konnte die Welt nur verschwommen sehen, als ob ich sie durch einen Schleier betrachten würde. Wir wichen manchen dunklen Orten aus, und manchmal hörte ich Stimmen, normalerweise wütende oder traurige, aus diesen Plätzen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wir wanderten, bis wir eine Stadt betraten, die viel größer als meine Heimatstadt war. Wir durchschritten sie bis zu einem gewaltigen Palast in ihrem Zentrum, der in Bronze und Schwarz gekleidet war. Wir gingen hindurch bis zur Thronhalle, und der Schleier war in der Mitte dieses Raumes verschwunden. Ein Mann mit elfenbeinerner Haut saß auf dem Thron, und hörte dem Streit zweier Kaufmänner zu. Der Mann war erschöpft, und ich wusste instinktiv, dass er einst einer der größten der Engel gewesen war, und nun die Last der Sterblichkeit und der Zeit trug.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ich hatte von einem Engel gehört, der zum Menschen geworden war, dem Erzengel Cassiel, der sich gegen die Götter gewendet hatte, der Religionen als Knechtschaften betrachtete, und ihnen nicht folgte. Aber nachdem, was ich gesehen, gefühlt, und erlebt hatte... konnte ich das nicht akzeptieren. Es gab einen Feind, eine Religion, die bekämpft werden sollte. Ich näherte mich seinem Thron, und wusste, dass er mich sehen konnte, auch wenn das sonst keiner konnte. [PARAGRAPH:1] "Cassiel, der Schleier hat mich getötet. Ihr könnt etwas dagegen tun, die Weisung versucht, den Schleier zu bekämpfen. Ihr könntet helfen."[PARAGRAPH:1]Er sah mich an, und ich erblickte eine große Traurigkeit in ihm. Die gleiche, die in meinem Vater war, als er in meinem Schlafzimmer gesessen und geweint hatte. Die streitenden Händler wurden still, da sie bemerkten, das Cassiels Aufmerksamkeit wo anders lag.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Öffne deine Augen."[PARAGRAPH:1]Er sprach zu mir, er bat mich und er befahl mir zur gleichen Zeit. Ich versuchte, es zu befolgen, und bis auf Cassiel schien alles weit entfernt zu liegen. Ich konnte Abagail zu meinen Füßen sehen, der Rest war Wolken aus grau, die ineinander flossen. Ich betrachtete diese Wolken, es waren Formen in ihnen, Figuren, Gesichter. Und ich begann, andere Geister in ihnen zu sehen. Männer und Frauen, Orks und Elfen, Kinder und Erwachsene, alle in ihrer eigenen grauen Welt gefangen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ich sprach mit dem Geist eines Mannes, der von einem Bekenner der Weisung getötet worden war, weil er gelogen hatte, einem Buben der verhungert war, weil seine Familie kein Essen mehr kaufen konnte, und die Lehren von Kilmorph's Nächstenliebe nicht für gut befunden hatte, einem Elfen, der Holz eines heiligen Baumes benutzt hatte, um sein Heim wieder aufzubauen, und von der Gefolgschaft dafür getötet worden war. Und mit tausenden, die in Kriegen gestorben waren, an die sie nicht geglaubt hatten, für Götter, denen sie nicht vertraut hatten, und die sie nicht angenommen hatten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Später ging ich zu Cassiel zurück, er saß allein auf dem Dach seines Palastes.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sind wir dazu verdammt, für immer in dieser Zwischenwelt zu bleiben? Ich verstehe jetzt, dass die Götter uns benutzen, aber wenn sie den einzigen Weg in den Himmel halten, was können wir tun, wenn wir nicht ihnen folgen?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel lächelte mich an. "Die Orte, die sie gemacht haben, sind nicht der Himmel, der wahre Himmel ist jedem verschlossen, sogar ihnen. Eines Tages werden sich die Tore öffnen, und wir werden wieder vereint sein. Bis dorthin werden wir warten, und versuchen, das zu verbessern, das uns gegeben wurde."[PARAGRAPH:1]Nachher saß ich am Fuße des Thrones, spielte mit Abagail, und achtete weniger und weniger auf die Vorkommnisse der sterblichen Welt. Bis ich eine bekannte Stimme im Thronsaal vernahm, die meines Vaters.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Fürst Cassiel, ich komme aus dem Reich der Bannor, ich habe meinem Volk und meinem Gott den Rücken zugekehrt. Die Religion, die mir einst so wichtig erschien, der ich mein Leben geweiht hatte, erwies mir keine Hilfe, als ich sie gebraucht hatte. Nur hohle Worte über Glauben und meine eigene Schwäche. Jetzt komme ich zu Euch. Vor drei Jahren wurde meine Tochter getötet, sie war noch ein Kind, und sie wurde in einer unheiligen Zeremonie geopfert. Wegen der Art ihres Todes sagten die Priester, dass sie nicht auf dem Friedhof begraben werden konnte, und sie verbrannten sie, damit nicht ein böser Geist in ihren winzigen Körper fahren würde."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mein Vater kämpfte mit sich, um gefasst zu bleiben. Er holte tief Luft, bevor er fortfuhr.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Jetzt komme ich zu Euch", wiederholte er, "um meine Hilfe anzubieten. Ich bin nur ein einfacher Händler, aber wenn Ihr mich behalten wollt, so wünsche ich, den Grigori beizutreten."[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel sah ihn an, Bitten wie diese waren nicht ungewöhnlich. Normalerweise kamen sie nicht einmal bis zu Cassiel selbst, außer die Person die sie stellte, war politisch wichtig[PARAGRAPH:1]"Du wirst heute Nacht im Palast bleiben. Morgen wirst du als neuer Mann erwachen, dein altes Leben hinter dir lassen, und hier ein neues beginnen. Dein Name wird Goodreau sein. Am Morgen wirst du in die Stadt gehen, einen Beruf finden, und dir deinen Platz im meinem Volk verdienen. Aber heute Nacht bist du immer noch Tamur der Händler. Mein Weibel wird dir dein Gemach zeigen, und dir zu essen und zu trinken geben. Iss und schlafe gut."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mein Vater dankte ihm, und folgte dem Weibel aus dem Thronsaal. Ich ging ihm nach, und saß in dem kleinen Schlafzimmer, das sie ihm gaben. Die Reise hatte ihn angestrengt, und er aß hastig und schlief dann ein. Ich saß in der Ecke des Zimmers, so wie ich in meinem Schlafzimmer gesessen hatte, als er nach meinem Tod geweint hatte.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Elisabeth?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Mein Vater war wach geworden, er war wach, und starrte mich an.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ja, Papa." [PARAGRAPH:1]Er sprang aus dem Bett, voll Furcht, aber nur voll Furcht, dass er sich das nur irgendwie vorstellte, und dass ich verschwinden würde, bevor er mich ergreifen könnte. Aber seine Arme gingen durch mich hindurch, und er fiel schluchzend zu Boden. Ich kniete mich an seiner Seite nieder, und er sah mich an, und versuchte, sich jede Kleinigkeit in meinem Gesicht einzuprägen.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh Kleine, es tut mir so leid...bitte...so leid...so leid"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Papa, es geht mir gut."[PARAGRAPH:1]Wir redeten, und ich erzählte ihm über die falschen Himmel und mein Leben im Palast. Wie es mir, obwohl es drei Jahre waren, nur wie ein paar Tage vorkam. Dass ich mich kaum ans Sterben erinnern konnte, aber sehr gut daran, mit ihm Spiele zu spielen, und an die Spaziergänge, die wir unternommen hatten. Ich log, und behauptete, dass ich nicht wusste, wer mich getötet hatte, ich wollte nicht, dass er zurückging. [PARAGRAPH:1] Wir sprachen bis zur Morgendämmerung. Als ich begann, aus seiner Sicht zu entschwinden, flehte er mich an, zu bleiben, und fragte, was er tun könnte, um bei mir zu bleiben. Ich wiederholte Cassiels Wörter.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Eines Tages werden sich die Tore öffnen, und wir werden wieder vereint sein. Bis dorthin werden wir warten, und versuchen, das zu verbessern, das uns gegeben wurde."[PARAGRAPH:1]Er sagte, dass er mich liebte, und dass er mich wieder sehen würde, und als ich ganz aus seiner Sicht verschwunden war, verließ der den Palast, und begann sein neues Leben unter den Grigori.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il mio nome è Elizabeth, e sono stata uccisa nel primo giorno d'inverno. Mio padre era al mercato. Nell'istante in cui sono morta stava comprando dei nastri per i miei capelli. In seguito li avrebbe messi sul mio cadavere.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mio padre conosceva l'uomo che mi ha ucciso, un vicino di casa che parlava con lui di commercio e di religione. In quanto seguace dell'Ordine mio padre lo promuoveva veementemente a chiunque lo ascolatava. Il vicinio mi guardava nello stesso modo in cui alcuni uomini guardavano le giovani ragazze, ma non mi aveva mai parlato sino a quel giorno.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ciao Elizabeth."[PARAGRAPH:1]Rimasi sorpresa del fatto che sapesse il mio nome. Stavo togliendo le ultime verdure dal nostro piccolo giardino, prima che il freddo della notte le uccidesse. Mi alzai e incosciamente aggiustai l'abito logoro che stavo indossando. Non gli risposi.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sai qualcosa sui gatti?" lui disse.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Avevo una gatta, ma è sparita qualche settimana fa."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Era bianca?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Si, l'hai vista?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Ero solo una bambina, mia madre era morta dandomi alla luce e la mia gatta Abagail era la custode dei miei segreti e compagna di giochi sin da quando avevo memoria. L'avevo cercata e stavo quasi per perdere la speranza.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Si, è entrata nella mia cantina. Si è presa un angolo per lei e i suoi gattini."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Gattini?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Lui ricambiò il mio sorriso. Teneva la mano sul suo coltello, la maggior parte degli uomini in città ne portava, ma poi si rilassò e la spostò.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Li vuoi vedere? Magari mi aiuti a spostarli a casa tua. Voglio assicurarmi che stiano in un posto caldo prima che arrivi la notte."[PARAGRAPH:1]Lo seguii alla sua casa; camminammo attraverso il mio cortile e un piccolo campo che separava le nostre case. In quel momento ero troppo eccitata per domandarmi perche non avessimo usato la strada. Il campo portava al retro della sua casa, in cui c'era l'entrata alla cantina. Lui l'aprì per me. Quella fu la prima volta che ebbi il sospetto che qualcosa non andava. Se fossi stata da sola non ci sarei mai scesa, ma gli avevo detto che l'avrei fatto e non volevo sembrare una bambina impaurita e cosi scesi le scale di legno. Lui mi seguì e chiuse le porte dietro di lui.[PARAGRAPH:1]La cantina era un santuario di Agares, decorato col sangue e armi dentellate. Mi attaccò appena io lo vidi. In seguito mi avrebbe sacrificato sull'altare marrone, ma prima mi furono fatte cose ben peggiori.[PARAGRAPH:1]Girovagai nel grigio. Vidi mio padre che mi cercava, il mio cadavere fu scoperto nella foresta fuori dal villaggio qualche giorno dopo, ricoperto di tagli rituali. Il mio assassino andò a casa mia e offrì le sue condoglianze insieme al resto del vicinato, fingendo di essere scioccato e irato. Osservai mio padre andare e venire, piangere e poi fingere di stare bene quando i vicini gli facevano visita. Distrutto dal pensiero che lui non era presente quando sua figlia aveva avuto veramente bisogno di lui.[PARAGRAPH:1]Col tempo mi accorsi di qualcosa'altro. Abagail arrivò trotterellando attraverso il muro, miagolando nel modo che usava quando mi dimenticavo di dargli da mangiare. Corsi da lei e la presi in braccio e la abbraciai mentre lei poggiava la testa sul mio collo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quando la misi a terra riniziò a camminare, per poi guardare se la stessi seguendo, cosa che stavo facendo. Uscimmo dalla città, camminammo attraverso foreste, campi e montagne. Non mi sentii mai stanca o affamata ed ebbi solo una visone offuscata del mondo, come se lo stessi osservando attraverso una foschia. Evitammo alcuni posti oscuri e potei sentire occasionalmente delle voci provenire da quei luoghi, di solito arrabbiate o tristi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Camminammo sino a quando entrammo in una città molto più grande della mia. La attraversammo tutta sino a un grande palazzo posto al centro di essa, decorato con del bronzo e di color nero. Camminammo sino alla sala del trono in cui la foschia non era presente al centro della stanza. Un'uomo con la pelle d'avorio sedeva sul trono, stava ascoltando la discussione tra due mercanti. L'uomo era stanco e sapevo in qualche modo che lui era un tempo il più grande degli angeli, ma che ora sopportava il peso della mortalità e del tempo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Avevo sentito di un'angelo che era diventato umano, l'arcangelo Cassiel, che si era ribellato agli dei, che affermava che la religione era una schiavitù e che non li avrebbe seguiti. Ma dopo tutto ciò che avevo visto, provato e subito... Io non potevo accettarlo. Vi era un nemico, una religione che doveva essere combattuta. Mi avvicinai al suo trono, sapendo che lui mi avrebbe visto anche se nessun'altro poteva.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Cassiel, il Velo mi ha ucciso. Tu puoi fare qualcosa al riguardo, l'Ordine sta cercando di combatterlo. Potresti dargli una mano."[PARAGRAPH:1]Lui mi guardò e io vidi in lui una grande tristezza. La stessa che aveva mio padre quando si sedeva in camera mia e piangeva. I mercanti che discutevano fecero silenzio, avendo compreso che l'attenzione di Cassiel era da un'altra parte.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Apri gli occhi."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mi disse, me lo stava chiedendo e ordinando allo stesso tempo. Provai a farlo e ogni cosa eccetto Cassiel sembrò distante. Potevo vedere Abagail ai miei piedi, ma il resto erano come nuvole grigie che finivano l'una nell'altra. Guardai queste nuvole, vi erano delle sagome in esse, persone, facce. Iniziai a vederci altri spiriti in esse. Uomini e donne, orchi ed elfi, bambini e adulti, tutti all'interno del loro grigio mondo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Parlai con lo spirito di un'uomo che era stato ucciso da un Confessore dell'Ordine per aver mentito, con quello di un ragazzo che era morto di fame perche la sua famiglia non si poteva permettere il cibo e gli insegnamenti di Kilmorph non promuovono la carità, con quello di un'elfo che aveva usato del legno di un'albero sacro per ricostruire la sua casa ed era stato ucciso dalla Confraternita per ciò. E con migliaia che erano morti in guerre in cui loro non credevano per degli dei di cui non si fidavano e che non li accettavano.[PARAGRAPH:1]Più tardi tornai da Cassiel, stava seduto da solo sul tetto del suo palazzo.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Siamo condannati a stare in questo limbo per sempre? Ora capisco che gli dei sono imperfetti, ma se loro detengono l'unica via per il paradiso, cos'altro possiamo fare se non seguirli?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel mi sorrise. "I piani che loro hanno creato non sono il paradiso, il vero paradiso è irraggiungibile per tutti, compresi loro. Un giorno vi si potrà rientrare e ci riuniremo. Nel frattempo aspettiamo e cerchiamo di migliorare ciò che ci è stato dato."[PARAGRAPH:1]Dopo quel giorno passai il tempo seduta ai piedi del suo trono, giocando con Abagail e prestando sempre meno attenzione agli avvenimenti del mondo. Sino a quando non sentii una voce familiare nella sala del trono, quella di mio padre.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Lord Cassiel, io provengo dall'impero Bannor e ho voltato le spalle al mio popolo e al mio dio. La religione che un tempo mi era cosi cara, alla quale ho dedicato la mia vita, non mi ha offerto conforto quando ne avevo bisogno. Solo parole vuote riguardo alla fede e alle mie debolezze. Ora io vengo da voi. Tre anni fa mia figlia fu uccisa, era solo una bambina ed è stata sacrificata in qualche rituale sacrilego. Per via del modo in cui è morta i sacerdoti disserò che non potevano seppellirla nel cimitero, ma bruciarono il suo piccolo corpo cosi da evitare che uno spirito malvagio se ne impossessasse."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mio padre si sforzò di mantenere il suo contegno. Fece un respiro profondo prima di continuare.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ora io vengo da voi." Ripeté. "Offrendo il mio aiuto, sono solo un semplice mercante ma se me lo permettete vorrei unirmi ai Grigori."[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel lo osservò, richeste simili non erano insolite. Di solito non giungevano direttamente a Cassiel a meno che la persona non fosse politicamente importante.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Rimarrai in questo palazzo stanotte. Domani ti sveglierai come un'uomo nuovo, lascierai dietro di te la tua vecchia vita e ne inizierai una nuova qui. Il tuo nome sarà Goodreau. Di mattina andrai in città, troverai un lavoro e ti guadagnerai un posto tra la mia gente. Ma per stanotte rimarrai Tamur il Mercante. Il sergente ti mostrerà la tua stanza e ti fornira da magiare e da bere. Mangia e dormi serenamente."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mio padre lo ringraziò e seguì il sergente fuori dalla sala del trono. Io li sguii e mi sedetti nella piccola stanza che gli assegnarono. Il viaggio era stato arduo per lui e mangio voracemente per poi addormentarsi rapidamente. Io ero seduta in un'angolo, nello stesso modo di quando lui piangeva nella mia camera dopo la mia morte.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Elizabeth?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Mio padre era sveglio, e mi stava fissando.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Si, papà."[PARAGRAPH:1]Saltò giu dal letto, terrorizzato, ma solo perche temeva di starmi soltanto immaginando e che io sarei sparita prima che potesse afferrarmi. Ma le sue braccia mi passarono attraverso e lui cadde sul pavimento singhiozzando. Io mi inginocchiai al suo fianco, lui mi guardò, cercando di memorizzare ogni dettaglio del mio volto.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh piccola, mi dispiace... per favore... mi dispiace... mi dispiace"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Papà, sto bene."[PARAGRAPH:1]Parlammo e gli raccontai dei falsi paradisi e della mia vita nel palazzo. Di come, se erano passati tre anni, a me sembravano solo qualche giorno. Che io non ricordavo la mia morte molto bene, ma che ricordavo di quando giocavo con lui e delle camminate che eravamo soliti fare. Mentii e gli dissi che non conoscevo chi mi aveva ucciso, non volevo tornasse indietro.[PARAGRAPH:1]Parlammo sino all'alba. Quando io iniziai a svanire dalla sua vista lui mi pregò di rimanere e chiese che cosa poteva fare per stare con me. Io ripetei le parole di Cassiel.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Un giorno le porte saranno aperte e ci riuniremo. Nel frattempo aspettiamo e cerchiamo di migliorare ciò che ci è stato dato."[PARAGRAPH:1]Disse che mi amava e che mi avrebbe rivista, e quando fui completamente svanita dalla sua vista lui lasciò il palazzo e iniziò la sua nuova vita tra i Grigori.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]My name is Elizabeth, and I was murdered on the first day of winter. My father was at the market. In the instant I died, he was buying ribbons for my hair. Later, he would put them on my corpse.[PARAGRAPH:1]My father knew the man who killed me, a neighbor that talked to him about trade and argued about religion. As a follower of the Order, my father was quick to advocate it to anyone who would listen. The neighbor looked at me the way some men look at teenage girls, but he had never spoken to me until that day.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Hello Elizabeth."[PARAGRAPH:1]I was surprised he knew my name. I was removing the last of the vegetables from our small garden before the night's frost killed them. I stood and subconsciously straightened the worn dress I was wearing. I didn't answer him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do you know anything about cats?" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I had a cat, she disappeared a few weeks ago."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Was she white?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, did you find her?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I was an only child, my mother died when I was born and my cat Abagail was the keeper of my secrets and playmate for as long as I could remember. I searched for her and had almost given up hope.[PARAGRAPH:1]"More like she found me, she's moved into my cellar. She's taken over a corner for herself and her kittens."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Kittens?"[PARAGRAPH:1]He returned my smile. His hand had been resting on his knife-most men in the city carried them-but now he relaxed and took his hand off of it.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Would you like to see them? Maybe help me move them to your house. I want to make sure they get somewhere warm before tonight."[PARAGRAPH:1]I followed him to his house; we walked across my yard and through a small field that separated our homes. At the time I was too excited to wonder why we didn't walk on the road. The field opened to the back of his house, which is where the cellar entrance was. He unlocked the cellar and opened it for me. This was the first time I had a suspicion that something was wrong. If I was by myself I wouldn't have gone down there, but I had told him I would and I didn't want to seem like a scared girl so I went down the wooden stairs. He followed and closed the doors behind him.[PARAGRAPH:1]The cellar was a shrine to Agares, decorated in blood and jagged weapons. He attacked me as soon as I saw it. In time he would sacrifice me on the cellar's brown altar, but even worse was done to me before.[PARAGRAPH:1]I wandered in the grey. I saw my father search for me, my body was found in the woods outside the village a few days later, covered with cuts and ritual marks. My killer came to my house and offered his condolences with the rest of the neighborhood, pretended to be shocked and upset. I watched my father come and go, cry and then pretend to be okay when neighbors came over. Crushed by the thought that when his daughter really needed him, he wasn't there.[PARAGRAPH:1]In time I became aware of something else. Abagail came trotting through a wall, meowing in that way she reserved for when I forgot to feed her. I rushed to her, picked her up and squeezed her as she nuzzled my neck with her head.[PARAGRAPH:1]When I set her down she started walking, then looked back to see if I was following, which I did. We left the city, walked through forests, fields, mountains. I was never tired or hungry and only had a dim view of the world, as if I was viewing it through a haze. Some dark places we avoided and I could occasionally hear voices, usually angry or sad from those places.[PARAGRAPH:1]We walked until we entered a city much larger than mine. We went through it to a grand palace at its center, decorated in bronze and black. We walked through to the throne room and the haze was gone from the center of this room. A man with ivory skin sat on a throne, listening to an argument between two merchants. The man was tired and I somehow knew that he was once one of the greatest of angels, now bearing the burden of mortality and time.[PARAGRAPH:1]I had heard of an angel that had become human, the archangel Cassiel who had turned against the gods, who claimed that religion was servitude and wouldn't follow them. But after what I saw, felt, experienced... I couldn't accept that. There was an enemy, a religion that should be battled. I approached his throne, knowing he would see me even if no one else did.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Cassiel, the Veil killed me. You can do something about that, the Order is trying to fight them. You could help."[PARAGRAPH:1]He looked at me, I saw a great sadness in him. The same as in my father when he sat in my bedroom and cried. The arguing merchants quieted, realizing Cassiel's attention was somewhere else.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Open your eyes."[PARAGRAPH:1]He said it to me, he was pleading with me and commanding me at the same time. I tried to follow it, everything except Cassiel seemed distant. I could see Abagail at my feet, the rest was clouds of grey flowing into each other. I looked at these clouds, there were shapes in them, figures, faces. And I began to see other spirits in them. Men and women, orcs and elves, children and adults, all caught in their own grey worlds.[PARAGRAPH:1]I talked to the spirit of a man who had been killed by an order Confessor for lying, a boy who had starved because his family couldn't afford food and the teachings of Kilmorph don't emphasize charity, an elf who had used wood from a sacred tree to rebuild his home and had been killed by the Fellowship for it. And thousands who had died in wars they didn't believe in for gods they didn't trust and who didn't accept them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Later I went back to Cassiel, he was sitting alone on the roof of his palace.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are we forever doomed to this in-between place? I understand now that the gods are flawed, but if they hold the only way into heaven, what else can we do but follow them?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel smiled at me. "The places they have made are not heaven, the true heaven is closed to everyone, even them. One day the doors will open and we will be rejoined. Until then we wait and we try to improve what we have been given."[PARAGRAPH:1]After that I sat at the feet of his throne, played with Abagail and paid less and less attention to the occurrences of the mortal world. Until I heard a familiar voice in the throne room, that of my father.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Lord Cassiel, I have come from the Bannor empire, I have turned my back on my people and my god. The religion that once seemed so important to me, that I dedicated my life to, offered no comfort to me when I needed it. Only hollow words about faith and my own weakness. Now I come to you. Three years ago my daughter was killed, she was only a child and she was sacrificed in some unholy ceremony. Because of the manner of her death the priests say they cannot bury her in the cemetery, they burned her so that an evil spirit wouldn't inhabit her tiny corpse."[PARAGRAPH:1]My father fought to keep his composure. He took a deep breath before continuing.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Now I come to you." He repeated. "To offer my help, I'm only a simple merchant but if you would have me I wish to join the Grigori."[PARAGRAPH:1]Cassiel looked at him, requests like this weren't uncommon. They usually wouldn't even get to Cassiel himself unless the person was someone politically important.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You will stay in the palace tonight. Tomorrow you will awake a new man, put your old life behind you and start a new one here. Your name will be Goodreau. In the morning you will go into the city, find a job and earn your place among my people. But for tonight you are still Tamur the Merchant. My sergeant will show you a room and provide you with food and drink. Eat and sleep well."[PARAGRAPH:1]My father thanked him and followed the sergeant out of the throne room. I followed them and sat in the small bedroom they gave him. Traveling had been hard on him and he ate ravenously and fell asleep. I sat in the corner of the room just as I had in my bedroom when he cried after my death.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Elizabeth?"[PARAGRAPH:1]My father was awake, awake and staring at me.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, daddy."[PARAGRAPH:1]He jumped out of the bed, terrified, but only terrified that he was somehow imaging this and I would disappear before he could grab me. But his arms passed right through me and he fell on the floor sobbing. I knelt down beside him, he stared at me, trying to memorize every detail of my face.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Oh sweetie, I'm so sorry... please... I'm sorry... I'm sorry"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Daddy, I'm okay."[PARAGRAPH:1]We talked and I told him about the fake heavens and my life at the palace. How, if it had been three years, it seemed like only a few days to me. That I really didn't remember dying that well, but I remembered playing games with him and the walks we used to take. I lied and told him I didn't know who killed me, I didn't want him going back.[PARAGRAPH:1]We talked until dawn. As I began to fade from his sight he pleaded with me to stay, asked what he could do to stay with me. I repeated Cassiel's words.[PARAGRAPH:1]"One day the doors will open and we will be rejoined. Until then we wait and we try to improve what we have been given."[PARAGRAPH:1]He said he loved me, that he would see me again and when I was completely gone from his view he left the palace and started his new life among the Grigori.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ESIRCE</Tag>
		<English>Prime Minister Esirce</English>
		<French>Prime Minister Esirce</French>
		<German>Premierminister Esirce</German>
		<Italian>Primo Ministro Esirce</Italian>
		<Spanish>Prime Minister Esirce</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ESIRCE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]When I came into the chamber, Prime Minister Esirce was sitting at the head of the table, surrounded by his various sycophants and false friends. "Let me guess," he said when he saw me. "The Calabim again?" I nodded. He said, "they are a necessary evil. Tell me what they did this time." "Well, some of them are beginning to demand a return to the Old Ways..." "yes, yes, yes, fine, whatever. Does that mean following their religion?" It didn't, of course. The only time Lord Esirce could be expected to grow a spine was if religion was involved. "No," I said, "just their... hunting celebration." "We need the Calabim," Esirce said, putting on his Brilliant Overlord tone.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, of course we do," Minister Alyeris said, smiling her false smile. Anybody with an ounce of sense knew that woman was loyal to either Faeryl Viconia or none but herself. It didn't matter, her effect on the empire was the same. She was presently bedding someone in the Calabim empire, I reckoned. Esirce was the only person on Erebus unaware of Alyeris' many, many questionable lovers. The debacle with the centaur was, of course, merely the most often joked about and satirized, but the list of confirmed partners ran on impressively, and was likely a fraction of the total. "You see," Alyeris continued, "the Calabim have many... unique skills that could serve our needs... wonderfully. As a matter of fact, I was speaking with Lady Tepes..." I grinned at my fellow clerk, Anna. "See," I said to her, "I told you, she likes women to." She silently handed over the coins we'd wagered as Alyeris continued gushing over the wonderful things the Calabim, especially the beautiful Lady Tepes, had to offer. Several other ministers went red, snickered, or showed sudden interest as they figured out the subtext. Esirce was completely blind to it all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ragas the Lone interrupted Alyeris' ramblings, to the relief of some and annoyance of others. Doviello were assumed to be big, brutish, and stupid. Ragas was definitely big, but while his methods were brutal, they were also surprisingly creative, and Ragas was far from stupid. He had an incredible animal cunning, and adapted just enough to Grigori culture to be tolerated, while still being seen as a fool. "My pack is interested in these gifts," he said. "Will the People of the Bat offer it to us, if we will provide them with much Prey?" Alyreis considered, but before she could respond, Ragas continued. "To speak of Prey, my assistant read me Words from Front." Another farce; Ragas' broken Grigori and illiteracy were both lies. He'd made mistakes that had revealed both; pass him a document, and he'd sometimes read it over before remembering to ask someone to do it for him, and he sometimes soliloquized in flawless Grigori when discussing his latest schemes with his allies. "People of the Dog," that was the Bannor, "will not kneel. I demand money given that I may make them heel." Esirce nodded. "You! Boy!" That meant me. "My name is Remus," I reminded him quietly. "Yes, yes," he said with a dismissive wave. "Make sure Minister Ragas gets the money he needs." His allies would be drinking well tonight. So be it. I made a note to do it later, and he quickly forgot me.[PARAGRAPH:1]Esirce then spoke to his fellow ministers. "Now, what shall we do about the economic crisis? My trusted assistant, Lord Wordsworth, has told me he has a solution to our problems. Care to tell the council?" Wordsworth grinned. "I have a proposal that would significantly increase our wealth through wise investing..." Anna was a merchant baron's daughter and heir apparent, and as Wordsworth explained in his double-talk, she translated. "He's proposing they invest in a bank owned by a man who, he failed to mention, is his brother-in-law. The interest rate is..." she quickly calculated, "less than half that offered by the Khazad banking establishments. He'll accuse the dwarves of being gold-hungry subhumans in... five, four, three, two... yep, there he goes. More racist ranting. If you start believing any of this nonsense, please tell me so I can hit you in the... ah, he's done. Now we get all sorts of words that don't have any meaning but sound really good, more, blah blah, yak yak, oh, looks like his bank is invested in only a few industries, none of them especially stable and... yeah, that's a pyramid scheme right there, with him and his political allies on top. And people ask me why I invest so heavily in foreign companies..."[PARAGRAPH:1]The meeting finally ended. The ministers all shuffled out, while Esirce stayed behind. He beckoned for me and Anna to come. "Ah, Romulus! And your girlfriend!" I didn't even bother correcting him on either. "See, what you saw there was politics at its finest! Did you not see how I played each and every one of my ministers for their strengths, while minimizing their weaknesses! How I kept their various little schemes and ambitions in my pocket, and force them to use their skills for the good of the Grigori empire! Watch me, and you may learn something!" He sounded so certain I almost believed him. Until he added, "I do wish Alyeris would find a husband, though. Why a woman of her beauty remains single is beyond me, especially considering how many excellent bachelors she knows."</English>
		<French>[TAB]When I came into the chamber, Prime Minister Esirce was sitting at the head of the table, surrounded by his various sycophants and false friends. "Let me guess," he said when he saw me. "The Calabim again?" I nodded. He said, "they are a necessary evil. Tell me what they did this time." "Well, some of them are beginning to demand a return to the Old Ways..." "yes, yes, yes, fine, whatever. Does that mean following their religion?" It didn't, of course. The only time Lord Esirce could be expected to grow a spine was if religion was involved. "No," I said, "just their... hunting celebration." "We need the Calabim," Esirce said, putting on his Brilliant Overlord tone.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, of course we do," Minister Alyeris said, smiling her false smile. Anybody with an ounce of sense knew that woman was loyal to either Faeryl Viconia or none but herself. It didn't matter, her effect on the empire was the same. She was presently bedding someone in the Calabim empire, I reckoned. Esirce was the only person on Erebus unaware of Alyeris' many, many questionable lovers. The debacle with the centaur was, of course, merely the most often joked about and satirized, but the list of confirmed partners ran on impressively, and was likely a fraction of the total. "You see," Alyeris continued, "the Calabim have many... unique skills that could serve our needs... wonderfully. As a matter of fact, I was speaking with Lady Tepes..." I grinned at my fellow clerk, Anna. "See," I said to her, "I told you, she likes women to." She silently handed over the coins we'd wagered as Alyeris continued gushing over the wonderful things the Calabim, especially the beautiful Lady Tepes, had to offer. Several other ministers went red, snickered, or showed sudden interest as they figured out the subtext. Esirce was completely blind to it all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ragas the Lone interrupted Alyeris' ramblings, to the relief of some and annoyance of others. Doviello were assumed to be big, brutish, and stupid. Ragas was definitely big, but while his methods were brutal, they were also surprisingly creative, and Ragas was far from stupid. He had an incredible animal cunning, and adapted just enough to Grigori culture to be tolerated, while still being seen as a fool. "My pack is interested in these gifts," he said. "Will the People of the Bat offer it to us, if we will provide them with much Prey?" Alyreis considered, but before she could respond, Ragas continued. "To speak of Prey, my assistant read me Words from Front." Another farce; Ragas' broken Grigori and illiteracy were both lies. He'd made mistakes that had revealed both; pass him a document, and he'd sometimes read it over before remembering to ask someone to do it for him, and he sometimes soliloquized in flawless Grigori when discussing his latest schemes with his allies. "People of the Dog," that was the Bannor, "will not kneel. I demand money given that I may make them heel." Esirce nodded. "You! Boy!" That meant me. "My name is Remus," I reminded him quietly. "Yes, yes," he said with a dismissive wave. "Make sure Minister Ragas gets the money he needs." His allies would be drinking well tonight. So be it. I made a note to do it later, and he quickly forgot me.[PARAGRAPH:1]Esirce then spoke to his fellow ministers. "Now, what shall we do about the economic crisis? My trusted assistant, Lord Wordsworth, has told me he has a solution to our problems. Care to tell the council?" Wordsworth grinned. "I have a proposal that would significantly increase our wealth through wise investing..." Anna was a merchant baron's daughter and heir apparent, and as Wordsworth explained in his double-talk, she translated. "He's proposing they invest in a bank owned by a man who, he failed to mention, is his brother-in-law. The interest rate is..." she quickly calculated, "less than half that offered by the Khazad banking establishments. He'll accuse the dwarves of being gold-hungry subhumans in... five, four, three, two... yep, there he goes. More racist ranting. If you start believing any of this nonsense, please tell me so I can hit you in the... ah, he's done. Now we get all sorts of words that don't have any meaning but sound really good, more, blah blah, yak yak, oh, looks like his bank is invested in only a few industries, none of them especially stable and... yeah, that's a pyramid scheme right there, with him and his political allies on top. And people ask me why I invest so heavily in foreign companies..."[PARAGRAPH:1]The meeting finally ended. The ministers all shuffled out, while Esirce stayed behind. He beckoned for me and Anna to come. "Ah, Romulus! And your girlfriend!" I didn't even bother correcting him on either. "See, what you saw there was politics at its finest! Did you not see how I played each and every one of my ministers for their strengths, while minimizing their weaknesses! How I kept their various little schemes and ambitions in my pocket, and force them to use their skills for the good of the Grigori empire! Watch me, and you may learn something!" He sounded so certain I almost believed him. Until he added, "I do wish Alyeris would find a husband, though. Why a woman of her beauty remains single is beyond me, especially considering how many excellent bachelors she knows."</French>
		<German>[TAB]When I came into the chamber, Prime Minister Esirce was sitting at the head of the table, surrounded by his various sycophants and false friends. "Let me guess," he said when he saw me. "The Calabim again?" I nodded. He said, "they are a necessary evil. Tell me what they did this time." "Well, some of them are beginning to demand a return to the Old Ways..." "yes, yes, yes, fine, whatever. Does that mean following their religion?" It didn't, of course. The only time Lord Esirce could be expected to grow a spine was if religion was involved. "No," I said, "just their... hunting celebration." "We need the Calabim," Esirce said, putting on his Brilliant Overlord tone.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, of course we do," Minister Alyeris said, smiling her false smile. Anybody with an ounce of sense knew that woman was loyal to either Faeryl Viconia or none but herself. It didn't matter, her effect on the empire was the same. She was presently bedding someone in the Calabim empire, I reckoned. Esirce was the only person on Erebus unaware of Alyeris' many, many questionable lovers. The debacle with the centaur was, of course, merely the most often joked about and satirized, but the list of confirmed partners ran on impressively, and was likely a fraction of the total. "You see," Alyeris continued, "the Calabim have many... unique skills that could serve our needs... wonderfully. As a matter of fact, I was speaking with Lady Tepes..." I grinned at my fellow clerk, Anna. "See," I said to her, "I told you, she likes women to." She silently handed over the coins we'd wagered as Alyeris continued gushing over the wonderful things the Calabim, especially the beautiful Lady Tepes, had to offer. Several other ministers went red, snickered, or showed sudden interest as they figured out the subtext. Esirce was completely blind to it all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ragas the Lone interrupted Alyeris' ramblings, to the relief of some and annoyance of others. Doviello were assumed to be big, brutish, and stupid. Ragas was definitely big, but while his methods were brutal, they were also surprisingly creative, and Ragas was far from stupid. He had an incredible animal cunning, and adapted just enough to Grigori culture to be tolerated, while still being seen as a fool. "My pack is interested in these gifts," he said. "Will the People of the Bat offer it to us, if we will provide them with much Prey?" Alyreis considered, but before she could respond, Ragas continued. "To speak of Prey, my assistant read me Words from Front." Another farce; Ragas' broken Grigori and illiteracy were both lies. He'd made mistakes that had revealed both; pass him a document, and he'd sometimes read it over before remembering to ask someone to do it for him, and he sometimes soliloquized in flawless Grigori when discussing his latest schemes with his allies. "People of the Dog," that was the Bannor, "will not kneel. I demand money given that I may make them heel." Esirce nodded. "You! Boy!" That meant me. "My name is Remus," I reminded him quietly. "Yes, yes," he said with a dismissive wave. "Make sure Minister Ragas gets the money he needs." His allies would be drinking well tonight. So be it. I made a note to do it later, and he quickly forgot me.[PARAGRAPH:1]Esirce then spoke to his fellow ministers. "Now, what shall we do about the economic crisis? My trusted assistant, Lord Wordsworth, has told me he has a solution to our problems. Care to tell the council?" Wordsworth grinned. "I have a proposal that would significantly increase our wealth through wise investing..." Anna was a merchant baron's daughter and heir apparent, and as Wordsworth explained in his double-talk, she translated. "He's proposing they invest in a bank owned by a man who, he failed to mention, is his brother-in-law. The interest rate is..." she quickly calculated, "less than half that offered by the Khazad banking establishments. He'll accuse the dwarves of being gold-hungry subhumans in... five, four, three, two... yep, there he goes. More racist ranting. If you start believing any of this nonsense, please tell me so I can hit you in the... ah, he's done. Now we get all sorts of words that don't have any meaning but sound really good, more, blah blah, yak yak, oh, looks like his bank is invested in only a few industries, none of them especially stable and... yeah, that's a pyramid scheme right there, with him and his political allies on top. And people ask me why I invest so heavily in foreign companies..."[PARAGRAPH:1]The meeting finally ended. The ministers all shuffled out, while Esirce stayed behind. He beckoned for me and Anna to come. "Ah, Romulus! And your girlfriend!" I didn't even bother correcting him on either. "See, what you saw there was politics at its finest! Did you not see how I played each and every one of my ministers for their strengths, while minimizing their weaknesses! How I kept their various little schemes and ambitions in my pocket, and force them to use their skills for the good of the Grigori empire! Watch me, and you may learn something!" He sounded so certain I almost believed him. Until he added, "I do wish Alyeris would find a husband, though. Why a woman of her beauty remains single is beyond me, especially considering how many excellent bachelors she knows."</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Quando entrai nell'aula il Primo Ministro Esirce era seduto a capotavola, circondato dai suoi vari amici leccapiedi e falsi. "Lasciami indovinare," disse quando mi vide. "I Calabim di nuovo?" Io annuii. Disse, "loro sono un male necessario. Dimmi cosa hanno fatto questa volta." "Beh, alcuni di loro stanno cominciando a chiedere di tornare alle vecchie usanze..." "si, si, si, va bene, comunque. Ciò comporta seguire la loro religione?" No, ovviamente. Le uniche volte in cui ci si poteva aspettare un pò di spina dorsale dal Primo Ministro Esirce era quando la religione era coinvolta. "No," dissi, "solo le loro... celebrazioni della caccia." "Abbiamo bisogno dei Calabim," disse Esirce, usando il suo tono brillante da governatore.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Si, ovviamente è cosi," disse il Ministro Alyeris, facendo il suo falso sorriso. Chiunque con un briciolo di buon senso sapeva che quella donna era fedele solo a Faeryl Viconia o se stessa. Non aveva importanza, il suo effetto sull'impero era lo stesso. Attualmente stava andando a letto con qualcuno dell'impero Calabim, pensai. Esirce era l'unica persona su Erebus ignara dei molteplici amanti discutibili di Alyeris. La tresca con il centauro era, ovviamente, quella più satirizzata, ma la lista di partner confermati era impressionante, e probabilmente solo una frazione di quelli totali. "Vedi," Alyeris continò, "i Calabim hanno molte... abilità uniche che potrebbero servire i nostri scopi... magnificamente. Infatti stavo parlando con Lady Tepes..." Io sorrisi alla mia collega impiegata Anna. "Vedi," gli dissi, "te l'avevo detto, a lei piacciono pure le donne." Lei mi diede silenziosamente le monete che avevamo scommesso mentre Alyeris continuava ad esporre le cose meravigliose che i Calabim, in paricolar modo la bellissima Lady Tepes, avevano da offrire. Diversi altri ministri divennerò rossi, ridacchiarono o mostrarono un'improvviso interesse dopo aver letto tra le righe. Esirce era completamente ignaro di tutto questo.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ragas il Solitario interruppé gli sproloqui di Alyeris, per il sollievo di alcuni e il fastidio di altri. Ci si aspettava che i Doviello fossero grandi, brutali e stupidi. Ragas era decisamente grande, ma sebbene i suoi metodi fossero brutali, erano anche sorprendentemente creativi, e Ragas era tutt'altro che stupido. Aveva un'incredibile astuzia animale, e si era adattato quel tanto che bastava alla cultura Grigori per essere tollerato, pur rimanendo visto come uno stupido. "Il mio branco è interessato in questi doni," disse. "Il Popolo del Pipistrello ce li offrirà se gli forniamo molte preda?" Alyreis rifletté, ma prima che potesse rispondere Ragas continuò. "Parlando di preda, il mio assistente mi ha letto parole dal fronte." Un'altra farsa; sia il Grigori sgangherato di Ragas che il suo analfabetismo erano menzogne. Aveva commesso errori che avevano rivelato entrambe; quando gli si passa un documento a volte lo legge prima di ricordarsi di chiedere a qualcun'altro di leggerglielo, e qualche volta fa monologhi in un Grigori impeccabile quando discute i suoi ultimi piani con i suoi alleati. "Popolo del Cane," che era quello Bannor, "non si inginocchierà. Io richiedo soldi cosi io posso calmarli." Esirce annuì. "Tu! Ragazzo!" Riferendosi a me. "Il mio nome è Remus," gli ricordai silenziosamente. "Si, si," disse in modo sprezzante. "Assiccurati che il Ministro Ragas ottenga i soldi di cui ha bisogno." I suoi alleati avrebbero bevuto ampiamente stanotte. Così sia. Lo annotai di farlo più tardi, e lui si dimentico di me rapidamente.[PARAGRAPH:1]Poi Esirce parlo ai suoi colleghi ministri. "Ora, cosa dovremmo fare riguardo alla crisi economica? Il mio fidato assistente, Lord Wordsworth, mi ha detto che ha una soluzione ai nostri problemi. Ti va di esporla al consiglio?" Wordsworth sorrise. "Ho una proposta che aumenterà significativamente la nostra richezza attraverso saggi investimenti..." Anna era la figlia di un barone mercante ed erede diretta, e mentre Wordsworth esponeva in modo ambiguo lei traduceva. "Lui sta proponendo di investire in una banca di proprietà di un'uomo che, aveva dimenticato di dirlo, è suo fratellastro. Il tasso d'interesse è..." lei lo calcolò rapidamente, "meno della metà di quello che offre il sistema bancario Khazad. Lui accuserà i nani di essere dei subumani avidi d'oro in... cinque, quattro, tre, due... infatti, eccolo li. Altri insulti razzisti. Se voi iniziate a credere a queste assurdità, per favore ditemelo cosi che possa colpirvi in... ah, ha finito. Ora avremmo un sacco di parole che non hanno alcun significato ma che suonano molto bene, altre, blah blah, yak yak, oh, sembra che la sua banca investisca in solo alcune industrie, nessuna di esse particolarmente stabile e... già, quello è uno schema a piramide, con lui e i suoi alleati politici in cima. E la gente mi chiede perche investo cosi tanto in compagnie straniere..."[PARAGRAPH:1]L'incontro finì finalmente. I ministri uscirono tutti, mentre Esirce rimase indietro. Fece cennò a me e Anna di andare da lui. "Ah, Romulus! E la tua fidanzata!" Non mi presi il disturbo di correggerlo su nessuna delle due affermazioni. "Vedete, quello che avete visto qui era il meglio della politica! Non avete notato come ho usato ognuno dei miei ministri per i loro punti di forza minimizzando allo stesso tempo le loro debolezze! Di come tengo sotto controllo i loro vari piccoli piani e ambizioni, e li obbligo ad usare le loro abilità per il bene dell'impero Grigori! Osservatemi, e magari potreste imparare qualcosa!" Sembrava cosi sicuro che io quasi gli credetti. Almeno sino a quando non aggiunse, "Anche se vorrei che Alyeris trovasse un marito. Perche una donna della sua bellezza rimanga celibe e fuori dalla mia comprensione, specialmente considerando tutti gli eccellenti scapoli che conosce."</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]When I came into the chamber, Prime Minister Esirce was sitting at the head of the table, surrounded by his various sycophants and false friends. "Let me guess," he said when he saw me. "The Calabim again?" I nodded. He said, "they are a necessary evil. Tell me what they did this time." "Well, some of them are beginning to demand a return to the Old Ways..." "yes, yes, yes, fine, whatever. Does that mean following their religion?" It didn't, of course. The only time Lord Esirce could be expected to grow a spine was if religion was involved. "No," I said, "just their... hunting celebration." "We need the Calabim," Esirce said, putting on his Brilliant Overlord tone.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Yes, of course we do," Minister Alyeris said, smiling her false smile. Anybody with an ounce of sense knew that woman was loyal to either Faeryl Viconia or none but herself. It didn't matter, her effect on the empire was the same. She was presently bedding someone in the Calabim empire, I reckoned. Esirce was the only person on Erebus unaware of Alyeris' many, many questionable lovers. The debacle with the centaur was, of course, merely the most often joked about and satirized, but the list of confirmed partners ran on impressively, and was likely a fraction of the total. "You see," Alyeris continued, "the Calabim have many... unique skills that could serve our needs... wonderfully. As a matter of fact, I was speaking with Lady Tepes..." I grinned at my fellow clerk, Anna. "See," I said to her, "I told you, she likes women to." She silently handed over the coins we'd wagered as Alyeris continued gushing over the wonderful things the Calabim, especially the beautiful Lady Tepes, had to offer. Several other ministers went red, snickered, or showed sudden interest as they figured out the subtext. Esirce was completely blind to it all.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ragas the Lone interrupted Alyeris' ramblings, to the relief of some and annoyance of others. Doviello were assumed to be big, brutish, and stupid. Ragas was definitely big, but while his methods were brutal, they were also surprisingly creative, and Ragas was far from stupid. He had an incredible animal cunning, and adapted just enough to Grigori culture to be tolerated, while still being seen as a fool. "My pack is interested in these gifts," he said. "Will the People of the Bat offer it to us, if we will provide them with much Prey?" Alyreis considered, but before she could respond, Ragas continued. "To speak of Prey, my assistant read me Words from Front." Another farce; Ragas' broken Grigori and illiteracy were both lies. He'd made mistakes that had revealed both; pass him a document, and he'd sometimes read it over before remembering to ask someone to do it for him, and he sometimes soliloquized in flawless Grigori when discussing his latest schemes with his allies. "People of the Dog," that was the Bannor, "will not kneel. I demand money given that I may make them heel." Esirce nodded. "You! Boy!" That meant me. "My name is Remus," I reminded him quietly. "Yes, yes," he said with a dismissive wave. "Make sure Minister Ragas gets the money he needs." His allies would be drinking well tonight. So be it. I made a note to do it later, and he quickly forgot me.[PARAGRAPH:1]Esirce then spoke to his fellow ministers. "Now, what shall we do about the economic crisis? My trusted assistant, Lord Wordsworth, has told me he has a solution to our problems. Care to tell the council?" Wordsworth grinned. "I have a proposal that would significantly increase our wealth through wise investing..." Anna was a merchant baron's daughter and heir apparent, and as Wordsworth explained in his double-talk, she translated. "He's proposing they invest in a bank owned by a man who, he failed to mention, is his brother-in-law. The interest rate is..." she quickly calculated, "less than half that offered by the Khazad banking establishments. He'll accuse the dwarves of being gold-hungry subhumans in... five, four, three, two... yep, there he goes. More racist ranting. If you start believing any of this nonsense, please tell me so I can hit you in the... ah, he's done. Now we get all sorts of words that don't have any meaning but sound really good, more, blah blah, yak yak, oh, looks like his bank is invested in only a few industries, none of them especially stable and... yeah, that's a pyramid scheme right there, with him and his political allies on top. And people ask me why I invest so heavily in foreign companies..."[PARAGRAPH:1]The meeting finally ended. The ministers all shuffled out, while Esirce stayed behind. He beckoned for me and Anna to come. "Ah, Romulus! And your girlfriend!" I didn't even bother correcting him on either. "See, what you saw there was politics at its finest! Did you not see how I played each and every one of my ministers for their strengths, while minimizing their weaknesses! How I kept their various little schemes and ambitions in my pocket, and force them to use their skills for the good of the Grigori empire! Watch me, and you may learn something!" He sounded so certain I almost believed him. Until he added, "I do wish Alyeris would find a husband, though. Why a woman of her beauty remains single is beyond me, especially considering how many excellent bachelors she knows."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_GOODREAU</Tag>
		<English>Goodreau</English>
		<French>Goodreau</French>
		<German>Goodreau</German>
		<Italian>Goodreau</Italian>
		<Spanish>Goodreau</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_GOODREAU_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The ale was bitter.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sighed as he the amber liquid sloshed in his mug, the wagon creaking as it passed through the crossroads. The road was desolate, dreary even as he clenched his teeth, a wind peircing through the thin cloak he wore. Raising the mug to his lips again, his face contorted as the pungent aroma of the booze wafted from the porcelain. Juno wasnt far, and from there it would be a two days ride to Midgar.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was sour.[PARAGRAPH:1]Memories of his past life plauged him as he took up the reins to his wagon, laden with goods as he left the gates of Juno. He remembered what Cassiel had told him in those halls, that day he had renounced his identity as Tamur. He didnt have this mug then.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was spilt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sighed, watching the barmaid wipe up the booze as it soaked into the floorboards. The roadside inn he had stopped at was perpetually caught in this thick haze of smoke, but his own pipe did nothing but add to the smog. Despite this, his thoughts always drifted back to one thing instead of being lost in the smoke of antiquity.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was bittersweet.[PARAGRAPH:1]He saw the grey haze of smoke part slightly, as the barmaid returned with another ale for him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau smiled. He saw Elizabeth in the haze, waiting for him to fufill his dream.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The ale was bitter.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sighed as he the amber liquid sloshed in his mug, the wagon creaking as it passed through the crossroads. The road was desolate, dreary even as he clenched his teeth, a wind peircing through the thin cloak he wore. Raising the mug to his lips again, his face contorted as the pungent aroma of the booze wafted from the porcelain. Juno wasnt far, and from there it would be a two days ride to Midgar.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was sour.[PARAGRAPH:1]Memories of his past life plauged him as he took up the reins to his wagon, laden with goods as he left the gates of Juno. He remembered what Cassiel had told him in those halls, that day he had renounced his identity as Tamur. He didnt have this mug then.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was spilt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sighed, watching the barmaid wipe up the booze as it soaked into the floorboards. The roadside inn he had stopped at was perpetually caught in this thick haze of smoke, but his own pipe did nothing but add to the smog. Despite this, his thoughts always drifted back to one thing instead of being lost in the smoke of antiquity.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was bittersweet.[PARAGRAPH:1]He saw the grey haze of smoke part slightly, as the barmaid returned with another ale for him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau smiled. He saw Elizabeth in the haze, waiting for him to fufill his dream.</French>
		<German>[TAB]The ale was bitter.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sighed as he the amber liquid sloshed in his mug, the wagon creaking as it passed through the crossroads. The road was desolate, dreary even as he clenched his teeth, a wind peircing through the thin cloak he wore. Raising the mug to his lips again, his face contorted as the pungent aroma of the booze wafted from the porcelain. Juno wasnt far, and from there it would be a two days ride to Midgar.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was sour.[PARAGRAPH:1]Memories of his past life plauged him as he took up the reins to his wagon, laden with goods as he left the gates of Juno. He remembered what Cassiel had told him in those halls, that day he had renounced his identity as Tamur. He didnt have this mug then.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was spilt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sighed, watching the barmaid wipe up the booze as it soaked into the floorboards. The roadside inn he had stopped at was perpetually caught in this thick haze of smoke, but his own pipe did nothing but add to the smog. Despite this, his thoughts always drifted back to one thing instead of being lost in the smoke of antiquity.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was bittersweet.[PARAGRAPH:1]He saw the grey haze of smoke part slightly, as the barmaid returned with another ale for him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau smiled. He saw Elizabeth in the haze, waiting for him to fufill his dream.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La birra era amara.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sospirò mentre il liquido color ambra si muoveva nella sua tazza mentre il carro scricchiolava nell'attraversare l'incrocio. La strada era deserta, cupo anche quando serrava i denti, il vento passava attraverso il sottile mantello che indossava. Alzando la tazza sino alle labbra contorse il viso quando l'aroma pungente dell'alcol uscì dalla porcellana. Juno non era distante, e da li sarebbero stati due giorni di cavallo sino a Midgar.[PARAGRAPH:1]La birra era aspra.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ricordi della sua vita passata lo affliggevano quando prendeva le redini del carro, carico di merci quando usciva dalle porte di Juno. Lui si ricordava cosa Cassiel gli aveva detto in quelle sale, quel giorno aveva rinunciato alla sua identità di Tamur. Non aveva questa tazza allora.[PARAGRAPH:1]La birra fu rovesciata.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sospirò mentre guardava la cameriera asciugare mentre l'alcol impregnava le assi del pavimento. La locanda in cui si era fermato era perennemente intrappolata in una coltre di fumo, e la sua pipa non faceva altro che aggiungerne altro. Nonostante ciò, i suoi pensieri tornavano sempre a una cosa sola invece di essere persi nel fumo del vecchio.[PARAGRAPH:1]La birra era agrodolce.[PARAGRAPH:1]Vide la foschia grigia diradarsi leggermente mentre la cameriera tornava con un'altra birra per lui.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sorrise. Vide Elizabeth nella foschia, in attesa che lui realizzasse il suo sogno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The ale was bitter.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sighed as he the amber liquid sloshed in his mug, the wagon creaking as it passed through the crossroads. The road was desolate, dreary even as he clenched his teeth, a wind peircing through the thin cloak he wore. Raising the mug to his lips again, his face contorted as the pungent aroma of the booze wafted from the porcelain. Juno wasnt far, and from there it would be a two days ride to Midgar.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was sour.[PARAGRAPH:1]Memories of his past life plauged him as he took up the reins to his wagon, laden with goods as he left the gates of Juno. He remembered what Cassiel had told him in those halls, that day he had renounced his identity as Tamur. He didnt have this mug then.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was spilt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau sighed, watching the barmaid wipe up the booze as it soaked into the floorboards. The roadside inn he had stopped at was perpetually caught in this thick haze of smoke, but his own pipe did nothing but add to the smog. Despite this, his thoughts always drifted back to one thing instead of being lost in the smoke of antiquity.[PARAGRAPH:1]The ale was bittersweet.[PARAGRAPH:1]He saw the grey haze of smoke part slightly, as the barmaid returned with another ale for him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goodreau smiled. He saw Elizabeth in the haze, waiting for him to fufill his dream.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_ARDOR</Tag>
		<English>Ardor</English>
		<French>Ardeur</French>
		<German>Großer Eifer</German>
		<Italian>Ardore</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ardor</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_ARDOR_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Resets the player's Great Person count</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Réinitialise le compteur des Personnages Illustres du joueur</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Setzt den große Persönlichkeiten-Zähler des Spielers zurück</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Azzera il contatore dei Grandi Personaggi del giocatore</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Resets the player's Great Person count</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ADVENTURERS_GUILD</Tag>
		<English>Adventurers' Guild</English>
		<French>Guilde des Aventuriers</French>
		<German>Gilde der Abenteurer</German>
		<Italian>Gilda degli Avventurieri</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gremio de Aventureros</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ADVENTURERS_GUILD_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>An Adventurers' Guild attracts adventurers to the city it is built in.</English>
		<French>Une Guilde des Aventuriers attire des aventuriers dans la ville où elle est construite.</French>
		<German>Eine Abenteurergilde lockt Abenteurer in die Stadt.</German>
		<Italian>Una Gilda degli Avventurieri attrae questi ultimi nella città in cui viene costruita e permette alle unità terrestri create in città di inizare con un pò di esperienza.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un Gremio de Aventureros atrae aventureros a la ciudad donde es construido.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DWELLING_OF_REFUGE</Tag>
		<English>Dwelling of Refuge</English>
		<French>Dwelling of Refuge</French>
		<German>Flüchtlingslager</German>
		<Italian>Abitazioni dei Rifugiati</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dwelling of Refuge</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FORUM</Tag>
		<English>Citizen's Forum</English>
		<French>Forum des citoyens</French>
		<German>Bürgerforum</German>
		<Italian>Forum dei Cittadini</Italian>
		<Spanish>Citizen's Forum</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FORUM_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows the [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT][LINK=SPECIALIST_STATESMAN]Statesman[\LINK][COLOR_REVERT] specialist to affect the Adventurer counter</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Allows the [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT][LINK=SPECIALIST_STATESMAN]Statesman[\LINK][COLOR_REVERT] specialist to affect the Adventurer counter</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt dem [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT][LINK=SPECIALIST_STATESMAN]Staatsmann[\LINK][COLOR_REVERT] Spezialisten, den Abenteurer Zähler zu beeinflussen</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Permette agli specialisti [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT][LINK=SPECIALIST_STATESMAN]Statisti[\LINK][COLOR_REVERT] di influenzare il contatore per Avventurieri</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Allows the [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT][LINK=SPECIALIST_STATESMAN]Statesman[\LINK][COLOR_REVERT] specialist to affect the Adventurer counter</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRIGORI_TEMPLE</Tag>
		<English>Dagda's Memorial</English>
		<French>Mémorial de Dagda</French>
		<German>Dagdas Gedächtnisstätte</German>
		<Italian>Memoriale di Dagda</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dagda's Memorial</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRIGORI_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>For all their well or ill meant actions, for all the gifts the gods have given us, the result of the fact that there are Gods, can be summarised in two words: Children Die. Therefore, let gods be a memory of the past, don't let their kindness, before the fall, be forgotten, but their chance has passed, let them fade to memories[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]On the Gods, prologue to the first part of Cassiels hundred treatises.</English>
		<French>For all their well or ill meant actions, for all the gifts the gods have given us, the result of the fact that there are Gods, can be summarised in two words: Children Die. Therefore, let gods be a memory of the past, don't let their kindness, before the fall, be forgotten, but their chance has passed, let them fade to memories[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]On the Gods, prologue to the first part of Cassiels hundred treatises.</French>
		<German>Für all ihre guten und schlechten Taten, für alle die Geschenke, die die Götter uns gegeben haben, das Ergebnis der Tatsache dass es Götter gibt, kann in zwei Wörtern zusammengefasst werden: Kinder sterben. Aus diesem Grund lasst die Götter eine Erinnerung aus der Vergangenheit sein, lasst uns nicht ihre Freundlichkeit vor ihrem Fall vergessen sein, aber ihre Chance ist vorbei, lasst sie zu Erinnerungen verblassen.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]über die Götter, Prolog des ersten Teils von Cassiels hundert Thesen</German>
		<Italian>Nonostante tutte le loro azioni buone o cattive, nonostante tutti i doni che gli Dei ci hanno dato, il fatto che ci siano degli Dei ha sempre lo stesso risultato, che può essere riassunto in poche parole: i bambini muoiono. Pertanto lasciate che gli dei siano una memoria del passato, non permettete alla loro gentilezza prima della caduta di essere dimenticata, hanno avuto la loro possibilità, che svaniscano nei ricordi[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Sugli Dei, prologo alla prima parte dei cento trattati di Cassiel.</Italian>
		<Spanish>For all their well or ill meant actions, for all the gifts the gods have given us, the result of the fact that there are Gods, can be summarised in two words: Children Die. Therefore, let gods be a memory of the past, don't let their kindness, before the fall, be forgotten, but their chance has passed, let them fade to memories[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]On the Gods, prologue to the first part of Cassiels hundred treatises.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEMORIAL_REFUGEE</Tag>
		<English>Memorial of the Refugee</English>
		<French>Mémorial des réfugiés</French>
		<German>Denkmal des Flüchtlings</German>
		<Italian>Memoriale dei Rifugiati</Italian>
		<Spanish>Memorial of the Refugee</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MEMORIAL_REFUGEE_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Causes Refugees to spawn in the city.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Fait apparaître des Réfugiés dans la ville.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Führt zur Entstehung von Flüchtlingen in der Stadt.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Permette la generazione di Rifugiati in città.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Causes Refugees to spawn in the city.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MUSEUM</Tag>
		<English>Museum</English>
		<French>Musée</French>
		<German>Museum</German>
		<Italian>Museo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Museum</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MUSEUM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Grigori Museums are standing testaments to the labor of the people. Each is a special place where artists, not gods, are praised for the beauty of their creations. Immigrants travel across the world to visit them, and adventurers come in hopes they may one day be depicted.</English>
		<French>Grigori Museums are standing testaments to the labor of the people. Each is a special place where artists, not gods, are praised for the beauty of their creations. Immigrants travel across the world to visit them, and adventurers come in hopes they may one day be depicted.</French>
		<German>Grigori Museums are standing testaments to the labor of the people. Each is a special place where artists, not gods, are praised for the beauty of their creations. Immigrants travel across the world to visit them, and adventurers come in hopes they may one day be depicted.</German>
		<Italian>I Musei Grigori sono dei luoghi che celebrano le opere delle persone. Onguno è un posto speciale dove gli artisti, e non gli dei, sono celebrati per la bellezza delle loro opere. Persone da tutto il mondo viaggiano per poterli visitare, e gli avventurieri li visitano sperando un giorno di esservi rappresentati.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grigori Museums are standing testaments to the labor of the people. Each is a special place where artists, not gods, are praised for the beauty of their creations. Immigrants travel across the world to visit them, and adventurers come in hopes they may one day be depicted.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_GRIGORI</Tag>
		<English>Grigori Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Grigori</French>
		<German>Palast der Grigori</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo dei Grigori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Grigori</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAVERN_GRIGORI</Tag>
		<English>Grigori Tavern</English>
		<French>Taverne Grigori</French>
		<German>Grigori Taverne</German>
		<Italian>Taverna Grigori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Taverna Grigori</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ADVENTURER</Tag>
		<English>Adventurer</English>
		<French>Aventurier</French>
		<German>Abenteurer</German>
		<Italian>Avventuriero</Italian>
		<Spanish>Adventurer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ADVENTURER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>An Adventurer is a hero unit that can be upgraded to any of the Melee, Archer, Mounted, Recon, or Adept units the owning civilization can build. They will gain 1 experience point per turn up to 100 experience points and can quickly become powerful units.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Un Aventurier est une unité de héros qui peut être améliorée en n'importe quelle unité de Mêlée, d'Archer, Montée, de Reconnaissance ou d'Adepte constructible par la civilisation qui le possède.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Der Abenteurer ist eine Heldeneinheit, die zu jeder Nahkampf-, Bogenschützen-, Berittenen, Erkundungs- oder Magisch begabten Einheit modernisiert werden kann, die eine Zivilisation aufstellen kann. Er erhält pro Runde 1 Erfahrungspunkt, bis 100 Erfahrungspunkte erreicht sind, und kann dadurch schnell zu einer mächtigen Einheit werden.</German>
		<Italian>L'avventuriero è un'unità eroe che può essere migliorata in qualsiasi unità da mischia, di arcieri, montata, da ricognizione o arcana disponibile alla civiltà d'appartenenza. Ottengono 1 punto esperienza a turno sino a quando non raggiungono i 100 punti esperienza, e possono diventare rapidamente potenti unità.</Italian>
		<Spanish>An Adventurer is a hero unit that can be upgraded to any of the Melee, Archer, Mounted, Recon, or Adept units the owning civilization can build. They will gain 1 experience point per turn up to 100 experience points and can quickly become powerful units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGON_SLAYER</Tag>
		<English>Dragon Slayer</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Tueur de Dragons:Tueurs de Dragons</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Drachentöter</German>
		<Italian>Sterminatore di Draghi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dragon Slayer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGON_SLAYER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Cassiel's creed of self-reliance and mortal empowerment yields more than philosophy discussions. His warriors often come to battle fearless, and as dedicated to their nation as most crusaders are to their god. And should any lazy dragons count upon their reputation to keep them safe, these Dragon Slayers will be more than happy to carry the treasure back home.</English>
		<French>Cassiel's creed of self-reliance and mortal empowerment yields more than philosophy discussions. His warriors often come to battle fearless, and as dedicated to their nation as most crusaders are to their god. And should any lazy dragons count upon their reputation to keep them safe, these Dragon Slayers will be more than happy to carry the treasure back home.</French>
		<German>Cassiel glaubt mehr an Selbstständigkeit und das Existenz-recht der sterblichen als an philosophische Diskussionen. Seine Krieger kämpfen furchtlos, und sie lieben ihre Nation wie die meisten Eroberer ihren Gott. Und falls ein fauler Drache auf seinen Ruf zählen sollte, um sie still zu halten, werden die Drachentöter überglücklich sein, des Drachens Schatz zu erbeuten.</German>
		<Italian>La filosofia di Cassiel riguardo l'autosufficenza e l'emancipazione dei mortali comporta più delle sole discussioni filosofiche. I suoi guerrieri vanno in battaglia senza paura, e sono fedeli alla loro nazione quanto i corciati lo sono al loro dio. E se qualche pigro drago si affida alla sua reputazione per stare al sicuro scoprirà che questi Sterminatori di Draghi saranno più che felici di portare il tesoro a casa loro.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cassiel's creed of self-reliance and mortal empowerment yields more than philosophy discussions. His warriors often come to battle fearless, and as dedicated to their nation as most crusaders are to their god. And should any lazy dragons count upon their reputation to keep them safe, these Dragon Slayers will be more than happy to carry the treasure back home.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGON_SLAYER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Don't let the name fool you, Dragon Slayers are proficient fighters against human opponents as well, and their courage promotion takes some burden off of your spell casters.</English>
		<French>Ne laissez pas le nom vous induire en erreur, les Tueurs de Dragon sont des guerriers tout aussi compétents contre les humains, et leur promotion Courage allège un fardeau de vos lanceurs de sorts.</French>
		<German>Die Bezeichnung Drachentöter ist trügerisch, denn sie sind im Kampf gegen menschliche Gegner nicht weniger gewandt und ihre Tapferkeit-Beförderung entlastet so manche magisch begabte Einheit.</German>
		<Italian>Non farti ingannare dal nome, gli Sterminatori di Draghi sono provetti combattenti anche contro avversari umani, e la loro promozione Coraggio rende i tuoi incantatori un pò più liberi di fare altro.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Don't let the name fool you, Dragon Slayers are proficient fighters against human opponents as well, and their courage promotion takes some burden off of your spell casters.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GRIGORI_MEDIC</Tag>
		<English>Grigori Medic</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Médecin Grigori:Médecins Grigori</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Grigori-Heiler</German>
		<Italian>Medico Grigori</Italian>
		<Spanish>Grigori Medic</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GRIGORI_MEDIC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Empire of the Grigori began to thrive, as men from all corners of Erebus, tired of being used as pawns by the Gods, sought a way to determine their own destiny. Whether carried by this wave of immigration, or inflicted upon them by the Gods as divine retribution, the Grigori began to suffer from diseases for which they knew no cure. Cassiel had the power to cure these ailments, and could even confer that power to others, however, he was also shrewd enough to realize that this would put him in the position of acting as a God himself, and all that he had been fighting for would be lost. Instead, Cassiel summoned the best herbalists and natural healers in the Kingdom, and formed the Ordine Medicos. Members of the Ordine Medicos travel throughout Erebus, seeking natural remedies to the ailments that inflict the Grigori, and are widely known for their ability to cure disease without divine intervention. Although quite often found travelling with Grigori military units, the Ordine Medicos take a vow of non-aggression, and will only fight to defend themselves, and those in their care.</English>
		<French>The Empire of the Grigori began to thrive, as men from all corners of Erebus, tired of being used as pawns by the Gods, sought a way to determine their own destiny. Whether carried by this wave of immigration, or inflicted upon them by the Gods as divine retribution, the Grigori began to suffer from diseases for which they knew no cure. Cassiel had the power to cure these ailments, and could even confer that power to others, however, he was also shrewd enough to realize that this would put him in the position of acting as a God himself, and all that he had been fighting for would be lost. Instead, Cassiel summoned the best herbalists and natural healers in the Kingdom, and formed the Ordine Medicos. Members of the Ordine Medicos travel throughout Erebus, seeking natural remedies to the ailments that inflict the Grigori, and are widely known for their ability to cure disease without divine intervention. Although quite often found travelling with Grigori military units, the Ordine Medicos take a vow of non-aggression, and will only fight to defend themselves, and those in their care.</French>
		<German>Das Reich der Grigori begann zu gedeihen, als Menschen von allen Enden Erebus', die genug davon hatten, von den Göttern als Spielfiguren benutzt zu werden, einen Weg suchten, ihr Schicksal selbst zu bestimmen. Ob von dieser Welle von Einwanderern getragen, oder von den Göttern selbst als göttliche Strafe gesandt, erkrankten die Grigori an Seuchen für die sie keine Heilung kannten. Cassiel hatte die Kraft, diese Leiden zu verarzten, und konnte diese sogar an andere weitergeben, jedoch war er auch scharfsinnig genug zu erkennen, dass ihn das in die Position bringen würde, selbst als Gott zu wirken, und alles wofür er gekämpft hatte, wäre verloren gewesen. Stattdessen also rief Cassiel die besten Kräuterkundigen und Naturheiler des Königreiches zusammen, und gründete den Medici-Orden. Mitglieder des Medici-Ordens reisen durch ganz Erebus, auf der Suche nach natürlichen Gegenmitteln für die Leiden, die die Grigori plagen, und sind weitaus bekannt für ihre Fähigkeit, Krankheiten ohne göttliche Einwirkungen zu heilen. Obwohl sie oft zusammen mit Militäreinheiten der Grigori reisen, leisten die Mitglieder des Medici-Ordens einen Eid, nicht anzugreifen, und werden nur kämpfen um sich selbst und die zu verteidigen, die unter ihrem Schutz stehen.</German>
		<Italian>L'impero dei Grigori iniziò a crescere quando uomini da tutti gli angoli di Erebus, stanchi di essere le pedine degli Dei, cercarono una via per creare il loro stesso destino. Portate da questa serie di immigrazioni, o inflittegli dagli Dei come forma di punizione divina, i Grigori iniziarono a soffrire di malattie di cui non conoscevano la cura. Cassiel aveva il potere di guarirle, e poteva persino conferire questo potere ad altri, però era anche abbastanza accorto dal capire che farlo sarebbe stato come comportarsi come un Dio, e tutto ciò per cui stava combattendo sarebbe stato perduto. Invece Cassiel convocò i migliori erboristi e guaritori naturali presenti nel regno e fondò l'Ordine Medicos. I membri dell'Ordine Medicos viaggiano per tutto Erebus, alla ricerca di rimedi naturali per le malattie che affliggono i Grigori, e sono ampiamente conosciuti per la loro abilità nel curare le malattie senza intervento divino. Sebbene spesso viaggino con le unità militari Grigori l'Ordine Medicos ha fatto voto di non aggressione, e combatterebbero solo per difendere loro stessi, e i loro pazienti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Empire of the Grigori began to thrive, as men from all corners of Erebus, tired of being used as pawns by the Gods, sought a way to determine their own destiny. Whether carried by this wave of immigration, or inflicted upon them by the Gods as divine retribution, the Grigori began to suffer from diseases for which they knew no cure. Cassiel had the power to cure these ailments, and could even confer that power to others, however, he was also shrewd enough to realize that this would put him in the position of acting as a God himself, and all that he had been fighting for would be lost. Instead, Cassiel summoned the best herbalists and natural healers in the Kingdom, and formed the Ordine Medicos. Members of the Ordine Medicos travel throughout Erebus, seeking natural remedies to the ailments that inflict the Grigori, and are widely known for their ability to cure disease without divine intervention. Although quite often found travelling with Grigori military units, the Ordine Medicos take a vow of non-aggression, and will only fight to defend themselves, and those in their care.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GRIGORI_MEDIC_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Use to provide increased healing and the ability to cure disease to your units.</English>
		<French>Utiliser pour fournir une guérison accélérée et la capacité de soigner la maladie de vos unités.</French>
		<German>Grigori-Heiler erhöhen die Heilungsrate befreundeter Einheiten und können Krankheiten heilen.</German>
		<Italian>Utilizzali per fornire cure aggiuntive alle tue unità e per curare le malattie che le affliggono.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Use to provide increased healing and the ability to cure disease to your units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LUONNOTAR</Tag>
		<English>Luonnotar</English>
		<French>Luonnotar</French>
		<German>Luonnotar</German>
		<Italian>Luonnotar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Luonnotar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LUONNOTAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Luonnotar believe that the gods are nothing but petulant children. Instead, they claim that the true creator god will one day return and separate the good from evil, and punish those worshiping false gods.</English>
		<French>The Luonnotar believe that the gods are nothing but petulant children. Instead, they claim that the true creator god will one day return and separate the good from evil, and punish those worshiping false gods.</French>
		<German>Die Luonnotar glauben, dass die Götter nichts weiter sind als gereizte Kinder. Sie behaupten dagegen, dass der wahre Gott, der die Welt erschaffen hat, eines Tages zurückkehren wird, um die Guten von den Bösen zu trennen und um die zu bestrafen, die falschen Göttern huldigen.</German>
		<Italian>I Luonnotar credono che gli dei non siano altro che bambini petulanti. Invece affermano che il vero dio creatore un giorno tornerà e separerà il bene dal male, e che punirà coloro che venerano falsi dei.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Luonnotar believe that the gods are nothing but petulant children. Instead, they claim that the true creator god will one day return and separate the good from evil, and punish those worshiping false gods.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LUONNOTAR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Luonnotar are the most powerful disciple units the Grigori have access to, though they lack priests and high priests spell abilities. They can still act as effective healers for your armies and inquisition your cities to remove religions that have spread into them.</English>
		<French>The Luonnotar are the most powerful disciple units the Grigori have access to, though they lack priests and high priests spell abilities. They can still act as effective healers for your armies and inquisition your cities to remove religions that have spread into them.</French>
		<German>The Luonnotar are the most powerful disciple units the Grigori have access to, though they lack priests and high priests spell abilities. They can still act as effective healers for your armies and inquisition your cities to remove religions that have spread into them.</German>
		<Italian>I Luonnotar sono le unità dicepoli più forti a cui i Grigori hanno accesso, sebbene non abbiano le magie dei sacerdoti e sommi sacerdoti. Possono comunque agire sempre da efficaci guaritori per le tue armate e indagare le tue città per rimuovere le religioni che vi si sono diffuse.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Luonnotar are the most powerful disciple units the Grigori have access to, though they lack priests and high priests spell abilities. They can still act as effective healers for your armies and inquisition your cities to remove religions that have spread into them.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_REFUGEE</Tag>
		<English>Refugee</English>
		<French>Réfugié</French>
		<German>Flüchtling</German>
		<Italian>Rifugiato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Refugee</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPECIALIST_STATESMAN</Tag>
		<English>Statesman</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Homme d'État:Hommes d'État</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Staatsmann</German>
		<Italian>Statista</Italian>
		<Spanish>Statesman</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_HOMESTEAD</Tag>
		<English>Homestead</English>
		<French>Hacienda</French>
		<German>Heimstatt</German>
		<Italian>Tenuta</Italian>
		<Spanish>Homestead</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MESSAGE_REFUGEE</Tag>
		<English>Refugee has arrived in your city!</English>
		<French>Un Réfugié est arrivé dans votre ville !</French>
		<German>Ein Flüchtling hat eure Stadt erreicht!</German>
		<Italian>Un rifugiato è arrivato nella tua città!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Refugee has arrived in your city!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
