<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with Notepad++ by Deon -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - TEXT -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MALAKIM_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Malakim</English>
		<French>malakim:malakime:malakims:malakimes</French>
		<German>Malakimisch</German>
		<Italian>Malakim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Malakim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MALAKIM_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Malakim</English>
		<French>Malak</French>
		<German>Reich der Malakim</German>
		<Italian>Malakim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Malakim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MALAKIM_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Malakim</English>
		<French>Malakims</French>
		<German>Malakim</German>
		<Italian>Malakim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Malakim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MALAKIM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The only elves the Malakim had seen were the  dark Svartalfar.  Yet, when a group of hunters happened across a nearly-dead elven man freezing in the wastes, they took him back to their village and agreed to tend to his injuries rather than kill him.  When he awoke in their care, he explained that he was Varn Gosam, and that he had fled from his homeland.  Sensing some truth in him, the Malakim believed him and allowed him to live among them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Varn built a shrine to Lugus in the small village and began spreading his newfound religion to the villagers.  His revival spread quickly, and the former elven prince found himself a leader of men.  Accepting that role, he set forth to lead the Malakim through the hard years to follow and into the light of Lugus.</English>
		<French>Les seuls elfes que les malakims eurent jamais vus étaient les sombres svartálfar. Pourtant, lorsqu'un groupe de chasseur découvrit un elfe mâle mourant, gelé dans les terres dévastées, ils le ramenèrent à leur village et décidèrent de soigner ses blessures plutôt que de le tuer. Lorsqu'il se réveilla grâce à leurs soins, il leur expliqua qu'il s'appelait Varn Gosam et qu'il avait fui sa patrie. Sentant de la vérité en lui, les malakims le crurent et lui permirent de vivre parmi eux. [PARAGRAPH:1]Varn construisit un autel dédié à Lugus dans le petit village et commença à prêcher sa nouvelle religion aux villageois. Ce réveil se répandit rapidement, et l'ancien prince elfe se trouva devenir un dirigeant des hommes. Acceptant ce rôle, il fit savoir qu'il dirigerait les malakims à travers les années difficiles qui allaient suivre, dans la lumière de Lugus.</French>
		<German>Die einzigen Elfen, die die Malakim bisher gekannt hatten, waren die finsteren Svartalfar. Als dann eine Gruppe von Jägern auf einen fast toten Elfen stieß, der in den Einöden langsam erfror, nahmen sie ihn mit in ihr Dorf und beschlossen seine Wunden zu versorgen, statt ihn zu töten. Als er erwachte, erklärte er, dass er Varn Gosam sei und dass er aus seiner Heimat geflohen wäre. Die Malakim spürten die Wahrheit in seinen Worten und erlaubten ihm, unter ihnen zu leben.[PARAGRAPH:1]Varn errichtete in dem kleinen Dorf einen Schrein für Lugus und begann, seine neu gegründete Religion unter den Dorfbewohnern zu verbreiten. Die Kunde von seiner Rückkehr von den Toten verbreitete sich ebenso schnell und so fand sich der ehemalige Elfenprinz bald in der Rolle eines Anführers wieder. Er akzeptierte seine neue Verantwortung und führte die Malakim durch die folgenden harten Jahre und hin zum Licht von Lugus.</German>
		<Italian>Gli unici elfi che i Malakim avessero mai visto erano gli oscuri Svartalfar. Eppure, quando un gruppo di cacciatori trovò un elfo moribondo nelle terre desolate lo portarono con loro al villaggio, e decisero di curare le sue ferite anziché ucciderlo. Quando l'elfo si svegliò gli disse il suo nome, Varn Gosam, e che lui era fuggitto dalla sua terra natia. Percependo della verità nelle sue parole i Malakim gli credetterò e gli permisero di vivere tra loro.[PARAGRAPH:1]Varn costruì un santuario a Lugus nel piccolo villaggio e iniziò a diffondere la sua nuova religione agli abitanti del villaggio. Quest'ultima si diffuse rapidamente, e l'ex principe elfico si ritrovò ad essere un condottiero di uomini. Accettando tale ruolo si impegnò a guidare i Malakim nei successivi anni difficili e verso la luce di Lugus.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los únicos elfos que los Malakim habían visto eran los oscuros Svartalfar.  Aún así, cuando un grupo de cazadores se cruzaron con un elfo moribundo congelándose en tierras baldías, se lo llevaron a su aldea y se pudieron de acuerdo en atender sus heridas en lugar de matarlo.  Cuando despertó entre sus cuidados, explicó que se llamaba Varn Gosam, y que huyó de su tierra natal.  Sintiendo la verdad en sus palabras, los Malakim le creyeron y le permitieron vivir entre ellos.[PARAGRAPH:1]Varn construyó un santuario dedicado a Lugus en la pequeña aldea y empezó a difundir su nueva religión a los aldeanos.  Su revelación se extendió con rapidez, y el legítimo príncipe elfo se descubrió a sí mismo como un líder de los hombres.  Aceptando el rol, puso el rumbo para liderar a los Malakim a través de los duros años por venir hacia la luz de Lugus.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MALAKIM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategy: Varn Gosam starts with the Spiritual and Charismatic traits, as well as the Merchant Civilization Trait, which is very powerful. The Malakim will tend to have poor production, but very high commerce. Cottage-spammers will enjoy this Civ, as they have a unique improvement functioning as a cross between a Cottage and a Farm. Malakim units also gain the Dunespeak promotion in Desert, allowing them to ignore the negative effect of deserts. The Malakim's World Spell will help them reach powerful priest units quickly if they spread it well and build temples beforehand. The Malakim gain many benefits from Desert terrain, so it is recommended you use your initial Lightbringer to Scorch your terrain.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Unique Spells:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_SCORCH]Scorch:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Lightbringers have access to a unique version of the Scorch spell in order to terraform Malakim lands. Takes 3 turns to cast.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_OASIS]Lugus' Gift:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Malakim Adepts can use the "Lugus' Gift" spell, allowing them to create an Oasis. Can not be cast within 5 tiles of any other Oasis, whether natural or created. Requires the ring of tiles immediately surrounding it to be desert, coast, or ocean.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_SPRING]Spring[\LINK]/[LINK=SPELL_VITALIZE]Vitalize:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Malakim cannot cast either Spring or Vitalize within one tile of an Oasis, either natural or magical.[NEWLINE]Spring and Vitalize can be cast on Floodplains, but they will be destroyed in the process.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Units and Promotions:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][NEWLINE][BOLD]Mounted Units:[\BOLD]Malakim Horsemen and Knights initially lose all bonuses, and start with one movement. Then, depending on which Stable the city has built, and which Mount resources are available, the unit will have access to one of two promotions.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Possession of Horses grant access to the Horse Rider/Knight promotion while in a city with a Stable. This restores the traditional 40% bonus vs Archery, increases movement by one, and changes the artstyle to that of a Horse Cavalry unit. It also reduces movement by one inside deserts and blocks access to the Dunespeak promotion.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Possession of Camels grant access to the Camel Rider/Knight promotion while in a city with a Camel Stable, which grants a 40% bonus vs Mounted, sets the artstyle to that of the new Camel units, and increases withdrawal rate in desert.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_DUNESPEAK]Dunespeak:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upkeep discounts removed.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can see invisible animals.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_DESERTWORKRATE]Desert Stealth:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+25% workrate on Desert. Balances out the negative on the terrain. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants Invisibility while in Desert.[NEWLINE]This promotion is only available to Malakim Workers, and is automatically applied to any worker in the Desert.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR]Conviction:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires Disciple unitclass.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Strength/Defense [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Granted by [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Mirrored Pylon[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Improvements, Features, Resources, and Buildings:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BONUS_CAMEL]Camels:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Camels are found in deserts. They are only able to be tamed by the Malakim, and are a requirement for their Camel Rider line.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=FEATURE_OASIS]Oases:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Malakim have Civilization Specific yields for the Oasis. 5 Food 3 Commerce rather than 3/2.[NEWLINE]Improvements can be constructed over Oases.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_BEDOUIN_SIT]Bedouin Improvements:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Bedouin Sits can be construced by a Bedouin unit at a cost of 15 Gold on desert tiles. Can NOT be constructed on Flood Plains.[NEWLINE]Will upgrade to a Bedouin Camp, then Gathering, and finally Village, in 15/30/60 turns respectively. This is half again the time required for Cottages to upgrade.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_CITADEL_OF_LIGHT]Citadel of Light:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Citadel of Light is a Malakim-only upgrade to the Citadel. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Any enemy unit who comes within a tile will be blasted by a Pillar of Fire. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Human players must have a unit in the Citadel for this to take effect, but AI players don't.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_STABLE_CAMEL]Caravanserai:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Caravanserai allows a city to make use of Camels rather than Horses. It allows Mounted units access to the Camel Rider promotions, and cannot be built in the same city as a Stable.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR]Resplendent Minaret:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Resplendent Minaret can only be constructed via an event, which occurs when the Malakim find the Mirror of Heaven. It grants one happiness to your capital city, and creates a [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Mirrored Pylon[\LINK] in all cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Mirrored Pylon:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Mirrored Pylon is automatically constructed in all Malakim cities when they gain the [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR]Resplendent Minaret[\LINK]. It allows you to assign one priest specialist, and grants the [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR]Conviction[\LINK] promotion to all Disciple units.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Tech, Trait:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=TECH_DESERTPEOPLE]'Dunespeakers' Tech:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Allows construction of the Bedouin improvement line, and reveals the Camel resource.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]'Merchant' Trait:[\BOLD][NEWLINE]Malakim Civtrait.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Health in each city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+15% Commerce.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50 Starting Gold.</English>
		<French>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Stratégie : Varn Gosam commence avec les traits Spirituel et Charismatique, de même que la caractéristique Civilisation Marchande, une combinaison puissante. Les Malakims auront tendance à avoir une faible production, mais un commerce très développé. Les constructeurs frénétiques de Cottages apprécieront cette civilisation, qui possède un aménagement unique fonctionnant comme une combinaison du Cottage et de la Ferme. Les unités Malakims gagnent également la promotion Connaissance du désert dans le Désert, leur permettant d'ignorer les malus du terrain. Le Sort Mondial Malakim leur permettra d'obtenir rapidement de puissants prêtres s'ils se développent convenablement et construisent des temples au préalable. Les Malakims profitant énormément du terrain désertique, il est recommandé d'utiliser votre Porteur de Lumière initial pour Brûler votre terrain.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Sorts Uniques :[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_SCORCH]Brûlure:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Les Porteurs de Lumière ont accès à une version unique du sort Brûlure, leur permettant de terraformer les territoires malakims et qui prend 3 tours pour être lancé.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_OASIS]Don de Lugus :[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Les Adeptes Malakims peuvent lancer le "Don de Lugus", leur permettant de créer une oasis. Ce sort ne peut être lancé à moins de 5 cases d'une auter oasis, qu'elle soit naturelle ou créée. Pour pouvoir être lancé, la case doit être entourée par du désert, de la côte ou de l'océan.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_SPRING]Printemps[\LINK]/[LINK=SPELL_VITALIZE]Fertilité:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Les Malakims ne peuvent pas lancer Printemps ou Fertilité à une case ou moins d'une oasis, qu'elle soit naturelle ou magique.[NEWLINE]Printemps et Fertilité peuvent être lancés sur les plaines inondables, mais elles seront alors détruites.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Unités et Promotions:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][NEWLINE][BOLD]Unités Montées:[\BOLD]Les Cavaliers et Chevaliers Malakims ne possèdent pas au départ les bonus de cavalerie, et commencent avec 1 de mouvement. Puis, selon le type d'écurie construit dans la ville et quelles Montures (ressources) sont disponibles, l'unité aura accès à une des deux promotions.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Posséder des Chevaux donne accès aux promotions Cavalier et Chevalier dans une ville avec une Écurie. Elles rétablissent le bonus traditionnel de 40% conter les Archers, augmente le mouvement de 1, et l'unité est affichée comme un Cavalier. De plus, le coût de mouvement dans les déserts est réduit de 1, et la promotion Autochtone n'est plus accessible.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Posséder des Chameaux donne accès aux promotions Méhariste et Chevalier Méhariste dans une ville avec un Caravansérail, qui confèrent une bonus de 40% contre les unités Montées, affiche l'unité comme chevauchant un Chameau, et augmente les chances de repli dans le désert.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_DUNESPEAK]Autochtone:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Pas de réduction sur l'entretien.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Peut voir les animaux invisibles.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_DESERTWORKRATE]Camouflage dans le Désert :[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+25% à la vitesse de travail dans le Désert. Supprime les effets négatifs du terrain.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Confère l'Invisibilité dans le Désert.[NEWLINE]Cette promotion n'est disponible que pour les ouvriers Malakims, les Bédouins, et donnée automatiquement à tout ouvrier dans le Désert.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR]Conviction:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Accessible uniquement aux Disciples.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Force/Défense[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fourni par [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Pylône de Miroirs[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Aménagements, Ressources et Bâtiments:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BONUS_CAMEL]Chameaux:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Les Chameaux se trouvent dans les déserts. Ils ne sont domesticables que par les Malakims et sont nécessaires pour toutes les unités méharistes.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=FEATURE_OASIS]Oasis:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Les Malakims exploitent différemment les oasis et en obtiennent 5 Nourriture et 3 Commerce au lieu de 3/2.[NEWLINE]Ils peuvent également construire des aménagements sur les Oasis.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_BEDOUIN_SIT]Aménagements Bédouins:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Les Haltes Bédouines peuvent être construites par un Bédouin pour 15 Or dans les désert, et ne peuvent pas être construits sur des plaines inondables.[NEWLINE]Elle s'améliorera en Camp Bédouin, puis en Rassemblement et enfin en Village en respectivement 15/30/60 tours, soit la moitié du temps nécessaire pour les Cottages.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_CITADEL_OF_LIGHT]Citadelle de la Lumière:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]La Citadelle de la Lumière est une amélioration unique de la Citadelle.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Toute unité ennemie pénétrant dans sa zone sera touchée par un Pilier de Feu.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Les joueurs Humains doivent conserver une unité dans la Citadelle pour que l'effet se produise, au contraire des joueurs IA.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_STABLE_CAMEL]Caravansérail:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Le Caravansérail permet d'utiliser des Chameaux en lieu et place des Chevaux. Il permet l'accès aux promotions de type Méhariste et ne peut être construit dans la même ville que les Écuries.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR]Minaret Resplendissant:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Le Minaret resplendissant ne peut être construit que via un évènement qui se déclenche quand les Malakims découvrent le Miroir du Paradis. il fournit +1 de bonheur dans votre capitale, et crée un [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Pylône de Miroirs[\LINK] dans toutes les villes.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Pylône de Miroirs:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Le Pylône de Miroirs est automatiquement construit dans toutes les villes Malakims quand ils obtiennent le [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR]Minaret Resplendissant[\LINK]. Il vous permet d'avoir un Spécialiste Prêtre et confère la promotion [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR]Conviction[\LINK] à toutes les unités de type Disciple.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Technologies, Traits:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=TECH_DESERTPEOPLE]Technologie 'Natifs du Désert':[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Permet la construction des aménagements de type Bédouine et révèle les Chameaux.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Trait 'Mercantile':[\BOLD][NEWLINE]Trait lié à la civilisation Malakim.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+1 de santé dans chaque ville.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+15% de Commerce.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50 d'Or de départ.</French>
		<German>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategie: Varn Gosam beginnt mit den Eigenschaften Kreativ und Finanziell, eine mächtige Kombination in Vanilla Civ, und hier genauso brauchbar. Schnelle Ausbreitung erbringt gute Resultate, da die kostenintensiven Obelisken für Malakim-Städte zur Expansion nicht gebraucht werden. Stadt-Spammer wird diese Zivilisation beglücken, aber andere Strategien sind genauso praktikabel. Das Feuermana, mit dem sie beginnen, führt schnell zu Feuerbällen für Magier. Malakim-Einheiten beginnen auch mit der Nomaden-Beförderung, die ihnen erlaubt, die negativen Auswirkungen von Wüsten zu ignorieren.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Unique Spells:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_SCORCH]Scorch:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Lightbringers have access to a unique version of the Scorch spell in order to terraform Malakim lands. Takes 3 turns to cast.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_OASIS]Lugus' Gift:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Malakim Adepts can use the "Lugus' Gift" spell, allowing them to create an Oasis. Can not be cast within 5 tiles of any other Oasis, whether natural or created. Requires the ring of tiles immediately surrounding it to be desert, coast, or ocean.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_SPRING]Spring[\LINK]/[LINK=SPELL_VITALIZE]Vitalize:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Malakim cannot cast either Spring or Vitalize within one tile of an Oasis, either natural or magical.[NEWLINE]Spring and Vitalize can be cast on Floodplains, but they will be destroyed in the process.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Units and Promotions:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][NEWLINE][BOLD]Mounted Units:[\BOLD]Malakim Horsemen and Knights initially lose all bonuses, and start with one movement. Then, depending on which Stable the city has built, and which Mount resources are available, the unit will have access to one of two promotions.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Possession of Horses grant access to the Horse Rider/Knight promotion while in a city with a Stable. This restores the traditional 40% bonus vs Archery, increases movement by one, and changes the artstyle to that of a Horse Cavalry unit. It also reduces movement by one inside deserts and blocks access to the Dunespeak promotion.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Possession of Camels grant access to the Camel Rider/Knight promotion while in a city with a Camel Stable, which grants a 40% bonus vs Mounted, sets the artstyle to that of the new Camel units, and increases withdrawal rate in desert.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_DUNESPEAK]Dunespeak:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upkeep discounts removed.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can see invisible animals.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_DESERTWORKRATE]Desert Stealth:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+25% workrate on Desert. Balances out the negative on the terrain. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants Invisibility while in Desert.[NEWLINE]This promotion is only available to Malakim Workers, and is automatically applied to any worker in the Desert.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR]Conviction:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires Disciple unitclass.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Strength/Defense [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Granted by [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Mirrored Pylon[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Improvements, Features, Resources, and Buildings:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BONUS_CAMEL]Camels:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Camels are found in deserts. They are only able to be tamed by the Malakim, and are a requirement for their Camel Rider line.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=FEATURE_OASIS]Oases:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Malakim have Civilization Specific yields for the Oasis. 5 Food 3 Commerce rather than 3/2.[NEWLINE]Improvements can be constructed over Oases.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_BEDOUIN_SIT]Bedouin Improvements:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Bedouin Sits can be construced by a Bedouin unit at a cost of 15 Gold on desert tiles. Can NOT be constructed on Flood Plains.[NEWLINE]Will upgrade to a Bedouin Camp, then Gathering, and finally Village, in 15/30/60 turns respectively. This is half again the time required for Cottages to upgrade.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_CITADEL_OF_LIGHT]Citadel of Light:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Citadel of Light is a Malakim-only upgrade to the Citadel. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Any enemy unit who comes within a tile will be blasted by a Pillar of Fire. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Human players must have a unit in the Citadel for this to take effect, but AI players don't.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_STABLE_CAMEL]Caravanserai:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Caravanserai allows a city to make use of Camels rather than Horses. It allows Mounted units access to the Camel Rider promotions, and cannot be built in the same city as a Stable.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR]Resplendent Minaret:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Resplendent Minaret can only be constructed via an event, which occurs when the Malakim find the Mirror of Heaven. It grants one happiness to your capital city, and creates a [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Mirrored Pylon[\LINK] in all cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Mirrored Pylon:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Mirrored Pylon is automatically constructed in all Malakim cities when they gain the [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR]Resplendent Minaret[\LINK]. It allows you to assign one priest specialist, and grants the [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR]Conviction[\LINK] promotion to all Disciple units.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Tech, Trait:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=TECH_DESERTPEOPLE]'Dunespeakers' Tech:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Allows construction of the Bedouin improvement line, and reveals the Camel resource.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]'Merchant' Trait:[\BOLD][NEWLINE]Malakim Civtrait.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Health in each city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+15% Commerce.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50 Starting Gold.</German>
		<Italian>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategia (da rifare in quanto vecchia): Varn Gosam starts with the Creative and Financial traits, a powerful combination in vanilla Civ, and useful here as well. Quick expansion yields good results, as monuments aren't necessary for Malakim cities to expand. Cottage-spammers will enjoy this Civ, but other strategies are viable as well. Malakim units also start with the nomad promotion, allowing them to ignore the negative effect of deserts. The Malakim's World Spell will help them reach powerful priest units quickly if they spread it well and build temples beforehand.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Magie Uniche:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_SCORCH]Bruciatura:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]I Portatori della Luce dispongono di una versione unica della magia Bruciatura permettendogli di terraformare le terre Malakim. Richede 3 turni per essere lanciata.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_OASIS]Dono di Lugus:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Gli Adepti Malakim possono usare la magia "Dono di Lugus" per creare un'Oasi. Non può essere lanciata entro 5 caselle da un'altra Oasi, sia essa naturale o creata. Richede che tutti i quadretti vicini siano deserto, costa o oceano.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_SPRING]Sorgente[\LINK]/[LINK=SPELL_VITALIZE]Vitalizza:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]I Malakim non possono lanciare ne Sorgente ne Vitalizza vicino a un'Oasi, sia essa naturale o creata.[NEWLINE]Sorgente e Vitalizza possono essere lanciate sui Terreni Allagati, che verranno distrutti nel processo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Unità e Promozioni:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][NEWLINE][BOLD]Unità Montate:[\BOLD]I cavalieri Malakim perdono inizialmente tutti i loro bonus, e iniziano con un punto movimento. Poi, a seconda di quale edificio è stato costruito nella città, e a seconda della risorsa disponibile, l'unità ha accesso a una di due promozioni.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Possedere i Cavalli fornisce accesso alle promozioni Cavalcatore di cavalli/Cavaliere se nella città è presente una Stalla. Queste ripristinano il tradizionale bonus del 40% contro gli Arcieri, aumenta i punti movimento di 1, e cambia l'estetica dell'unità in quella classica da cavaliere. Riduce però il movimento di 1 all'interno del deserto e impedisce di ottenere la promozione Conoscenza del Deserto.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Possedere i Cammelli fornisce accesso alle promozioni Cavalcatore di Cammelli/Cavaliere Cammellato se in città è presente il Caravanserraglio, che forniscono un bonus del 40% contro altre unità montate, cambia l'estetica dell'unità in quella delle unità cammellate, e aumenta la probabilità di ritirarsi nel deserto.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_DUNESPEAK]Conoscenza del Deserto:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Sconti mantenimento rimossi.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Può vedere gli animali invisibili.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_DESERTWORKRATE]Mimetizzazione Desertica:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+25% al tasso di lavoro del Deserto. Bilancia quella negativa dovuta al terreno. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornisce Invisibilità quando nel Deserto.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Questa promozione è disponibile solo ai Lavoratori Malakim, ed è automaticamente applicata ad ogni lavoratore in un deserto.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR]Convinzione:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Richede un'unità Discepolo.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Forza/Difesa [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Fornita da [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Pilone specchiato[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Miglioramenti, Caratteristiche, Risorse, e Edifici:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BONUS_CAMEL]Cammelli:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]I Cammelli si trovano nei deserti. Sono ammaestrabili solo dai Malakim, e sono un requisito per la linea di promozioni cavalcatore di cammelli.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=FEATURE_OASIS]Oasi:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]I Malakim hanno una rendita fissa dalle Oasi. 5 Cibo 3 Commercio al contrario del normale 3/2.[NEWLINE]I miglioramenti possono essere costruiti sulle Oasi.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_BEDOUIN_SIT]Miglioramenti Beduini:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Il Rifugio Beduino può essere costruito dal un'unità Beduino al costo di 15 Oro sui Deserti. NON può essere costruito sui terreni allagati.[NEWLINE]Si svilupperà poi in un Campo Beduino, e poi in un Raduno Beduino, e infine in un Villaggio Beduino, in 15/30/60 turni rispettivamente. Ovvero metà del tempo necessario alle Villette per svilupparsi.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_CITADEL_OF_LIGHT]Cittadella della luce:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]La Cittadella della luce è un miglioramento della normale Cittadella unico dei Malakim. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Qualsiasi unità nemica che gli si avvicini sarà colpita da un Pilastro di Fuoco. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]I giocatori umani devono avere almeno un'unità nella Cittadella della Luce perché ciò avvenga, ma non l'IA.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_STABLE_CAMEL]Caravanserraglio:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Il Caravanserraglio permette alla città di usare i Cammelli al posto dei Cavalli. Fornisce accesso alle unità montate alle promozioni Cavalcatore di Cammelli, e non può essere costruito in una città con una Stalla.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR]Minareto Risplendente:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Il Minareto Risplendente può essere costruito solamente tramite un'evento, che avviene quando i Malakim trovano lo Specchio del Cielo. Fornisce uno di Felicità nella tua capitale, e crea un [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Pilone Specchiato[\LINK] in tutte le tue città.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Pilone Specchiato:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Il Pilone Specchiato viene costruito automaticamente in tutte le città Malakim quando ottengono il [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR]Minareto Risplendente[\LINK]. Permette di assegnare uno specialista Sacerdote, e fornisce la promozione [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR]Convinzione[\LINK] a tutte le unità Discepolo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Tecnologie, Tratti:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=TECH_DESERTPEOPLE]Tecnologia 'Popolo del Deserto':[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Permette la costruzione della linea di miglioramenti Beduini, e rivela la risorsa Cammelli.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Tratto 'Commerciante':[\BOLD][NEWLINE]Tratto della civiltà Malakim.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+2 Salute in ogni città.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+30% Cibo dalle Rotte commerciali.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+15% Commercio.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50 Oro iniziale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Estrategia: Varn Gosam empieza con los rasgos Creativo y Financiero, una poderosa combinación, y muy útil. Una rápida expansión proporciona buenos resultados, ya que los obeliscos absorve-dinero no son necesarios para expandir las ciudades Malakim. A los constructores de villas les gustará esta civilización, pero también son viables otras estrategias. El maná de fuego con el que empiezan lleva facilmente las bolas de fuego a los magos.  Las unidades Malakim también empiezan con el ascenso nómada, permitiéndoles ignorar los efectos negativos de los desiertos.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Unique Spells:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_SCORCH]Scorch:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Lightbringers have access to a unique version of the Scorch spell in order to terraform Malakim lands. Takes 3 turns to cast.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_OASIS]Lugus' Gift:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Malakim Adepts can use the "Lugus' Gift" spell, allowing them to create an Oasis. Can not be cast within 5 tiles of any other Oasis, whether natural or created. Requires the ring of tiles immediately surrounding it to be desert, coast, or ocean.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=SPELL_SPRING]Spring[\LINK]/[LINK=SPELL_VITALIZE]Vitalize:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Malakim cannot cast either Spring or Vitalize within one tile of an Oasis, either natural or magical.[NEWLINE]Spring and Vitalize can be cast on Floodplains, but they will be destroyed in the process.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Units and Promotions:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][NEWLINE][BOLD]Mounted Units:[\BOLD]Malakim Horsemen and Knights initially lose all bonuses, and start with one movement. Then, depending on which Stable the city has built, and which Mount resources are available, the unit will have access to one of two promotions.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Possession of Horses grant access to the Horse Rider/Knight promotion while in a city with a Stable. This restores the traditional 40% bonus vs Archery, increases movement by one, and changes the artstyle to that of a Horse Cavalry unit. It also reduces movement by one inside deserts and blocks access to the Dunespeak promotion.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Possession of Camels grant access to the Camel Rider/Knight promotion while in a city with a Camel Stable, which grants a 40% bonus vs Mounted, sets the artstyle to that of the new Camel units, and increases withdrawal rate in desert.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_DUNESPEAK]Dunespeak:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Upkeep discounts removed.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Can see invisible animals.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_DESERTWORKRATE]Desert Stealth:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+25% workrate on Desert. Balances out the negative on the terrain. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Grants Invisibility while in Desert.[NEWLINE]This promotion is only available to Malakim Workers, and is automatically applied to any worker in the Desert.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR]Conviction:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires Disciple unitclass.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Strength/Defense [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Granted by [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Mirrored Pylon[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Improvements, Features, Resources, and Buildings:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BONUS_CAMEL]Camels:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Camels are found in deserts. They are only able to be tamed by the Malakim, and are a requirement for their Camel Rider line.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=FEATURE_OASIS]Oases:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Malakim have Civilization Specific yields for the Oasis. 5 Food 3 Commerce rather than 3/2.[NEWLINE]Improvements can be constructed over Oases.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_BEDOUIN_SIT]Bedouin Improvements:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Bedouin Sits can be construced by a Bedouin unit at a cost of 15 Gold on desert tiles. Can NOT be constructed on Flood Plains.[NEWLINE]Will upgrade to a Bedouin Camp, then Gathering, and finally Village, in 15/30/60 turns respectively. This is half again the time required for Cottages to upgrade.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_CITADEL_OF_LIGHT]Citadel of Light:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Citadel of Light is a Malakim-only upgrade to the Citadel. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Any enemy unit who comes within a tile will be blasted by a Pillar of Fire. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Human players must have a unit in the Citadel for this to take effect, but AI players don't.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_STABLE_CAMEL]Caravanserai:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Caravanserai allows a city to make use of Camels rather than Horses. It allows Mounted units access to the Camel Rider promotions, and cannot be built in the same city as a Stable.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR]Resplendent Minaret:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Resplendent Minaret can only be constructed via an event, which occurs when the Malakim find the Mirror of Heaven. It grants one happiness to your capital city, and creates a [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Mirrored Pylon[\LINK] in all cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR]Mirrored Pylon:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]The Mirrored Pylon is automatically constructed in all Malakim cities when they gain the [LINK=BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR]Resplendent Minaret[\LINK]. It allows you to assign one priest specialist, and grants the [LINK=PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR]Conviction[\LINK] promotion to all Disciple units.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][H1]Tech, Trait:[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD][LINK=TECH_DESERTPEOPLE]'Dunespeakers' Tech:[\LINK][\BOLD][NEWLINE]Allows construction of the Bedouin improvement line, and reveals the Camel resource.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]'Merchant' Trait:[\BOLD][NEWLINE]Malakim Civtrait.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+1 Health in each city.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+15% Commerce.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]+50 Starting Gold.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_KANE</Tag>
		<English>Kane</English>
		<French>Kane</French>
		<German>Kane</German>
		<Italian>Kane</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kane</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_KANE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Kane looked upon the spoils of his latest conquest, piled impressively in his throne room. Gold and silver, jewels, and most beautiful of all, weapons and armor... the demon-kings, the wretched Calabim, had started another skirmish with his people, and been beaten back by the might of the Malakim empire. They were arrogant, Alexis and Flauros, even though they continued existing only because Kane whimmed it. They were a useful way to dispose of lesser warlords. But every so often, as now, they tried to attack him. As ever, they failed. Which gave Kane an excuse to send raiding parties of his own, to remind them of their place in the world; his pets, his hounds, nothing more Kane smiled, and thought it good.[PARAGRAPH:1]But that was not all. A minor tribe of orcs had attempted to defy his glory. Their precious "Bhall" had been deaf to their pleas as Kane's soldiers had slaughtered every man, woman, and child in one of their stinking towns. Kane had sent a few skulls to each and every other orcish tribe, and kept a few for his own; their warlord's in particular would serve as an excellent cup for his collection. It was a waste of lives, and Kane hardly enjoyed such slaughter, but the Orcs would not respect anything but brutality. Suffice it to say, the raids had stopped. Kane smiled, and thought it good.[PARAGRAPH:1]Meanwhile, Kane suspected the Svartalfar had planted yet another agent in his harem... they seemed to have an unusually large number of pretty women. He'd feed her some minor misinformation, and see if the Svartalfar acted on it. Sadly, after what happened to the first one he'd captured alive, the Svartalfar agents had taken to committing suicide upon discovery, or even suspicion of such. A shame, seeing how much fun he'd had with that first one. Kane was known to be far gentler to his women them most of the Malakim warlords, but when this wench had awoken the beast within him... Kane smiled, and thought it good.[PARAGRAPH:1]A messenger burst in. "My lord, word from Golden Leane." Kane regretted not burning that place to the ground. Technically, the man should have announced himself, and not charged in as he had, but Kane knew better then to do anything foolish. He waved off his attendants and gestured for the man to continue. "They've revolted. Again. They're lead by... an elf, of all things, name Varn Gosam." "Kill Varn. Is that so hard?" The messenger paused. Kane gussed from the look on the man's face that the answer was "yes." "I'll arrange for one of the elite to deal with this man. Tell me about him." The messenger did... and as he listened to the tales, Kane stopped smiling.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Kane observa les reliques de sa dernière conquête, empilés de lanière impressionnante dans sa chambre du trône. Or et argent, bijoux, et le plus beau de tous, armes et armures... Les rois-démons, les misérables Calabions, avaient déclenché une autre bataille contre son peuple, et avaient été battus par la puissance de l'empire malakim. Ils étaient arrogants, Alexis et Flauros, bien qu'ils n'aient survécu que parce que c'était le caprice de Kane. Ils étaient un moyen efficace de se débarasser des chefs de guerre mineurs. Mais trop souvent, comme aujourd'hui, ils tentaient de l'attaquer. Comme toujours, ils avaient échoué. Ce qui avait donné à Kane une excuse pour envoyer ses propres pillards, pour leur rappeler leur place dans ce monde : ses jouets, ses chiens, rien de plus. Kane sourit, et pensa que c'était bien.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mais ce n'était pas tout. Une insignifiante tribu d'orcs avaient tenté de le défier dans sa gloire. Leur précieux "Bhall" avait été sourd à leurs supplications tandis que les soldats de Kane avaient massacré chaque homme, femme, et enfant dans une de leurs villes puantes. Kane avait envoyé à chaque autre tribu orque quelques crânes, et en avait gardé pour lui quelques uns ; leur seigneur de guerre en particulier ferait une excellente coupe pour sa collection. C'était un gâchis de vies, et Kane n'appréciait guère ces massacres, mais les orcs ne respectent rien d'autre que la brutalité. Il va sans dire que les raids avaient été stoppés. Kane sourit, et pensa que c'était bien.[PARAGRAPH:1]Pendant ce temps, Kane suspectait les svartálfar d'avoir introduit un auter de leurs agents dans son harem... Ils semblaient disposer d'un nombre inhabituel de jolies femmes. Il lui fournirait quelques fausses informations mienures, et verrait si les svartálfar agissent en conséquence. Tristement, après ce qui était arrivé à la première qu'il avait capturée vivante, les agents svartálfar avaient pris l'habitude de se suicider en cas de découverte, ou même de suspicion. Une honte, quand on voit le plaisir qu'il avait pris avec cette première. Kane était connu pour être bien plus doux avec ses femmes que la plupart des seigneurs de guerre malakims, mais quand cette catin a éveillé la bête en lui... Kane sourit, et pensa que c'était bien.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un messager fit irruption. "Monseigneur, des nouvelles de Golden Leane !" Kane regretta de ne pas avoir entièrement brûlé cette ville. Techniquement, l'homme aurait dû s'annoncer au lieu de se précipiter comme il l'avait fait, mais Kane avait mieux à faire que quelque chose de stupide. Il renvoya ses gardes et invita l'homme à poursuivre. "Ils se sont révoltés. À nouveau. Ils sont guidés par... un elfe, nommé Varn Gosam.[PARAGRAPH:1]Tuez Varn. Est-ce donc si difficile ?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Le messager fit une pause. Kane devina à l'expression de l'homme que la réponse était 'oui'. "Je vais envoyer une des élites se charger de cet homme. Dites moi tout à props de lui." Ainsi fit le messager... et tandis qu'il écoutait les récits, Kane arrêta de sourire.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Kane looked upon the spoils of his latest conquest, piled impressively in his throne room. Gold and silver, jewels, and most beautiful of all, weapons and armor... the demon-kings, the wretched Calabim, had started another skirmish with his people, and been beaten back by the might of the Malakim empire. They were arrogant, Alexis and Flauros, even though they continued existing only because Kane whimmed it. They were a useful way to dispose of lesser warlords. But every so often, as now, they tried to attack him. As ever, they failed. Which gave Kane an excuse to send raiding parties of his own, to remind them of their place in the world; his pets, his hounds, nothing more Kane smiled, and thought it good.[PARAGRAPH:1]But that was not all. A minor tribe of orcs had attempted to defy his glory. Their precious "Bhall" had been deaf to their pleas as Kane's soldiers had slaughtered every man, woman, and child in one of their stinking towns. Kane had sent a few skulls to each and every other orcish tribe, and kept a few for his own; their warlord's in particular would serve as an excellent cup for his collection. It was a waste of lives, and Kane hardly enjoyed such slaughter, but the Orcs would not respect anything but brutality. Suffice it to say, the raids had stopped. Kane smiled, and thought it good.[PARAGRAPH:1]Meanwhile, Kane suspected the Svartalfar had planted yet another agent in his harem... they seemed to have an unusually large number of pretty women. He'd feed her some minor misinformation, and see if the Svartalfar acted on it. Sadly, after what happened to the first one he'd captured alive, the Svartalfar agents had taken to committing suicide upon discovery, or even suspicion of such. A shame, seeing how much fun he'd had with that first one. Kane was known to be far gentler to his women them most of the Malakim warlords, but when this wench had awoken the beast within him... Kane smiled, and thought it good.[PARAGRAPH:1]A messenger burst in. "My lord, word from Golden Leane." Kane regretted not burning that place to the ground. Technically, the man should have announced himself, and not charged in as he had, but Kane knew better then to do anything foolish. He waved off his attendants and gestured for the man to continue. "They've revolted. Again. They're lead by... an elf, of all things, name Varn Gosam." "Kill Varn. Is that so hard?" The messenger paused. Kane gussed from the look on the man's face that the answer was "yes." "I'll arrange for one of the elite to deal with this man. Tell me about him." The messenger did... and as he listened to the tales, Kane stopped smiling.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Kane guardò il bottino della sua ultima conquista, ammucchiato in maniera impressionante nella sua sala del trono. Oro, argento, gioieli, e più belle di tutto il resto, armi e armature... i re demoni, i miserabili Calabim, avevano iniziato un'altra schermaglia con il suo popolo, ed erano stati schiacciati dalla potenza dell'impero Malakim. Rimanevano arroganti, Alexis e Flauros, nonostante loro rimanevano in vita solo perché Kane cosi voleva. Erano utili per disfarsi di signori della guerra minori. Ma ogni tanto, come adesso, cercavano di attaccarlo. Come sempre fallivano. Il che dava a Kane una scusa per inviare razziatori per conto suo, per ricordargli il loro posto nel mondo; i suoi animaletti, i suoi mastini, nulla di più Kane sorrise, e pensò fosse bene.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ma non era tutto. Una tribù minore di orchi aveva cercato di sfidare la sua gloria. La loro preziosa "Bhall" era stata sorda alle loro suppliche mentre i soldati di Kane uccidevano ogni orco, orchessa e orchetto in una delle loro schifose città. Kane aveva spedito qualche teschio ad ogni altra tribù orchesca, e ne tennè qualcuno per se; quella del loro signore della guerra in particolare sarebbe stata un'eccellente coppa per la sua collezione. Era uno spreco di vite, e a Kane non piacevano tali massacri, ma gli Orchi non avrebbero rispettato nulla oltre alla brutalità. A dimostrazione di questo le incursioni cessarono. Kane sorrise, e pensò che fosse bene.[PARAGRAPH:1]Nel frattempo, Kane sospettava che gli Svartalfar avessero infiltrato un'altro agente nel suo harem... sembravano avere un'insolito gran numero di belle donne. Gli aveva dato qualche falsa informazione minore e aspettava di vedere se gli Svartalfar avrebbero agito basandosi su esse. Purtroppo dopo quello che è successo alla prima che aveva catturato viva le agenti Svartalfar avevano iniziato a suicidarsi quando scoperte, o anche solo se sospettavano di esserlo. Un peccato, visto quanto divertimento aveva avuto con la prima. Kane era conosciuto per essere molto più gentile con le sue donne di quanto non fossero gli altri signori della guerra Malakim, ma quando quella ragazza aveva risvegliato la bestia che è in lui... Kane sorrise, e pensò fosse bene.[PARAGRAPH:1]Un messaggero irruppé. "Mio signore, un messaggio da Golden Leane." Kane rimpianse di non aver raso al suolo quel posto. Tecnicamente, il messaggero si sarebbe dovuto annunciare, e non entrare come ha fatto, ma Kane sapeva bene che non era una cosa da prendere alla leggera. Allontanò con un gesto i servitori e sempre con un gesto disse al messaggero di continuare. "Si sono ribellati. Di nuovo. Sono guidati da... un'elfo, il cui nome è Varn Gosam." "Uccidete Varn. È cosi difficile?" Il messaggero fece una pausa. Kane intuì dalla faccia che fece il messaggero che la risposta fosse "si". "Manderò uno dell'elite ad occuparsi di questo elfo. Parlami di lui". Il messaggero cosi fece... e, mentre ascoltava i racconti, Kane smise di sorridere.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Kane looked upon the spoils of his latest conquest, piled impressively in his throne room. Gold and silver, jewels, and most beautiful of all, weapons and armor... the demon-kings, the wretched Calabim, had started another skirmish with his people, and been beaten back by the might of the Malakim empire. They were arrogant, Alexis and Flauros, even though they continued existing only because Kane whimmed it. They were a useful way to dispose of lesser warlords. But every so often, as now, they tried to attack him. As ever, they failed. Which gave Kane an excuse to send raiding parties of his own, to remind them of their place in the world; his pets, his hounds, nothing more Kane smiled, and thought it good.[PARAGRAPH:1]But that was not all. A minor tribe of orcs had attempted to defy his glory. Their precious "Bhall" had been deaf to their pleas as Kane's soldiers had slaughtered every man, woman, and child in one of their stinking towns. Kane had sent a few skulls to each and every other orcish tribe, and kept a few for his own; their warlord's in particular would serve as an excellent cup for his collection. It was a waste of lives, and Kane hardly enjoyed such slaughter, but the Orcs would not respect anything but brutality. Suffice it to say, the raids had stopped. Kane smiled, and thought it good.[PARAGRAPH:1]Meanwhile, Kane suspected the Svartalfar had planted yet another agent in his harem... they seemed to have an unusually large number of pretty women. He'd feed her some minor misinformation, and see if the Svartalfar acted on it. Sadly, after what happened to the first one he'd captured alive, the Svartalfar agents had taken to committing suicide upon discovery, or even suspicion of such. A shame, seeing how much fun he'd had with that first one. Kane was known to be far gentler to his women them most of the Malakim warlords, but when this wench had awoken the beast within him... Kane smiled, and thought it good.[PARAGRAPH:1]A messenger burst in. "My lord, word from Golden Leane." Kane regretted not burning that place to the ground. Technically, the man should have announced himself, and not charged in as he had, but Kane knew better then to do anything foolish. He waved off his attendants and gestured for the man to continue. "They've revolted. Again. They're lead by... an elf, of all things, name Varn Gosam." "Kill Varn. Is that so hard?" The messenger paused. Kane gussed from the look on the man's face that the answer was "yes." "I'll arrange for one of the elite to deal with this man. Tell me about him." The messenger did... and as he listened to the tales, Kane stopped smiling.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_VARN</Tag>
		<English>Varn Gosam</English>
		<French>Varn Gosam</French>
		<German>Varn Gosam</German>
		<Italian>Varn Gosam</Italian>
		<Spanish>Varn Gosam</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_VARN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Elven servants of Arawn fled his domain into the Shadowed Vale, a valley kept perpetually in darkness by a thick mist that obscured the border between the Vale and Creation. In the 15th year of the 4th age, a young Auric Ulvin and his companions were trapped in the vale and accused of stealing from the elves. Varn, a prince of the elves, believed Ulvin's denials, although his fellow elves did not. When Varn tried to sneak them out of the vale, his brother caught them and an elven warband was sent to catch and kill the companions. Auric was just growing into his affinity for magic at the time and as the elven warband set upon them he reached through the vale for any source of magic he could find to use. The faint source he felt through it was the Sun, when he pulled its power through he destroyed the barrier between the worlds and flooded the perpetually dark vale with light. The elvish warband was blinded, but Varn underwent a transformation, he saw Lugus in that light and was rewarded for his commitment to the truth (by trying to save the children) by becoming a priest of Lugus. He fled from the Vale into the cold wastes of Creation on whatever path Lugus had planned for him.</English>
		<French>Les servants elfes d'Arawn ont fui son domaine pour la Vallée des Ombres, une vallée plongée perpétuellement dans l'obscurité par un brouillard épais, qui obscurcit la frontière entre la Vallée et Création. Dans la 15ème année du 4ème âge, le jeune Auric Ulvin et ses compagnons furent pris au piège dans la vallée et accusés d'avoir volé les elfes. Varn, un prince elfe, crut les dénégations d'Ulvin au contraire de ses semblables. Quand Varn tenta de les exfiltrer de la vallée, son frère les surprit et un groupe d'elfes fut envoyé pour les attraper et les tuer. Auric commençait juste à apprivoiser la magie en ce temps là, et tandis que les elfes les pourchassaient, il recherchait dans la vallée n'importe quelle source de magie utilisable. La seule maigre source qu'il trouva était le Soleil, et lorsqu'il fit appel à son pouvoir i lbrisa la barrière entre les mondes, inondant de lumière la vallée éternellement sombre. Le groupe d'elfes fut aveuglé mais Varn en fut transformé :  il avait vu Lugus dans cette lumière et fut récompensé pour son engagement pour la vérité (en essayent de sauver ces enfants) en devenant prêtre de Lugus. Il s'enfuit de la Vallée pour rejoindre les désolations glacées de Création et suivre la voie que Lugus avait tracée pour lui.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Elfenbediensteten von Arawn flohen in das Tal der Schatten, ein Tal welches Permanent in einen dicken allgegenwärtigen Nebel gehüllt ist und die Grenze zwischen dem Tal und der Schöpfung immer mehr verschwimmen lässt. Im Jahre 15 des 4. Zeitalters, waren ein Junger Auric Ulvin und seine ebenfalls kinderlichen Freunde in diesem Tal eingeschlossen und wurden von den Elfen des Tales des stehlens bezichtigt. Varn, ein Prinz der Elfen, schenkte Ulvin's ausreden, im Gegensatz zu den ihm Untergebenen Elfen, glauben. Als Varn versuchte Ulvin und seine treuen Freunde aus dem Tal hinaus zu befördern, durchkreuzte sein Bruder die Bemühungen und setzte den Prinz fest. Er schickte eine Gruppe von Elfenkriegern aus um Auric und die restlichen Kinder zu fangen und zu töten. Zu dieser Zeit jedoch, wuchs Ulvins Begeisterung für die Magie immer mehr und so streifte er durch das Tal, unentwegt auf der Suche nach einer Quelle der Magie, als der Verband aus Elfenkriegern seine Gruppe erreichte. Ulvin konnte einzig eine Schwache Quelle der Magie fühlen, es war die Sonne. Als er begann ihre Macht und Stärke freizusetzen, zerstörte er die Weltenbarriere und flutete das Tal mit grellem Licht, dem Licht der Sonne. Zwar waren die Elfenkrieger geblendet, doch nicht so Varn. Varn unterzog sich einer Wandlung, er sah Lugus im Licht und wurde für seinen Einsatz für die Wahrheit und den Versuch die Kinder zu Retten belohnt. Er wurde zur Belohnung ein Priester des Lugus und floh aus dem Tal, in die Kalte Wüste der Schöpfung, wo immer Lugus in hingeleiten möge.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Dei servitori elfici di Arawn fuggirono dal suo reame giungendo nella Valle Adombrata, una valle perennemente al buio per via di una fitta nebbia che oscurava il confine tra la valle e la Creazione. Nel 15° anno della 4° era, un giovane Auric Ulvin e i suoi compagni rimasero intrappolati nella valle e accusati di furto dagli elfi che ci abitavano. Varn, un principe di quegli elfi, credeva a Ulvin quando rigettava le accuse, sebbene gli altri elfi non erano dello stesso parere. Quando Varn cercò di farli fuggire dalla valle fu visto dal fratello e una squadra di elfi fu inviata a ucciderli. Auric stava ancora sviluppando la sua affinità alla magia e quando la squadra elfica li raggiunse lui cercò qualsiasi fonte di magia che avrebbe potuto usare. La debole fonte che percepì fu il Sole, e, nell'attingere da esso potere, distrusse la barriera tra i mondi e inondò la valle di luce. La squadra elfica rimase accecata, mentre Varn subì una trasformazione, lui vide Lugus in quella luce e fù ricompensato per la sua dedizione alla verità (avendo cercato di salvare i bambini) divenendo un sacerdote di Lugus. In seguito scappò dalla Valle andando nelle fredde distese della Creazione seguendo qualsiasi strada che Lugus aveva pianificato per lui.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Elven servants of Arawn fled his domain into the Shadowed Vale, a valley kept perpetually in darkness by a thick mist that obscured the border between the Vale and Creation. In the 15th year of the 4th age, a young Auric Ulvin and his companions were trapped in the vale and accused of stealing from the elves. Varn, a prince of the elves, believed Ulvin's denials, although his fellow elves did not. When Varn tried to sneak them out of the vale, his brother caught them and an elven warband was sent to catch and kill the companions. Auric was just growing into his affinity for magic at the time and as the elven warband set upon them he reached through the vale for any source of magic he could find to use. The faint source he felt through it was the Sun, when he pulled its power through he destroyed the barrier between the worlds and flooded the perpetually dark vale with light. The elvish warband was blinded, but Varn underwent a transformation, he saw Lugus in that light and was rewarded for his commitment to the truth (by trying to save the children) by becoming a priest of Lugus. He fled from the Vale into the cold wastes of Creation on whatever path Lugus had planned for him.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RELIGIOUS_FERVOR</Tag>
		<English>Religious Fervor</English>
		<French>Ferveur Religieuse</French>
		<German>Religiöser Eifer</German>
		<Italian>Fervore Religioso</Italian>
		<Spanish>Religious Fervor</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RELIGIOUS_FERVOR_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Creates a Priest in every city with your state religion that starts with 1XP for every city you have with your state religion </English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Crée un prêtre dans chacune de vos villes avec votre religion d'état, qui commencent avec un Exp pour chacune des villes avec cette religion</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erschafft einen Priester in jeder Stadt mit deiner Staatsreligion, Priester starten mit 1 EP für jede Stadt in der die Staatsreligion verbreitet ist</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Crea un sacerdote in ogni città che abbia la tua religione di stato che iniziano con 1 punto esperienza per ogni città che possiedi che abbia la tua religione di stato</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Creates a priest in every city with your state religion, priests start with 1 xp for every city you have with your state religion</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DESERT_SHRINE</Tag>
		<English>Desert Shrine</English>
		<French>Sanctuaire du désert</French>
		<German>Wüstenschrein</German>
		<Italian>Santuario del Deserto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Desert Shrine</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR</Tag>
		<English>Mirrored Pylon</English>
		<French>Pylône de Miroirs</French>
		<German>Verspiegelter Pylone</German>
		<Italian>Pilone Specchiato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mirrored Pylon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MALAKIM_SHRINE_MIRROR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>What is Enlightenment, my son? There are many definitions, take your pick.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The strength needed to do what must be done, no matter the cost to yourself." -From the Code of Junil[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The wisdom to forgive those who have transgressed, and show mercy to those who have earned it." -From the Empyrean[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The virtues of the Earthmother: hard work, diligence, perseverance." -From the Tablets of Bambur[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"To see the world as it is, and accept both its glories and terrors as equally necessary." -From the Song of Autumn[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The knowledge of all the wonderful little dark nooks and crannies in men's hearts... including, of course, your own." -From the Council of Esus[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"To see the world, not covered in all the little lies men tell themselves in order to preserve their precious 'sanity,' but as it truly is." -From the Necronomicon[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The strength needed to do what must be done, no matter the cost to others." -From the Ashen Veil </English>
		<French>Qu'est ce que l'Illumination, mon fils ? Il existe de nombreuses définitions, fais ton choix.[PARAGRAPH:2]"La force nécessaire pour faire ce qui doit être fait, quel qu'en soit le coût personnel." - Du code de Junil[PARAGRAPH:2]"La sagesse de pardonner aux pêcheurs, et faire preuve de pitié envers ceux qui l'ont gagnée." - De l'Empiréen[PARAGRAPH:2]"Les qualités de la Terre Mère : travail acharné, obéissance, persévérance." - Des tablettes de Bambur[PARAGRAPH:2]"De voir le monde tel qu'il est, et en accepter ses gloires et ses terreurs comme autant nécessaires." - Du Chant de l'Automne[PARAGRAPH:2]"La connaissance de tous ces merveilleux coins et recoins sombres dans le c&#156;ur des hommes, y compris bien sûr le votre." - Du Conseil d'Esus[PARAGRAPH:2]"Afin de voir le monde tel qu'il est réellement, et non recouvert de tous ces petits mensonges que les hommes se racontent afin de préserver leur précieuse santé mentale." - Du Nécronomicon[PARAGRAPH:2]"La force de faire ce qui doit être fait, quel qu'en soit le coût pour les autres." - Du Voile Cendré</French>
		<German>What is Enlightenment, my son? There are many definitions, take your pick.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The strength needed to do what must be done, no matter the cost to yourself." -From the Code of Junil[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The wisdom to forgive those who have transgressed, and show mercy to those who have earned it." -From the Empyrean[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The virtues of the Earthmother: hard work, diligence, perseverance." -From the Tablets of Bambur[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"To see the world as it is, and accept both its glories and terrors as equally necessary." -From the Song of Autumn[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The knowledge of all the wonderful little dark nooks and crannies in men's hearts... including, of course, your own." -From the Council of Esus[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"To see the world, not covered in all the little lies men tell themselves in order to preserve their precious 'sanity,' but as it truly is." -From the Necronomicon[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The strength needed to do what must be done, no matter the cost to others." -From the Ashen Veil </German>
		<Italian>Cos'è l'Illuminazione, figlio mio? Ci sono molte definizioni, scegli la tua.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"La forza necessaria per fare ciò che dev'essere fatto, non importa il prezzo che dovrai pagare". -Dal Codice di Junil[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"La saggezza per perdonare coloro che hanno trasgredito, ed essere clemente con chi se lo merita". -Dall'Empireo[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Le virtù della Madre Terra: duro lavoro, rigore, perseveranza". -Dalle Tavole di Bambur[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Vedere il mondo cosi come è, e accettarne sia le glorie che gli orrori come equamente necessari". -Dalla Canzone dell'Autunno[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"La conoscenza di tutte le piccole fessure e recessi oscuri presenti nel cuore degli uomini... inclusi, ovviamente, i tuoi". -Dal Concilio di Esus[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Nel vedere il mondo, non coperto da tutte le piccole menzogne che gli uomini si dicono per mantenere la loro preziosa 'sanità', ma per come è realmente". -Dal Necronomicon[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"La forza necessaria per fare ciò che deve essere fatto, non importa il prezzo da pagare per gli altri". -Dal Velo Cinereo</Italian>
		<Spanish>What is Enlightenment, my son? There are many definitions, take your pick.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The strength needed to do what must be done, no matter the cost to yourself." -From the Code of Junil[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The wisdom to forgive those who have transgressed, and show mercy to those who have earned it." -From the Empyrean[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The virtues of the Earthmother: hard work, diligence, perseverance." -From the Tablets of Bambur[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"To see the world as it is, and accept both its glories and terrors as equally necessary." -From the Song of Autumn[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The knowledge of all the wonderful little dark nooks and crannies in men's hearts... including, of course, your own." -From the Council of Esus[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"To see the world, not covered in all the little lies men tell themselves in order to preserve their precious 'sanity,' but as it truly is." -From the Necronomicon[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"The strength needed to do what must be done, no matter the cost to others." -From the Ashen Veil </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MALAKIM_TEMPLE_MIRROR</Tag>
		<English>Resplendent Minaret</English>
		<French>Minaret Resplendissant</French>
		<German>Prächtiges Minarett</German>
		<Italian>Minareto Risplendente</Italian>
		<Spanish>Resplendent Minaret</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_MALAKIM</Tag>
		<English>Malakim Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Malakim</French>
		<German>Palast der Malakim</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo dei Malakim</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Malakim</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STABLE_CAMEL</Tag>
		<English>Caravanserai</English>
		<French>Caravansérail</French>
		<German>Kamelstall</German>
		<Italian>Caravanserraglio</Italian>
		<Spanish>Camel Stable</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STABLE_CAMEL_PEDIA</tag>
		<English>The Caravanserai allows a city to make use of Camels rather than Horses. It allows Mounted units access to the Camel Rider promotions, and cannot be built in the same city as a Stable.</English>
		<French>Le Caravansérail permet à une ville d'utiliser des Chameaux plutôt que des Chevaux. Il permet aux unités montées d'accéder aux promotions de Chevaucheur de Chameau, et ne peut être construit dans la même ville que des Écuries.</French>
		<German>The Camel Stable allows a city to make use of Camels rather than Horses. It allows Mounted units access to the Camel Rider promotions, and cannot be built in the same city as a Stable.</German>
		<Italian>Il Caravanserraglio permette alla città di utilizzare i Cammelli al posto dei Cavalli. Permette alle unità montate di accedere alle promozioni Cavalvatore di Cammelli, e non può essere construito nella stessa città in cui è presente una Stalla.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Camel Stable allows a city to make use of Camels rather than Horses. It allows Mounted units access to the Camel Rider promotions, and cannot be built in the same city as a Stable.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MALAKIM_MIRROR</Tag>
		<English>Finally, your armies have reached the Mirror of Heaven. You received an epiphany here long ago, and have returned to seek guidance once again.</English>
		<French>Finalement, vos armées ont atteint le Miroir du Paradis. Ici, vous aviez reçu une Épiphanie il y a bien longtemps, et maintenant vous voilà de retour à la recherche de conseils.</French>
		<German>Endlich, Eure Armeen haben den Himmelspiegel erreicht. Hier habt Ihr vor langen Zeiten eine Erleuchtung gehabt, und seid nun zurückgekehrt, um erneut Hilfe zu erhalten.</German>
		<Italian>Infine le tue armate hanno raggiunto lo Specchio del Cielo. Hai ricevuto un'illuminazione qui molto tempo fa, e sei tornato di nuovo per cercare ancora consiglio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Finally, your armies have reached the Mirror of Heaven. You received an epiphany here long ago, and have returned to seek guidance once again.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MALAKIM_MIRROR_1</Tag>
		<English>There is nothing we can do here.</English>
		<French>Il n'y a plus rien à faire ici.</French>
		<German>Wir können hier leider nichts mehr tun.</German>
		<Italian>Non c'è nulla che possiamo fare qui.</Italian>
		<Spanish>There is nothing we can do here.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MALAKIM_MIRROR_2</Tag>
		<English>A holy man, inspired by this sacred place, has offered to join our cause.</English>
		<French>Un Saint Homme, inspiré par ce lieu sacré a offert de se joindre à votre cause.</French>
		<German>Ein heiliger Mann wartet neben dem Himmelspiegel und hat angeboten, sich Euch anzuschließen. Der Spiegel wollte es so.</German>
		<Italian>Un santone, ispirato da questo luogo sacro, si è offerto di unirsi alla nostra causa.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A holy man, inspired by this sacred place, has offered to join our cause.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MALAKIM_MIRROR_2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]receive a Heroic Lightbringer.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Recevoir un Porteur de Lumière Héroïque.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erhalte einen "Heldenhaften Lichtbringer"</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Ricevi un Portatore di Luce Eroico.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]receive a Heroic Lightbringer.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MALAKIM_MIRROR_3</Tag>
		<English>Our people will benefit from the relics recovered from this site.</English>
		<French>Notre peuple profitera des reliques trouvées sur ce site.</French>
		<German>Unser Volk wird von den Artefakten dieses Ortes profitieren.</German>
		<Italian>Il nostro popolo beneficierà delle reliquie recuperate da questo posto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Our people will benefit from the relics recovered from this site.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MALAKIM_MIRROR_3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Creates a 'Resplendent Minaret' in your Capital, granting Conviction to all Disciple units.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Crée un "Minaret Resplendissant" dans votre Capitale, conférant la promotion Conviction à tous vos Disciples.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erschafft ein 'Prächtiges Minarett' in der Hauptstadt, bringt allen geweihten Einheiten '&#220;berzeugung'.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Crea un 'Minareto Risplendente' nella tua capitale, che fornisce la promozione Convinzione a tutte le unità Discepoli.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Creates a 'Resplendent Minaret' in your Capital, granting Conviction to all Disciple units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_CAMEL_ARCHER</Tag>
		<English>Camel Archer</English>
		<French>Archer Méhariste</French>
		<German>Kamelbogenschütze</German>
		<Italian>Arciere Cammellato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Camel Archer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_CAMEL_RIDER</Tag>
		<English>Camel Rider</English>
		<French>Méhariste</French>
		<German>Kamelreiter</German>
		<Italian>Cavalcatore di Cammelli</Italian>
		<Spanish>Camel Rider</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_CAMEL_KNIGHT</Tag>
		<English>Camel Knight</English>
		<French>Chevalier Méhariste</French>
		<German>Kamelritter</German>
		<Italian>Cavaliere Cammellato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Camel Knight</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_DESERT_STEALTH</Tag>
		<English>Desert Stealth</English>
		<French>Camouflage Désertique</French>
		<German>Wüstentarnung</German>
		<Italian>Mimetizzarsi nel Deserto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Desert Stealth</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_DUNESPEAK</Tag>
		<English>Dunespeak</English>
		<French>Connaissance du Désert</French>
		<German>Sprecher der Düne</German>
		<Italian>Conoscenza del Deserto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dunespeak</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_STRONG_MIRROR</Tag>
		<English>Conviction</English>
		<French>Conviction</French>
		<German>&#220;berzeugung</German>
		<Italian>Convinzione</Italian>
		<Spanish>Conviction</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_OASIS</Tag>
		<English>Lugus' Gift</English>
		<French>Don de Lugus</French>
		<German>Lugus' Gabe</German>
		<Italian>Dono di Lugus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lugus' Gift</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_OASIS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Creates an Oasis. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires at least 5 tiles between Oases.  [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires all surrounding tiles be desert, coast, or ocean.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Crée une oasis.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requiert au moins 5 cases entre chaque oasis.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requiert que toutes les cases environnantes soient du désert, des côtes ou de l'océan.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erschafft eine Oase[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Erfordert mindestens 5 Felder Abstand zwischen Oasen[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Alle umliegenden Felder müssen Wüste, Küste oder Ozean sein</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Crea un'Oasi. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Richiede almeno 5 caselle di distanza da altre Oasi.  [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Richiede che le caselle circostanti siano di deserto, costa o oceano.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Creates an Oasis. [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires at least 5 tiles between Oases.  [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Requires all surrounding tiles be desert, coast, or ocean.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_OASIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>After generations in the desert, the Malakim have become adept at finding sources of water.</English>
		<French>Après avec vécu dans le désert pendant de nombreuses générations, les Malakims sont devenus spécialistes de la découverte de sources d'eau.</French>
		<German>After generations in the desert, the Malakim have become adept at finding sources of water.</German>
		<Italian>Avendo vissuto per generazioni nel deserto i Malakim sono diventati molto abili a trovare fonti d'acqua.</Italian>
		<Spanish>After generations in the desert, the Malakim have become adept at finding sources of water.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DESERTPEOPLE</Tag>
		<English>Dunespeakers</English>
		<French>Natifs du désert</French>
		<German>Wüstenmenschen</German>
		<Italian>Popolo del Deserto</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los habitantes del desierto</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DESERTPEOPLE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Sand has a nasty tendency to get into places it should not get. Myself, I'll just stay in our cities..."[NEWLINE][BOLD]Vizi, Amurite Wizard[\BOLD]</English>
		<French>"Le sable a une tendance exaspérante à s'infiltrer là où il ne devrait pas. Personnellement, je ne quitterai pas nos villes..."[NEWLINE][BOLD]Vizi, Mage Amurite</French>
		<German>"Sand has a nasty tendency to get into places it should not get. Myself, I'll just stay in our cities..."[NEWLINE][BOLD]Vizi, Amurite Wizard[\BOLD]</German>
		<Italian>"La sabbia ha la brutta tendenza di andare in posti in cui non dovrebbe. Io, semplicemente, rimarrò nelle nostre città..."[NEWLINE][BOLD]Vizi, Stregone Amurite[\BOLD]</Italian>
		<Spanish>"Sand has a nasty tendency to get into places it should not get. Myself, I'll just stay in our cities..."[NEWLINE][BOLD]Vizi, Amurite Wizard[\BOLD]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DESERTPEOPLE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Malakim starting technology.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]No roads required in arid terrain</English>
		<French>La technologie de départ des Malakims[NEWLINE]Sur les cases de désert, les Malakim n'ont pas besoin de route.</French>
		<German>The Malakim starting technology.[NEWLINE]No roads required in arid terrain</German>
		<Italian>La tecnologia iniziale dei Malakim.[NEWLINE]Non sono richeste strade nei terreni aridi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Malakim starting technology.[NEWLINE]No roads required in arid terrain</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ANUBIS</Tag>
		<English>Anubite</English>
		<French>Anubite</French>
		<German>Anubite</German>
		<Italian>Anubita</Italian>
		<Spanish>Anubite</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ANUBIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Anubites are one of the last vestiges of Malakim civilization from the days before Varn Gosam and the worship of Lugus. Cloaked in the shadows of the harsh desert night, an Anubite is dedicated to two things - the worship of the Malakim's long-forgotten pagan gods, and the defense of her peoples in the most savage manner possible. While other troops may wish to stand and fight, the Anubites charge in with their claw-like blades, carving up enemy units and dissapearing again into the deserts.</English>
		<French>Les Anubites sont parmi les derniers vestiges de la civilisation Malakim précédant Varn Gosam et le culte de Lugus. Dissimulé dans les ombres de la rude nuit désertique, l'Anubite se consacre à deux choses : le culte des antiques dieux malakims païens oubliés, et la défense des leurs de la manière la plus sauvage possible. Tandis que d'autres pourraient souhaiter se mettre en formation et se battre, les Anubites foncent dans la mélée avec leur épées en forme de griffes, déchiquettant leurs adversaires et disparaissant à nouveau dans les déserts.</French>
		<German>Anubites are one of the last vestiges of Malakim civilization from the days before Varn Gosam and the worship of Lugus. Cloaked in the shadows of the harsh desert night, an Anubite is dedicated to two things - the worship of the Malakim's long-forgotten pagan gods, and the defense of her peoples in the most savage manner possible. While other troops may wish to stand and fight, the Anubites charge in with their claw-like blades, carving up enemy units and dissapearing again into the deserts.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Anubiti sono una delle ultime vestigia della civiltà Malakim prima dell'arrivo di Varn Gosam e della venerazione di Lugus. Avvolto dalle ombre delle rigide notti del deserto, un'Anubita si dedica a due cose, la venerazione degli dei pagani Malakim da tempo dimenticati, e alla difesa del suo popolo nella maniera più selvaggia possibile. Mentre altri combattenti preferirebbero mantenere la posizione, gli Anubiti caricano il nemico con le loro lame simili ad artigli, eliminando intere unità nemiche prima di scomparire di nuovo nel deserto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Anubites are one of the last vestiges of Malakim civilization from the days before Varn Gosam and the worship of Lugus. Cloaked in the shadows of the harsh desert night, an Anubite is dedicated to two things - the worship of the Malakim's long-forgotten pagan gods, and the defense of her peoples in the most savage manner possible. While other troops may wish to stand and fight, the Anubites charge in with their claw-like blades, carving up enemy units and dissapearing again into the deserts.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ANUBIS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Anubites replace Berserkers for the Malakim. While doing less overall damage they have a much better defensive rating, and have a high withdrawal rate and many first strikes, allowing them to strike repeatedly, wearing down any enemy foolish enough to come near.</English>
		<French>Les Anubites remplacent les Berserkers pour les Malakim. Bien qu'ils infligent globalement moins de dégâts, ils ont globalement de bien meilleurs capacités défensives, et ont de fortes chances de repli et de nombreuses premières attaques, leur permettant de frapper encore et encore, épuisant n'importe quel ennemi assez fou pour s'approcher.</French>
		<German>Anubites replace Berserkers for the Malakim. While doing less overall damage they have a much better defensive rating, and have a high withdrawal rate and many first strikes, allowing them to strike repeatedly, wearing down any enemy foolish enough to come near.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Anubiti rimpiazzano i Berserker per i Malakim. Sebbene infliggano meno danni possiedono una forza difensiva maggiore, oltre ad un'alta probabilità di ritirarsi, e molti attacchi improvvisi, che gli permettono di colpire ripetutamente, abbattendo qualsiasi nemico sia cosi folle da avvicinarglisi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Anubites replace Berserkers for the Malakim. While doing less overall damage they have a much better defensive rating, and have a high withdrawal rate and many first strikes, allowing them to strike repeatedly, wearing down any enemy foolish enough to come near.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ASSASSIN_MALAKIM</Tag>
		<English>Dervish</English>
		<French>Derviche</French>
		<German>Derwisch</German>
		<Italian>Derviscio</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dervish</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ASSASSIN_MALAKIM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Gods Damn the Malakim, and their bastard Dervishes! [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I was part of an expedition deep into Malakim lands... All went well until we camped. The very instant we relaxed, the Dervishes were upon us. They fight like Demons, I tell you! [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Of the entire unit, only I made it out alive... Not because I beat them, no. They wanted me to spread their myth, and spread it I shall." - Unknown Bloodpet</English>
		<French>"Maudits soient ces Malakims, et leur horribles Dervishs ![PARAGRAPH:2]J'ai fait partie d'une expédition loin en territoire malakim... Tout allait bien jusqu'à ce que nous montions le campement. À l'instant même où nous nous relachions notre attention, les Dervishs nous tombaient dessus. Ils se battent comme des Démons, je vous jure ! [PARAGRAPH:2]De tous, je fus le seul survivant... Pas parce que je les ai vaincus, non. Ils voulaient que je répande leur mythe, et c'est ce que je fais." - Familier Sanguin inconnu</French>
		<German>"Gods Damn the Malakim, and their bastard Dervishes! [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I was part of an expedition deep into Malakim lands... All went well until we camped. The very instant we relaxed, the Dervishes were upon us. They fight like Demons, I tell you! [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Of the entire unit, only I made it out alive... Not because I beat them, no. They wanted me to spread their myth, and spread it I shall." - Unknown Bloodpet</German>
		<Italian>"Gli dei maledicano i Malakim, e i loro maledetti Dervisci! [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Facevo parte di una spedizione nel profondo delle terre dei Malakim... Tutto è andato bene fino a quando ci siamo accampati. Nell'esatto istante in cui ci siamo rilassati i Dervisci ci sono saltati addosso. Combattono come Demoni, ti dico! [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Dell'intera unità solo io ne sono uscito vivo... Non perché li ho battuti, no. Volevano che io spargessi il loro mito, e cosi farò." - Famiglio sconosciuto</Italian>
		<Spanish>"Gods Damn the Malakim, and their bastard Dervishes! [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I was part of an expedition deep into Malakim lands... All went well until we camped. The very instant we relaxed, the Dervishes were upon us. They fight like Demons, I tell you! [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Of the entire unit, only I made it out alive... Not because I beat them, no. They wanted me to spread their myth, and spread it I shall." - Unknown Bloodpet</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ASSASSIN_MALAKIM_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Unlike the typical Shadow, the Dervish does not require you to worship Esus. In addition, it is stronger, with Fire damage rather than poison and the potential for vast strength gain through a Sun mana affinity. In exchange for this power, the Dervish is tied to the Desert, unable to become invisible in any other terrain, and must be upgraded from a level 6 Assassin or Champion.</English>
		<French>Contrairement à l'Ombre classique, le Dervish ne nécessite pas l'adoption du conseil d'Esus. De plus, il est plus puissant, grâce des dégâts de Feu plutôt que de Poison et un gain potentiel énorme via son affinité au mana de Soleil. En contrepartie, le Dervish est lié au Désert, incapable de devenir invisible sur tout autre terrain, et doit être amélioré à partir d'un Assassin ou un Champion de niveau 6 ou plus.</French>
		<German>Unlike the typical Shadow, the Dervish does not require you to worship Esus. In addition, it is stronger, with Fire damage rather than poison and the potential for vast strength gain through a Sun mana affinity. In exchange for this power, the Dervish is tied to the Desert, unable to become invisible in any other terrain, and must be upgraded from a level 6 Assassin or Champion.</German>
		<Italian>Diversamente dalle tipiche Ombre, il Derviscio non richede la venerazione di Esus. In aggiunta è più forte, con danno da Fuoco al posto di quello da Veleno e la possibilità di guadagnare forza attraverso l'affinità al mana del Sole. In cambio di questo potere il Derviscio è legato al deserto, incapace di diventare invisibile in qualsiasi altro terreno, e si deve ottenere migliorando un Assassino o Campione di livello 6 o più.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Unlike the typical Shadow, the Dervish does not require you to worship Esus. In addition, it is stronger, with Fire damage rather than poison and the potential for vast strength gain through a Sun mana affinity. In exchange for this power, the Dervish is tied to the Desert, unable to become invisible in any other terrain, and must be upgraded from a level 6 Assassin or Champion.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CAMEL_ARCHER</Tag>
		<English>Camel Archer</English>
		<French>Archer Méhariste</French>
		<German>Kamelbogenschütze</German>
		<Italian>Arciere Cammellato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Camel Archer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CAMEL_ARCHER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Long accustomed to dodging abrupt sandstorms before the Malakim began utilizing them for their mounted archers, if a trained camel is matched with a capable rider they can virtually become the sandstorms themselves, arriving in a flurry and disappearing at a moments notice.[TAB]In the Malakim Desert, cavalrymen may ride on either horse or camel. While horses are somewhat easier to train than camels, camels are the obvious choice for forces operating in the deep desert. Tribesmen such as the Bedouin have always been fearsome warriors, and their prowess with bow and arrow from atop a mount has become the stuff of legend.</English>
		<French>Habitués à éviter les tempêtes de sable soudaines bien avant que les malakims commencent à les utiliser pour leurs archers montés, lorsqu'un chameau entraîné est associé à un cavalier doué, ils peuvent devenir les tempêtes de sable elles-mêmes, apparaissant comme des furies et disparaissant en un instant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dans le désert malakim, les cavaliers peuvent chevaucher des chevaux ou des chameaux. Tandis que les chevaux sont plus simples à entraîner que les chameaux, ces derniers sont un choix évident pour des unités opérant dans le désert profond. Les Bédouins ont toujours été des combattants redoutés, et leurs prouesses avec un arc et des flèches depuis une monture sont devenues un sujet de légende.</French>
		<German>Schon lange bevor die Malakim sie domestizierten, waren sie daran gewöhnt, sich vor plötzlich aufkommenden Sandstürmen zu verstecken. Wenn ein trainiertes Kamel mit einem fähigen Reiter zusammengebracht wird, dann kann praktisch selbst zu einem Sandsturm werden, welcher wie ein Windstoß erscheint und jederzeit wieder verschwinden kann.[TAB]In der Wüste der Malakim reitet Kavallerie sowohl auf Pferden als auch auf Kamelen. Während Pferde etwas leichter als Kamele abgerichtet werden können, sind letztere doch ein einleuchtende Wahl für Truppen in der tiefen Wüste. Stammesleute wie die Beduinen waren schon immer furchtlose Krieger, und ihre Kunst im Umgang mit Pfeil und Bogen vom Rücken eines Reittiers herab ist der Stoff von schon vielen Legenden geworden.</German>
		<Italian>Abituati a evitare improvvise tempeste di sabbia ancor prima che i Malakim iniziarono ad usarli come cavalcatura per i loro arcieri, i cammelli se addestrati e affidati a un buon cavaliere, possono diventare come le tempeste di sabbia stesse, arrivando improvvisamente e sparendo poco dopo. Nei deserti Malakim, i cavalieri possono usare sia i cavalli che i cammelli. Sebbene i cavalli siano più facili da addestrare dei cammelli questi ultimi sono oggettivamente la scelta migliore per chi deve agire nel deserto. I popoli tribali come i Beduini sono sempre stati temibili guerrieri, e la loro abilità con l'arco in groppa a una cavalcatura è diventata oggetto di leggende.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Long accustomed to dodging abrupt sandstorms before the Malakim began utilizing them for their mounted archers, if a trained camel is matched with a capable rider they can virtually become the sandstorms themselves, arriving in a flurry and disappearing at a moments notice.[TAB]In the Malakim Desert, cavalrymen may ride on either horse or camel. While horses are somewhat easier to train than camels, camels are the obvious choice for forces operating in the deep desert. Tribesmen such as the Bedouin have always been fearsome warriors, and their prowess with bow and arrow from atop a mount has become the stuff of legend.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CAMEL_ARCHER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Camel Archers are identical to other civilizations Horse Archers except they don't require horses, which are hard to find in the Malakim's deserts.</English>
		<French>Les archers méharistes sont identiques aux archers montés des autres civilisations, mais ne requièrent pas de chevaux, difficiles à trouver dans le désert malakim.</French>
		<German>Camel Archers are identical to other civilizations Horse Archers except they don't require horses, which are hard to find in the Malakim's deserts.</German>
		<Italian>Gli Arcieri Cammellati sono identici agli Arcieri a Cavallo delle altre civiltà tranne per il fatto che non richedono i cavalli, che sono difficili da trovare nei deserti Malakim.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Camel Archers are identical to other civilizations Horse Archers except they don't require horses, which are hard to find in the Malakim's deserts.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HORSEMAN_MALAKIM</Tag>
		<English>Raider</English>
		<French>Raideur</French>
		<German>Räuber</German>
		<Italian>Predone</Italian>
		<Spanish>Raider</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIGHTBRINGER</Tag>
		<English>Lightbringer</English>
		<French>Porteur de Lumière</French>
		<German>Lichtbringer</German>
		<Italian>Portatore di Luce</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lightbringer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIGHTBRINGER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Well before the founding of any of the great polarizing religions in the Age of Rebirth Varn Gosam of the Malakim had already consolidated the multiplicity of prophets in his land into one faith, though before the Revelation of the Mirror there was no formal creed or name for this nascent religion. It would come to be called the Empyrean, and it would change and grow from the tribal faith it was in those days as it spread across Erebus. The Lightbringer was widely used in Malakim lands due to their divine scrying powers in those early days, and retained a ceremonial position well after the ecclesiastics superseded them in importance.</English>
		<French>Well before the founding of any of the great polarizing religions in the Age of Rebirth Varn Gosam of the Malakim had already consolidated the multiplicity of prophets in his land into one faith, though before the Revelation of the Mirror there was no formal creed or name for this nascent religion. It would come to be called the Empyrean, and it would change and grow from the tribal faith it was in those days as it spread across Erebus. The Lightbringer was widely used in Malakim lands due to their divine scrying powers in those early days, and retained a ceremonial position well after the ecclesiastics superseded them in importance.</French>
		<German>Lange vor der Gründung der fünf großen Religionen des Zeitalters der Wiedergeburt hatte Varn Gosam von den Malakim bereits die Vielzahl an Propheten in seinem Land in einem Glauben vereint: die Verehrung von Lugus. Es ist interessant sich auszumalen, ob sich das Zeitalter anders entwickelt hätte, wenn Lugus sich direkt in dessen Konflikte eingemischt hätte. Was auch immer sich ereignet haben mag, Varn Gosam nahm für die Malakim eine der fünf großen Glaubensrichtungen an, obwohl er eifrig die Werte des Herrn des Lichts predigte und bis zu seinem Tod einen Lichtbringer als persönlichen Berater hatte. Trotz allem wurden die Lichtbringer in den Ländern der Malakim aufgrund ihrer göttlichen Wahrnehmung sehr geschätzt.</German>
		<Italian>Molto prima della fondazione di qualsiasi grande religione dell'Era della Rinascita Varn Gosam dei Malakim aveva già consolidato i molteplici profeti nelle sue terre in un'unica fede, anche se prima della Rivelazione dello Specchio essa non aveva alcun credo formale o nome. Sarebbe stata poi chiamata l'Empireo, naque e modificò le fedi tribali presenti mentre si diffondeva su Erebus. I Portatori di Luce furono ampiamente utilizzati nelle terre Malakim per via dei loro poteri divinatori, e mantennerò una posizione cerimoniale anche dopo che gli ecclesiastici li superarono in importanza.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Well before the founding of any of the great polarizing religions in the Age of Rebirth Varn Gosam of the Malakim had already consolidated the multiplicity of prophets in his land into one faith, though before the Revelation of the Mirror there was no formal creed or name for this nascent religion. It would come to be called the Empyrean, and it would change and grow from the tribal faith it was in those days as it spread across Erebus. The Lightbringer was widely used in Malakim lands due to their divine scrying powers in those early days, and retained a ceremonial position well after the ecclesiastics superseded them in importance.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LIGHTBRINGER_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Lightbringers have extra visibility, making them useful for scouting or to prevent barbarian spawning.</English>
		<French>Lightbringers have extra visibility, making them useful for scouting or to prevent barbarian spawning.</French>
		<German>Lichtbringer besitzen zusätzliche Sichtweite, was sie nützlich gegen das Auftauchen von Barbaren macht. Außerdem verfügen sie über die Fähigkeit zu heilen oder eine kleine Menge Kultur zu erzeugen.</German>
		<Italian>I Portatori di Luce hanno una maggiore visibilità, che li rende molto utili per esplorare o per prevenire la generazione di barbari.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lightbringers have extra visibility, making them useful for scouting or to prevent barbarian spawning.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAND_LION</Tag>
		<English>Sand Lion</English>
		<French>Lion des Sables</French>
		<German>Sandlöwe</German>
		<Italian>Leone di Sabbia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sand Lion</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAND_LION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The shifting desert sands themselves, or creatures perfectly designed for them? Either way, these elusive creatures are never seen outside their desert homes unless compelled to travel their by a powerful conjurer or summoner. Whereas interlopers to their harsh realms often suffer delusions in the heat, Sand Lions see with a sight even rangers envy, discerning reality from mirage natural or otherwise. </English>
		<French>Les sables changeants du désert  eux-mêmes, ou des créatures parfaitements adaptées à eux ? N'importe, ces créatures insaisissables ne sont jamais observées hors de leur désert natal, à moins d'être forcées à voyager par un sorcier ou un invocateur puissant. Là où des étrangers à leurs rudes contrées souffrent souvent de mirages dans la chaleur, les Lions des Sables ont une vision à faire palir un ranger, distinguant la réalité et les mirages naturels ou autres.</French>
		<German>Ist es der veränderliche Wüstensand selbst oder ist die Kreatur perfekt dafür geschaffen? Beides. Diese einzigartigen Kreaturen wurden noch nie außerhalb ihrer wüstenhaften Heimat gesehen, es sei denn sie werden gezwungen durch einen mächtigen Beschwörer oder Rufer zu reisen. Wohingegen Eindringlinge in ihren lebensfeindlichen Gebieten oft mit Wahnvorstellungen in der Hitze konfrontiert werden. Sandlöwen sehen mit einer Schärfe um die sie sogar Waldläufer beneiden, sie unterscheiden deutlich zwischen Luftspiegelung und Realität.</German>
		<Italian>Le stesse sabbie dei deserti mutevoli o creature perfettamente adattate ad essi? In entrambi i casi cqueste creature elusive non vengono mai viste fuori dai deserti a meno di essere costrette a viaggiare con un potente evocatore. Mentre gli invasori dei loro reami spesso soffrono di miraggi dovuti al caldo, i Leoni di Sabbia possiedono una vista che persino i ranger invidiano, distinguendo la realtà dai miraggi, naturali o no. </Italian>
		<Spanish>The shifting desert sands themselves, or creatures perfectly designed for them? Either way, these elusive creatures are never seen outside their desert homes unless compelled to travel their by a powerful conjurer or summoner. Whereas interlopers to their harsh realms often suffer delusions in the heat, Sand Lions see with a sight even rangers envy, discerning reality from mirage natural or otherwise. </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAND_LION_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Sand Lions can only be summoned by Malakim Mages, and only on desert tiles. Despite those restrictions, when they are summoned they are powerful attackers with a high movement that allow them to surprise victims.</English>
		<French>Les Lions des Sables ne peuvent être invoqués que par des Mages malakims, et uniquement sur des cases de désert. Malgré ces restrictions, quand ils sont invoqués ce sont des attaquants puissants et mobiles qui leur permet de surprendre leurs victimes.</French>
		<German>Sand Lions can only be summoned by Malakim Mages, and only on desert tiles. Despite those restrictions, when they are summoned they are powerful attackers with a high movement that allow them to surprise victims.</German>
		<Italian>I Leoni di Sabbia possono essere evocati solo dai Maghi Malakim, e solo su caselle di deserto. Nonostante queste restrizioni, una volta evocati sono dei potenti attaccanti con molti punti movimento che gli permettono di sorprendere le loro vittime.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sand Lions can only be summoned by Malakim Mages, and only on desert tiles. Despite those restrictions, when they are summoned they are powerful attackers with a high movement that allow them to surprise victims.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TEUTORIX</Tag>
		<English>Teutorix</English>
		<French>Teutorix</French>
		<German>Teutorix</German>
		<Italian>Teutorix</Italian>
		<Spanish>Teutorix</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WORKER_MALAKIM</Tag>
		<English>Bedouin</English>
		<French>Bédouin</French>
		<German>Beduine</German>
		<Italian>Beduino</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bedouin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>