<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meiers Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - Units -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MECHANOS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Mechanos</English>
		<French>Mechanos</French>
		<German>Reich der Mechanos</German>
		<Italian>Mechanos</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mechanos</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MECHANOS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Mechanos</English>
		<French>Mécanistes</French>
		<German>Mechanos</German>
		<Italian>Mechanos</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mechanos</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MECHANOS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Mechanos</English>
		<French>mécaniste:mécaniste:mécanistes:mécanistes</French>
		<German>Mechanos</German>
		<Italian>Mechanos</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mechanos</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MECHANOS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The beginning of the Mechanos dates back to many years before the Age of Rebirth. With dragons and warring gods causing destruction all over Erebus, some people refused to pay respect to any god. Such beliefs before the Compact were almost inevitable death sentences, as without the protection of the patron god no city would survive more than a few weeks.[PARAGRAPH:1] Much has changed after the signing of the Compact at the Seven Pines. Still, only the most powerful individuals or groups would dare to speak their atheism openly. And even less would survive doing so, as they soon were attacked by joined crusaders of even conflicting faiths. In the eyes of priests, paladins, and eidolons, the only thing worse than followers of the opposite angel were those that refused to take part in the crusades and just wanted to be left alone. [PARAGRAPH:1]Then a second change occured. Just before the Age of Ice, some of the unbelievers came into contact with dwarven engineers and were allowed to learn some of their secrets. This was a key to their survival. Steam engines allowed them not only to heat the caves that sheltered them during Age of Ice, but also to live quite comfortably despite severe weather. This, combined with human curiosity and ingenuity, led them to developing bigger and better engines and perfecting the technology.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was the first sign of a change. While the dwarven ideal is Arete - the perfection in the craft and dedication to the work, Mechanos, as they began to call themselves, adopted a new one: Bigger and Faster. Their machines lack the artistry of the dwarven craft, but ARE big and fast. Confident in their new power, the Mechanos emerged from their caves. Now they are refusing not only to pray to the gods, but also to use any of the aspects of the magic. They regard all spells as tainted with the gods' powers and manifestation of their will. Instead, they use mana nodes as a power source and feed refined mana to so called "mechanical spirits", cryptic beings that inhabit Mechanos machines.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The beginning of the Mechanos dates back to many years before the Age of Rebirth. With dragons and warring gods causing destruction all over Erebus, some people refused to pay respect to any god. Such beliefs before the Compact were almost inevitable death sentences, as without the protection of the patron god no city would survive more than a few weeks.[PARAGRAPH:1] Much has changed after the signing of the Compact at the Seven Pines. Still, only the most powerful individuals or groups would dare to speak their atheism openly. And even less would survive doing so, as they soon were attacked by joined crusaders of even conflicting faiths. In the eyes of priests, paladins, and eidolons, the only thing worse than followers of the opposite angel were those that refused to take part in the crusades and just wanted to be left alone. [PARAGRAPH:1]Then a second change arrived. Just before the Age of Ice, some of the unbelievers come into contact with dwarven engineers and were allowed to learn some of their secrets. This was a key to their survival. Steam engines allowed them not only to heat the caves that sheltered them during Age of Ice, but also to live quite comfortably despite severe weather. This, combined with human curiosity and ingenuity, led them to developing bigger and better engines and perfecting the technology.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was the first sign of a change. While the dwarven ideal is Arete - the perfection in the craft and dedication to the work, Mechanos, as they began to call themselves, adopted a new one: Bigger and Faster. Their machines lack the artistry of the dwarven craft, but ARE big and fast. Confident in their new power, the Mechanos emerged from their caves. Now they are refusing not only to pray to the gods, but also to use any of the aspects of the magic. They regard all spells as tainted with the gods' powers and manifestation of their will. Instead, they use mana nodes as a power source and feed refined mana to so called "mechanical spirits", cryptic beings that inhabit Mechanos machines.</French>
		<German>[TAB]The beginning of the Mechanos dates back to many years before the Age of Rebirth. With dragons and warring gods causing destruction all over Erebus, some people refused to pay respect to any god. Such beliefs before the Compact were almost inevitable death sentences, as without the protection of the patron god no city would survive more than a few weeks.[PARAGRAPH:1] Much has changed after the signing of the Compact at the Seven Pines. Still, only the most powerful individuals or groups would dare to speak their atheism openly. And even less would survive doing so, as they soon were attacked by joined crusaders of even conflicting faiths. In the eyes of priests, paladins, and eidolons, the only thing worse than followers of the opposite angel were those that refused to take part in the crusades and just wanted to be left alone. [PARAGRAPH:1]Then a second change arrived. Just before the Age of Ice, some of the unbelievers come into contact with dwarven engineers and were allowed to learn some of their secrets. This was a key to their survival. Steam engines allowed them not only to heat the caves that sheltered them during Age of Ice, but also to live quite comfortably despite severe weather. This, combined with human curiosity and ingenuity, led them to developing bigger and better engines and perfecting the technology.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was the first sign of a change. While the dwarven ideal is Arete - the perfection in the craft and dedication to the work, Mechanos, as they began to call themselves, adopted a new one: Bigger and Faster. Their machines lack the artistry of the dwarven craft, but ARE big and fast. Confident in their new power, the Mechanos emerged from their caves. Now they are refusing not only to pray to the gods, but also to use any of the aspects of the magic. They regard all spells as tainted with the gods' powers and manifestation of their will. Instead, they use mana nodes as a power source and feed refined mana to so called "mechanical spirits", cryptic beings that inhabit Mechanos machines.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Le origini dei Mechanos risalgono a molto prima dell'Era della Rinascita. Perfino quando i draghi e le divinità si facevano la guerra seminando distruzione per tutto Erebus alcuni uomini rifiutavano di rendere omaggio a qualsiasi dio. Tali convinzioni prima del Patto erano quasi delle inevitabili condanne a morte, in quanto senza la protezione di un dio nessuna città sarebbe sopravvissuta per più di qualche settimana.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ma molto è cambiato dopo la firma del Patto ai Sette Pini. Comunque, anche dopo di ciò, solo gli individui più potenti osavano dichiararsi apertamente atei. E persino un numero minore di loro sarebbe sopravvissuto in seguito a ciò, in quanto poco dopo venivano attaccati da crociati appartenenti persino a fedi in conflitto. Agli occhi dei sacerdoti, paladini e eidolon, l'unica cosa peggiore dei seguaci di un'angelo opposto sono coloro che si rifiutano di prendere parte alle crociate e vogliono essere lasciati in pace.[PARAGRAPH:1]Poi ci fù un'altro cambiamento. Poco prima dell'Era del Ghiaccio, alcuni non credenti entrarono in contatto con degli ingegneri nanici e gli fu permesso di apprendere alcuni dei segreti degli ingegneri. Questo fu la chiave per la loro sopravvivenza. Le macchine a vapore gli permisero non solo di riscaldare le caverne in cui si erano rifugiati durante l'Era del Ghiaccio, ma anche di vivere confortevolmente nonostante il clima rigido. Tutto questo, unito alla curiosità e ingegno umano, li portò  a sviluppare macchine più grandi e migliori oltre a perfezionare la tecnologia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quello fù il primo segno del cambiamento. Mentre l'ideale dei nani è Arete, ovvero la perfezione nel lavoro e la dedizione ad esso, i Mechanos, che avevano iniziato a chiamarsi così, ne adottarono uno nuovo: Più Grande e Più Veloce. Le loro macchine mancano dello stile artistico dei nani, ma SONO grandi e veloci. Fiduciosi nel loro nuovo potere i Mechanos emersero dalle loro caverne. Ora non solo si rifutano di venerare gli dei, ma anche di usare qualsiasi aspetto della magia. Considerano tutte le magie contaminate dal potere degli dei e manifestazione della loro volontà. Invece usano i nodi di mana come fonti di energia e usano il mana raffinato per alimentare i cosidetti "Spiriti Macchina", entità criptiche che dimorano nella macchine Mechanos.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The beginning of the Mechanos dates back to many years before the Age of Rebirth. With dragons and warring gods causing destruction all over Erebus, some people refused to pay respect to any god. Such beliefs before the Compact were almost inevitable death sentences, as without the protection of the patron god no city would survive more than a few weeks.[PARAGRAPH:1] Much has changed after the signing of the Compact at the Seven Pines. Still, only the most powerful individuals or groups would dare to speak their atheism openly. And even less would survive doing so, as they soon were attacked by joined crusaders of even conflicting faiths. In the eyes of priests, paladins, and eidolons, the only thing worse than followers of the opposite angel were those that refused to take part in the crusades and just wanted to be left alone. [PARAGRAPH:1]Then a second change arrived. Just before the Age of Ice, some of the unbelievers come into contact with dwarven engineers and were allowed to learn some of their secrets. This was a key to their survival. Steam engines allowed them not only to heat the caves that sheltered them during Age of Ice, but also to live quite comfortably despite severe weather. This, combined with human curiosity and ingenuity, led them to developing bigger and better engines and perfecting the technology.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was the first sign of a change. While the dwarven ideal is Arete - the perfection in the craft and dedication to the work, Mechanos, as they began to call themselves, adopted a new one: Bigger and Faster. Their machines lack the artistry of the dwarven craft, but ARE big and fast. Confident in their new power, the Mechanos emerged from their caves. Now they are refusing not only to pray to the gods, but also to use any of the aspects of the magic. They regard all spells as tainted with the gods' powers and manifestation of their will. Instead, they use mana nodes as a power source and feed refined mana to so called "mechanical spirits", cryptic beings that inhabit Mechanos machines.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_VEROCCHIO</Tag>
		<English>Verocchio</English>
		<French>Verocchio</French>
		<German>Verocchio</German>
		<Italian>Verocchio</Italian>
		<Spanish>Verocchio</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_VEROCCHIO_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A map. Erebus. Crusts and cliffs, inlets and isles, all present and correct. Lines. They dance. Spirals, whirls, loops, swirl hypnotic. A forced march, a practiced waltz, always ordered, always predictable.[NEWLINE]A face. Black as ink, jewels for eyes, nose that shines, smile as thin as cobwebs. More than a face, less than a face, the suggestion of a face.[NEWLINE]_AwAy. FaLsE/tRuE. iLlEgAl OpErAnD._[NEWLINE]"I lie to others. You lie to yourself"[NEWLINE]The face blinks. A man sits in contemplation. On one shoulder, a crimson imp whispering into his ear. On the other shoulder, a brasswork imp whispering into his ear.[NEWLINE]_Aw4y. FaLs3/tReE. iLlEg l oP3rAnD._[NEWLINE]"Trick me, snare me, catch me if you can."[NEWLINE]The face blinks. Mountains burn. Light flees a gate. Trees made of men, impossibly curved. A bird on the throne wears a cooking pot crown.[NEWLINE]_Aw... FcIs3/tReF. i 4IH l oP3rZOC._[NEWLINE]"Off I go, back I come. The first lie, the last lie."[NEWLINE]_E4=+. %$hIl%F32@. ]p~yT]v Jk.{t£D._[NEWLINE]"You'll say I'm gone, but I'll stay on. The only truth is the lie lives on."[NEWLINE]The face blinks and takes it wings; a butterfly stirs with bumblebee stings.[NEWLINE]A map. Erebus. Crusts and cliffs, inlets and isles, all present and correct. Lines. They dance. Spirals, whirls, loops, swirl hypnotic. A crazed jig, a frenzied frolic, never the same, never predictable.[NEWLINE]The face blinks. A worm on a spit. A mouth drips honey. Bubbles form a helix. Elephants grow spindle legs. Clocks melt.[NEWLINE]Verrochio awoke, his heart beating fast. The nightmare flees with the first breath of the day. His alchemists tell him that nightmares are fantasies of subconscious caused by fears and worries, but Verrochio cannot help but wonder, why they haunt him so?</English>
		<French>A map. Erebus. Crusts and cliffs, inlets and isles, all present and correct. Lines. They dance. Spirals, whirls, loops, swirl hypnotic. A forced march, a practiced waltz, always ordered, always predictable.[NEWLINE]A face. Black as ink, jewels for eyes, nose that shines, smile as thin as cobwebs. More than a face, less than a face, the suggestion of a face.[NEWLINE]_AwAy. FaLsE/tRuE. iLlEgAl OpErAnD._[NEWLINE]"I lie to others. You lie to yourself"[NEWLINE]The face blinks. A man sits in contemplation. On one shoulder, a crimson imp whispering into his ear. On the other shoulder, a brasswork imp whispering into his ear.[NEWLINE]_Aw4y. FaLs3/tReE. iLlEg l oP3rAnD._[NEWLINE]"Trick me, snare me, catch me if you can."[NEWLINE]The face blinks. Mountains burn. Light flees a gate. Trees made of men, impossibly curved. A bird on the throne wears a cooking pot crown.[NEWLINE]_Aw... FcIs3/tReF. i 4IH l oP3rZOC._[NEWLINE]"Off I go, back I come. The first lie, the last lie."[NEWLINE]_E4=+. %$hIl%F32@. ]p~yT]v Jk.{t£D._[NEWLINE]"You'll say I'm gone, but I'll stay on. The only truth is the lie lives on."[NEWLINE]The face blinks and takes it wings; a butterfly stirs with bumblebee stings.[NEWLINE]A map. Erebus. Crusts and cliffs, inlets and isles, all present and correct. Lines. They dance. Spirals, whirls, loops, swirl hypnotic. A crazed jig, a frenzied frolic, never the same, never predictable.[NEWLINE]The face blinks. A worm on a spit. A mouth drips honey. Bubbles form a helix. Elephants grow spindle legs. Clocks melt.[NEWLINE]Verrochio awoke, his heart beating fast. The nightmare flees with the first breath of the day. His alchemists tell him that nightmares are fantasies of subconscious caused by fears and worries, but Verrochio cannot help but wonder, why they haunt him so?</French>
		<German>A map. Erebus. Crusts and cliffs, inlets and isles, all present and correct. Lines. They dance. Spirals, whirls, loops, swirl hypnotic. A forced march, a practiced waltz, always ordered, always predictable.[NEWLINE]A face. Black as ink, jewels for eyes, nose that shines, smile as thin as cobwebs. More than a face, less than a face, the suggestion of a face.[NEWLINE]_AwAy. FaLsE/tRuE. iLlEgAl OpErAnD._[NEWLINE]"I lie to others. You lie to yourself"[NEWLINE]The face blinks. A man sits in contemplation. On one shoulder, a crimson imp whispering into his ear. On the other shoulder, a brasswork imp whispering into his ear.[NEWLINE]_Aw4y. FaLs3/tReE. iLlEg l oP3rAnD._[NEWLINE]"Trick me, snare me, catch me if you can."[NEWLINE]The face blinks. Mountains burn. Light flees a gate. Trees made of men, impossibly curved. A bird on the throne wears a cooking pot crown.[NEWLINE]_Aw... FcIs3/tReF. i 4IH l oP3rZOC._[NEWLINE]"Off I go, back I come. The first lie, the last lie."[NEWLINE]_E4=+. %$hIl%F32@. ]p~yT]v Jk.{t£D._[NEWLINE]"You'll say I'm gone, but I'll stay on. The only truth is the lie lives on."[NEWLINE]The face blinks and takes it wings; a butterfly stirs with bumblebee stings.[NEWLINE]A map. Erebus. Crusts and cliffs, inlets and isles, all present and correct. Lines. They dance. Spirals, whirls, loops, swirl hypnotic. A crazed jig, a frenzied frolic, never the same, never predictable.[NEWLINE]The face blinks. A worm on a spit. A mouth drips honey. Bubbles form a helix. Elephants grow spindle legs. Clocks melt.[NEWLINE]Verrochio awoke, his heart beating fast. The nightmare flees with the first breath of the day. His alchemists tell him that nightmares are fantasies of subconscious caused by fears and worries, but Verrochio cannot help but wonder, why they haunt him so?</German>
		<Italian>Una mappa. Erebus. Croste e scogliere, insenature e isole, tutte presenti e corrette. Linee. Danzano. Spirali, vortici, anelli, mulinelli ipnotici. Una marcia forzata, un valzer ben eseguito, sempre ordinato, sempre prevedibile.[NEWLINE]Un volto. Nero come l'inchiostro, dei gioielli come occhi, il naso che brilla, un sorriso sottile come una ragnatela. Più che un volto, meno di un volto, l'ipotesi di un volto.[NEWLINE]_LoNtAno. FaLsO/vErO. OpErAnDo ErRatO._[NEWLINE]"Io mento agli altri. Tu menti a te stesso"[NEWLINE]Il volto sbatte le palpebre. Un uomo siede in contemplazione. Su una spalla, un imp cremisi che gli sussurra nell'orecchio. Sull'altra spalla, un imp d'ottone gli sussurra nell'orecchio.[NEWLINE]_LoNtAn0. FaLs0/vEr0. OpErAnDo ErRat0._[NEWLINE]"Ingannami, intrappolami, prendimi se ci riesci."[NEWLINE]Il volto sbatte le palpebre. Montagne bruciano. Della luce esce da un cancello. Alberi fatti di uomini, incredibilmente curvi. Un uccello sul trono indossa una corona di pentole.[NEWLINE]_Lo... FeIsQ/v3Ru. i 4IH l oP3rZOC._[NEWLINE]"Me ne vado, torno. La prima bugia, l'ultima bugia."[NEWLINE]_E4=+. %$hIl%F32@. ]p~yT]v Jk.{t£D._[NEWLINE]"Dirai che me ne sono andato, ma rimarrò. L'unica verità è che la bugia rimane."[NEWLINE]Il volto sbatte le palpebre e prende le ali; una farfalla si agita con punture di calabrone.[NEWLINE]Una mappa. Erebus. Croste e scogliere, insenature e isole, tutte presenti e corrette. Linee. Danzano. Spirali, vortici, anelli, mulinelli ipnotici. Un balletto folle, uno scorrazzare frenetico, mai uguale, mai prevedibile.[NEWLINE]Il volto sbatte le palpebre. Un verme allo spiedo. Una bocca dalla quale gocciola miele. Bolle formano una spirale. Gli elefanti hanno gambe fini e lunghe. Gli orologi si sciolgono.[NEWLINE]Verrochio si sveglia, il suo cuore batte rapidamente. L'incubo svanisce con il primo respiro della giornata. I suoi alchimisti gli dicono che gli incubi sono fantasie del subconscio create da paure e preocupazioni, ma Verrochio non può fare a meno di chiedersi, perché lo perseguitano cosi?</Italian>
		<Spanish>A map. Erebus. Crusts and cliffs, inlets and isles, all present and correct. Lines. They dance. Spirals, whirls, loops, swirl hypnotic. A forced march, a practiced waltz, always ordered, always predictable.[NEWLINE]A face. Black as ink, jewels for eyes, nose that shines, smile as thin as cobwebs. More than a face, less than a face, the suggestion of a face.[NEWLINE]_AwAy. FaLsE/tRuE. iLlEgAl OpErAnD._[NEWLINE]"I lie to others. You lie to yourself"[NEWLINE]The face blinks. A man sits in contemplation. On one shoulder, a crimson imp whispering into his ear. On the other shoulder, a brasswork imp whispering into his ear.[NEWLINE]_Aw4y. FaLs3/tReE. iLlEg l oP3rAnD._[NEWLINE]"Trick me, snare me, catch me if you can."[NEWLINE]The face blinks. Mountains burn. Light flees a gate. Trees made of men, impossibly curved. A bird on the throne wears a cooking pot crown.[NEWLINE]_Aw... FcIs3/tReF. i 4IH l oP3rZOC._[NEWLINE]"Off I go, back I come. The first lie, the last lie."[NEWLINE]_E4=+. %$hIl%F32@. ]p~yT]v Jk.{t£D._[NEWLINE]"You'll say I'm gone, but I'll stay on. The only truth is the lie lives on."[NEWLINE]The face blinks and takes it wings; a butterfly stirs with bumblebee stings.[NEWLINE]A map. Erebus. Crusts and cliffs, inlets and isles, all present and correct. Lines. They dance. Spirals, whirls, loops, swirl hypnotic. A crazed jig, a frenzied frolic, never the same, never predictable.[NEWLINE]The face blinks. A worm on a spit. A mouth drips honey. Bubbles form a helix. Elephants grow spindle legs. Clocks melt.[NEWLINE]Verrochio awoke, his heart beating fast. The nightmare flees with the first breath of the day. His alchemists tell him that nightmares are fantasies of subconscious caused by fears and worries, but Verrochio cannot help but wonder, why they haunt him so?</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MAER</Tag>
		<English>Maer</English>
		<French>Maer</French>
		<German>Maer</German>
		<Italian>Maer</Italian>
		<Spanish>Maer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MAER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Maer retired from the hall with the usual pleasantries. Yes, she was excited by the new challenges ahead. No, she didn't think age and experience were the same thing. Yes, she was aware that she was the youngest engineer to hold the title of Mechana Excelsior. No, she wasn't apprehensive about the Bannor reinforcements. Yes, she would strengthen trade ties with the Luichirp. No, the recent incident with the Sheaim ambassador was not a cause for concern.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Order of Arches could be quite demanding. What was meant to have been a celebration for her investiture as chief architect for the Mechanos Empire had turned into an ever-so-polite but firm interrogation. She would have practice the art of rhetoric in the future. Damn it, why couldn't people be as predictable as machines?[PARAGRAPH:1]And then the red cloud came upon her again and she collapsed onto the bed in a coughing fit.[PARAGRAPH:1]
		_EvErYtHiNg Is FuNcTiOnInG wItHiN eXpEcTeD pArAmEtErS?_[PARAGRAPH:1]She had not heard Talos come in. She never did. Considering his bulk, he could be damn quiet when he wanted to. He glided over to her bed and removed her gown.[PARAGRAPH:1]_YoUr UpPeR aPpEnDaGeS aRe OpErAtIoNaL?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer shook her head. The pain had been getting worse recently. It had spread from her left breast along her shoulder and ran down her arm to her elbow. The liquid Talos had given her was no longer as effective as it used to be.[PARAGRAPH:1]_PaIn ReCePtOrS dEmOnStRaTe TrEaTmEnT iNeFfEcTiVe By TwOfOlD fAcToR?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer nodded her head and coughed once more. She could feel Talos unscrewing the silver plate hidden in her chest. Her curiosity was insatiable, but the flap opened towards her face and she could never focus enough to determine Talos' movements. She felt a sudden lurch in her side and asked Talos to talk to her about something else.[PARAGRAPH:1]_EcOnOmIc AnAlYsEs AvAiLaBlE. oUtPuT?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer murmured her assent. It was all she could do to keep the pain away. She would have died in the explosion if Talos hadn't inserted that machine in her. She wasn't ungrateful, but she wished she knew how it worked. In desperation she tried to open the panel once... Talos had found her on the floor of her workshop. Maybe if she set up a feedback loop on an Aether soaked mirror and diverted her nerve endings through a resonance trap...[PARAGRAPH:1]_ReFiNeD mAnA sUpPlIeS oCcUpY tHe LoWeSt QuArTiLe FoR eFfEcTiVe SoCiAl CoNdItIoNiNg. ReMeDiAl AcTiOn ReCoMmEnDeD._[PARAGRAPH:1]Supplies of refined mana had been hard to come by since the loss of Pavona to the Bannor. Why did the hard-liners always want war? The whole thing had been a massive miscalculation. Were it not for the rain, the Mechanos would have burnt down the temple containing the master manuscript of the Code of Junil and then nothing would have stopped the Bannor in their bloodlust. As it was, only a rogue assault by a Lanun warship had distracted the Bannor long enough for the Mechanos to sue for peace.[PARAGRAPH:1]_ThReE sOuRcEs LiE wItHiN dIsPuTeD bOuNdArIeS. VaRgStAd Is SuScEpTiBlE tO aCqUiSiTiOn._[PARAGRAPH:1]Vargstad. Maer had heard of it. The rumours spoke that they were preparing the way for the King of Hope, whoever he might be. Hope or no, the Mechanos needed to regroup, not start a new war.[PARAGRAPH:1]_SlEeP nOw. ReStOrAtIoN iS nEcEsSaRy FoR oPtiMaL pErFoRmAnCe._[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer felt her eyelids droop. Within her chest a new heart beat with clockwork precision and a sibilant voice whispered stories of Sheaim treachery into her dreams.</English>
		<French>Maer retired from the hall with the usual pleasantries. Yes, she was excited by the new challenges ahead. No, she didn't think age and experience were the same thing. Yes, she was aware that she was the youngest engineer to hold the title of Mechana Excelsior. No, she wasn't apprehensive about the Bannor reinforcements. Yes, she would strengthen trade ties with the Luichirp. No, the recent incident with the Sheaim ambassador was not a cause for concern.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Order of Arches could be quite demanding. What was meant to have been a celebration for her investiture as chief architect for the Mechanos Empire had turned into an ever-so-polite but firm interrogation. She would have practice the art of rhetoric in the future. Damn it, why couldn't people be as predictable as machines?[PARAGRAPH:1]And then the red cloud came upon her again and she collapsed onto the bed in a coughing fit.[PARAGRAPH:1]
		_EvErYtHiNg Is FuNcTiOnInG wItHiN eXpEcTeD pArAmEtErS?_[PARAGRAPH:1]She had not heard Talos come in. She never did. Considering his bulk, he could be damn quiet when he wanted to. He glided over to her bed and removed her gown.[PARAGRAPH:1]_YoUr UpPeR aPpEnDaGeS aRe OpErAtIoNaL?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer shook her head. The pain had been getting worse recently. It had spread from her left breast along her shoulder and ran down her arm to her elbow. The liquid Talos had given her was no longer as effective as it used to be.[PARAGRAPH:1]_PaIn ReCePtOrS dEmOnStRaTe TrEaTmEnT iNeFfEcTiVe By TwOfOlD fAcToR?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer nodded her head and coughed once more. She could feel Talos unscrewing the silver plate hidden in her chest. Her curiosity was insatiable, but the flap opened towards her face and she could never focus enough to determine Talos' movements. She felt a sudden lurch in her side and asked Talos to talk to her about something else.[PARAGRAPH:1]_EcOnOmIc AnAlYsEs AvAiLaBlE. oUtPuT?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer murmured her assent. It was all she could do to keep the pain away. She would have died in the explosion if Talos hadn't inserted that machine in her. She wasn't ungrateful, but she wished she knew how it worked. In desperation she tried to open the panel once... Talos had found her on the floor of her workshop. Maybe if she set up a feedback loop on an Aether soaked mirror and diverted her nerve endings through a resonance trap...[PARAGRAPH:1]_ReFiNeD mAnA sUpPlIeS oCcUpY tHe LoWeSt QuArTiLe FoR eFfEcTiVe SoCiAl CoNdItIoNiNg. ReMeDiAl AcTiOn ReCoMmEnDeD._[PARAGRAPH:1]Supplies of refined mana had been hard to come by since the loss of Pavona to the Bannor. Why did the hard-liners always want war? The whole thing had been a massive miscalculation. Were it not for the rain, the Mechanos would have burnt down the temple containing the master manuscript of the Code of Junil and then nothing would have stopped the Bannor in their bloodlust. As it was, only a rogue assault by a Lanun warship had distracted the Bannor long enough for the Mechanos to sue for peace.[PARAGRAPH:1]_ThReE sOuRcEs LiE wItHiN dIsPuTeD bOuNdArIeS. VaRgStAd Is SuScEpTiBlE tO aCqUiSiTiOn._[PARAGRAPH:1]Vargstad. Maer had heard of it. The rumours spoke that they were preparing the way for the King of Hope, whoever he might be. Hope or no, the Mechanos needed to regroup, not start a new war.[PARAGRAPH:1]_SlEeP nOw. ReStOrAtIoN iS nEcEsSaRy FoR oPtiMaL pErFoRmAnCe._[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer felt her eyelids droop. Within her chest a new heart beat with clockwork precision and a sibilant voice whispered stories of Sheaim treachery into her dreams.</French>
		<German>Maer retired from the hall with the usual pleasantries. Yes, she was excited by the new challenges ahead. No, she didn't think age and experience were the same thing. Yes, she was aware that she was the youngest engineer to hold the title of Mechana Excelsior. No, she wasn't apprehensive about the Bannor reinforcements. Yes, she would strengthen trade ties with the Luichirp. No, the recent incident with the Sheaim ambassador was not a cause for concern.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Order of Arches could be quite demanding. What was meant to have been a celebration for her investiture as chief architect for the Mechanos Empire had turned into an ever-so-polite but firm interrogation. She would have practice the art of rhetoric in the future. Damn it, why couldn't people be as predictable as machines?[PARAGRAPH:1]And then the red cloud came upon her again and she collapsed onto the bed in a coughing fit.[PARAGRAPH:1]
		_EvErYtHiNg Is FuNcTiOnInG wItHiN eXpEcTeD pArAmEtErS?_[PARAGRAPH:1]She had not heard Talos come in. She never did. Considering his bulk, he could be damn quiet when he wanted to. He glided over to her bed and removed her gown.[PARAGRAPH:1]_YoUr UpPeR aPpEnDaGeS aRe OpErAtIoNaL?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer shook her head. The pain had been getting worse recently. It had spread from her left breast along her shoulder and ran down her arm to her elbow. The liquid Talos had given her was no longer as effective as it used to be.[PARAGRAPH:1]_PaIn ReCePtOrS dEmOnStRaTe TrEaTmEnT iNeFfEcTiVe By TwOfOlD fAcToR?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer nodded her head and coughed once more. She could feel Talos unscrewing the silver plate hidden in her chest. Her curiosity was insatiable, but the flap opened towards her face and she could never focus enough to determine Talos' movements. She felt a sudden lurch in her side and asked Talos to talk to her about something else.[PARAGRAPH:1]_EcOnOmIc AnAlYsEs AvAiLaBlE. oUtPuT?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer murmured her assent. It was all she could do to keep the pain away. She would have died in the explosion if Talos hadn't inserted that machine in her. She wasn't ungrateful, but she wished she knew how it worked. In desperation she tried to open the panel once... Talos had found her on the floor of her workshop. Maybe if she set up a feedback loop on an Aether soaked mirror and diverted her nerve endings through a resonance trap...[PARAGRAPH:1]_ReFiNeD mAnA sUpPlIeS oCcUpY tHe LoWeSt QuArTiLe FoR eFfEcTiVe SoCiAl CoNdItIoNiNg. ReMeDiAl AcTiOn ReCoMmEnDeD._[PARAGRAPH:1]Supplies of refined mana had been hard to come by since the loss of Pavona to the Bannor. Why did the hard-liners always want war? The whole thing had been a massive miscalculation. Were it not for the rain, the Mechanos would have burnt down the temple containing the master manuscript of the Code of Junil and then nothing would have stopped the Bannor in their bloodlust. As it was, only a rogue assault by a Lanun warship had distracted the Bannor long enough for the Mechanos to sue for peace.[PARAGRAPH:1]_ThReE sOuRcEs LiE wItHiN dIsPuTeD bOuNdArIeS. VaRgStAd Is SuScEpTiBlE tO aCqUiSiTiOn._[PARAGRAPH:1]Vargstad. Maer had heard of it. The rumours spoke that they were preparing the way for the King of Hope, whoever he might be. Hope or no, the Mechanos needed to regroup, not start a new war.[PARAGRAPH:1]_SlEeP nOw. ReStOrAtIoN iS nEcEsSaRy FoR oPtiMaL pErFoRmAnCe._[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer felt her eyelids droop. Within her chest a new heart beat with clockwork precision and a sibilant voice whispered stories of Sheaim treachery into her dreams.</German>
		<Italian>Maer lasciò la sala con i soliti convenevoli. Si, era eccitata dalle nuove sfide che avrebbe affrontato. No, non riteneva che l'età e l'esperienza fossero la stessa cosa. Si, sapeva di essere l'ingegnere più giovane fin ora ad ottenere il titolo di Mechana Excelsior. No, non era preoccupata per i rinforzi Bannor. Si, avrebbe rafforzato i legami commerciali con i Luichirp. No, il recente incidente con l'ambasciatore Sheaim non è stato motivo di preoccupazione.[PARAGRAPH:1]L'Ordine degli Archi poteva essere piuttosto impegnativo. Quella che doveva essere una celebrazione della sua investitura come Capo Architetto dell'Impero Mechanos era diventata un interrogatorio educato ma risoluto. Avrebbe fatto pratica con l'arte della retorica in futuro. Dannazione, perché le persone non potevano essere prevedibili come le macchine?[PARAGRAPH:1]Infine la nuvola rossa la raggiunse di nuovo facendola crollare sul letto con un attacco di tosse.[PARAGRAPH:1]
		_TuTtO sTa FuNzIoNaNdO eNtRo I pArAmEtRi PrEvIsTi?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Lei non aveva sentito Talos entrare. Non lo sentiva mai. Considerando la sua mole, lui riusciva ad essere dannatamente silenzioso quando voleva. Lui andò verso letto e gli tolse il vestito.[PARAGRAPH:1]_Le TuE aPpEnDiCi SuPeRiOrI sOnO oPeRaTiVe?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer scosse la testa. Il dolore stava peggiorando ultimamente. Si era diffuso dal seno sinistro lungo la spalla e le correva lungo il braccio fino al gomito. Il liquido che Talos gli aveva dato non era più efficace come una volta.[PARAGRAPH:1]_I rEcEtToRi DeL dOlOrE dImOsTrAnO cHe Il TrAtTaMeNtO è InEfFiCaCe Di Un FaTtOrE dOpPiO?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer annuì tossendo di nuovo. Percepiva Talos svitare la piastra d'argento nascosta nel suo petto. La sua curiosità era insaziabile, ma la piastra si apriva verso il suo viso, e non riusciva mai a concentrarsi abbastanza per capire i movimenti di Talos. Sentì un sussulto improvviso al suo fianco e chiese a Talos di parlare di qualcos'altro.[PARAGRAPH:1]_AnAlIsI eCoNoMiCa DiSpOnIbIlE. EsPoRrE?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer mormorò il suo assenso. Era tutto ciò che poteva fare per tenere lontano il dolore. Sarebbe morta nell'esplosione se Talos non avesse inserito quella macchina dentro di lei. Non era ingrata, ma avrebbe voluto sapere come funzionava. In preda alla disperazione tentò di aprire il pannello una volta... Talos la trovò svenuta sul pavimeto del suo laboratorio. Forse se creava un circuito di feedback su uno specchio imbevuto d'Etere e deviava le sue terminazioni nervose attraverso una trappola di risonanza...[PARAGRAPH:1]_RiFoRnImEnTi Di MaNa RaFfInAtO oCcuPaNo Il QuArTiLe Più bAsSo PeR cOnDiZiOnAmEnTo SoCiAlE eFfiCaCe. AzIoNe CoReTtiVa CoNsIgLiAtA._[PARAGRAPH:1]Era difficile trovare rifornimenti di mana raffinato da quando Pavona era stata presa dai Bannor. Perché gli integralisti volevano sempre la guerra? L'intera faccenda era stata un'enorme errore di calcolo. Se non fosse stato per la pioggia, i Mechanos avrebbero bruciato completamente il tempio che conteneva il manoscritto principale del Codice di Junil e nulla avrebbe potuto poi fermare la sete di sangue dei Bannor. In realtà, solo l'attacco immotivato di una nave da guerra Lanun era riuscito a distrarre abbastanza a lungo i Bannor permettendo ai Mechanos di chiedere la pace.[PARAGRAPH:1]_TrE fOnTi GiAcCiOnO eNtRo CoNfInI cOnTeStAtI. VaRgStAd È sEnSiBiLe Ad Un'AcQuIsIzIoNe._[PARAGRAPH:1]Vargstad. Maer ne aveva sentito parlare. Le voci dicevano che stavano preparando la strada per il Re della Speranza, chiunque possa essere. Speranza o no, i Mechanos dovevano riorganizzarsi, non iniziare un altra guerra.[PARAGRAPH:1]_DoRmI oRa. ReCuPeRo NeCeSsaRiO pEr PrEsTaZiOnI oTtiMaLi._[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer sentì le palpebre chiudersi. Dentro il suo petto un nuovo cuore batteva con precisione meccanica e una voce sibilante sussurrava della slealtà degli Sheaim nei suoi sogni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Maer retired from the hall with the usual pleasantries. Yes, she was excited by the new challenges ahead. No, she didn't think age and experience were the same thing. Yes, she was aware that she was the youngest engineer to hold the title of Mechana Excelsior. No, she wasn't apprehensive about the Bannor reinforcements. Yes, she would strengthen trade ties with the Luichirp. No, the recent incident with the Sheaim ambassador was not a cause for concern.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Order of Arches could be quite demanding. What was meant to have been a celebration for her investiture as chief architect for the Mechanos Empire had turned into an ever-so-polite but firm interrogation. She would have practice the art of rhetoric in the future. Damn it, why couldn't people be as predictable as machines?[PARAGRAPH:1]And then the red cloud came upon her again and she collapsed onto the bed in a coughing fit.[PARAGRAPH:1]
		_EvErYtHiNg Is FuNcTiOnInG wItHiN eXpEcTeD pArAmEtErS?_[PARAGRAPH:1]She had not heard Talos come in. She never did. Considering his bulk, he could be damn quiet when he wanted to. He glided over to her bed and removed her gown.[PARAGRAPH:1]_YoUr UpPeR aPpEnDaGeS aRe OpErAtIoNaL?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer shook her head. The pain had been getting worse recently. It had spread from her left breast along her shoulder and ran down her arm to her elbow. The liquid Talos had given her was no longer as effective as it used to be.[PARAGRAPH:1]_PaIn ReCePtOrS dEmOnStRaTe TrEaTmEnT iNeFfEcTiVe By TwOfOlD fAcToR?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer nodded her head and coughed once more. She could feel Talos unscrewing the silver plate hidden in her chest. Her curiosity was insatiable, but the flap opened towards her face and she could never focus enough to determine Talos' movements. She felt a sudden lurch in her side and asked Talos to talk to her about something else.[PARAGRAPH:1]_EcOnOmIc AnAlYsEs AvAiLaBlE. oUtPuT?_[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer murmured her assent. It was all she could do to keep the pain away. She would have died in the explosion if Talos hadn't inserted that machine in her. She wasn't ungrateful, but she wished she knew how it worked. In desperation she tried to open the panel once... Talos had found her on the floor of her workshop. Maybe if she set up a feedback loop on an Aether soaked mirror and diverted her nerve endings through a resonance trap...[PARAGRAPH:1]_ReFiNeD mAnA sUpPlIeS oCcUpY tHe LoWeSt QuArTiLe FoR eFfEcTiVe SoCiAl CoNdItIoNiNg. ReMeDiAl AcTiOn ReCoMmEnDeD._[PARAGRAPH:1]Supplies of refined mana had been hard to come by since the loss of Pavona to the Bannor. Why did the hard-liners always want war? The whole thing had been a massive miscalculation. Were it not for the rain, the Mechanos would have burnt down the temple containing the master manuscript of the Code of Junil and then nothing would have stopped the Bannor in their bloodlust. As it was, only a rogue assault by a Lanun warship had distracted the Bannor long enough for the Mechanos to sue for peace.[PARAGRAPH:1]_ThReE sOuRcEs LiE wItHiN dIsPuTeD bOuNdArIeS. VaRgStAd Is SuScEpTiBlE tO aCqUiSiTiOn._[PARAGRAPH:1]Vargstad. Maer had heard of it. The rumours spoke that they were preparing the way for the King of Hope, whoever he might be. Hope or no, the Mechanos needed to regroup, not start a new war.[PARAGRAPH:1]_SlEeP nOw. ReStOrAtIoN iS nEcEsSaRy FoR oPtiMaL pErFoRmAnCe._[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer felt her eyelids droop. Within her chest a new heart beat with clockwork precision and a sibilant voice whispered stories of Sheaim treachery into her dreams.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_STEAMWORKS</Tag>
		<English>Steamworks</English>
		<French>Fonder l'Usine à Vapeur</French>
		<German>Dampfantrieb</German>
		<Italian>Steamworks</Italian>
		<Spanish>Steamworks</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_STEAMWORKS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Grants research for every workshop, watermill and windmill in territory, creates Steamworks building in the city it is cast in.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Fournit de la recherche pour chaque atelier, moulin à eau ou à vent de votre territoire. Crée le bâtiment « Usine à Vapeur » dans la ville où vous lancez ce sort.</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erschafft das Geböde Dampfantrieb in der Stadt. Jede Werkstatt, jede Wassermühle und jede Windmühle auf Eurem Territorium liefert ihren Beitrag zur Forschung.</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Fornisce ricerca per ogni bottega, mulino ad acqua e mulino a vento presente sul territorio, crea l'edificio Steamworks nella città in cui viene lanciata.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Grants research for every workshop, watermill and windmill in territory, creates Steamworks building in the city it is cast in.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FACTORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>How sad to see the Mechanos' natural philosophy writ large into the culture. Their Technopriests study nature and invent amazing discoveries, yet what do they do with them? They use them to create great factories that eat men like a fire eats coal. Day and night the factories operate; men toiling by the eerie light of the lumos bulbs. Who is the master here? The men who toil till they drop in oily squalor or the machines that they tend? In studying nature, they have created their own antithesis of it; a hell they willingly go into.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Scouting report, Elohim Devout Idore Lykasu[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Powered by steam, lit by lumos bulbs, the Mechanos factories work night and day. Young and old, men and women work to keep the machines running. The foremans roam up and down the lanes, watching for anyone shirking their duty to the machines; Mechanos ideals made manifest in iron and copper. The steam whistle brings in a new shift as the outgoing one staggers off to their cramped living quarters...if living is what it can be called.</English>
		<French>How sad to see the Mechanos' nature philosophy writ large into the culture. Their Technopriest study nature and invent amazing discoveries. Yet what do they do with them? They use them to create great factories that eat men like a fire eats coal. Day and night the factories operate; men toiling by the eerie light of the lumos bulbs. Who is the master here? The men who toil till they drop in oily squalor or the machines that they tend? In studying nature, they have created their own antithesis of it; a hell they willingly go into.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Scouting report, Elohim Devout Idore Lykasu[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Powered by steam, lit by lumos bulbs, the Mechanos factories work night and day. Young and old, man and women work to keep the machines running. The foremans roam up and down the lanes, watching for anyone shirking their duty to the machines; Mechanos ideals made manifest in iron and copper. The steam whistle brings in a new shift as the outgoing one staggers off to their cramped living quarters...if living is what it can be called.</French>
		<German>How sad to see the Mechanos' nature philosophy writ large into the culture. Their Technopriest study nature and invent amazing discoveries. Yet what do they do with them? They use them to create great factories that eat men like a fire eats coal. Day and night the factories operate; men toiling by the eerie light of the lumos bulbs. Who is the master here? The men who toil till they drop in oily squalor or the machines that they tend? In studying nature, they have created their own antithesis of it; a hell they willingly go into.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Scouting report, Elohim Devout Idore Lykasu[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Powered by steam, lit by lumos bulbs, the Mechanos factories work night and day. Young and old, man and women work to keep the machines running. The foremans roam up and down the lanes, watching for anyone shirking their duty to the machines; Mechanos ideals made manifest in iron and copper. The steam whistle brings in a new shift as the outgoing one staggers off to their cramped living quarters...if living is what it can be called.</German>
		<Italian>Che triste che è vedere la filosofia Mechanos cosi presente nella cultura. I loro Tecnopreti studiano la natura e scoprono cose incredibili. Eppure cosa fanno con esse? Le usano per creare grandi fabbriche che divorano uomini come il fuoco divora il carbone. Le fabbriche lavorano giorno e notte; uomini lavorano illuminati dalla tetra luce di lampade ad incandescenza. Chi è il padrone? Gli uomini che lavorano fino a quando non crollano o le macchine con cui lavorano? Nello studiare la natura hanno creato la sua antitesi; un inferno in cui vanno di loro sponte.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Rapporto di esplorazione, Devoto Elohim Idore Lykasu[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]STORIA: Alimentate dal vapore, illuminate da lampadine ad incandescenza, le fabbriche Mechanos lavorano giorno e notte. Giovani e vecchi, uomini e donne lavorano per mantenere le macchine funzionanti. I caposquadra vanno avanti e indietro per le postazioni, assicurandosi che nessuno venga meno al proprio dovere verso le macchine; gli ideali Mechanos fatti di ferro e rame. Un fischio segnala l'arrivo di un nuovo turno mentre quello attuale si dirige arrancando verso gli alloggi...</Italian>
		<Spanish>How sad to see the Mechanos' nature philosophy writ large into the culture. Their Technopriest study nature and invent amazing discoveries. Yet what do they do with them? They use them to create great factories that eat men like a fire eats coal. Day and night the factories operate; men toiling by the eerie light of the lumos bulbs. Who is the master here? The men who toil till they drop in oily squalor or the machines that they tend? In studying nature, they have created their own antithesis of it; a hell they willingly go into.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Scouting report, Elohim Devout Idore Lykasu[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Powered by steam, lit by lumos bulbs, the Mechanos factories work night and day. Young and old, man and women work to keep the machines running. The foremans roam up and down the lanes, watching for anyone shirking their duty to the machines; Mechanos ideals made manifest in iron and copper. The steam whistle brings in a new shift as the outgoing one staggers off to their cramped living quarters...if living is what it can be called.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FACTORY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Factory</English>
		<French>Usine</French>
		<German>Fabrik</German>
		<Italian>Fabbrica</Italian>
		<Spanish>Factory</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_MECHANOS</Tag>
		<English>Mechanos Palace</English>
		<French>Palais Mechanos</French>
		<German>Palast der Mechanos</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo dei Mechanos</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mechanos Palace</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_POWER_PLANT</Tag>
		<English>Power Plant</English>
		<French>Centrale à vapeur</French>
		<German>Kraftwerk</German>
		<Italian>Centrale Elettrica</Italian>
		<Spanish>Power Plant</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_POWER_PLANT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English> You have to learn to listen to the whistle, my boy. All power has a voice, be it the crash of the waves on the rocks, the creak of a wind or watermill. The fires of the coke ovens will belch out information if you know how to hear it. Here, though, power has a scream all of its own. You learn how to listen to that whistle, that scream and you'll stay alive.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Foreman Sansone Tiziano to his 4th apprentice in a month[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: While most civilizations on Erebus were content with mills powered by the wind and water or the mana nodes for power, the naturalistic philosophers of the Mechanos went a step further. While decrying the God-Believers, these naturalist noticed the duality in the Gods and saw it in nature as well; hot and cold, light and dark. It was from these observations that the Mechanos discovered that in a union of opposites, in this case fire and water, a powerful energy could be harnessed. Soon mighty factories would be built, all powered by the turbines and steam of the powerhouse.</English>
		<French> You have to learn to listen to the whistle, my boy. All power has a voice, be it the crash of the waves on the rocks, the creak of a wind or watermill. The fires of the coke ovens will belch out information if you know how to hear it. Here, though, power has a scream all of its own. You learn how to listen to that whistle, that scream and you'll stay alive.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Foreman Sansone Tiziano to his 4th apprentice in a month[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: While most civilizations on Erebus were content with mills powered by the wind and water or the mana nodes for power, the naturalistic philosophers of the Mechanos went a step further. While decrying the God-Believers, these naturalist noticed the duality in the Gods and saw it in nature as well; hot and cold, light and dark. It was from these observations that the Mechanos discovered that in a union of opposites, in this case fire and water, a powerful energy could be harnessed. Soon mighty factories would be built, all powered by the turbines and steam of the powerhouse.</French>
		<German> You have to learn to listen to the whistle, my boy. All power has a voice, be it the crash of the waves on the rocks, the creak of a wind or watermill. The fires of the coke ovens will belch out information if you know how to hear it. Here, though, power has a scream all of its own. You learn how to listen to that whistle, that scream and you'll stay alive.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Foreman Sansone Tiziano to his 4th apprentice in a month[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: While most civilizations on Erebus were content with mills powered by the wind and water or the mana nodes for power, the naturalistic philosophers of the Mechanos went a step further. While decrying the God-Believers, these naturalist noticed the duality in the Gods and saw it in nature as well; hot and cold, light and dark. It was from these observations that the Mechanos discovered that in a union of opposites, in this case fire and water, a powerful energy could be harnessed. Soon mighty factories would be built, all powered by the turbines and steam of the powerhouse.</German>
		<Italian>Devi imparare a riconoscere i fischi, ragazzo. Ogni energia ha una voce, che sia l'impattare delle onde sulle rocce, lo scricchiolio di un mulino a vento o di un mulino ad acqua. Le fiamme degli altoforni possono darti parecchie informazioni se impari ad ascoltarle. Qui, però, l'energia ha un grido tutto suo. Impara a riconoscere quel fischio, quell'urlo e sopravvivrai.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Caposquadra Sansone Tiziano al suo 4° apprendista in un mese[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]STORIA: Mentre la maggior parte delle civiltà su Erebus si accontentano dei mulini alimentati dal vento e dall'acqua o usano nodi di mana come fonte di energia, i naturalisti Mechanos sono andati oltre. Mentre schernivano i Credenti notarono la dualità tra gli Dei e videro la stessa cosa nella natura; caldo e freddo, luce e oscurità. Fu da queste osservazioni che i Mechanos scoprirono che dall'unione degli opposti, fuoco e acqua in questo caso, una potente forza poteva essere imbrigliata. Poco dopo imponenti fabbriche furono costruite, tutte alimentate dalle turbine e dal vapore della centrale elettrica.</Italian>
		<Spanish> You have to learn to listen to the whistle, my boy. All power has a voice, be it the crash of the waves on the rocks, the creak of a wind or watermill. The fires of the coke ovens will belch out information if you know how to hear it. Here, though, power has a scream all of its own. You learn how to listen to that whistle, that scream and you'll stay alive.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Foreman Sansone Tiziano to his 4th apprentice in a month[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: While most civilizations on Erebus were content with mills powered by the wind and water or the mana nodes for power, the naturalistic philosophers of the Mechanos went a step further. While decrying the God-Believers, these naturalist noticed the duality in the Gods and saw it in nature as well; hot and cold, light and dark. It was from these observations that the Mechanos discovered that in a union of opposites, in this case fire and water, a powerful energy could be harnessed. Soon mighty factories would be built, all powered by the turbines and steam of the powerhouse.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STEAMWORKS</Tag>
		<English>Steamworks</English>
		<French>Usine à Vapeur</French>
		<German>Dampfantrieb</German>
		<Italian>Steamworks</Italian>
		<Spanish>Steamworks</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STEAMWORKS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The greatest invention of the Mechanos is not using unrefined mana. It's the realization that with enough hot air you can achieve anything even without mana. - Felix Askanier, Scholar</English>
		<French>The greatest invention of the Mechanos is not using unrefined mana. It's the realization that with enough hot air you can achieve anything even without mana. - Felix Askanier, Scholar</French>
		<German>The greatest invention of the Mechanos is not using unrefined mana. It's the realization that with enough hot air you can achieve anything even without mana. - Felix Askanier, Scholar</German>
		<Italian>La più grande invenzione dei Mechanos non è usare mana grezzo. È la consapevolezza che con abbastanza aria calda si può realizzare qualsiasi cosa anche senza mana. - Felix Askanier, Studioso</Italian>
		<Spanish>The greatest invention of the Mechanos is not using unrefined mana. It's the realization that with enough hot air you can achieve anything even without mana. - Felix Askanier, Scholar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLE_MECHANOS</Tag>
		<English>Clock Tower</English>
		<French>Tour de l'Horloge</French>
		<German>Uhrenturm</German>
		<Italian>Torre dell'Orologio</Italian>
		<Spanish>Clock Tower</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLE_MECHANOS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Clock Tower is the most important building in all Mechanos cities. Not only does the great clock regulate the life of all citizens, it is also home to adepts of the Cult of Technology, venerating all machines and the power of the human mind. Moreover, deep within the clock, surrounded by rotating gears and fuelled by refined mana, live the machine spirits. New spirits are born here and can be transfered to the newly built machines.</English>
		<French>The Clock Tower is the most important building in all Mechanos cities. Not only the great clock regulates the live of all citizens. It is also home to adepts of the Cult of Technology, venerating all machines and the power of the human mind. Moreover, deep within the clock, surrounded by rotating gears and fuelled by refined mana, live the machine spirits. New spirits are born here and can be transfered to the newly built machines.</French>
		<German>The Clock Tower is the most important building in all Mechanos cities. Not only the great clock regulates the live of all citizens. It is also home to adepts of the Cult of Technology, venerating all machines and the power of the human mind. Moreover, deep within the clock, surrounded by rotating gears and fuelled by refined mana, live the machine spirits. New spirits are born here and can be transfered to the newly built machines.</German>
		<Italian>La Torre dell'Orologio è l'edificio più importante in tutte le città Mechanos. Non solo perché il grande orologio regola le vite di tutti i cittadini. Essa è anche la casa degli adepti del Culto della Tecnologia, in cui venerano tutte le macchine e il potere della mente umana. Inoltre, in profondità all'interno dell'orologio, circondati da ingranaggi e alimentati dal mana raffinato, vivono gli spiriti macchina. È qui che nascono nuovi spiriti che poi possono essere trasferiti nelle macchine appena create.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Clock Tower is the most important building in all Mechanos cities. Not only the great clock regulates the live of all citizens. It is also home to adepts of the Cult of Technology, venerating all machines and the power of the human mind. Moreover, deep within the clock, surrounded by rotating gears and fuelled by refined mana, live the machine spirits. New spirits are born here and can be transfered to the newly built machines.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ADEPTUS</Tag>
		<English>Adeptus</English>
		<French>Adeptus</French>
		<German>Adeptus</German>
		<Italian>Adeptus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Adeptus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ADEPTUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Of course the Gods exist, boy! The point I am trying to get into your sheepherders skull is what is a God? Power? I have power but that doesn't make me a God. Is it magic? Look at that lumos bulb over there? To some Doviello savage, I'm sure that looks as magical as any fireball but its just something we know how to do that he doesn't. So these Gods are merely beings that have power we don't have and knowledge we don't know...yet. If you'd knock out those old superstitions out of your head, you'd be on your way in finding those answers that will enable us to challenge these so called Gods and keep them from meddling in our rightful affairs."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Lecture in progress, Vaul Academy of Natural Sciences[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: In a magical world, there is often little reason to question how something works since since the answer, "It is magic" is often a true statement. To the natural philosophy of the Mechanos, this answer is not enough. What is magic and how does it fit in to the rest of the universe? In asking these questions, the Mechanos Adeptus have taken the road less traveled and thus have brought forth knowledge and technology no other civilization of Erebus could even conceive of due to their preconceived acceptance of that simple answer "It is magic" as an answer to all things.</English>
		<French>"Of course the Gods exist, boy! The point I'm trying to get into your sheepherders skull is what is a God? Power? I have power but that doesn't make me a God. Is it magic? Look at that lumos bulb over there? To some Doviello savage, I'm sure that looks as magical as any fireball but its just something we know how to do that he doesn't. So these Gods are merely beings that have power we don't have and knowledge we don't know...yet. If you'd knock out those old superstitions out of your head, you'd be on your way in finding those answers that will enable us to challenge these so called Gods and keep them from meddling in our rightful affairs."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Lecture in progress, Vaul Academy of Natural Sciences[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: In a magical world, there is often little reason to question how something works since since the answer, "It is magic" is often a true statement. To the natural philosophy of the Mechanos, this answer is not enough. What is magic and how does it fit in to the rest of the universe? In asking these questions, the Mechanos Adeptus have taken the road less traveled and thus have brought forth knowledge and technology no other civilization of Erebus could even conceive of due to their preconceived acceptance of that simple answer "It is magic" as an answer to all things.</French>
		<German>"Of course the Gods exist, boy! The point I'm trying to get into your sheepherders skull is what is a God? Power? I have power but that doesn't make me a God. Is it magic? Look at that lumos bulb over there? To some Doviello savage, I'm sure that looks as magical as any fireball but its just something we know how to do that he doesn't. So these Gods are merely beings that have power we don't have and knowledge we don't know...yet. If you'd knock out those old superstitions out of your head, you'd be on your way in finding those answers that will enable us to challenge these so called Gods and keep them from meddling in our rightful affairs."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Lecture in progress, Vaul Academy of Natural Sciences[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: In a magical world, there is often little reason to question how something works since since the answer, "It is magic" is often a true statement. To the natural philosophy of the Mechanos, this answer is not enough. What is magic and how does it fit in to the rest of the universe? In asking these questions, the Mechanos Adeptus have taken the road less traveled and thus have brought forth knowledge and technology no other civilization of Erebus could even conceive of due to their preconceived acceptance of that simple answer "It is magic" as an answer to all things.</German>
		<Italian>"È ovvio che esistono gli dei, ragazzo! Il concetto che sto cercando di far entrare nella tua testa da pastore è: cos'è un dio? Potere? Io ho potere, ma questo non mi rende un dio. È la magia? Guarda quella lampadina? Sono certo che a qualche selvaggio Doviello essa è magica allo stesso modo di una palla di fuoco, ma in realtà è soltanto qualcosa che noi sappiamo come funziona e come crearla, mentre lui no. Perciò questi dei non sono altro che esseri che hanno poteri che noi non abbiamo e conoscenze che noi non possediamo...per ora. Se rimuovessi alcune di quelle vecchie superstizioni dalla tua testa saresti sulla buona strada nel trovare quelle risposte che ci permetterebbero di sfidare questi cosiddetti dei impedendogli di intrommetersi nei nostri affari."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Intervento durante una lezione, Accademia di Scienze Naturali di Vaul[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]STORIA: In un mondo in cui è presente la magia spesso ci sono pochi motivi per chiedersi come funziona qualcosa in quanto la risposta, "È magico" è spesso vera. Per gli studiosi Mechanos questa risposta non è sufficente. Cos'è la magia e come si rapporta con il resto dell'universo? Nel porre queste domande, gli Adeptus dei Mechanos hanno imboccato la strada meno percorsa e faccendo ciò hanno sviluppato conoscenze e tecnologie che nessun'altra civiltà su Erebus potrebbe persino immaginare per via della loro accettazione del "È magico" per la maggior parte delle cose.</Italian>
		<Spanish>"Of course the Gods exist, boy! The point I'm trying to get into your sheepherders skull is what is a God? Power? I have power but that doesn't make me a God. Is it magic? Look at that lumos bulb over there? To some Doviello savage, I'm sure that looks as magical as any fireball but its just something we know how to do that he doesn't. So these Gods are merely beings that have power we don't have and knowledge we don't know...yet. If you'd knock out those old superstitions out of your head, you'd be on your way in finding those answers that will enable us to challenge these so called Gods and keep them from meddling in our rightful affairs."[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Lecture in progress, Vaul Academy of Natural Sciences[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: In a magical world, there is often little reason to question how something works since since the answer, "It is magic" is often a true statement. To the natural philosophy of the Mechanos, this answer is not enough. What is magic and how does it fit in to the rest of the universe? In asking these questions, the Mechanos Adeptus have taken the road less traveled and thus have brought forth knowledge and technology no other civilization of Erebus could even conceive of due to their preconceived acceptance of that simple answer "It is magic" as an answer to all things.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AQUILAN_THOPTER</Tag>
		<English>Aquilan Thopter</English>
		<French>Mécanoptère aquilin</French>
		<German>Aquilanischer Thopter</German>
		<Italian>Ornitottero Aquilino</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aquilan Thopter</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AQUILAN_THOPTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Yes, yes, yes, your fiery broadsides of the Decimator are impressive. I am sure the Khazad did their best when making those iron beasts for you. But let me ask you this laddy; how much good are they when we drop a bomb down into your hold, right into the lap of your cabin boy? You will be dining with the Aifons and those pretty cannons of yours will be the Overlords new play-toys![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Skyshark Crewman First Class Vitos remark which started the brawl at the Dancing Sea Turtle between crews according to witnesses.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]History: Advances in metallurgy and wood crafting made the Windriders airship design possible but didn't allow for much in the way of armaments. However with the advent of mana refining, Technomage Alset conceived the radical idea of using the refined mana as a fuel source similar to that of the newer steam engines being designed for the Ironclads. This mana fueled engined was much lighter but produced more power allowing for more armor and armaments. While far weaker than any ocean going vessel, the Skyraider airship's ability to quickly cross any terrain or body of water makes it feared throughout Erebus.</English>
		<French>"Yes, yes, yes, your fiery broadsides of the Decimator are impressive. I'm sure the Khazad did their best when making those iron beasts for you. But let me ask you this laddy; how much good are they when we drop a bomb down into your hold, right into the lap of your cabin boy? You'll be dining with the Aifons and those pretty cannons of yours will be the Overlords new play-toys!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Skyshark Crewman First Class Vito's remark which started the brawl at the Dancing Sea Turtle between crews according to witnesses.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]History: Advances in metallurgy and wood crafting made the Windriders airship design possible but didn't allow for much in the way of armaments. However with the advent of mana refining, Technomage Alset conceived the radical idea of using the refined mana as a fuel source similar to that of the newer steam engines being designed for the Ironclads. This mana fueled engined was much lighter but produced more power allowing for more armor and armaments. While far weaker than any ocean going vessel, the Skyraider airship's ability to quickly cross any terrain or body of water makes it feared throughout Erebus.</French>
		<German>"Yes, yes, yes, your fiery broadsides of the Decimator are impressive. I'm sure the Khazad did their best when making those iron beasts for you. But let me ask you this laddy; how much good are they when we drop a bomb down into your hold, right into the lap of your cabin boy? You'll be dining with the Aifons and those pretty cannons of yours will be the Overlords new play-toys!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Skyshark Crewman First Class Vito's remark which started the brawl at the Dancing Sea Turtle between crews according to witnesses.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]History: Advances in metallurgy and wood crafting made the Windriders airship design possible but didn't allow for much in the way of armaments. However with the advent of mana refining, Technomage Alset conceived the radical idea of using the refined mana as a fuel source similar to that of the newer steam engines being designed for the Ironclads. This mana fueled engined was much lighter but produced more power allowing for more armor and armaments. While far weaker than any ocean going vessel, the Skyraider airship's ability to quickly cross any terrain or body of water makes it feared throughout Erebus.</German>
		<Italian>"Si, si, si, le bordate del tuo Decimatore sono impressionanti. Sono sicuro che i Khazad hanno fatto del loro meglio quando creavano quei cannoni per te. Ma lascia che ti chieda questo ragazzo; quanto sono utili quando noi sganciamo una bomba dentro la tua stiva, proprio tra le mani del tuo ragazzo da cabina? Staresti cenando con gli Aifons e quei tuoi bei cannoni sarebbero il nuovo giocattolo dei Padroni!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Commento di Vito, Marinaio di Prima Classe della Skyshark, che scatenò una rissa tra equipaggi alla Tartaruga di Mare Danzante secondo i testimoni.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]STORIA: I progressi fatti nella metallurgia e nella lavorazione del legno resero il progetto dell'aeronave Cavalcavento fattibile anche se non permettevano molto riguardo gli armamenti. Tuttavia con l'avvento della raffinazione del mana il Tecnomago Alset concepì l'idea di usare il mana raffinato come carburante in maniera simile a quella dei nuovi motori a vapore progettati per le Corazzate. Questo motore alimentato a mana raffinato era molto più leggero ma produceva più energia permettendo di avere più armi e armatura. Sebbene parecchio più fragile di qualsiasi nave la aeronave Cavalcacielo poteva attraversare rapidamente quasiasi terreno o corpo d'acqua, rendendola temuta su Erebus.</Italian>
		<Spanish>"Yes, yes, yes, your fiery broadsides of the Decimator are impressive. I'm sure the Khazad did their best when making those iron beasts for you. But let me ask you this laddy; how much good are they when we drop a bomb down into your hold, right into the lap of your cabin boy? You'll be dining with the Aifons and those pretty cannons of yours will be the Overlords new play-toys!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Skyshark Crewman First Class Vito's remark which started the brawl at the Dancing Sea Turtle between crews according to witnesses.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]History: Advances in metallurgy and wood crafting made the Windriders airship design possible but didn't allow for much in the way of armaments. However with the advent of mana refining, Technomage Alset conceived the radical idea of using the refined mana as a fuel source similar to that of the newer steam engines being designed for the Ironclads. This mana fueled engined was much lighter but produced more power allowing for more armor and armaments. While far weaker than any ocean going vessel, the Skyraider airship's ability to quickly cross any terrain or body of water makes it feared throughout Erebus.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BORIS</Tag>
		<English>Boris</English>
		<French>Boris</French>
		<German>Boris</German>
		<Italian>Boris</Italian>
		<Spanish>Boris</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_BORIS_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>From that fateful day when stinking bits of slime first crawled from the sea and shouted to the cold stars, "I am man.", our greatest dread has always been the knowledge of our mortality. But tonight, we shall hurl the gauntlet of science into the frightful face of death itself. Tonight, we shall ascend into the heavens. We shall mock the earthquake. We shall command the thunders, and penetrate into the very womb of impervious nature herself.</English>
		<French>From that fateful day when stinking bits of slime first crawled from the sea and shouted to the cold stars, "I am man.", our greatest dread has always been the knowledge of our mortality. But tonight, we shall hurl the gauntlet of science into the frightful face of death itself. Tonight, we shall ascend into the heavens. We shall mock the earthquake. We shall command the thunders, and penetrate into the very womb of impervious nature herself.</French>
		<German>Von diesem schicksalshaften Tag an, als stinkende Schleimklumpen erstmals aus dem Meer krochen und den kalten Gestirnen entgegenbrüllten: "Seht her, ich bin ein Mensch!", von diesem Tage an entsprang unsere größte Frucht dem Wissen um unsere eigene Sterblichkeit. Doch heute Nacht werden wir den Fehdehandschuh erheben und ihn dem Tod selbst ins schreckliche Gesicht schleudern. Heut Nacht werden wir uns in den Himmel erheben. Wir werden dem Erdbeben trotzen. Wir werden den Donner beherrschen und in den undurchdringlichen Schoß von Mutter Natur selbst vordringen. </German>
		<Italian>From that fateful day when stinking bits of slime first crawled from the sea and shouted to the cold stars, "I am man.", our greatest dread has always been the knowledge of our mortality. But tonight, we shall hurl the gauntlet of science into the frightful face of death itself. Tonight, we shall ascend into the heavens. We shall mock the earthquake. We shall command the thunders, and penetrate into the very womb of impervious nature herself.</Italian>
		<Spanish>From that fateful day when stinking bits of slime first crawled from the sea and shouted to the cold stars, "I am man.", our greatest dread has always been the knowledge of our mortality. But tonight, we shall hurl the gauntlet of science into the frightful face of death itself. Tonight, we shall ascend into the heavens. We shall mock the earthquake. We shall command the thunders, and penetrate into the very womb of impervious nature herself.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DIRIGIBLE</Tag>
		<English>Dirigible Fleet</English>
		<French>Flotte de dirigeables</French>
		<German>Luftschiffflotte</German>
		<Italian>Flotta di Dirigibili</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dirigible Fleet</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGOON</Tag>
		<English>Dragoon</English>
		<French>Dragon</French>
		<German>Dragoner</German>
		<Italian>Dragone</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dragoon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DRAGOON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"The perfect marriage of man, mount and machine"[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer, Mechana Excelsior</English>
		<French>"The perfect marriage of man, mount and machine"[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer, Mechana Excelsior</French>
		<German>"Die perfekte Hochzeit von Mensch, Pferd und Maschine"[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer, Mechana Excelsior</German>
		<Italian>"L'unione perfetta tra uomo, cavalcatura e macchina"[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer, Mechana Excelsior</Italian>
		<Spanish>"The perfect marriage of man, mount and machine"[PARAGRAPH:1]Maer, Mechana Excelsior</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FERIS</Tag>
		<English>Feris</English>
		<French>Feris</French>
		<German>Feris</German>
		<Italian>Feris</Italian>
		<Spanish>Feris</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FERIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]How sharp is an eagle's eye but may be as blind as a mere mole compared to her steady gaze?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Technopriest Aslet after witnessing a shooting demonstration at the Mechanos Court.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Little is know of Feris' early life. Reliable rumors place her being born to a captain of horse in the village of Oakley but rumors these still be. Unlike so many bardic stories, the girl that would grow to become Feris' felt no need to pretend to be a man to enter military service. She marched right into tent of the commander of the newly formed Dragoons and made him a bet; if she could out-shoot him and his officers, they would allow her to join. Not only did she win, but to prove herself to all, she out-shot all of the officers a second time while mounted with the rest shot again while still on foot.[PARAGRAPH:1]Known for her unearthly sight, calm under pressure, soon Feris's fame was known to every Mechanos and many a enemy commander was knocked from their horse from a distances no one thought possible that a shot could be made. Yet for all her ability to shoot, Feris is beloved by her men for knowing when prudence is the better part of valor and not to be thrown away in useless charges done to coddle a male commander's ego.</English>
		<French>[TAB]How sharp is an eagle's eye but may be as blind as a mere mole compared to her steady gaze?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Technopriest Aslet after witnessing a shooting demonstration at the Mechanos Court.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Little is know of Feris' early life. Reliable rumors place her being born to a captain of horse in the village of Oakley but rumors these still be. Unlike so many bardic stories, the girl that would grow to become Feris' felt no need to pretend to be a man to enter military service. She marched right into tent of the commander of the newly formed Dragoons and made him a bet; if she could out-shoot him and his officers, they would allow her to join. Not only did she win, but to prove herself to all, she out-shot all of the officers a second time while mounted with the rest shot again while still on foot.[PARAGRAPH:1]Known for her unearthly sight, calm under pressure, soon Feris's fame was known to every Mechanos and many a enemy commander was knocked from their horse from a distances no one thought possible that a shot could be made. Yet for all her ability to shoot, Feris is beloved by her men for knowing when prudence is the better part of valor and not to be thrown away in useless charges done to coddle a male commander's ego.</French>
		<German>[TAB]How sharp is an eagle's eye but may be as blind as a mere mole compared to her steady gaze?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Technopriest Aslet after witnessing a shooting demonstration at the Mechanos Court.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Little is know of Feris' early life. Reliable rumors place her being born to a captain of horse in the village of Oakley but rumors these still be. Unlike so many bardic stories, the girl that would grow to become Feris' felt no need to pretend to be a man to enter military service. She marched right into tent of the commander of the newly formed Dragoons and made him a bet; if she could out-shoot him and his officers, they would allow her to join. Not only did she win, but to prove herself to all, she out-shot all of the officers a second time while mounted with the rest shot again while still on foot.[PARAGRAPH:1]Known for her unearthly sight, calm under pressure, soon Feris's fame was known to every Mechanos and many a enemy commander was knocked from their horse from a distances no one thought possible that a shot could be made. Yet for all her ability to shoot, Feris is beloved by her men for knowing when prudence is the better part of valor and not to be thrown away in useless charges done to coddle a male commander's ego.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Per quanto possa essere acuta la vista di un'aquila non sarebbe forse come quella di una talpa se messa a confronto con il suo sguardo fisso?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Tecnoprete Aslet dopo aver assistito a una dimostrazione di tiro alla corte Mechanos.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]STORIA: Poco si sa riguardo l'infanzia di Feris. Voci attendibili dicono che sia la figlia di un capitano di cavalleria nel villaggio di Oakley, ma rimangono pur sempre voci. Diversamente dalla maggior parte delle storie dei bardi la ragazza che crescendo sarebbe diventata Feris non sentiva alcun bisogno di fingere di essere un uomo per entrare nelle forze armate. Lei marciò sin dentro la tenda del comandante dei Dragoni appena istituiti e gli propose una scommessa; se fosse riuscita a battere lui e i suoi ufficiali a una gara di tiro, loro gli avrebbero permesso di unirsi a loro. Non solo lei vinse, ma per dimostrare quanto valesse, li batté tutti una seconda volta mentre lei sparava da cavallo e gli altri in piedi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rinomata per la sua vista soprannaturale e la calma sotto pressione, in poco tempo Feris fu nota a tutti i Mechanos e diversi comandanti nemici furono eliminati da una distanza alla quale nessuno pensava fosse possibile colpire. Inoltre, oltre alla sua abilità nel tiro, Feris è amata dai suoi uomini per sapere quando la prudenza è preferibile al fare inutili cariche per soddisfare l'ego di un comandante maschio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]How sharp is an eagle's eye but may be as blind as a mere mole compared to her steady gaze?[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Technopriest Aslet after witnessing a shooting demonstration at the Mechanos Court.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Little is know of Feris' early life. Reliable rumors place her being born to a captain of horse in the village of Oakley but rumors these still be. Unlike so many bardic stories, the girl that would grow to become Feris' felt no need to pretend to be a man to enter military service. She marched right into tent of the commander of the newly formed Dragoons and made him a bet; if she could out-shoot him and his officers, they would allow her to join. Not only did she win, but to prove herself to all, she out-shot all of the officers a second time while mounted with the rest shot again while still on foot.[PARAGRAPH:1]Known for her unearthly sight, calm under pressure, soon Feris's fame was known to every Mechanos and many a enemy commander was knocked from their horse from a distances no one thought possible that a shot could be made. Yet for all her ability to shoot, Feris is beloved by her men for knowing when prudence is the better part of valor and not to be thrown away in useless charges done to coddle a male commander's ego.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_FERIS_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>Known for her unearthly sight, calm under pressure, soon Feris's fame was known to every Mechanos and many a enemy commander was knocked from their horse from a distances no one thought possible that a shot could be made. Yet for all her ability to shoot, Feris is beloved by her men for knowing when prudence is the better part of valor and not to be thrown away in useless charges done to coddle a male commander's ego.</English>
		<French>Known for her unearthly sight, calm under pressure, soon Feris's fame was known to every Mechanos and many a enemy commander was knocked from their horse from a distances no one thought possible that a shot could be made. Yet for all her ability to shoot, Feris is beloved by her men for knowing when prudence is the better part of valor and not to be thrown away in useless charges done to coddle a male commander's ego.</French>
		<German>Aufgrund ihrer überirdischen Sichtweite und ihrer Gelassenheit war Feris bald jedem Mechanos bekannt. Nicht wenige feindliche Kommandanten fielen von ihren Pferden, ohne glauben zu können, dass aus dieser Entfernung überhaupt ein Schuss möglich sei. Neben ihrer Zielgenauigkeit ist Feris jedoch mehr noch bei ihren Leuten aufgrund der Tatsache beliebt, dass sehr gut weiß, wann Besonnenheit besser als Heldenmut ist, und dass ihr Gefolge nicht in sinnlosen Angriffen verpulvert wird, um ein männliches Ego zu streicheln.</German>
		<Italian>Rinomata per la sua vista soprannaturale e la calma sotto pressione, in poco tempo Feris fu nota a tutti i Mechanos e diversi comandanti nemici furono eliminati da una distanza alla quale nessuno pensava fosse possibile colpire. Inoltre, oltre alla sua abilità nel tiro, Feris è amata dai suoi uomini per sapere quando la prudenza è preferibile al fare inutili cariche per soddisfare l'ego di un comandante maschio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Known for her unearthly sight, calm under pressure, soon Feris's fame was known to every Mechanos and many a enemy commander was knocked from their horse from a distances no one thought possible that a shot could be made. Yet for all her ability to shoot, Feris is beloved by her men for knowing when prudence is the better part of valor and not to be thrown away in useless charges done to coddle a male commander's ego.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FLAMETHROWER</Tag>
		<English>Flamethrower</English>
		<French>Lance-flammes</French>
		<German>Flammenwerfer</German>
		<Italian>Lanciafiamme</Italian>
		<Spanish>Flamethrower</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FLAMETHROWER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Think for a moment about the concept of the flamethrower. Okay? The flamethrower. Because we have them. Well, *we* don't have them, the Mechanos has them. That's right. We don't have any flamethrowers. I' would say we are screwed if we have to go up against the Mechanos , would you not? But there are flamethrowers. And what this indicates to me, it means that at some point, some person said to himself, "Gee, I sure would like to set those people on fire over there. But I am way to far away to get the job done. If only I had something that would throw flame on them." Well, it might have ended right there, but he mentioned it to his Adeptus friend. His friend who was good with tools. And about a month later, he was back. "Hey, quite a concept!" WHHOOOOOOOOSSHHH! And of course the Mechanos army heard about it, and they came around. "We would like to buy about five hundred-thousand of them please. We have some people we'd like to throw flame on. Give us five hundred thousand and paint them dark brown. We don't want anyone to see them!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Balseraph comedic thespian Gyorgy Karlyn before the Perpentarch Court[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Soldiers throughout the ages have steeled themselves to the onrushing line of troops or stood firm even when charged by cavalry or hail of arrows. Yet few are those that can stand to when a fire is directed at them with hellish precision. The Mechanos 'firemen' are a special kind of soldier; some are volunteers while others enlist for a certain time to be pardoned for their crimes. For while they are feared, the danger of going into battle with a tank of volatile liquid on their back is one that rarely allows them to retire after the wars are done.</English>
		<French>"Think for a moment about the concept of the flamethrower. Okay? The flamethrower. Because we have them. Well, *we* don't have them, the Mechanos has them. That's right. We don't have any flamethrowers. I' would say we are screwed if we have to go up against the Mechanos , would you not? But there are flamethrowers. And what this indicates to me, it means that at some point, some person said to himself, "Gee, I sure would like to set those people on fire over there. But I am way to far away to get the job done. If only I had something that would throw flame on them." Well, it might have ended right there, but he mentioned it to his Adeptus friend. His friend who was good with tools. And about a month later, he was back. "Hey, quite a concept!" WHHOOOOOOOOSSHHH! And of course the Mechanos army heard about it, and they came around. "We would like to buy about five hundred-thousand of them please. We have some people we'd like to throw flame on. Give us five hundred thousand and paint them dark brown. We don't want anyone to see them!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Balseraph comedic thespian Gyorgy Karlyn before the Perpentarch Court[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Soldiers throughout the ages have steeled themselves to the onrushing line of troops or stood firm even when charged by cavalry or hail of arrows. Yet few are those that can stand to when a fire is directed at them with hellish precision. The Mechanos 'firemen' are a special kind of soldier; some are volunteers while others enlist for a certain time to be pardoned for their crimes. For while they are feared, the danger of going into battle with a tank of volatile liquid on their back is one that rarely allows them to retire after the wars are done.</French>
		<German>"Think for a moment about the concept of the flamethrower. Okay? The flamethrower. Because we have them. Well, *we* don't have them, the Mechanos has them. That's right. We don't have any flamethrowers. I' would say we are screwed if we have to go up against the Mechanos , would you not? But there are flamethrowers. And what this indicates to me, it means that at some point, some person said to himself, "Gee, I sure would like to set those people on fire over there. But I am way to far away to get the job done. If only I had something that would throw flame on them." Well, it might have ended right there, but he mentioned it to his Adeptus friend. His friend who was good with tools. And about a month later, he was back. "Hey, quite a concept!" WHHOOOOOOOOSSHHH! And of course the Mechanos army heard about it, and they came around. "We would like to buy about five hundred-thousand of them please. We have some people we'd like to throw flame on. Give us five hundred thousand and paint them dark brown. We don't want anyone to see them!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Balseraph comedic thespian Gyorgy Karlyn before the Perpentarch Court[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Soldiers throughout the ages have steeled themselves to the onrushing line of troops or stood firm even when charged by cavalry or hail of arrows. Yet few are those that can stand to when a fire is directed at them with hellish precision. The Mechanos 'firemen' are a special kind of soldier; some are volunteers while others enlist for a certain time to be pardoned for their crimes. For while they are feared, the danger of going into battle with a tank of volatile liquid on their back is one that rarely allows them to retire after the wars are done.</German>
		<Italian>"Pensate per un momento a un lanciafiamme. Okay? Il lanciafiamme. Perché noi li abbiamo. Beh, *noi* non li abbiamo, i Mechanos li hanno. Giusto. Noi non abbiamo alcun lanciafiamme. Direi che saremo fregati se dovessimo andare contro i Mechanos, non credete? Ma esistono i lanciafiamme. E questo mi suggerisce che a un certo punto qualcuno si è detto "Eee, mi piacerebbe incendiare quelle persone li. Ma io sono troppo distante per farlo. Se solo avessi qualcosa per lanciargli le fiamme addosso". Insomma, si sarebbe potuto fermare li, ma lui lo disse al suo amico Adeptus. L'amico che era bravo con gli strumenti. E quasi un mese dopo lui tornò. "Hey, bella idea!" WHHOOOOOOOOSSHHH! E ovviamente l'esercito Mechanos lo venne a sapere, e dissero. "Ci piacerebbe comprare intorno alle 500.000 unità per favore. Ci sono alcune persone a cui vorremmo lanciare delle fiamme. Datecene 500.000 e colorateli marrone scuro. Non vogliamo che qualcuno li veda!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Comico Balseraph Gyorgy Karlyn alla Corte di Perpentarch[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]STORIA: I soldati, nel corso delle ere, si preparavano all'urto contro i nemici e rimanevano fermi anche quando caricati dalla cavalleria o presi di mira dalle frecce. Nonostante ciò pochi erano coloro che rimanevano fermi quando il fuoco veniva diretto verso di loro con precisione infernale. Gli 'uomini del fuoco' Mechanos sono un tipo speciale di soldato; alcuni sono volontari mentre altri si arruolano per un certo periodo di tempo per ottenere la grazia per i loro crimini. In quanto, sebbene temuti, l'andare in battaglia con un serbatoio di liquido infiammabile sulla schiena raramente gli permette di arrivare alla fine della guerra.</Italian>
		<Spanish>"Think for a moment about the concept of the flamethrower. Okay? The flamethrower. Because we have them. Well, *we* don't have them, the Mechanos has them. That's right. We don't have any flamethrowers. I' would say we are screwed if we have to go up against the Mechanos , would you not? But there are flamethrowers. And what this indicates to me, it means that at some point, some person said to himself, "Gee, I sure would like to set those people on fire over there. But I am way to far away to get the job done. If only I had something that would throw flame on them." Well, it might have ended right there, but he mentioned it to his Adeptus friend. His friend who was good with tools. And about a month later, he was back. "Hey, quite a concept!" WHHOOOOOOOOSSHHH! And of course the Mechanos army heard about it, and they came around. "We would like to buy about five hundred-thousand of them please. We have some people we'd like to throw flame on. Give us five hundred thousand and paint them dark brown. We don't want anyone to see them!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Balseraph comedic thespian Gyorgy Karlyn before the Perpentarch Court[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]HISTORY: Soldiers throughout the ages have steeled themselves to the onrushing line of troops or stood firm even when charged by cavalry or hail of arrows. Yet few are those that can stand to when a fire is directed at them with hellish precision. The Mechanos 'firemen' are a special kind of soldier; some are volunteers while others enlist for a certain time to be pardoned for their crimes. For while they are feared, the danger of going into battle with a tank of volatile liquid on their back is one that rarely allows them to retire after the wars are done.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GOLIATH</Tag>
		<English>Goliath</English>
		<French>Goliath</French>
		<German>Goliath</German>
		<Italian>Goliath</Italian>
		<Spanish>Goliath</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GOLIATH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]What thoughts do you have for the machine? How do you deny the guilt when even your tears stalk the earth crushing those who would oppose its ruin? How cold is the sense of isolation when nature lies dead and frost seizes all in its thrall? But for memories of the world as was, would the world always be white? And what would be worse, to surrender the memories of better times or to discard the error that it might be repeated? When can the pain ever grow numb, when even the escape of dream is denied? Let the memories of all that is hateful, of all the sin and guilt, run through the cracks of the earth, that they might burn in the fires beyond.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Barnaxus, acting on inscrutable commands that even he did not understand, crafted Ice Golems for the great god Mulcarn, he chose to forget all that he had done, forever cursed to repeat his mistake until Spring dawned upon Erebus. Every regret was ejected in a cascade of sparks, fleeting moments that die upon the wind.[PARAGRAPH:1]But no sin is truly vanquished without repentance. The shadow thoughts drifted forgotten in dark corners until they found a home they recognised. Settling in the cogs and the camshafts and the gears and the cranks, the first machine spirits were born. Swearing revenge on the gods that had forgotten the world, they sought to bring about new age without gods: the Age of Machines.[PARAGRAPH:1]All they needed was a body.</English>
		<French>[PARAGRAPH:1]What thoughts for the machine? How deny the guilt when even your tears stalk the earth crushing those who would oppose its ruin? How cold the sense of isolation when nature lies dead and frost seizes all in its thrall? But for memories of the world as was, would the world always be white? And what would it be worse to surrender the memories of better times or to discard the error that it might be repeated? For when can the pain ever grow numb, when even the escape of dream is denied. Let the memories of all that is hateful, of all the sin and guilt run through the cracks of the earth, that they might burn in the fires beyond.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Barnaxus, acting on the inscrutable commands that even he did not understand, crafted Ice Golems for the great god Mulcarn, he chose to forget all that he had done, forever cursed to repeat his mistake until Spring dawned upon Erebus. Every regret was ejected in a cascade of sparks, fleeting moments that die upon the wind.[PARAGRAPH:1]But no sin is truly vanquished without repentance. The shadow thoughts drifted forgotten in dark corners until they found a home they recognised. Settling in the cogs and the camshafts and the gears and the cranks, the first machine spirits were born. Swearing revenge on the gods that had forgotten the world, they sought to bring about new age without gods: the Age of Machines.[PARAGRAPH:1]All they needed was a body.</French>
		<German>[PARAGRAPH:1]What thoughts for the machine? How deny the guilt when even your tears stalk the earth crushing those who would oppose its ruin? How cold the sense of isolation when nature lies dead and frost seizes all in its thrall? But for memories of the world as was, would the world always be white? And what would it be worse to surrender the memories of better times or to discard the error that it might be repeated? For when can the pain ever grow numb, when even the escape of dream is denied. Let the memories of all that is hateful, of all the sin and guilt run through the cracks of the earth, that they might burn in the fires beyond.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Barnaxus, acting on the inscrutable commands that even he did not understand, crafted Ice Golems for the great god Mulcarn, he chose to forget all that he had done, forever cursed to repeat his mistake until Spring dawned upon Erebus. Every regret was ejected in a cascade of sparks, fleeting moments that die upon the wind.[PARAGRAPH:1]But no sin is truly vanquished without repentance. The shadow thoughts drifted forgotten in dark corners until they found a home they recognised. Settling in the cogs and the camshafts and the gears and the cranks, the first machine spirits were born. Swearing revenge on the gods that had forgotten the world, they sought to bring about new age without gods: the Age of Machines.[PARAGRAPH:1]All they needed was a body.</German>
		<Italian>[PARAGRAPH:1]Cosa pensi della macchina? Come puoi negare la tua colpa quando persino le tue lacrime vagano per il mondo schiacciando coloro che si oppongono alla sua rovina? Quanto è freddo il senso di isolamento quando la natura giace morta e tutto è gelato? Ma per quanto ricordi il mondo sarebbe sempre stato bianco? E cosa sarebbe peggio, eliminare i ricordi di tempi migliori o dimenticare l'errore che può essere ripetuto? Per quando il dolore ti intorpidisce, quando persino la fuga nel sogno viene negata. Lascia che i ricordi di tutto ciò che odia, di tutti i peccati e le colpe passi nelle crepe della terra, cosi che possano bruciare nelle fiamme.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quando Barnaxus, seguendo ordini imperscrutabili che persino lui non comprendeva, creava i Golem di Ghiaccio per il grande dio Mulcarn, decise di dimenticare tutto ciò che faceva, condannato a ripetere sempre lo stesso errore fino a quando la Primavera sarebbe arrivata su Erebus. Ogni rimpianto fu espulso con una cascata di scintille, momenti fugaci che sarebbero morti nel vento.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ma nessun crimine è sparisce veramente senza pentimento. Questi pensieri ombra vagarono dimenticati in posti oscuri fino a quando non trovarono una posto che riconoscevano. Insediandosi in ingranaggi, leve e meccanismi nacquero i primi spiriti macchina. Giurando vendetta verso gli dei che avevano dimenticato il mondo intendono iniziare una nuova era senza dei: l'Era delle Macchine.[PARAGRAPH:1]Tutto ciò di cui avevano bisogno era un corpo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[PARAGRAPH:1]What thoughts for the machine? How deny the guilt when even your tears stalk the earth crushing those who would oppose its ruin? How cold the sense of isolation when nature lies dead and frost seizes all in its thrall? But for memories of the world as was, would the world always be white? And what would it be worse to surrender the memories of better times or to discard the error that it might be repeated? For when can the pain ever grow numb, when even the escape of dream is denied. Let the memories of all that is hateful, of all the sin and guilt run through the cracks of the earth, that they might burn in the fires beyond.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Barnaxus, acting on the inscrutable commands that even he did not understand, crafted Ice Golems for the great god Mulcarn, he chose to forget all that he had done, forever cursed to repeat his mistake until Spring dawned upon Erebus. Every regret was ejected in a cascade of sparks, fleeting moments that die upon the wind.[PARAGRAPH:1]But no sin is truly vanquished without repentance. The shadow thoughts drifted forgotten in dark corners until they found a home they recognised. Settling in the cogs and the camshafts and the gears and the cranks, the first machine spirits were born. Swearing revenge on the gods that had forgotten the world, they sought to bring about new age without gods: the Age of Machines.[PARAGRAPH:1]All they needed was a body.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_GOLIATH_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>Goliath was created</English>
		<French>Goliath a été créé</French>
		<German>Goliath wurde erschaffen</German>
		<Italian>Goliath è stato creato</Italian>
		<Spanish>Goliath was created</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GRENADIER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Ya see, we was lined up in formation like we always was, ya see? Them Mechanos was running at us with rocks, ya see? No metal monstrosities, no boomsticks, just rocks. And we wasn't very worried ya see, cause what can rocks do to armor and swords? But ya see, when they were still 20 paces off, they raised their arms and started throwing their rocks. Sure, the rocks bounced off our armor, and the order to march was given. But ya see, we hadn't marched four steps when I hear the loudest sound I ever heard. Them wasn't no rocks. 'T was some new Mechanos contraption. The screams of my fellow soldiers still haunt my dreams. By the Gods, if they don't use magic, I don't know what they use.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]A former Bannor champion, telling the tale of the defeat of the "invincible" 2nd legion[\ITALICS][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I've found a new use for gunpowder. Musket balls are all well and good at long range, but what about when the enemy is right on top of you? We take a metal canister, fill it with 2 dozen musket balls and plenty of powder, then seal it up good. When the soldier is ready, he inserts the detonator cap, this small cylindrical object, and breaks it off. He now has 8 seconds, more or less,before it goes off. He throws it into the enemy line, and BOOM, several dead enemies and many more wounded ones. A good soldier should be able to throw 2 of them in 10 seconds. Are you interested in putting the new weapon into production?[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]The Mechanos Weapons Researcher Grenadier, the day before the raising of the "First Hand Held Explosives Unit."[\ITALICS]</English>
		<French>Ya see, we was lined up in formation like we always was, ya see? Them Mechanos was running at us with rocks, ya see? No metal monstrosities, no boomsticks, just rocks. And we wasn't very worried ya see, cause what can rocks do to armor and swords? But ya see, when they were still 20 paces off, they raised their arms and started throwing their rocks. Sure, the rocks bounced off our armor, and the order to march was given. But ya see, we hadn't marched four steps when I hear the loudest sound I ever heard. Them wasn't no rocks. 'T was some new Mechanos contraption. The screams of my fellow soldiers still haunt my dreams. By the Gods, if they don't use magic, I don't know what they use.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]A former Bannor champion, telling the tale of the defeat of the "invincible" 2nd legion[\ITALICS][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I've found a new use for gunpowder. Musket balls are all well and good at long range, but what about when the enemy is right on top of you? We take a metal canister, fill it with 2 dozen musket balls and plenty of powder, then seal it up good. When the soldier is ready, he inserts the detonator cap, this small cylindrical object, and breaks it off. He now has 8 seconds, more or less,before it goes off. He throws it into the enemy line, and BOOM, several dead enemies and many more wounded ones. A good soldier should be able to throw 2 of them in 10 seconds. Are you interested in putting the new weapon into production?[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]The Mechanos Weapons Researcher Grenadier, the day before the raising of the "First Hand Held Explosives Unit."[\ITALICS]</French>
		<German>Ya see, we was lined up in formation like we always was, ya see? Them Mechanos was running at us with rocks, ya see? No metal monstrosities, no boomsticks, just rocks. And we wasn't very worried ya see, cause what can rocks do to armor and swords? But ya see, when they were still 20 paces off, they raised their arms and started throwing their rocks. Sure, the rocks bounced off our armor, and the order to march was given. But ya see, we hadn't marched four steps when I hear the loudest sound I ever heard. Them wasn't no rocks. 'T was some new Mechanos contraption. The screams of my fellow soldiers still haunt my dreams. By the Gods, if they don't use magic, I don't know what they use.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]A former Bannor champion, telling the tale of the defeat of the "invincible" 2nd legion[\ITALICS][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I've found a new use for gunpowder. Musket balls are all well and good at long range, but what about when the enemy is right on top of you? We take a metal canister, fill it with 2 dozen musket balls and plenty of powder, then seal it up good. When the soldier is ready, he inserts the detonator cap, this small cylindrical object, and breaks it off. He now has 8 seconds, more or less,before it goes off. He throws it into the enemy line, and BOOM, several dead enemies and many more wounded ones. A good soldier should be able to throw 2 of them in 10 seconds. Are you interested in putting the new weapon into production?[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]The Mechanos Weapons Researcher Grenadier, the day before the raising of the "First Hand Held Explosives Unit."[\ITALICS]</German>
		<Italian>Vedi, eravamo schierati in formazione come sempre, vedi? I Mechanos stavano correndo verso di noi con delle pietre, vedi? Nessuna mostruosità metallica, nessun bastone tonante, solo pietre. E noi non eravamo molto preoccupati vedi, perché cosa possono fare delle pietre contro le armature e spade? Ma vedi, quando erano ancora a 20 passi di distanza iniziarono a lanciarle. Certo, le pietre rimbalzarono sulle nostre armature, e l'ordine di avanzare fu dato. Ma vedi, non avevamo fatto neppure quattro passi quando sentii il rumore più forte della mia vita. Quelle non erano pietre. Erano una nuova diavoleria Mechanos. Le urla dei miei compagni mi perseguitano tuttora negli incubi. Per gli Dei, se non usano la magia non ho idea di cosa fosse.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Un ex campione Bannor che racconta la sconfitta della "invincibile" 2° legione[\ITALICS][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ho un nuovo utilizzo per la polvere da sparo. I proiettili per moschetto vanno bene alle lunghe distanze, ma per quando il nemico ti è praticamente a fianco? Prendiamo un contenitore metallico, lo riempiamo di due dozzine di proiettili da moschetto e abbondante polvere e poi lo sigilliamo bene. Quando il soldato è pronto inserisce l'innesco, questo piccolo cilindretto, e lo spezza. Dal quel momento ha 8 secondi, più o meno, prima che esploda. La lancia verso i nemici e BOOM, molteplici nemici morti e ancor più feriti. Un soldato capace dovrebbe riuscire a lanciarne 2 in 10 secondi. Siete interessati a produrre questa nuova arma?[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Lo Svilupatore di Armi Mechanos Grenadier, il giorno prima dell'istituzione della "Prima Unità Esplosivi Portatili."[\ITALICS]</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ya see, we was lined up in formation like we always was, ya see? Them Mechanos was running at us with rocks, ya see? No metal monstrosities, no boomsticks, just rocks. And we wasn't very worried ya see, cause what can rocks do to armor and swords? But ya see, when they were still 20 paces off, they raised their arms and started throwing their rocks. Sure, the rocks bounced off our armor, and the order to march was given. But ya see, we hadn't marched four steps when I hear the loudest sound I ever heard. Them wasn't no rocks. 'T was some new Mechanos contraption. The screams of my fellow soldiers still haunt my dreams. By the Gods, if they don't use magic, I don't know what they use.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]A former Bannor champion, telling the tale of the defeat of the "invincible" 2nd legion[\ITALICS][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]I've found a new use for gunpowder. Musket balls are all well and good at long range, but what about when the enemy is right on top of you? We take a metal canister, fill it with 2 dozen musket balls and plenty of powder, then seal it up good. When the soldier is ready, he inserts the detonator cap, this small cylindrical object, and breaks it off. He now has 8 seconds, more or less,before it goes off. He throws it into the enemy line, and BOOM, several dead enemies and many more wounded ones. A good soldier should be able to throw 2 of them in 10 seconds. Are you interested in putting the new weapon into production?[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]The Mechanos Weapons Researcher Grenadier, the day before the raising of the "First Hand Held Explosives Unit."[\ITALICS]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HANDGUNNER</Tag>
		<English>Handgunner</English>
		<French>Fusilier</French>
		<German>Gewehrschütze</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Schioppettiere:Schioppettieri</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>Handgunner</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HANDGUNNER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>What infernal mind come have created such a device? It requires no strength to hold nor skill to aim. It bursts with the crack of the demons whip and runs on the ash of fires burnt dim. The wielder has little need for training and need never view the countenance of his victim. I can only be thankful that the Mechanos are presently engaged against the Bannor and show no interest in our forest lands.[PARAGRAPH:1]Algas the Mild, Elven Herbalist</English>
		<French>What infernal mind come have created such a device? It requires no strength to hold nor skill to aim. It bursts with the crack of the demons whip and runs on the ash of fires burnt dim. The wielder has little need for training and need never view the countenance of his victim. I can only be thankful that the Mechanos are presently engaged against the Bannor and show no interest in our forest lands.[PARAGRAPH:1]Algas the Mild, Elven Herbalist</French>
		<German>What infernal mind come have created such a device? It requires no strength to hold nor skill to aim. It bursts with the crack of the demons whip and runs on the ash of fires burnt dim. The wielder has little need for training and need never view the countenance of his victim. I can only be thankful that the Mechanos are presently engaged against the Bannor and show no interest in our forest lands.[PARAGRAPH:1]Algas the Mild, Elven Herbalist</German>
		<Italian>Quale mente infernale può aver creato tale strumento? Non richiede alcuna forza ne abilità nella mira. Fa lo stesso rumore delle fruste demoniache e usa la cenere di fuochi soffocati. L'utilizzatore necessità di poco addestramento e non vede mai il volto della sua vittima. Posso solo essere grato che i Mechanos siano attualmente impegnati con i Bannor e non mostrino interesse nelle nostre foreste.[PARAGRAPH:1]Algas il Mite, Erborista Elfico</Italian>
		<Spanish>What infernal mind come have created such a device? It requires no strength to hold nor skill to aim. It bursts with the crack of the demons whip and runs on the ash of fires burnt dim. The wielder has little need for training and need never view the countenance of his victim. I can only be thankful that the Mechanos are presently engaged against the Bannor and show no interest in our forest lands.[PARAGRAPH:1]Algas the Mild, Elven Herbalist</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_LENORA</Tag>
		<English>Lenora</English>
		<French>Lenora</French>
		<German>Lenora</German>
		<Italian>Lenora</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lenora</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MECHANOS_CANNON</Tag>
		<English>Howitzer</English>
		<French>Obusier</French>
		<German>Howitzer</German>
		<Italian>Obice</Italian>
		<Spanish>Howitzer</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOBILE_FORTRESS</Tag>
		<English>Mobile Fortress</English>
		<French>Forteresse mobile</French>
		<German>Mobile Festung</German>
		<Italian>Fortezza Mobile</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mobile Fortress</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOBILE_FORTRESS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>And now I come to one of the most feared weapons in the Mechanos arsenal. The Mobile Fortress. They are the size of cites and citadels. They are ringed with layers upon layers of defensive works and cannons of all sizes. They can inflict terrible damage at ranges thought unimaginable. To all Bannor Generals, I implore you to evade these terrible fortresses at all costs. This war will not be one by destroying the enemies armies. Their black powder and cannon ensure that. We will win by attacking their farmland, and their people. In an open battle against of their armies lead by such a terrible monstrosity, only death awaits. You will hear and smell the enemy long before you see him. Black smoke will fill the sky, just as the sound of ten thousand gears and crankshafts and hammers will fill the air. The only advantage you retain is speed. Such dreadful enemies as the fortress are slow, and easy to avoid. A city cannot escape however. We must bring the war to an end before our people are slowly decimated by these ten story tall giants.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]A page out of a manuscript entitled "The Mechanos: Their Armies, Equipment, and Tactics"[\ITALICS]</English>
		<French>And now I come to one of the most feared weapons in the Mechanos arsenal. The Mobile Fortress. They are the size of cites and citadels. They are ringed with layers upon layers of defensive works and cannons of all sizes. They can inflict terrible damage at ranges thought unimaginable. To all Bannor Generals, I implore you to evade these terrible fortresses at all costs. This war will not be one by destroying the enemies armies. Their black powder and cannon ensure that. We will win by attacking their farmland, and their people. In an open battle against of their armies lead by such a terrible monstrosity, only death awaits. You will hear and smell the enemy long before you see him. Black smoke will fill the sky, just as the sound of ten thousand gears and crankshafts and hammers will fill the air. The only advantage you retain is speed. Such dreadful enemies as the fortress are slow, and easy to avoid. A city cannot escape however. We must bring the war to an end before our people are slowly decimated by these ten story tall giants.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]A page out of a manuscript entitled "The Mechanos: Their Armies, Equipment, and Tactics"[\ITALICS]</French>
		<German>And now I come to one of the most feared weapons in the Mechanos arsenal. The Mobile Fortress. They are the size of cites and citadels. They are ringed with layers upon layers of defensive works and cannons of all sizes. They can inflict terrible damage at ranges thought unimaginable. To all Bannor Generals, I implore you to evade these terrible fortresses at all costs. This war will not be one by destroying the enemies armies. Their black powder and cannon ensure that. We will win by attacking their farmland, and their people. In an open battle against of their armies lead by such a terrible monstrosity, only death awaits. You will hear and smell the enemy long before you see him. Black smoke will fill the sky, just as the sound of ten thousand gears and crankshafts and hammers will fill the air. The only advantage you retain is speed. Such dreadful enemies as the fortress are slow, and easy to avoid. A city cannot escape however. We must bring the war to an end before our people are slowly decimated by these ten story tall giants.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]A page out of a manuscript entitled "The Mechanos: Their Armies, Equipment, and Tactics"[\ITALICS]</German>
		<Italian>Ed ora arrivo a una delle armi più temute dell'arsenale Mechanos. La Fortezza Mobile. Grandi quanto città e roccaforti. Sono circondate da strati di opere difensive e cannoni di tutti i tipi. Possono infliggere terribili danni a distanze inimmaginabili. A tutti i Generali Bannor, vi imploro di evitare queste terribili fortezze ad ogni costo. Questa guerra non si può vincere distruggendo i loro eserciti. La loro polvere nera e i loro cannoni non lo permettono. La possiamo vincere attaccando le loro fattorie e la loro gente. In una battaglia campale contro i loro eserciti guidati da tali terribili mostruosità la morte è l'unico risultato. Sentirete il rumore e l'odore del nemico molto prima di vederlo. Del fumo nero riempirà il cielo, mentre il rumore di migliaia di inggranaggi, leve e martelli riempira l'aria. Il vostro unico vantaggio è la velocità. Tali nemici sono lenti, e facili da evitare. Una città però non può scappare. Dobbiamo terminare la guerra prima che il nostro popolo sia lentamente decimato da questi colossi.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]Una pagina dal manoscritto intitolato "I Mechanos: I loro Eserciti, Equipaggiamenti e Tattiche"[\ITALICS]</Italian>
		<Spanish>And now I come to one of the most feared weapons in the Mechanos arsenal. The Mobile Fortress. They are the size of cites and citadels. They are ringed with layers upon layers of defensive works and cannons of all sizes. They can inflict terrible damage at ranges thought unimaginable. To all Bannor Generals, I implore you to evade these terrible fortresses at all costs. This war will not be one by destroying the enemies armies. Their black powder and cannon ensure that. We will win by attacking their farmland, and their people. In an open battle against of their armies lead by such a terrible monstrosity, only death awaits. You will hear and smell the enemy long before you see him. Black smoke will fill the sky, just as the sound of ten thousand gears and crankshafts and hammers will fill the air. The only advantage you retain is speed. Such dreadful enemies as the fortress are slow, and easy to avoid. A city cannot escape however. We must bring the war to an end before our people are slowly decimated by these ten story tall giants.[PARAGRAPH:2][ITALICS]A page out of a manuscript entitled "The Mechanos: Their Armies, Equipment, and Tactics"[\ITALICS]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MUSKETMAN</Tag>
		<English>Musketman</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Mousquetaire</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Musketier</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Moschettiere:Moschettieri</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>
			<Text>Mosquete:Mosquetes</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MUSKETMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Handle your piece![NEWLINE][TAB]Take forth your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Blow off your coal![NEWLINE][TAB]Cock your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Try your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Guard your pan![NEWLINE][TAB]Blow off the coal![NEWLINE][TAB]Present and give fire![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Mechanos Master Sergeant of Drill Massimiliano giving musket commands to recruits[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]History: To the those unfamiliar with the tools of war, the musket seems at first to be a poor substitute to the bow. Yet while a trained bowman can often fire faster, farther and with greater accuracy, the musket provides three things that make it the "Queen of Battle" and that is shock, wounding power and ease of training. While a wave of arrows arcing into a formation is impressive, the truth is that in the time it took to train all those archers, many more musketmen could be fielded. As dangerous as the arrows of the Ljosalfar are, they often fail to create a killing or incapacitating wound. Not so the musket ball and even if the bullet fails to kill, if the wounded doesn't get prompt surgery or magical healing, infection from the embedded ball will send them to their God just as surely. Finally, while waves of arrows can shatter the nerve of even the most hardened veteran, the full shock of a line of musketeers giving fire is hard to beat. Even Bannor crusaders have been known to check their headlong rush when faced with the tight, disciplined blocks of Mechanos musketmen.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Handle your piece![NEWLINE][TAB]Take forth your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Blow off your coal![NEWLINE][TAB]Cock your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Try your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Guard your pan![NEWLINE][TAB]Blow off the coal![NEWLINE][TAB]Present and give fire![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Mechanos Master Sergeant of Drill Massimiliano giving musket commands to recruits[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]History: To the those unfamiliar with the tools of war, the musket seems at first to be a poor substitute to the bow. Yet while a trained bowman can often fire faster, farther and with greater accuracy, the musket provides three things that make it the "Queen of Battle" and that is shock, wounding power and ease of training. While a wave of arrows arcing into a formation is impressive, the truth is that in the time it took to train all those archers, many more musketmen could be fielded. As dangerous as the arrows of the Ljosalfar are, they often fail to create a killing or incapacitating wound. Not so the musket ball and even if the bullet fails to kill, if the wounded doesn't get prompt surgery or magical healing, infection from the embedded ball will send them to their God just as surely. Finally, while waves of arrows can shatter the nerve of even the most hardened veteran, the full shock of a line of musketeers giving fire is hard to beat. Even Bannor crusaders have been known to check their headlong rush when faced with the tight, disciplined blocks of Mechanos musketmen.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Handle your piece![NEWLINE][TAB]Take forth your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Blow off your coal![NEWLINE][TAB]Cock your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Try your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Guard your pan![NEWLINE][TAB]Blow off the coal![NEWLINE][TAB]Present and give fire![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Mechanos Master Sergeant of Drill Massimiliano giving musket commands to recruits[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]History: To the those unfamiliar with the tools of war, the musket seems at first to be a poor substitute to the bow. Yet while a trained bowman can often fire faster, farther and with greater accuracy, the musket provides three things that make it the "Queen of Battle" and that is shock, wounding power and ease of training. While a wave of arrows arcing into a formation is impressive, the truth is that in the time it took to train all those archers, many more musketmen could be fielded. As dangerous as the arrows of the Ljosalfar are, they often fail to create a killing or incapacitating wound. Not so the musket ball and even if the bullet fails to kill, if the wounded doesn't get prompt surgery or magical healing, infection from the embedded ball will send them to their God just as surely. Finally, while waves of arrows can shatter the nerve of even the most hardened veteran, the full shock of a line of musketeers giving fire is hard to beat. Even Bannor crusaders have been known to check their headlong rush when faced with the tight, disciplined blocks of Mechanos musketmen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Imbracciate il pezzo![NEWLINE][TAB]Portate avanti la miccia![NEWLINE][TAB]Soffiateci piano sopra![NEWLINE][TAB]Sistemate la miccia![NEWLINE][TAB]Assicurate la miccia![NEWLINE][TAB]Chiudete la scodellina![NEWLINE][TAB]Soffiate piano sulla miccia![NEWLINE][TAB]Puntate e fate fuoco![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Sergente maggiore Mechanos Massimiliano addestrando delle reclute[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Storia: Per coloro senza familiarità con gli strumenti della guerra il moschetto può apparire come inferiore all'arco. Eppure, sebbene un arciere addestrato possa tirare più rapidamente, più lontano e con maggiore precisione, il moschetto ha dalla sua tre cose che lo rendono la "Regina della Battaglia" e queste sono lo shock, il potere d'arresto e la facilità di addestramento. Sebbene l'effetto di una pioggia di frecce su una formazione sia impressionante, nello stesso tempo necessario per addestrare gli arcieri richiesti un numero molto maggiore di moschettieri può essere invece dispiegato. Per quanto siano pericolose, le frecce dei Ljosalfar, spesso non riescono a uccidere o incapacitare il bersaglio. Invece i proiettili dei moschetti, nel caso non uccidano, richiedono un intervento chirurgico o magico per prevenire un'infezione con risultati mortali. Infine, è difficile battere lo shock causato da un'intera linea di moschettieri che fanno fuoco. Persino i crociati Bannor ci pensano su prima di partire alla carica quando affrontano i moschettieri Mechanos.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Handle your piece![NEWLINE][TAB]Take forth your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Blow off your coal![NEWLINE][TAB]Cock your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Try your match![NEWLINE][TAB]Guard your pan![NEWLINE][TAB]Blow off the coal![NEWLINE][TAB]Present and give fire![NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Mechanos Master Sergeant of Drill Massimiliano giving musket commands to recruits[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]History: To the those unfamiliar with the tools of war, the musket seems at first to be a poor substitute to the bow. Yet while a trained bowman can often fire faster, farther and with greater accuracy, the musket provides three things that make it the "Queen of Battle" and that is shock, wounding power and ease of training. While a wave of arrows arcing into a formation is impressive, the truth is that in the time it took to train all those archers, many more musketmen could be fielded. As dangerous as the arrows of the Ljosalfar are, they often fail to create a killing or incapacitating wound. Not so the musket ball and even if the bullet fails to kill, if the wounded doesn't get prompt surgery or magical healing, infection from the embedded ball will send them to their God just as surely. Finally, while waves of arrows can shatter the nerve of even the most hardened veteran, the full shock of a line of musketeers giving fire is hard to beat. Even Bannor crusaders have been known to check their headlong rush when faced with the tight, disciplined blocks of Mechanos musketmen.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MUSKETMAN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>An elite arquebus. For a cost increase of 22%, this unit gets better stats. It aims better and hits stronger; and when defending the stack, it hurts more. Moreover, it can use bronze and iron weapons.</English>
		<French>An elite arquebus. For a cost increase of 22%, this unit gets better stats. It aims better and hits stronger; and when defending the stack, it hurts more. Moreover, it can use bronze and iron weapons.</French>
		<German>An elite arquebus. For a cost increase of 22%, this unit gets better stats. It aims better and hits stronger; and when defending the stack, it hurts more. Moreover, it can use bronze and iron weapons.</German>
		<Italian>Un archibuggiere d'elite. Con un incremento del costo del 22%, quest'unità possiede statistiche migliori. È più precisa e colpisce più duramente; e quando difende un gruppo infligge più danno. In aggiunta può usare armi di bronzo e ferro.</Italian>
		<Spanish>An elite arquebus. For a cost increase of 22%, this unit gets better stats. It aims better and hits stronger; and when defending the stack, it hurts more. Moreover, it can use bronze and iron weapons.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OPERATOR</Tag>
		<English>Operator</English>
		<French>Opérateur</French>
		<German>Operator</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Operatore:Operatori</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>Operator</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OPERATOR_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Operator is the only worker who can build railroads.</English>
		<French>L'Opérateur est le seul ouvrier pouvant poser des rails.</French>
		<German>The Operator is the only worker who can build railroads.</German>
		<Italian>L'Operatore è l'unico lavoratore che può costruire delle ferrovie.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Operator is the only worker who can build railroads.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ORGAN_GUN</Tag>
		<English>Organ Gun</English>
		<French>Canon multiple</French>
		<German>Kanonier</German>
		<Italian>Cannone ad Organo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Organ Gun</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_STEAMTANK</Tag>
		<English>Steam Tank</English>
		<French>Tank à vapeur</French>
		<German>Dampfpanzer</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Carro a Vapore:Carri a Vapore</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>Steam Tank</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_STEAMTANK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>You are saying that you can make that contraption move by lighting a fire in it? Excellent work, I want 50 of this by next month [PARAGRAPH:2] Verocchio to an unnamed Adeptus.</English>
		<French>You are saying that you can make that contraption move by lighting a fire in it? Excellent work, I want 50 of this by next month [PARAGRAPH:2] Verocchio to an unnamed Adeptus.</French>
		<German>You are saying that you can make that contraption move by lighting a fire in it? Excellent work, I want 50 of this by next month [PARAGRAPH:2] Verocchio to an unnamed Adeptus.</German>
		<Italian>Mi stai dicendo che puoi far muovere quel marchingegno accendendo un fuoco all'interno? Ottimo lavoro, ne voglio 50 entro il prossimo mese [PARAGRAPH:2] Verocchio ad un Adeptus.</Italian>
		<Spanish>You are saying that you can make that contraption move by lighting a fire in it? Excellent work, I want 50 of this by next month [PARAGRAPH:2] Verocchio to an unnamed Adeptus.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TECHPRIEST</Tag>
		<English>Techpriest</English>
		<French>Technoprêtre</French>
		<German>Technikpriester</German>
		<Italian>
			<Text>Tecnoprete:Tecnopreti</Text>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</Italian>
		<Spanish>Techpriest</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TECHPRIEST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>...The tech-priests of the Mechanos are another good example of a surrogacy. Although the Mechanos claim to have forgone ritualised religion, it is clear to even the most sympathetic observer, that they have merely replaced faith in external power with faith in machinery. Deus ex Machina, as one cynical commentator wryly noted.[PARAGRAPH:1]It is not clear how this order is chosen although there appears to be a strong affinity between the priesthood and the craftsman and artisan classes. Secretive in the extreme, tech-priests dress in long flowing robes which hide their bodies. They adorn their faces with silver masks that completely obscure their identity, leaving some to speculate as to whether or not the body beneath the apparel is composed of flesh or metal.[PARAGRAPH:1]To hear a tech-priest speak is a unique experience. Their mouths smothered with soulless facade, no lips move as they voice their sentiment. For many it is a mere approximation of speech. What sense is there in the grinding of metal upon metal, the scrape of manifolds and grooves, the click of wheels sliding into place or hot air whistling over piping? But to those attuned to the din of the forge and rhythm of the clock-tower, the tech-priest sings majestic hymns of triumph with ethereal grace. All is well, the clarion throb of the machine is in perfect working order...[PARAGRAPH:1]Minor Faiths of Erebus, Ozziel</English>
		<French>...The tech-priests of the Mechanos are another good example of a surrogacy. Although the Mechanos claim to have forgone ritualised religion, it is clear to even the most sympathetic observer, that they have merely replaced faith in external power with faith in machinery. Deus ex Machina, as one cynical commentator wryly noted.[PARAGRAPH:1]It is not clear how this order is chosen although there appears to be a strong affinity between the priesthood and the craftsman and artisan classes. Secretive in the extreme, tech-priests dress in long flowing robes which hide their bodies. They adorn their faces with silver masks that completely obscure their identity, leaving some to speculate as to whether or not the body beneath the apparel is composed of flesh or metal.[PARAGRAPH:1]To hear a tech-priest speak is a unique experience. Their mouths smothered with soulless facade, no lips move as they voice their sentiment. For many it is a mere approximation of speech. What sense is there in the grinding of metal upon metal, the scrape of manifolds and grooves, the click of wheels sliding into place or hot air whistling over piping? But to those attuned to the din of the forge and rhythm of the clock-tower, the tech-priest sings majestic hymns of triumph with ethereal grace. All is well, the clarion throb of the machine is in perfect working order...[PARAGRAPH:1]Minor Faiths of Erebus, Ozziel</French>
		<German>...The tech-priests of the Mechanos are another good example of a surrogacy. Although the Mechanos claim to have forgone ritualised religion, it is clear to even the most sympathetic observer, that they have merely replaced faith in external power with faith in machinery. Deus ex Machina, as one cynical commentator wryly noted.[PARAGRAPH:1]It is not clear how this order is chosen although there appears to be a strong affinity between the priesthood and the craftsman and artisan classes. Secretive in the extreme, tech-priests dress in long flowing robes which hide their bodies. They adorn their faces with silver masks that completely obscure their identity, leaving some to speculate as to whether or not the body beneath the apparel is composed of flesh or metal.[PARAGRAPH:1]To hear a tech-priest speak is a unique experience. Their mouths smothered with soulless facade, no lips move as they voice their sentiment. For many it is a mere approximation of speech. What sense is there in the grinding of metal upon metal, the scrape of manifolds and grooves, the click of wheels sliding into place or hot air whistling over piping? But to those attuned to the din of the forge and rhythm of the clock-tower, the tech-priest sings majestic hymns of triumph with ethereal grace. All is well, the clarion throb of the machine is in perfect working order...[PARAGRAPH:1]Minor Faiths of Erebus, Ozziel</German>
		<Italian>...I Tecnopreti dei Mechanos sono un altro buon esempio di surrogazione. Anche se i Mechanos affermano di aver abbandonato la religione, è palese anche all'osservatore più fazioso che hanno semplicemente rimpiazzato la fede verso un potere esterno con quella verso le macchine. Deus ex Machina, come ha fatto notare cinicamente uno.[PARAGRAPH:1]Non è chiaro come si accede a quest'ordine anche se pare esserci una forte affinità tra il clero e la classe artigiana. Estremamente riservati, i Tecnopreti indossano lunghe vesti che nascondono i loro corpi. E usano maschere d'argento per nascondere il loro volto lasciando alcuni a domandarsi se il corpo sottostante sia fatto di metallo o carne.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sentir parlare un Tecnoprete è un'esperienza unica. Per molti è solo un'approssimazione di linguaggio. Che senso può avere lo stridio di metallo contro metallo, il graffiare tra scanalature, il ticchettio di ruote che scivolano in posizione o il fischio del vapore nei tubi? Ma per coloro in sintonia con i suoni della forgia e il ritmo della torre dell'orologio, i Tecnopreti intonano maestosi inni di trionfo con grazia eterea. Tutto è a posto, la macchina è perfettamente funzionante...[PARAGRAPH:1]Fedi Minori di Erebus, Ozziel</Italian>
		<Spanish>...The tech-priests of the Mechanos are another good example of a surrogacy. Although the Mechanos claim to have forgone ritualised religion, it is clear to even the most sympathetic observer, that they have merely replaced faith in external power with faith in machinery. Deus ex Machina, as one cynical commentator wryly noted.[PARAGRAPH:1]It is not clear how this order is chosen although there appears to be a strong affinity between the priesthood and the craftsman and artisan classes. Secretive in the extreme, tech-priests dress in long flowing robes which hide their bodies. They adorn their faces with silver masks that completely obscure their identity, leaving some to speculate as to whether or not the body beneath the apparel is composed of flesh or metal.[PARAGRAPH:1]To hear a tech-priest speak is a unique experience. Their mouths smothered with soulless facade, no lips move as they voice their sentiment. For many it is a mere approximation of speech. What sense is there in the grinding of metal upon metal, the scrape of manifolds and grooves, the click of wheels sliding into place or hot air whistling over piping? But to those attuned to the din of the forge and rhythm of the clock-tower, the tech-priest sings majestic hymns of triumph with ethereal grace. All is well, the clarion throb of the machine is in perfect working order...[PARAGRAPH:1]Minor Faiths of Erebus, Ozziel</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_THOPTER</Tag>
		<English>Thopter</English>
		<French>Mécanoptère</French>
		<German>Thopter</German>
		<Italian>Ornitottero</Italian>
		<Spanish>Thopter</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_THOPTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Lad, many a boy has left home to get away from being stuck behind a plow for the rest of his life and gone to sea. What does it get them? Eaten by sea serpents? Enslaved by Doviello raiders? Sunk by Lanun pirates? No boy, the sea is a vast blue death trap! The smart ones are those who take to the air and challenge the sky! Leave the oceans for the God-Believers! Join up with the crew of the Windjammer and you'll see lands never before seen. Come with us and and conquer the sky!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Air Captain Chkalov, recruiting at the Spring Solstice faire[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]While most races of Erebus strove to unlock the Knowledge of the Ether and devised methods of using mana in spellwork, the Mechanos took a road less traveled. Steeped in the principles of natural philosophy, adeptus experiments led to the discovery of many of the property inherent in the elements. Experiments with air led to the study of gasses and thus the Blimp was born. While small and weak compared to its oceanic kin, the Blimps's ability to defy terrain and water obstacles allowed Mechanos explorers to chart many areas deemed far to dangerous by the other factions of Erebus.</English>
		<French>"Lad, many a boy has left home to get away from being stuck behind a plow for the rest of his life and gone to sea. What does it get them? Eaten by sea serpents? Enslaved by Doviello raiders? Sunk by Lanun pirates? No boy, the sea is a vast blue death trap! The smart ones are those who take to the air and challenge the sky! Leave the oceans for the God-Believers! Join up with the crew of the Windjammer and you'll see lands never before seen. Come with us and and conquer the sky!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Air Captain Chkalov, recruiting at the Spring Solstice faire[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]While most races of Erebus strove to unlock the Knowledge of the Ether and devised methods of using mana in spellwork, the Mechanos took a road less traveled. Steeped in the principles of natural philosophy, adeptus experiments led to the discovery of many of the property inherent in the elements. Experiments with air led to the study of gasses and thus the Blimp was born. While small and weak compared to its oceanic kin, the Blimps's ability to defy terrain and water obstacles allowed Mechanos explorers to chart many areas deemed far to dangerous by the other factions of Erebus.</French>
		<German>"Lad, many a boy has left home to get away from being stuck behind a plow for the rest of his life and gone to sea. What does it get them? Eaten by sea serpents? Enslaved by Doviello raiders? Sunk by Lanun pirates? No boy, the sea is a vast blue death trap! The smart ones are those who take to the air and challenge the sky! Leave the oceans for the God-Believers! Join up with the crew of the Windjammer and you'll see lands never before seen. Come with us and and conquer the sky!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Air Captain Chkalov, recruiting at the Spring Solstice faire[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]While most races of Erebus strove to unlock the Knowledge of the Ether and devised methods of using mana in spellwork, the Mechanos took a road less traveled. Steeped in the principles of natural philosophy, adeptus experiments led to the discovery of many of the property inherent in the elements. Experiments with air led to the study of gasses and thus the Blimp was born. While small and weak compared to its oceanic kin, the Blimps's ability to defy terrain and water obstacles allowed Mechanos explorers to chart many areas deemed far to dangerous by the other factions of Erebus.</German>
		<Italian>"Figliolo, parecchi ragazzi scappano di casa per non finire dietro all'aratro per il resto della loro vita e vanno per mare. E cosa ottengono? Mangiati dai serpenti marini? Schiavizzati da razziatori Doviello? Affondati da pirati Lanun? No ragazzo, il mare è una grande trappola mortale blu! Quelli intelligenti sono coloro che vanno per aria e sfidano il cielo! Lascia gli oceani ai Credenti! Unisciti all'equipaggio della Windjammer e vedrai terre mai viste prima. Vieni con noi e conquista il cielo!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Capitano dell'Aria Chkalov, reclutando alla fiera del Solstizio di Primavera[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mentre la maggior parte delle razze di Erebus si sforzano per ottenere la Conoscenza dell'Etere ed escogitare metodi per usare il mana per magie, i Mechanos intraprendono una strada meno trafficata. Esperti dei principi della natura gli esperimenti degli adeptus portano alla scoperta di molte proprietà degli elementi. Gli esperimenti con l'aria hanno portato allo studio dei gas e cosi sono nati i dirigibili. Sebbene piccoli e fragili se paragonati alle imbarcazioni oceaniche, la capacità dei dirigibili di ignorare gli ostacoli terrestri e marini permette agli esploratori Mechanos di mappare diverse zone considerate troppo pericolose dalle altre civiltà di Erebus.</Italian>
		<Spanish>"Lad, many a boy has left home to get away from being stuck behind a plow for the rest of his life and gone to sea. What does it get them? Eaten by sea serpents? Enslaved by Doviello raiders? Sunk by Lanun pirates? No boy, the sea is a vast blue death trap! The smart ones are those who take to the air and challenge the sky! Leave the oceans for the God-Believers! Join up with the crew of the Windjammer and you'll see lands never before seen. Come with us and and conquer the sky!"[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]Air Captain Chkalov, recruiting at the Spring Solstice faire[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]While most races of Erebus strove to unlock the Knowledge of the Ether and devised methods of using mana in spellwork, the Mechanos took a road less traveled. Steeped in the principles of natural philosophy, adeptus experiments led to the discovery of many of the property inherent in the elements. Experiments with air led to the study of gasses and thus the Blimp was born. While small and weak compared to its oceanic kin, the Blimps's ability to defy terrain and water obstacles allowed Mechanos explorers to chart many areas deemed far to dangerous by the other factions of Erebus.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MORTAR_MACHINARUM</Tag>
		<English>Mortar</English>
		<French>Mortier</French>
		<German>Mörser</German>
		<Italian>Mortar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mortar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VULTURE</Tag>
		<English>Vulture</English>
		<French>Vautour</French>
		<German>Geier</German>
		<Italian>Vulture</Italian>
		<Spanish>Vulture</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WITCHHUNTER</Tag>
		<English>Witch Hunter</English>
		<French>Chasseur de sorcières</French>
		<German>Hexenjäger</German>
		<Italian>Cacciatore di Streghe</Italian>
		<Spanish>Witch Hunter</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WITCHHUNTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>I'm sorry, Princess Keelyn. But, you don't understand. I tried, honestly, I did. But, the Mechanos... you don't understand! No, no, please! Listen! Their agents... the Witch Hunters... wherever they go, a cloud follows... I reach out for magic, and I find... nothing... just cold... no, I tried that. It's not like ice, it's like steel, steel and steam and nothing... empty... please, forgive me, my lady! Forgive me! No, no, anything but...[NEWLINE] -Last words of Paulos the Blue</English>
		<French>I'm sorry, Princess Keelyn. But, you don't understand. I tried, honestly, I did. But, the Mechanos... you don't understand! No, no, please! Listen! Their agents... the Witch Hunters... wherever they go, a cloud follows... I reach out for magic, and I find... nothing... just cold... no, I tried that. It's not like ice, it's like steel, steel and steam and nothing... empty... please, forgive me, my lady! Forgive me! No, no, anything but...[NEWLINE] -Last words of Paulos the Blue</French>
		<German>I'm sorry, Princess Keelyn. But, you don't understand. I tried, honestly, I did. But, the Mechanos... you don't understand! No, no, please! Listen! Their agents... the Witch Hunters... wherever they go, a cloud follows... I reach out for magic, and I find... nothing... just cold... no, I tried that. It's not like ice, it's like steel, steel and steam and nothing... empty... please, forgive me, my lady! Forgive me! No, no, anything but...[NEWLINE] -Last words of Paulos the Blue</German>
		<Italian>I'm sorry, Princess Keelyn. But, you don't understand. I tried, honestly, I did. But, the Mechanos... you don't understand! No, no, please! Listen! Their agents... the Witch Hunters... wherever they go, a cloud follows... I reach out for magic, and I find... nothing... just cold... no, I tried that. It's not like ice, it's like steel, steel and steam and nothing... empty... please, forgive me, my lady! Forgive me! No, no, anything but...[NEWLINE] -Last words of Paulos the Blue</Italian>
		<Spanish>I'm sorry, Princess Keelyn. But, you don't understand. I tried, honestly, I did. But, the Mechanos... you don't understand! No, no, please! Listen! Their agents... the Witch Hunters... wherever they go, a cloud follows... I reach out for magic, and I find... nothing... just cold... no, I tried that. It's not like ice, it's like steel, steel and steam and nothing... empty... please, forgive me, my lady! Forgive me! No, no, anything but...[NEWLINE] -Last words of Paulos the Blue</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_MECHANOS_AFFINITY</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Boosts Ranged Attack by +%d1, and Ranged Damage Limit by +%d2</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Augmente l'attaque à distance de +%d1, et la limite de dégâts associée de +%d2</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erhüht die Angriffsreichweite für Fernangriffe um +%d1 und deren Schadenslimit um +%d2</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Aumenta l'attacco a distanza di +%d1, e il Limite di Danno a Distanza di +%d2</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Boosts Ranged Attack by +%d1, and Ranged Damage Limit by +%d2</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PYHELP_NEWLINE</Tag>
		<English>[NEWLINE]</English>
		<French>[NEWLINE]</French>
		<German>[NEWLINE]</German>
		<Italian>[NEWLINE]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[NEWLINE]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_ERA_MACHINARUM</Tag>
		<English>System-Use Only</English>
		<French>System-Use Only</French>
		<German>Nur System bedingter Text</German>
		<Italian>System-Use Only</Italian>
		<Spanish>System-Use Only</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>