<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Game Text - CIV Name -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ABASHI</Tag>
		<English>Abashi the Black Dragon</English>
		<French>Abashi le Dragon Noir</French>
		<German>Abashi der Schwarze Drache</German>
		<Italian>Abashi the Black Dragon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Abashi the Black Dragon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ABASHI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Only 4 days. 4 days without sleep, of constant battle. I would have laid down and died for the chance to just rest for a few seconds, but there was no rest here. Every defeated soldier was raised as another member of the undead horde. Within minutes of their corpse hitting the cursed land their arms were twitching again with an unholy life, then they would reach for their weapon and we, who fought and bled beside them as brothers, would be forced to kill them.[PARAGRAPH:1]We had come through the Aduro Straight, where angels and demons battled across bleeding lands and had thought the worst was past when they came through to the calm Meditor Sea. Our fleet of white sails and cheering men, an army of many nations landed as one on the shores of this island. Was that really only 4 short days ago? How I wished for the days spent in that hell, they are fond memories compared to this land.[PARAGRAPH:1]The paladins are our inspiration. They fight tirelessly, never questioning, fighting for every inch of ground as if it was any different than the cracked earth we just came from. Even now Vaghan stands surrounded, his armor gleams even on this moonless night and the power of the Empyrean flows through him.[PARAGRAPH:1]An Ash Bearer comes at me, using his sword to thrust rather than slash. If he was to dismember me I would be weaker when raised as an undead. I parry the clumsy attack but he continues on, throwing his shoulder into me and pushing me back. I stumble into Vaghan and realize this is the Ash Bearers real intent, that he could use me to distract the paladin, to make him vulnerable if only for a second.[PARAGRAPH:1]I fall out of the way, trying to keep from interfering with Vaghan's fight even if I am sacrificed in doing so. The Ash Bearer comes quickly upon me but is stopped when Vaghan steps over me and slashes through him. I have a brief glimpse of those Vaghan was fighting with, a wraith and a juggernaut of sewn corpses setting upon his now exposed back. Vaghan seems to ignore them, thrusting his arm up there is a flash and a ring of blinding light explodes from him. The wraith is destroyed, the juggernaut reels backwards and is hacked apart by our men.[PARAGRAPH:1]Vaghan grabs me and pulls me to my feet, "Do not despair, hope yet remains."[PARAGRAPH:1]Then he is gone. There is only a slight whistle to indicate that anything passed through the night until it turns back towards the army. A dragon of sleek black scales is silhouetted briefly against the sky, darker even than the night like a hole in sackcloth. The dragon spits out Vaghan's remains, a small rain of blood and once perfect holy vestments. Then she roars and I find myself suddenly nostalgic for the days of constant battle.[PARAGRAPH:2]- Visions from the Pool of Tears and revelation that the Sheaim had awoken Abashi and was using her in the Battle of the Black Tower</English>
		<French>Only 4 days. 4 days without sleep, of constant battle. I would have laid down and died for the chance to just rest for a few seconds, but there was no rest here. Every defeated soldier was raised as another member of the undead horde. Within minutes of their corpse hitting the cursed land their arms were twitching again with an unholy life, then they would reach for their weapon and we, who fought and bled beside them as brothers, would be forced to kill them.[PARAGRAPH:1]We had come through the Aduro Straight, where angels and demons battled across bleeding lands and had thought the worst was past when they came through to the calm Meditor Sea. Our fleet of white sails and cheering men, an army of many nations landed as one on the shores of this island. Was that really only 4 short days ago? How I wished for the days spent in that hell, they are fond memories compared to this land.[PARAGRAPH:1]The paladins are our inspiration. They fight tirelessly, never questioning, fighting for every inch of ground as if it was any different than the cracked earth we just came from. Even now Vaghan stands surrounded, his armor gleams even on this moonless night and the power of the Empyrean flows through him.[PARAGRAPH:1]An Ash Bearer comes at me, using his sword to thrust rather than slash. If he was to dismember me I would be weaker when raised as an undead. I parry the clumsy attack but he continues on, throwing his shoulder into me and pushing me back. I stumble into Vaghan and realize this is the Ash Bearers real intent, that he could use me to distract the paladin, to make him vulnerable if only for a second.[PARAGRAPH:1]I fall out of the way, trying to keep from interfering with Vaghan's fight even if I am sacrificed in doing so. The Ash Bearer comes quickly upon me but is stopped when Vaghan steps over me and slashes through him. I have a brief glimpse of those Vaghan was fighting with, a wraith and a juggernaut of sewn corpses setting upon his now exposed back. Vaghan seems to ignore them, thrusting his arm up there is a flash and a ring of blinding light explodes from him. The wraith is destroyed, the juggernaut reels backwards and is hacked apart by our men.[PARAGRAPH:1]Vaghan grabs me and pulls me to my feet, "Do not despair, hope yet remains."[PARAGRAPH:1]Then he is gone. There is only a slight whistle to indicate that anything passed through the night until it turns back towards the army. A dragon of sleek black scales is silhouetted briefly against the sky, darker even than the night like a hole in sackcloth. The dragon spits out Vaghan's remains, a small rain of blood and once perfect holy vestments. Then she roars and I find myself suddenly nostalgic for the days of constant battle.[PARAGRAPH:2]- Visions from the Pool of Tears and revelation that the Sheaim had awoken Abashi and was using her in the Battle of the Black Tower</French>
		<German>Nur vier Tage. Vier Tage ohne Schlaf in andauernder, nicht enden wollenden Schlacht. Ich hätte mich niedergelegt und wäre gestorben nur um einige Sekunden ruhen zu können, doch es gab keine Pausen. Jeder besiegte Soldat stand als Mitglied der Untoten Horde wieder auf. Innerhalb von Minuten, nachdem ihre Leiche auf die verfluchten Lande gefallen sind, zuckten ihre Arme wieder in unheiligem Leben und griffen nach ihrer Waffe und wir, mit ihnen als Brüder kämpfend und blutend, wurden gezwungen sie zu töten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wir mussten durch die Adurolinie, wo sich Engel und Dämonen auf blutenden Landen bekämpften und dachten, das Schlimmste wäre vorüber, als wir bis zum ruhigen Meditormeer durchkamen. Unsere Flotten von weißen Segeln und jubelnden Männern, einer Armee vieler Nationen, landete in einem Stück an den Gestaden dieser Insel. War das wirklich nur vier kurze Tage her? Wie ich mich zu den Tagen in dieser Hölle zurückwünschte, sie wirkten wie verliebte Erinnerungen im Vergleich zu diesem Land.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Paladine sind unsere Inspiration. Sie schlugen sich unermüdlich, niemals fragend, um jeden Zoll Land kämpfend als wäre es auch nur im Entferntesten anders als das gebrochene Land aus dem wir gerade kamen. Gerade jetzt steht Vaghan umringt von Feinden, die Rüstung schimmernd sogar in dieser mondlosen Nacht und von der Macht der Empyräischen durchflossen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Aschenträger kommt auf mich zu, das Schwert eher zum Stoß als zum Schlag gehalten. Würde er mich zerstückeln, wäre ich schwächer sobald ich als Untoter wiederauferstehe. Ich pariere die schwerfällige Attacke aber er steckt nicht auf, wirft sich mit der Schulter in mich rein und stößt mich zurück. Ich stolpere auf Vaghan zu und realisiere, dass dies das Ziel des Aschenträgers ist, dass er mich benutzt um den Paladin abzulenken um ihn eine Sekunde verwundbar zu machen. Ich lass mich fallen, in dem Versuch Vaghan nicht zu behindern auch wenn ich mich dadurch opfere. Der Aschenträger kommt rasch auf mich zu, wird jedoch gestoppt als Vaghan über mich herüber steigt und ihn aufschlitzt. Ich erhasche einen flüchtigen Blick auf jenen, den Vaghan bekämpfte, einen Geist und einen Moloch aus zusammengenähten Leichen auf seinem entblößten Rücken. Vaghan scheint sie zu ignorieren, doch als er seinen Arm vorstreckte explodiert ein Blitz und ein Ring aus blendendem Licht vor ihm. Der Geist ist zerstört, der Moloch taumelt zurück und wird von unseren Männern zerhackt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Vaghan packt mich und zieht mich auf die Füße: "Verzage nicht, die Hoffnung bleibt."[PARAGRAPH:1]Dann ist er verschwunden. Es ist nur ein leises Flüstern zu hören, das verrät, dass irgendetwas durch die Nacht streift bis es sich zurück zur Armee wendet. Ein Drache mit glatten, schwarzen Schuppen umreißt flüchtig den Himmel, sogar dunkler als die Nacht wie ein Loch in Sackleinen. Der Drache speiht Vaghans Überreste aus, ein kleiner Regen von Blut und einst perfekten, heiligen Gewändern. Dann brüllt sie und ich finde mich plötzlich voller Heimweh in den Tagen der immerwährenden Schlachten wieder.[PARAGRAPH:2]- Visionen vom Teich der Tränen und der Offenbarung, dass die Abashi durch die Sheaim erweckt wurde, um sie in der Schlacht um den Schwarzen Turm zu benutzen. </German>
		<Italian>Only 4 days. 4 days without sleep, of constant battle. I would have laid down and died for the chance to just rest for a few seconds, but there was no rest here. Every defeated soldier was raised as another member of the undead horde. Within minutes of their corpse hitting the cursed land their arms were twitching again with an unholy life, then they would reach for their weapon and we, who fought and bled beside them as brothers, would be forced to kill them.[PARAGRAPH:1]We had come through the Aduro Straight, where angels and demons battled across bleeding lands and had thought the worst was past when they came through to the calm Meditor Sea. Our fleet of white sails and cheering men, an army of many nations landed as one on the shores of this island. Was that really only 4 short days ago? How I wished for the days spent in that hell, they are fond memories compared to this land.[PARAGRAPH:1]The paladins are our inspiration. They fight tirelessly, never questioning, fighting for every inch of ground as if it was any different than the cracked earth we just came from. Even now Vaghan stands surrounded, his armor gleams even on this moonless night and the power of the Empyrean flows through him.[PARAGRAPH:1]An Ash Bearer comes at me, using his sword to thrust rather than slash. If he was to dismember me I would be weaker when raised as an undead. I parry the clumsy attack but he continues on, throwing his shoulder into me and pushing me back. I stumble into Vaghan and realize this is the Ash Bearers real intent, that he could use me to distract the paladin, to make him vulnerable if only for a second.[PARAGRAPH:1]I fall out of the way, trying to keep from interfering with Vaghan's fight even if I am sacrificed in doing so. The Ash Bearer comes quickly upon me but is stopped when Vaghan steps over me and slashes through him. I have a brief glimpse of those Vaghan was fighting with, a wraith and a juggernaut of sewn corpses setting upon his now exposed back. Vaghan seems to ignore them, thrusting his arm up there is a flash and a ring of blinding light explodes from him. The wraith is destroyed, the juggernaut reels backwards and is hacked apart by our men.[PARAGRAPH:1]Vaghan grabs me and pulls me to my feet, "Do not despair, hope yet remains."[PARAGRAPH:1]Then he is gone. There is only a slight whistle to indicate that anything passed through the night until it turns back towards the army. A dragon of sleek black scales is silhouetted briefly against the sky, darker even than the night like a hole in sackcloth. The dragon spits out Vaghan's remains, a small rain of blood and once perfect holy vestments. Then she roars and I find myself suddenly nostalgic for the days of constant battle.[PARAGRAPH:2]- Visions from the Pool of Tears and revelation that the Sheaim had awoken Abashi and was using her in the Battle of the Black Tower</Italian>
		<Spanish>Only 4 days. 4 days without sleep, of constant battle. I would have laid down and died for the chance to just rest for a few seconds, but there was no rest here. Every defeated soldier was raised as another member of the undead horde. Within minutes of their corpse hitting the cursed land their arms were twitching again with an unholy life, then they would reach for their weapon and we, who fought and bled beside them as brothers, would be forced to kill them.[PARAGRAPH:1]We had come through the Aduro Straight, where angels and demons battled across bleeding lands and had thought the worst was past when they came through to the calm Meditor Sea. Our fleet of white sails and cheering men, an army of many nations landed as one on the shores of this island. Was that really only 4 short days ago? How I wished for the days spent in that hell, they are fond memories compared to this land.[PARAGRAPH:1]The paladins are our inspiration. They fight tirelessly, never questioning, fighting for every inch of ground as if it was any different than the cracked earth we just came from. Even now Vaghan stands surrounded, his armor gleams even on this moonless night and the power of the Empyrean flows through him.[PARAGRAPH:1]An Ash Bearer comes at me, using his sword to thrust rather than slash. If he was to dismember me I would be weaker when raised as an undead. I parry the clumsy attack but he continues on, throwing his shoulder into me and pushing me back. I stumble into Vaghan and realize this is the Ash Bearers real intent, that he could use me to distract the paladin, to make him vulnerable if only for a second.[PARAGRAPH:1]I fall out of the way, trying to keep from interfering with Vaghan's fight even if I am sacrificed in doing so. The Ash Bearer comes quickly upon me but is stopped when Vaghan steps over me and slashes through him. I have a brief glimpse of those Vaghan was fighting with, a wraith and a juggernaut of sewn corpses setting upon his now exposed back. Vaghan seems to ignore them, thrusting his arm up there is a flash and a ring of blinding light explodes from him. The wraith is destroyed, the juggernaut reels backwards and is hacked apart by our men.[PARAGRAPH:1]Vaghan grabs me and pulls me to my feet, "Do not despair, hope yet remains."[PARAGRAPH:1]Then he is gone. There is only a slight whistle to indicate that anything passed through the night until it turns back towards the army. A dragon of sleek black scales is silhouetted briefly against the sky, darker even than the night like a hole in sackcloth. The dragon spits out Vaghan's remains, a small rain of blood and once perfect holy vestments. Then she roars and I find myself suddenly nostalgic for the days of constant battle.[PARAGRAPH:2]- Visions from the Pool of Tears and revelation that the Sheaim had awoken Abashi and was using her in the Battle of the Black Tower</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ABASHI_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The Sheaim hero is able to breathe fire, and her roar will convert any surrounding cult of the dragon units to her cause. She is also immune to magic and weaker units will often be too afraid to attack her.</English>
		<French>Le héros Sheaïm peut souffler du feu, et son rugissement peut convertir à sa cause les unités du Culte du Dragon aux alentours. De plus il est immunisé à la magie et les unités faibles auront trop peur pour l'attaquer.</French>
		<German>Der Held der Sheaïm ist fähig Feuer zu spucken und sein Schrei wird jede ihn umgebene Einheit des Drachenkultes auf seine Seite konvertieren lassen. Ausserdem ist er magieresistent und schwächere Einheiten werden oft zu verängstigt sein um ihn anzugreifen.</German>
		<Italian>The Sheaim hero is able to breathe fire, and her roar will convert any surrounding cult of the dragon units to her cause. She is also immune to magic and weaker units will often be too afraid to attack her.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Sheaim hero is able to breathe fire, and her roar will convert any surrounding cult of the dragon units to her cause. She is also immune to magic and weaker units will often be too afraid to attack her.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ACHERON</Tag>
		<English>Acheron the Red Dragon</English>
		<French>Acheron le Dragon Rouge</French>
		<German>Acheron der Rote Drache</German>
		<Italian>Acheron the Red Dragon</Italian>
		<Spanish>Acheron the Red Dragon</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_ACHERON_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>Acheron the Red Dragon has awoken and made a barbarian city his lair. Civilized empires fear the great dragon, and covet the hoard Acheron is rumored to guard.</English>
		<French>Achéron le Dragon Rouge s'est réveillé et a fait d'une ville barbare son repaire. Les empires civilisés craignent le grand dragon et convoitent le trésor dont on dit qu'Achéron à la garde.</French>
		<German>Acheron der Rote Drache ist erwacht und hat eine Stadt der Barbaren zu seinem Hort erkoren. Auch wenn die Völker den großen Drachen fürchten, so ist doch jedes von ihnen begierig, seinen Hort zu plündern.</German>
		<Italian>Acheron the Red Dragon has awoken and made a barbarian city his lair. Civilized empires fear the great dragon, and covet the hoard Acheron is rumored to guard.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Acheron the Red Dragon has awoken and made a barbarian city his lair. Civilized empires fear the great dragon, and covet the hoard Acheron is rumored to guard.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ACHERON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]It flittered about impatiently as the ages passed, in this place without time. In this almost nothingness where myths go when dead but not forgotten. And Erebus would not soon forget Acheron, the flame lord, the beast of destruction, the Red Dragon. The earth had trembled when he walked. Centuries old Fir trees had been uprooted when he took flight. When he and his adversaries clashed, it was a sight like no other before or since.[PARAGRAPH:1]But at the Compact, the power that sustained him was withdrawn. He was as fearsome as ever but his wounds did not heal so fast. When he brought forth his fire, now he got a taste of the pain he inflicted. And one fateful battle, he was not quite fast enough, and he fell, never to rise again.[PARAGRAPH:1]He could not rest here as most of the others did, content in the majesty of myth. It was not his nature. His nature was that of fire. Fire, the ravenous devourer. Fire, the nimble dancer brought aloft on the winds. And fire, patient when defeated, but ever eager to spring to life again with the faintest fuel. And at last he detected it. The essence of his mistress Bhall. Not the goddess herself, but some people close to her-and Acheron's-fiery nature. They reproduced quickly, grew fast, fought with a roar, and died with rage. Chaotic, but strictly following the laws that governed them. Violent, but leaving a void that encouraged new growth. Nimble, but leaving a lasting mark.[PARAGRAPH:1]They didn't know they called to him, that they gave him strength, but they did. Their rage opened a portal that he alone could take and returned substance to his long decayed flesh and bones.[PARAGRAPH:2]Three-Tooth dumped his bag on the ground in Ahepetr. Three human skulls, an iron knife, and a handful of shiny trinkets tumbled out. Half-Nose reached for a diamond ring, and Three-Tooth jumped him. The two orcs tumbled around the ground as the nearby goblins cheered them on, sneaking Three-Tooth's spoils when they could.[PARAGRAPH:1]They were interrupted by an earth shaking roar. All turned to face him. Resplendent in primal glory, Acheron stood. His leathery skin had the luster of rubies, all the more so when his breath illuminated the dusk with a billowing cloud of fire. Every tooth, fang, and claw shone, sharp and perfect, as if he had not fought countless battles. His leathery wings embraced the humble village. His face wore a fearsome snarl ... or possibly, though it seemed so out of place on this beast, a smile.[PARAGRAPH:1]As one the orcs and goblins gathered their war spoils and carried them before the mighty dragon, laying them at his feet. In time, the pile would grow to a mountain as the legend was reborn.</English>
		<French>[TAB]It flittered about impatiently as the ages passed, in this place without time. In this almost nothingness where myths go when dead but not forgotten. And Erebus would not soon forget Acheron, the flame lord, the beast of destruction, the Red Dragon. The earth had trembled when he walked. Centuries old Fir trees had been uprooted when he took flight. When he and his adversaries clashed, it was a sight like no other before or since.[PARAGRAPH:1]But at the Compact, the power that sustained him was withdrawn. He was as fearsome as ever but his wounds did not heal so fast. When he brought forth his fire, now he got a taste of the pain he inflicted. And one fateful battle, he was not quite fast enough, and he fell, never to rise again.[PARAGRAPH:1]He could not rest here as most of the others did, content in the majesty of myth. It was not his nature. His nature was that of fire. Fire, the ravenous devourer. Fire, the nimble dancer brought aloft on the winds. And fire, patient when defeated, but ever eager to spring to life again with the faintest fuel. And at last he detected it. The essence of his mistress Bhall. Not the goddess herself, but some people close to her-and Acheron's-fiery nature. They reproduced quickly, grew fast, fought with a roar, and died with rage. Chaotic, but strictly following the laws that governed them. Violent, but leaving a void that encouraged new growth. Nimble, but leaving a lasting mark.[PARAGRAPH:1]They didn't know they called to him, that they gave him strength, but they did. Their rage opened a portal that he alone could take and returned substance to his long decayed flesh and bones.[PARAGRAPH:2]Three-Tooth dumped his bag on the ground in Ahepetr. Three human skulls, an iron knife, and a handful of shiny trinkets tumbled out. Half-Nose reached for a diamond ring, and Three-Tooth jumped him. The two orcs tumbled around the ground as the nearby goblins cheered them on, sneaking Three-Tooth's spoils when they could.[PARAGRAPH:1]They were interrupted by an earth shaking roar. All turned to face him. Resplendent in primal glory, Acheron stood. His leathery skin had the luster of rubies, all the more so when his breath illuminated the dusk with a billowing cloud of fire. Every tooth, fang, and claw shone, sharp and perfect, as if he had not fought countless battles. His leathery wings embraced the humble village. His face wore a fearsome snarl ... or possibly, though it seemed so out of place on this beast, a smile.[PARAGRAPH:1]As one the orcs and goblins gathered their war spoils and carried them before the mighty dragon, laying them at his feet. In time, the pile would grow to a mountain as the legend was reborn.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Es flatterte ungeduldig umher, als die Zeitalter vergingen, an diesem zeitlosen Ort. In dieser dem Nichts ähnlichen Existent, wo die Legenden bestehen, die tot aber noch nicht vergessen sind. Und Erebus würde ihn noch lange nicht vergessen, Acheron, den Flammenherr, die Bestie der Zerstörung, den Roten Drachen. Die Erde hatte erzittert, wenn er sie beschritten hatte. Jahrhunderte alte Fichten waren entwurzelt worden, wenn er über sie hinweg flog. Wenn er und seine Gegner aufeinander prallten, war dies eine Ansicht wie keine je zuvor oder danach.[PARAGRAPH:1]Aber bei dem Pakt wurde ihm die Kraft, die ihn unterstützt hatte, entzogen. Er war so Angst einflößend wie immer, aber seine Wunden heilten nicht mehr so schnell. Wenn er nun sein Feuer hervorstieß, bekam er einen Geschmack des Schmerzes, den er dadurch bewirkte. Und in einer schicksalhaften Schlacht war er gerade nicht mehr schnell genug, und fiel, um niemals wieder aufzuerstehen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er konnte hier nicht ruhig verbleiben, wie es die meisten anderen Taten, zufrieden in der Majestät der Legende. Das war nicht seine Natur. Seine Natur war die des Feuers. Feuer, der immerhungrige Verzehrer. Feuer, der geschickte Tänzer den der Wind brachte. Und Feuer, geduldig wenn es besiegt wurde, doch immer bereit wieder aufzuleben mit nur dem geringsten Brennstoff. Und endlich entdeckte er sie. Die Essenz seiner Herrin Bhall. Nicht die Göttin selbst, aber ein paar Anhänger die ihrer, und Acherons, feuriger Natur nahe standen. Sie vermehrten sich eilig, wuchsen schnell heran, kämpften mit loderndem Herzen, und starben in Wut. Chaotisch, aber strikt die Gesetze befolgend, die sie beherrschten. Gewalttätig, aber eine Leere hinterlassend, die ein neues Wachstum ermutigte. Hastig, aber eine bleibende Markierung hinterlassend.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie wussten nicht, dass sie ihn anriefen, und ihm Stärke verliehen, aber sie taten es trotzdem. Ihre Wut öffnete ein Portal, das nur er durchschreiten konnte, und fügte neue Materie zu seinem schon lange verrotteten Fleisch und seinen Knochen hinzu.[PARAGRAPH:2]Drei-Zahn ließ seinen Beutel auf den Boden von Ahepetr fallen. Drei Menschenschädel, ein eisernes Messer, und eine Handvoll billiger Schmuck rollten heraus. Halb-Nase griff nach einem Diamantenring, und Drei-Fuß sprang ihn an. Die beiden Orks rollten über den Boden, während die dabei stehenden Goblins sie anfeuerten, und Drei-Zahns entglittene Sachen stibitzten, wann immer sie konnten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie wurden von einem Brüllen unterbrochen, das die Erde erbeben ließ. Alle drehten sich zu ihm um. Erstrahlend in ursprünglicher Glorie stand Acheron vor ihnen. Seine lederne Haut hatte den Glanz von Rubinen, mehr sogar wenn sein Atem die Dämmerung mit einer wogenden Wolke des Feuers erhellte. Seine Zähne, jeder Reißzahn, jede Klaue erstrahlte, scharf und unversehrt, als ob er nie in den zahlreichen Schlachten gekämpft hätte. Seine ledernen Schwingen umschlungen die lumpige Stadt. Sein Gesicht zeigte eine Angst einflößende Grimasse … oder vielleicht, obwohl es völlig ungewohnt an so einer Bestie wirkte, ein Lächeln.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wie auf Kommando sammelten die Orks und Goblins ihre Kriegsbeute und trugen ihn vor den mächtigen Drachen, und legten sie ihm zu Füßen. Beizeiten würde dieser Haufen zu einem Berg anwachsen, denn die Legende war wiedergeboren worden.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]It flittered about impatiently as the ages passed, in this place without time. In this almost nothingness where myths go when dead but not forgotten. And Erebus would not soon forget Acheron, the flame lord, the beast of destruction, the Red Dragon. The earth had trembled when he walked. Centuries old Fir trees had been uprooted when he took flight. When he and his adversaries clashed, it was a sight like no other before or since.[PARAGRAPH:1]But at the Compact, the power that sustained him was withdrawn. He was as fearsome as ever but his wounds did not heal so fast. When he brought forth his fire, now he got a taste of the pain he inflicted. And one fateful battle, he was not quite fast enough, and he fell, never to rise again.[PARAGRAPH:1]He could not rest here as most of the others did, content in the majesty of myth. It was not his nature. His nature was that of fire. Fire, the ravenous devourer. Fire, the nimble dancer brought aloft on the winds. And fire, patient when defeated, but ever eager to spring to life again with the faintest fuel. And at last he detected it. The essence of his mistress Bhall. Not the goddess herself, but some people close to her-and Acheron's-fiery nature. They reproduced quickly, grew fast, fought with a roar, and died with rage. Chaotic, but strictly following the laws that governed them. Violent, but leaving a void that encouraged new growth. Nimble, but leaving a lasting mark.[PARAGRAPH:1]They didn't know they called to him, that they gave him strength, but they did. Their rage opened a portal that he alone could take and returned substance to his long decayed flesh and bones.[PARAGRAPH:2]Three-Tooth dumped his bag on the ground in Ahepetr. Three human skulls, an iron knife, and a handful of shiny trinkets tumbled out. Half-Nose reached for a diamond ring, and Three-Tooth jumped him. The two orcs tumbled around the ground as the nearby goblins cheered them on, sneaking Three-Tooth's spoils when they could.[PARAGRAPH:1]They were interrupted by an earth shaking roar. All turned to face him. Resplendent in primal glory, Acheron stood. His leathery skin had the luster of rubies, all the more so when his breath illuminated the dusk with a billowing cloud of fire. Every tooth, fang, and claw shone, sharp and perfect, as if he had not fought countless battles. His leathery wings embraced the humble village. His face wore a fearsome snarl ... or possibly, though it seemed so out of place on this beast, a smile.[PARAGRAPH:1]As one the orcs and goblins gathered their war spoils and carried them before the mighty dragon, laying them at his feet. In time, the pile would grow to a mountain as the legend was reborn.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]It flittered about impatiently as the ages passed, in this place without time. In this almost nothingness where myths go when dead but not forgotten. And Erebus would not soon forget Acheron, the flame lord, the beast of destruction, the Red Dragon. The earth had trembled when he walked. Centuries old Fir trees had been uprooted when he took flight. When he and his adversaries clashed, it was a sight like no other before or since.[PARAGRAPH:1]But at the Compact, the power that sustained him was withdrawn. He was as fearsome as ever but his wounds did not heal so fast. When he brought forth his fire, now he got a taste of the pain he inflicted. And one fateful battle, he was not quite fast enough, and he fell, never to rise again.[PARAGRAPH:1]He could not rest here as most of the others did, content in the majesty of myth. It was not his nature. His nature was that of fire. Fire, the ravenous devourer. Fire, the nimble dancer brought aloft on the winds. And fire, patient when defeated, but ever eager to spring to life again with the faintest fuel. And at last he detected it. The essence of his mistress Bhall. Not the goddess herself, but some people close to her-and Acheron's-fiery nature. They reproduced quickly, grew fast, fought with a roar, and died with rage. Chaotic, but strictly following the laws that governed them. Violent, but leaving a void that encouraged new growth. Nimble, but leaving a lasting mark.[PARAGRAPH:1]They didn't know they called to him, that they gave him strength, but they did. Their rage opened a portal that he alone could take and returned substance to his long decayed flesh and bones.[PARAGRAPH:2]Three-Tooth dumped his bag on the ground in Ahepetr. Three human skulls, an iron knife, and a handful of shiny trinkets tumbled out. Half-Nose reached for a diamond ring, and Three-Tooth jumped him. The two orcs tumbled around the ground as the nearby goblins cheered them on, sneaking Three-Tooth's spoils when they could.[PARAGRAPH:1]They were interrupted by an earth shaking roar. All turned to face him. Resplendent in primal glory, Acheron stood. His leathery skin had the luster of rubies, all the more so when his breath illuminated the dusk with a billowing cloud of fire. Every tooth, fang, and claw shone, sharp and perfect, as if he had not fought countless battles. His leathery wings embraced the humble village. His face wore a fearsome snarl ... or possibly, though it seemed so out of place on this beast, a smile.[PARAGRAPH:1]As one the orcs and goblins gathered their war spoils and carried them before the mighty dragon, laying them at his feet. In time, the pile would grow to a mountain as the legend was reborn.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ANESIDORA</Tag>
		<English>Anesidora</English>
		<French>Anesidora</French>
		<German>Anesidora</German>
		<Italian>Anesidora</Italian>
		<Spanish>Anesidora</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ANESIDORA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Anesidora is the only human soul who isn't descended from Nemed. She was given an immortal soul but without a true divine birthright the ages have worn heavily on her. Though trapped in Arawn's realm since her death early in the Age of Dragons her cold heart was secreted out of the afterworld in the Age of Rebirth and she now exists as a dark draconic shadow under the sway of her heart's possessor. Though she isn't evil, she is destructive and manifests such sorrow that most enemies fall into despair when confronted by her.</English>
		<French>Anesidora is the only human soul who isn't descended from Nemed. She was given an immortal soul but without a true divine birthright the ages have worn heavily on her. Though trapped in Arawn's realm since her death early in the Age of Dragons her cold heart was secreted out of the afterworld in the Age of Rebirth and she now exists as a dark draconic shadow under the sway of her heart's possessor. Though she isn't evil, she is destructive and manifests such sorrow that most enemies fall into despair when confronted by her.</French>
		<German>Anesidora is the only human soul who isn't descended from Nemed. She was given an immortal soul but without a true divine birthright the ages have worn heavily on her. Though trapped in Arawn's realm since her death early in the Age of Dragons her cold heart was secreted out of the afterworld in the Age of Rebirth and she now exists as a dark draconic shadow under the sway of her heart's possessor. Though she isn't evil, she is destructive and manifests such sorrow that most enemies fall into despair when confronted by her.</German>
		<Italian>Anesidora is the only human soul who isn't descended from Nemed. She was given an immortal soul but without a true divine birthright the ages have worn heavily on her. Though trapped in Arawn's realm since her death early in the Age of Dragons her cold heart was secreted out of the afterworld in the Age of Rebirth and she now exists as a dark draconic shadow under the sway of her heart's possessor. Though she isn't evil, she is destructive and manifests such sorrow that most enemies fall into despair when confronted by her.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Anesidora is the only human soul who isn't descended from Nemed. She was given an immortal soul but without a true divine birthright the ages have worn heavily on her. Though trapped in Arawn's realm since her death early in the Age of Dragons her cold heart was secreted out of the afterworld in the Age of Rebirth and she now exists as a dark draconic shadow under the sway of her heart's possessor. Though she isn't evil, she is destructive and manifests such sorrow that most enemies fall into despair when confronted by her.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ANESIDORA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Created through the [LINK=SPELL_SUMMON_ANESIDORA]Summon Anesidora[\LINK] spell</English>
		<French>Created through the [LINK=SPELL_SUMMON_ANESIDORA]Summon Anesidora[\LINK] spell</French>
		<German>Created through the [LINK=SPELL_SUMMON_ANESIDORA]Summon Anesidora[\LINK] spell</German>
		<Italian>Created through the [LINK=SPELL_SUMMON_ANESIDORA]Summon Anesidora[\LINK] spell</Italian>
		<Spanish>Created through the [LINK=SPELL_SUMMON_ANESIDORA]Summon Anesidora[\LINK] spell</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARS</Tag>
		<English>Ars Moriendi</English>
		<French>Ars Moriendi</French>
		<German>Ars Moriendi</German>
		<Italian>Ars Moriendi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ars Moriendi</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Parih stood unmoving, surrounded by the chaos of the battlefield. The screams and clash of weapons were only distant echoes to him. Soldiers fought and died for the ground he stood on, but he did not budge. They pushed through him, and he could not feel it.[PARAGRAPH:1]His broken body lay before him, covered with blood and indistinguishable from the corpses of enemies that lay around him. The Hippus had appeared so different to him, like another breed of men, before now. A lifetime of stories meant to turn hearts against them, extolling the differences in their culture and history. But now they looked the same, battered and bloody.[PARAGRAPH:1]The world faded around him, it would be as if Parih's vision grew worse except he felt so real and the world seemed to be nothing but a dream. The sounds of battle were replaced by the whispered prayers of the soldiers. A few requesting protection, most asking for the death of their enemies, all scared.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are you prepared for death?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The words reached into Parih, seeking the answer, touching every dark thought he maintained. A man on a pale horse rode toward him and though Parih felt evil from the man he was unable to lie.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I'm scared."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do not be afraid of death, you have been dead before. Do you believe that time began when you were born? Do you believe your soul to be immortal?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Parih was unable to answer. The demon smirked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You are not the catalyst of creation, flesh is an unfit and temporary vessel for a soul. If you know that your soul exists after your life ends, shouldn't you believe that it existed before your birth? And if your soul existed in a place before your birth, why would it not return there after your death?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The demon paused, reading Parih's thoughts, making sure this was the correct moment.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Take my hand mortal and I will lead you to the afterlife."[PARAGRAPH:1]Parih reached out and took Ars skeletal hand. In that instant the memories of his life were lost and he was reborn as one of the mindless Mane legions of hell.[PARAGRAPH:1]"That soul was not yours to claim demon!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Ars turned to see a Valkyrie with her weapon drawn. She paled when she recognized him, instinctively stepping back even though he hadn't made any move towards her.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am unbound, and claim any I choose."[PARAGRAPH:1]He rode forward and the Valkyrie moved out of his way.</English>
		<French>Parih stood unmoving, surrounded by the chaos of the battlefield. The screams and clash of weapons were only distant echoes to him. Soldiers fought and died for the ground he stood on, but he did not budge. They pushed through him, and he could not feel it.[PARAGRAPH:1]His broken body lay before him, covered with blood and indistinguishable from the corpses of enemies that lay around him. The Hippus had appeared so different to him, like another breed of men, before now. A lifetime of stories meant to turn hearts against them, extolling the differences in their culture and history. But now they looked the same, battered and bloody.[PARAGRAPH:1]The world faded around him, it would be as if Parih's vision grew worse except he felt so real and the world seemed to be nothing but a dream. The sounds of battle were replaced by the whispered prayers of the soldiers. A few requesting protection, most asking for the death of their enemies, all scared.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are you prepared for death?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The words reached into Parih, seeking the answer, touching every dark thought he maintained. A man on a pale horse rode toward him and though Parih felt evil from the man he was unable to lie.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I'm scared."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do not be afraid of death, you have been dead before. Do you believe that time began when you were born? Do you believe your soul to be immortal?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Parih was unable to answer. The demon smirked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You are not the catalyst of creation, flesh is an unfit and temporary vessel for a soul. If you know that your soul exists after your life ends, shouldn't you believe that it existed before your birth? And if your soul existed in a place before your birth, why would it not return there after your death?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The demon paused, reading Parih's thoughts, making sure this was the correct moment.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Take my hand mortal and I will lead you to the afterlife."[PARAGRAPH:1]Parih reached out and took Ars skeletal hand. In that instant the memories of his life were lost and he was reborn as one of the mindless Mane legions of hell.[PARAGRAPH:1]"That soul was not yours to claim demon!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Ars turned to see a Valkyrie with her weapon drawn. She paled when she recognized him, instinctively stepping back even though he hadn't made any move towards her.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am unbound, and claim any I choose."[PARAGRAPH:1]He rode forward and the Valkyrie moved out of his way.</French>
		<German>Parih stand unbewegt umgeben vom Chaos des Schlachtfelds. Die Schreie und das Klirren der Waffen waren für ihn nur entfernte Echos. Soldaten kämpften und starben für den Boden, auf dem er stand, aber er rührte sich nicht. Sie stürmten durch ihn, doch er fühlte es nicht.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sein geborstener Körper lag vor ihm, bedeckt mit Blut und so nicht von den Leichen seiner Feinde zu unterscheiden. Die Hippus waren ihm bis zu diesem Augenblick fremd vorgekommen, wie eine andere Art von Menschen. Ein Menschenleben voller Geschichten, die die Herzen der Zuhörer gegen sie aufbringen sollten, die die Unterschiede zwischen den Kulturen und ihrer Geschichte hervorhoben. Aber nun waren sie alle gleich, erschlagen und blutüberströmt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Welt um ihn herum verblich, und gegen den Eindruck, all dies sei nur ein Traum, sprach nur das Gefühl, er sei wach. Die Klänge der Schlacht räumten den Gebeten der Soldaten den Platz. Manche flehten um Schutz, das Groß jedoch bat für den Tod ihrer Feinde - allesamt in Todesangst. [PARAGRAPH:1] "Bist du bereit für den Tod?" [PARAGRAPH:1]Die Worte drangen in Parih ein, während er die Antwort suchte, sie streiften jeden der finsteren Gedanken, den er in sich bewahrte. Ein Mann auf einem blassen Pferd ritt auf ihn zu, und von ihm ging eine Boshaftigkeit aus, die es Parih unmöglich machte, zu Lügen.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich habe Angst."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Habe keine Angst vor dem Tod, du bist schließlich schon zuvor Tod gewesen. Glaubst du, das diese zeit mit deiner Geburt begann? Glaubst du an die unsterbliche Seele?" [PARAGRAPH:1] Parih konnte nicht antworten. Der Dämon lächelte süffisant.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Du bist nicht der Höhepunkt der Schöpfung, das Fleisch ist eine untaugliche, zeitweilige Fessel, an die die Seele gebunden ist. Wenn du weisst, das deine Seele nach deinem Ende weiterhin existiert, warum sollte man dann nicht auch annehmen, das sie vor deiner Geburt existierte? Und wenn deine Seele vor deiner Geburt an einem anderen Ort war, ist es dann nicht sinnvoll, anzunehmen, dass sie nach deinem Tod wieder dorthin zurückkehrt?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Dämon pausierte, um in Parihs Geist zu lesen, ob nun der rechte Moment gekommen wäre. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Nimm meine Hand, Sterblicher, und ich führe dich in das ewige Leben."[PARAGRAPH:1]Parih griff Ars skelettgleiche Hand, und im selben Atemzug wichen alle Erinnerungen an sein Leben aus ihm und er wurde als eine der zahlreichen willenlosen Geister der Verfallenen der Hölle wiedergeboren.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Du hast nicht das Recht, diese Seele zu stehlen, Dämon!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Reiter der Apokalypse drehte sich um und sah eine Walküre, die mit gezogener Waffe dastand. Sie erblasste, als sie Ars Morendi erkannte. Instinktiv ging sie einige Schritte zurück, ohne das er auch nur einen Schritt in ihre Richtung gemacht hätte.[PARAGRAPH:1]" Ich bin frei, und ich nehme mir alles, was ich will."[PARAGRAPH:1]Er ritt vorwärts, und die Walküre wich seinem Weg</German>
		<Italian>Parih stood unmoving, surrounded by the chaos of the battlefield. The screams and clash of weapons were only distant echoes to him. Soldiers fought and died for the ground he stood on, but he did not budge. They pushed through him, and he could not feel it.[PARAGRAPH:1]His broken body lay before him, covered with blood and indistinguishable from the corpses of enemies that lay around him. The Hippus had appeared so different to him, like another breed of men, before now. A lifetime of stories meant to turn hearts against them, extolling the differences in their culture and history. But now they looked the same, battered and bloody.[PARAGRAPH:1]The world faded around him, it would be as if Parih's vision grew worse except he felt so real and the world seemed to be nothing but a dream. The sounds of battle were replaced by the whispered prayers of the soldiers. A few requesting protection, most asking for the death of their enemies, all scared.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are you prepared for death?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The words reached into Parih, seeking the answer, touching every dark thought he maintained. A man on a pale horse rode toward him and though Parih felt evil from the man he was unable to lie.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I'm scared."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do not be afraid of death, you have been dead before. Do you believe that time began when you were born? Do you believe your soul to be immortal?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Parih was unable to answer. The demon smirked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You are not the catalyst of creation, flesh is an unfit and temporary vessel for a soul. If you know that your soul exists after your life ends, shouldn't you believe that it existed before your birth? And if your soul existed in a place before your birth, why would it not return there after your death?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The demon paused, reading Parih's thoughts, making sure this was the correct moment.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Take my hand mortal and I will lead you to the afterlife."[PARAGRAPH:1]Parih reached out and took Ars skeletal hand. In that instant the memories of his life were lost and he was reborn as one of the mindless Mane legions of hell.[PARAGRAPH:1]"That soul was not yours to claim demon!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Ars turned to see a Valkyrie with her weapon drawn. She paled when she recognized him, instinctively stepping back even though he hadn't made any move towards her.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am unbound, and claim any I choose."[PARAGRAPH:1]He rode forward and the Valkyrie moved out of his way.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Parih stood unmoving, surrounded by the chaos of the battlefield. The screams and clash of weapons were only distant echoes to him. Soldiers fought and died for the ground he stood on, but he did not budge. They pushed through him, and he could not feel it.[PARAGRAPH:1]His broken body lay before him, covered with blood and indistinguishable from the corpses of enemies that lay around him. The Hippus had appeared so different to him, like another breed of men, before now. A lifetime of stories meant to turn hearts against them, extolling the differences in their culture and history. But now they looked the same, battered and bloody.[PARAGRAPH:1]The world faded around him, it would be as if Parih's vision grew worse except he felt so real and the world seemed to be nothing but a dream. The sounds of battle were replaced by the whispered prayers of the soldiers. A few requesting protection, most asking for the death of their enemies, all scared.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Are you prepared for death?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The words reached into Parih, seeking the answer, touching every dark thought he maintained. A man on a pale horse rode toward him and though Parih felt evil from the man he was unable to lie.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I'm scared."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do not be afraid of death, you have been dead before. Do you believe that time began when you were born? Do you believe your soul to be immortal?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Parih was unable to answer. The demon smirked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You are not the catalyst of creation, flesh is an unfit and temporary vessel for a soul. If you know that your soul exists after your life ends, shouldn't you believe that it existed before your birth? And if your soul existed in a place before your birth, why would it not return there after your death?"[PARAGRAPH:1]The demon paused, reading Parih's thoughts, making sure this was the correct moment.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Take my hand mortal and I will lead you to the afterlife."[PARAGRAPH:1]Parih reached out and took Ars skeletal hand. In that instant the memories of his life were lost and he was reborn as one of the mindless Mane legions of hell.[PARAGRAPH:1]"That soul was not yours to claim demon!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Ars turned to see a Valkyrie with her weapon drawn. She paled when she recognized him, instinctively stepping back even though he hadn't made any move towards her.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am unbound, and claim any I choose."[PARAGRAPH:1]He rode forward and the Valkyrie moved out of his way.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARTHENDAIN</Tag>
		<English>Arthendain</English>
		<French>Arthendain</French>
		<German>Arthendain</German>
		<Italian>Arthendain</Italian>
		<Spanish>Arthendain</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARTHENDAIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An entire company was wiped out by her. She wore a ragged white dress and matted red hair, both of which clung to her like grease on a pan. She didn't carry any weapons, she didn't need them. Her claws were like iron, she was stronger than any girl. But she was just a girl, or at least once she had been. She clawed and bit at them, coughed and wheezed and fled. One of their number was dead and several were injured.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain began applying healing poultices to the wounds, but they were already growing green with infection. The finger sized gashes broke open, skin and muscle peeled back as if it was trying to escape the bone. They writhed in pain, and in minutes they looked as if they had been flogged with a whip; after a few more, they appeared as fresh zombies, still screaming, minds alive as their bodies died. Then finally, mercifully, they died.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain was uninjured from the fight, but still the disease spread. He grabbed his crossbow intent on making sure the girl didn't spread her disease any further. As he gripped the polished handle of his crossbow, he noticed his own hands had begun to redden and swell. He hurried to water; they were in the sewers beneath Prespur and normally he wouldn’t touch the water here, but it had to be better than what was on him. He scrubbed his hands, but it just got worse, then the coughing began.[PARAGRAPH:1]He heard himself screaming, exactly as the others. He fell into the water and died.[PARAGRAPH:1]The disease spread in the water; the next morning, the city would have awoken to a Plague. There would be barely any left by nightfall, if Sucellus had not interfered. His shadow passed through the sewers and gathered the disease into a earthen flask. He spoke to the water and it brought Arthendain from its depths and laid him at the god's feet. Sucellus asked for the dwarf's spirit and Arawn consented.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain doesn't remember much, everything from scrubbing his hands to waking up that next morning in a local tavern is little more than a blur. He remembers a man who healed him. He remembers being given the flask and told to keep it safe, and never open it. He remembers being told that he must find that girl. And to this day he has worked toward that goal.</English>
		<French>An entire company was wiped out by her. She wore a ragged white dress and matted red hair, both of which clung to her like grease on a pan. She didn't carry any weapons, she didn't need them. Her claws were like iron, she was stronger than any girl. But she was just a girl, or at least once she had been. She clawed and bit at them, coughed and wheezed and fled. One of their number was dead and several were injured.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain began applying healing poultices to the wounds, but they were already growing green with infection. The finger sized gashes broke open, skin and muscle peeled back as if it was trying to escape the bone. They writhed in pain, and in minutes they looked as if they had been flogged with a whip; after a few more, they appeared as fresh zombies, still screaming, minds alive as their bodies died. Then finally, mercifully, they died.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain was uninjured from the fight, but still the disease spread. He grabbed his crossbow intent on making sure the girl didn't spread her disease any further. As he gripped the polished handle of his crossbow, he noticed his own hands had begun to redden and swell. He hurried to water; they were in the sewers beneath Prespur and normally he wouldn’t touch the water here, but it had to be better than what was on him. He scrubbed his hands, but it just got worse, then the coughing began.[PARAGRAPH:1]He heard himself screaming, exactly as the others. He fell into the water and died.[PARAGRAPH:1]The disease spread in the water; the next morning, the city would have awoken to a Plague. There would be barely any left by nightfall, if Sucellus had not interfered. His shadow passed through the sewers and gathered the disease into a earthen flask. He spoke to the water and it brought Arthendain from its depths and laid him at the god's feet. Sucellus asked for the dwarf's spirit and Arawn consented.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain doesn't remember much, everything from scrubbing his hands to waking up that next morning in a local tavern is little more than a blur. He remembers a man who healed him. He remembers being given the flask and told to keep it safe, and never open it. He remembers being told that he must find that girl. And to this day he has worked toward that goal.</French>
		<German>Eine ganze Gesellschaft wurde von ihr ausgelöscht. Sie trug ein zerrissenes weißes Kleid und hatte mattes rotes Haar. Sie trug keine Waffen, denn sie brauchte keine. Ihre Klauen waren hart wie Eisen, sie war stärker als jedes andere Mädchen. Aber sie war nur ein Mädchen, zumindest war sie es einst. Sie zerkratzte sie, biss sie, dann keuchte und hustete sie und floh. Einer von ihnen war tot und viele waren verletzt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain begann damit die Wunden mit Heilumschlägen zu versorgen, doch sie färbten sich bereits grün von der Infektion. Die fingerbreiten Wunden brachen auf, Haut und Muskeln fielen ab als ob sie versuchten vor dem Knochen zu fliehen. Sie krümmten sich vor Schmerz und Minuten später sahen sie aus, als wären sie mit einer Peitsche geschlagen worden, weitere Minuten später sahen sie aus wie auferstandene Zombies, noch immer schreiend, wie lebende Seelen deren Körper stirbt. Dann schließlich, gnädigerweise, starben sie. [PARAGRAPH:1] Arthendain war vom Kampf unverletzt, aber noch immer verbreitete sich die Seuche. Er griff nach seinem Bogen um sicherzugehen, dass das Mädchen die Krankheit nicht noch weiter verbreitete. Als er den polierten Griff seines Bogens berührte fiel ihm auf, dass seine eigenen Hände zu erröten begannen und anschwollen. Er eilte zum Wasser, sie waren in der Kanalisation unter Prespur und normalerweise würde er dieses Wasser nicht benutzen, aber er vermutete das er damit die Seuche von seinen Händen Wischen konnte. Er schrubbte seine Hände, aber es wurde nur noch schlimmer, dann begann das husten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er hörte sich selbst schreien, so wie all die anderen. Er fiel in das Wasser und starb.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Seuche verbreitete sich im Wasser und am nächsten Morgen wäre die Stadt Prespur verseucht gewesen. Bis zum Abend wären dann alle Bewohner der stadt gestorben, hätte Sucellus nicht eingegriffen. Sein Schatten wanderte durch die Kanalisation und sammelte die Krankheit in einer Flasche aus Erde. Er sprach zum Wasser und es brachte Arthendain aus seinen Tiefen und legte ihn zu Füßen Gottes. Sucellus bat um den Geist des Zwerges und Arawn stimmte zu. [PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain erinnerte sich nicht an viel, alles ab dem schrubben der Hände bis zu seinem Erwachen am nächsten Morgen in einer der Örtlichen Tavernen ist wenig mehr als ein verschwommener Schleier. Er erinnerte sich an einen Mann der ihn heilte. Er erinnerte sich daran die Flasche erhalten zu haben um sie sicher zu verwahren und niemals zu öffnen. Er erinnerte sich daran dass er das Mädchen finden muss. Und bis zum heutigen Tage hat er auf dieses Ziel hingearbeitet.</German>
		<Italian>An entire company was wiped out by her. She wore a ragged white dress and matted red hair, both of which clung to her like grease on a pan. She didn't carry any weapons, she didn't need them. Her claws were like iron, she was stronger than any girl. But she was just a girl, or at least once she had been. She clawed and bit at them, coughed and wheezed and fled. One of their number was dead and several were injured.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain began applying healing poultices to the wounds, but they were already growing green with infection. The finger sized gashes broke open, skin and muscle peeled back as if it was trying to escape the bone. They writhed in pain, and in minutes they looked as if they had been flogged with a whip; after a few more, they appeared as fresh zombies, still screaming, minds alive as their bodies died. Then finally, mercifully, they died.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain was uninjured from the fight, but still the disease spread. He grabbed his crossbow intent on making sure the girl didn't spread her disease any further. As he gripped the polished handle of his crossbow, he noticed his own hands had begun to redden and swell. He hurried to water; they were in the sewers beneath Prespur and normally he wouldn’t touch the water here, but it had to be better than what was on him. He scrubbed his hands, but it just got worse, then the coughing began.[PARAGRAPH:1]He heard himself screaming, exactly as the others. He fell into the water and died.[PARAGRAPH:1]The disease spread in the water; the next morning, the city would have awoken to a Plague. There would be barely any left by nightfall, if Sucellus had not interfered. His shadow passed through the sewers and gathered the disease into a earthen flask. He spoke to the water and it brought Arthendain from its depths and laid him at the god's feet. Sucellus asked for the dwarf's spirit and Arawn consented.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain doesn't remember much, everything from scrubbing his hands to waking up that next morning in a local tavern is little more than a blur. He remembers a man who healed him. He remembers being given the flask and told to keep it safe, and never open it. He remembers being told that he must find that girl. And to this day he has worked toward that goal.</Italian>
		<Spanish>An entire company was wiped out by her. She wore a ragged white dress and matted red hair, both of which clung to her like grease on a pan. She didn't carry any weapons, she didn't need them. Her claws were like iron, she was stronger than any girl. But she was just a girl, or at least once she had been. She clawed and bit at them, coughed and wheezed and fled. One of their number was dead and several were injured.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain began applying healing poultices to the wounds, but they were already growing green with infection. The finger sized gashes broke open, skin and muscle peeled back as if it was trying to escape the bone. They writhed in pain, and in minutes they looked as if they had been flogged with a whip; after a few more, they appeared as fresh zombies, still screaming, minds alive as their bodies died. Then finally, mercifully, they died.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain was uninjured from the fight, but still the disease spread. He grabbed his crossbow intent on making sure the girl didn't spread her disease any further. As he gripped the polished handle of his crossbow, he noticed his own hands had begun to redden and swell. He hurried to water; they were in the sewers beneath Prespur and normally he wouldn’t touch the water here, but it had to be better than what was on him. He scrubbed his hands, but it just got worse, then the coughing began.[PARAGRAPH:1]He heard himself screaming, exactly as the others. He fell into the water and died.[PARAGRAPH:1]The disease spread in the water; the next morning, the city would have awoken to a Plague. There would be barely any left by nightfall, if Sucellus had not interfered. His shadow passed through the sewers and gathered the disease into a earthen flask. He spoke to the water and it brought Arthendain from its depths and laid him at the god's feet. Sucellus asked for the dwarf's spirit and Arawn consented.[PARAGRAPH:1]Arthendain doesn't remember much, everything from scrubbing his hands to waking up that next morning in a local tavern is little more than a blur. He remembers a man who healed him. He remembers being given the flask and told to keep it safe, and never open it. He remembers being told that he must find that girl. And to this day he has worked toward that goal.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ARTHENDAIN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Arthendain will only join Runes of Kilmorph civilizations. He is a healer who is able to cure disease on units in the same stack and is immune to disease himself.[NEWLINE]Note on promotions: First Aid is mostly useless on Arthendain since Medic3 promotion already adds 60% to the normal heal rate.</English>
		<French>Arthendain rejoindra seulement les civilisations des Runes de Kilmorph. C'est un guérisseur qui est capable de guérir les maladie des unités dans la même pile et qui est lui-même immunisé à la maladie.</French>
		<German>Arthendain schliesst sich nur Zivilisationen der Runen von Kilmorph an. Er besitzt die Fähigkeit, kranke Einheiten zu heilen und ist selbst immun.</German>
		<Italian>Arthendain will only join Runes of Kilmorph civilizations. He is a healer who is able to cure disease on units in the same stack and is immune to disease himself.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Arthendain will only join Runes of Kilmorph civilizations. He is a healer who is able to cure disease on units in the same stack and is immune to disease himself.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BARBATOS</Tag>
		<English>Barbatos The Lich</English>
		<French>Barbatos la Liche</French>
		<German>Barbatos The Lich</German>
		<Italian>Barbatos The Lich</Italian>
		<Spanish>Barbatos The Lich</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BARBATOS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Member of the Imprimatur Council. Member of the Coven of the Black Candle. Duke of the Patrian Duchy of Palus.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Barbatos was a warlord during the godswar. One of the few humans to join the conflict he led a tribe of men against Arawn, the god of death. They killed Arawn's servants, and reached Arawn's throne where Arawn was recovering from battle. Barbatos and his men attacked the god. Arawn lashed out, killing all the tribesmen instantly. But he cursed Barbatos, that he would be ever dying, but may never enter Arawn's realm. Barbatos has a Rod of Summoning and is fond of summoning earth elementals in a graveyard so they have rotting corpses in them.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Age of Magic, he was found by Kylorin who formally taught him Magic, making Barbatos one of his apprentices and the best Necromancer of Patria. He joined The Coven of the Black Candle (and thus own one of the Masks) and participated in the Ritual of the Endless Night. During the third Patrian Revolution, Kylorin ended up locking Barbatos into his Sepulchar, from which he was freed at some point during the Age of Rebirth.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Age of Invention Barbatos traded away his Mask of the Coven of the Black Candle so that it can be used to steal the Opalus Mortis. In exchange he wanted the Opalus Mortis used to break the curse and end his life, which it was.</English>
		<French>Member of the Imprimatur Council. Member of the Coven of the Black Candle. Duke of the Patrian Duchy of Palus.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Barbatos was a warlord during the godswar. One of the few humans to join the conflict he led a tribe of men against Arawn, the god of death. They killed Arawn's servants, and reached Arawn's throne where Arawn was recovering from battle. Barbatos and his men attacked the god. Arawn lashed out, killing all the tribesmen instantly. But he cursed Barbatos, that he would be ever dying, but may never enter Arawn's realm. Barbatos has a Rod of Summoning and is fond of summoning earth elementals in a graveyard so they have rotting corpses in them.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Age of Magic, he was found by Kylorin who formally taught him Magic, making Barbatos one of his apprentices and the best Necromancer of Patria. He joined The Coven of the Black Candle (and thus own one of the Masks) and participated in the Ritual of the Endless Night. During the third Patrian Revolution, Kylorin ended up locking Barbatos into his Sepulchar, from which he was freed at some point during the Age of Rebirth.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Age of Invention Barbatos traded away his Mask of the Coven of the Black Candle so that it can be used to steal the Opalus Mortis. In exchange he wanted the Opalus Mortis used to break the curse and end his life, which it was.</French>
		<German>Member of the Imprimatur Council. Member of the Coven of the Black Candle. Duke of the Patrian Duchy of Palus.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Barbatos was a warlord during the godswar. One of the few humans to join the conflict he led a tribe of men against Arawn, the god of death. They killed Arawn's servants, and reached Arawn's throne where Arawn was recovering from battle. Barbatos and his men attacked the god. Arawn lashed out, killing all the tribesmen instantly. But he cursed Barbatos, that he would be ever dying, but may never enter Arawn's realm. Barbatos has a Rod of Summoning and is fond of summoning earth elementals in a graveyard so they have rotting corpses in them.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Age of Magic, he was found by Kylorin who formally taught him Magic, making Barbatos one of his apprentices and the best Necromancer of Patria. He joined The Coven of the Black Candle (and thus own one of the Masks) and participated in the Ritual of the Endless Night. During the third Patrian Revolution, Kylorin ended up locking Barbatos into his Sepulchar, from which he was freed at some point during the Age of Rebirth.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Age of Invention Barbatos traded away his Mask of the Coven of the Black Candle so that it can be used to steal the Opalus Mortis. In exchange he wanted the Opalus Mortis used to break the curse and end his life, which it was.</German>
		<Italian>Member of the Imprimatur Council. Member of the Coven of the Black Candle. Duke of the Patrian Duchy of Palus.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Barbatos was a warlord during the godswar. One of the few humans to join the conflict he led a tribe of men against Arawn, the god of death. They killed Arawn's servants, and reached Arawn's throne where Arawn was recovering from battle. Barbatos and his men attacked the god. Arawn lashed out, killing all the tribesmen instantly. But he cursed Barbatos, that he would be ever dying, but may never enter Arawn's realm. Barbatos has a Rod of Summoning and is fond of summoning earth elementals in a graveyard so they have rotting corpses in them.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Age of Magic, he was found by Kylorin who formally taught him Magic, making Barbatos one of his apprentices and the best Necromancer of Patria. He joined The Coven of the Black Candle (and thus own one of the Masks) and participated in the Ritual of the Endless Night. During the third Patrian Revolution, Kylorin ended up locking Barbatos into his Sepulchar, from which he was freed at some point during the Age of Rebirth.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Age of Invention Barbatos traded away his Mask of the Coven of the Black Candle so that it can be used to steal the Opalus Mortis. In exchange he wanted the Opalus Mortis used to break the curse and end his life, which it was.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Member of the Imprimatur Council. Member of the Coven of the Black Candle. Duke of the Patrian Duchy of Palus.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Barbatos was a warlord during the godswar. One of the few humans to join the conflict he led a tribe of men against Arawn, the god of death. They killed Arawn's servants, and reached Arawn's throne where Arawn was recovering from battle. Barbatos and his men attacked the god. Arawn lashed out, killing all the tribesmen instantly. But he cursed Barbatos, that he would be ever dying, but may never enter Arawn's realm. Barbatos has a Rod of Summoning and is fond of summoning earth elementals in a graveyard so they have rotting corpses in them.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Age of Magic, he was found by Kylorin who formally taught him Magic, making Barbatos one of his apprentices and the best Necromancer of Patria. He joined The Coven of the Black Candle (and thus own one of the Masks) and participated in the Ritual of the Endless Night. During the third Patrian Revolution, Kylorin ended up locking Barbatos into his Sepulchar, from which he was freed at some point during the Age of Rebirth.
[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the Age of Invention Barbatos traded away his Mask of the Coven of the Black Candle so that it can be used to steal the Opalus Mortis. In exchange he wanted the Opalus Mortis used to break the curse and end his life, which it was.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WRATH</Tag>
		<English>Avatar of Wrath</English>
		<French>Avatar du Courroux</French>
		<German>Avatar des Zorns</German>
		<Italian>Avatar of Wrath</Italian>
		<Spanish>Avatar of Wrath</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WRATH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Avatar of Wrath is a powerful unit which is created when the Armageddon Counter gets high enough. Wrath comes into play as a barbarian unit and a large percentage of the worlds living units will convert to his cause when he appears.</English>
		<French>[TAB]L'Avatar du Courroux est une puissante unité qui est créé lorsque la merveille Fureur Déchaînée est terminée. Le Courroux entre en jeu comme une unité barbare et conquiert une ville au hasard.</French>
		<German>Der Avatar des Zorns ist eine mächtige Einheit, welche bei Fertigstellung des Wunders "Entfesselter Zorn" die Welt betritt. Als barbarische Einheit übernimmt er eine zufällig gewählte Stadt.</German>
		<Italian>The Avatar of Wrath is a powerful unit which is created when the Armageddon Counter gets high enough. Wrath comes into play as a barbarian unit and a large percentage of the worlds living units will convert to his cause when he appears.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Avatar of Wrath is a powerful unit which is created when the Armageddon Counter gets high enough. Wrath comes into play as a barbarian unit and a large percentage of the worlds living units will convert to his cause when he appears.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_YERSINIA</Tag>
		<English>Yersinia</English>
		<French>Yersinia</French>
		<German>Yersinia</German>
		<Italian>Yersinia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Yersinia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_YERSINIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Father abandoned child, wife husband, one brother another; for this illness seemed to strike through the breath and sight. And so they died. And none could be found to bury the dead for money or friendship. Members of a household brought their dead to a ditch as best they could, without priest, without divine offices ... great pits were dug and piled deep with the multitude of dead. And they died by the hundreds both day and night... And as soon as those ditches were filled more were dug ... And I, Agnolo di Tura, called the Fat, buried my five children with my own hands. And there were also those who were so sparsely covered with earth that the dogs dragged them forth and devoured many bodies throughout the city. There was no one who wept for any death, for all awaited death. And so many died that all believed it was the end of the world."</English>
		<French>"Father abandoned child, wife husband, one brother another; for this illness seemed to strike through the breath and sight. And so they died. And none could be found to bury the dead for money or friendship. Members of a household brought their dead to a ditch as best they could, without priest, without divine offices ... great pits were dug and piled deep with the multitude of dead. And they died by the hundreds both day and night... And as soon as those ditches were filled more were dug ... And I, Agnolo di Tura, called the Fat, buried my five children with my own hands. And there were also those who were so sparsely covered with earth that the dogs dragged them forth and devoured many bodies throughout the city. There was no one who wept for any death, for all awaited death. And so many died that all believed it was the end of the world."</French>
		<German>"Der Vater verliess das Kind, die Frau ihren Mann, ein Bruder den anderen, für diese Krankheit schien zu gelten, dass sie sich durch den Atem und allein durch sehen verbreitet. Und so starben sie. Und niemand ließ sich finden, die Toten zu begraben nicht für Geld und nicht aus Freundschaft. Die Mitglieder einer Hausgemeinschaft brachten ihre Toten zu einer der Gruben, es war das beste was sie tun konnten, ohne Priester, ohne Gottesdienst... große Gruben wurden ausgehoben und aufgefüllt mit der Vielzahl der verstorbenen. Und sie starben zu hunderten sowohl am Tage als auch in der Nacht... Und sobald die Gräben gefüllt waren, gruben sie neue... Und ich , Agnolo di Tura, genannt der Fette, begrub meine fünf Kinder mit meinen eigenen Händen. Und es gab auch jene welche so dürftig mit Erde bedeckt waren, dass die Hunde sie durch die Stadt schleiften und verschlangen. Es gab niemanden der um die Toten geweint hat, weil, alle erwarteten den Tod. Und so viele starben das alle dachten das sei  das Ende der Welt."</German>
		<Italian>"Father abandoned child, wife husband, one brother another; for this illness seemed to strike through the breath and sight. And so they died. And none could be found to bury the dead for money or friendship. Members of a household brought their dead to a ditch as best they could, without priest, without divine offices ... great pits were dug and piled deep with the multitude of dead. And they died by the hundreds both day and night... And as soon as those ditches were filled more were dug ... And I, Agnolo di Tura, called the Fat, buried my five children with my own hands. And there were also those who were so sparsely covered with earth that the dogs dragged them forth and devoured many bodies throughout the city. There was no one who wept for any death, for all awaited death. And so many died that all believed it was the end of the world."</Italian>
		<Spanish>"Father abandoned child, wife husband, one brother another; for this illness seemed to strike through the breath and sight. And so they died. And none could be found to bury the dead for money or friendship. Members of a household brought their dead to a ditch as best they could, without priest, without divine offices ... great pits were dug and piled deep with the multitude of dead. And they died by the hundreds both day and night... And as soon as those ditches were filled more were dug ... And I, Agnolo di Tura, called the Fat, buried my five children with my own hands. And there were also those who were so sparsely covered with earth that the dogs dragged them forth and devoured many bodies throughout the city. There was no one who wept for any death, for all awaited death. And so many died that all believed it was the end of the world."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_YVAIN</Tag>
		<English>Yvain</English>
		<French>Yvain l'Elfe Sylvain</French>
		<German>Yvain der Waldelf</German>
		<Italian>Yvain</Italian>
		<Spanish>Yvain</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_YVAIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Yvain's eccentric nature leads him across Erebus, visiting secluded glades, talking to exotic animals and chasing nymphs across pebbled river banks.[PARAGRAPH:1]Even some within the Fellowship question if Yvain has the sincerity his respected stature would seem to require of him, but none doubt that he is the favored child of Cernunnos. It was Yvain that first dreamed of the Ancient Forests and who is the first to face every newly discovered wilderness. To everyone who delights in finding the wonders of this world, know that Yvain has walked through these places before, and that they are all the more amazing because of it.</English>
		<French>Yvain's eccentric nature leads him across Erebus, visiting secluded glades, talking to exotic animals and chasing nymphs across pebbled river banks.[PARAGRAPH:1]Even some within the Fellowship question if Yvain has the sincerity his respected stature would seem to require of him, but none doubt that he is the favored child of Cernunnos. It was Yvain that first dreamed of the Ancient Forests and who is the first to face every newly discovered wilderness. To everyone who delights in finding the wonders of this world, know that Yvain has walked through these places before, and that they are all the more amazing because of it.</French>
		<German>Seine Ideen und seine Art lassen Andere oftmals glauben, Yvain könnte vom Mond gekommen sein anstatt aus seinen geliebten Wäldern. Seine exzentrische Natur führt ihn quer durch Erebus, er besucht abgelegene Lichtungen, spricht mit exotischen Tieren und jagt Nymphen über die mit Kieselsteinen übersäten Flussufer.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sogar einige der Gefährten fragen, ob Yvain die nötige Ernsthaftigkeit mitbringt, welche sein Status als angesehene Persönlichkeit scheinbar von ihm abverlangt, doch niemand zweifelt daran, dass er der mächtigste aller Druiden und das Lieblingskind von Cernunnos ist. Es war Yvain, welcher zuerst von den alten Wäldern geträumt hat und jedes neu entdeckte Gebiet wird zuerst von ihm erkundet. Jeder, dem es eine Freude ist die Wunder dieser Welt zu finden, weiß genau, dass der Waldelf all diese Orte bereits besucht hat, und dass sie dadurch noch bewundernswerter sind.</German>
		<Italian>Yvain's eccentric nature leads him across Erebus, visiting secluded glades, talking to exotic animals and chasing nymphs across pebbled river banks.[PARAGRAPH:1]Even some within the Fellowship question if Yvain has the sincerity his respected stature would seem to require of him, but none doubt that he is the favored child of Cernunnos. It was Yvain that first dreamed of the Ancient Forests and who is the first to face every newly discovered wilderness. To everyone who delights in finding the wonders of this world, know that Yvain has walked through these places before, and that they are all the more amazing because of it.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Yvain's eccentric nature leads him across Erebus, visiting secluded glades, talking to exotic animals and chasing nymphs across pebbled river banks.[PARAGRAPH:1]Even some within the Fellowship question if Yvain has the sincerity his respected stature would seem to require of him, but none doubt that he is the favored child of Cernunnos. It was Yvain that first dreamed of the Ancient Forests and who is the first to face every newly discovered wilderness. To everyone who delights in finding the wonders of this world, know that Yvain has walked through these places before, and that they are all the more amazing because of it.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_YVAIN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Yvain can move in mountains, summon treants, and is a powerful defender when fighting in forests.</English>
		<French>Yvain can move in mountains, summon treants, and is a powerful defender when fighting in forests.</French>
		<German>Yvain kann sich im Gebirge bewegen, Baumhirten und Dornenwände beschwören, und besitzt eine erhebliche Durchschlagskraft bei Kämpfen im Wald.</German>
		<Italian>Yvain can move in mountains, summon treants, and is a powerful defender when fighting in forests.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Yvain can move in mountains, summon treants, and is a powerful defender when fighting in forests.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MARY</Tag>
		<English>Mary Morbus</English>
		<French>Marie Typhoïde</French>
		<German>Marie Morbus</German>
		<Italian>Mary Morbus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mary Morbus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>We were at the gates, we were almost there. Everything was going so well. The Citadel lay within our grasp, the battle would soon be over. Then we heard it. A death rattle of a cough that froze the blood to ice. No one had told us Mary was here. No one had warned us...And then the horrible screech, and she was on us, tearing into the men in front of me, a cloud of pestilence following her like an aura. She...I...I'm sorry, Master. We failed Junil. She was too much.-Dying words of Truls Dagrend, 1st. Order Shield Troops, recorded at Crusader Plague Hospital.[PARAGRAPH:1] Mary is like a dread creature from some fevered nightmare. Pale as death and twisted into a crippled and deformed shadow of a human being, her appearance reveals the madness within. She is surprisingly dangerous, biting and slashing with her clawlike nails. Even those who survive initial contacts often succumb to the insidious plague she carries-but not before they spread it to those unfortunate enough to come in contact with them. Despite her appearance and homicidal fury, Mary's story is a pitiful one. Born of unholy experiments in alchemy, she has never lived a normal life-in fact, she has never truly "lived" at all. She is a human biological weapon, twisted and permanently tortured by her man-made disease. Perhaps her bloodlust is a hunt to find someone who can finally kill her and give her release?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As I beheld the child, for a child she was despite everything, the true horror of what they were doing to her, what they had done to her, suddenly struck me. I beheld her deformed limbs, the green sticky filth her body was soiled in, but most of all the expression on her face as she screamed. I don't think I've ever seen a being in such agony, and every night since that horrible day, I've prayed in vain for the gods to strike me with amnesia.-Vilys Meer, Midwife</English>
		<French>We were at the gates, we were almost there. Everything was going so well. The Citadel lay within our grasp, the battle would soon be over. Then we heard it. A death rattle of a cough that froze the blood to ice. No one had told us Mary was here. No one had warned us...And then the horrible screech, and she was on us, tearing into the men in front of me, a cloud of pestilence following her like an aura. She...I...I'm sorry, Master. We failed Junil. She was too much.-Dying words of Truls Dagrend, 1st. Order Shield Troops, recorded at Crusader Plague Hospital.[PARAGRAPH:1] Mary is like a dread creature from some fevered nightmare. Pale as death and twisted into a crippled and deformed shadow of a human being, her appearance reveals the madness within. She is surprisingly dangerous, biting and slashing with her clawlike nails. Even those who survive initial contacts often succumb to the insidious plague she carries-but not before they spread it to those unfortunate enough to come in contact with them. Despite her appearance and homicidal fury, Mary's story is a pitiful one. Born of unholy experiments in alchemy, she has never lived a normal life-in fact, she has never truly "lived" at all. She is a human biological weapon, twisted and permanently tortured by her man-made disease. Perhaps her bloodlust is a hunt to find someone who can finally kill her and give her release?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As I beheld the child, for a child she was despite everything, the true horror of what they were doing to her, what they had done to her, suddenly struck me. I beheld her deformed limbs, the green sticky filth her body was soiled in, but most of all the expression on her face as she screamed. I don't think I've ever seen a being in such agony, and every night since that horrible day, I've prayed in vain for the gods to strike me with amnesia.-Vilys Meer, Midwife</French>
		<German>Wir waren schon an den Toren, wir hatten es fast geschafft. Alles war glatt gelaufen. Vor uns erhob sich die Zitadelle, bald würde der Kampf vorbei sein. Dann hörten wir es. Ein röchelndes Husten, das uns das Blut in den Adern gefrieren lies. Niemand hatte uns gesagt, das Mary hier sein würde. Niemand hatte uns gewarnt… Ein grauenerregendes Kreischen, und schon war sie da, mein Vordermann wurde förmlich von ihr zerfetzt. Um sie herum waberten Schwaden, eine greifbare Aura der Pestilenz. Sie… Es… Es tut mir leid Meister… Wir haben es nicht bis zu Junil geschafft… Sie war einfach... zu mächtig... - Truls Dagrend, Streiter der 1. Schildtruppe der Weisung, letzte Worte, aufgezeichnet im Seuchenhospiz der Kreuzritter[PARAGRAPH:1]Marys Aussehen erweckt den Anschein, als sei sie dem Fieberwahn eines Kranken entsprungen: Bleich wie die Toten ist sie, ihre menschenähnliche Gestalt ist bis zur Unkenntlichkeit deformiert, als sei der Wahnsinn ihres Geistes selbst nach außen gekehrt worden. Ihr Aussehen mag schrecklich genug sein, aber noch schlimmer sind ihr Gebiss und ihre klauenartigen Fingernägel. Selbst jene, die die Begegnung mit ihr überleben, sind dem Tod geweiht: Krankheiten und Seuchen folgen Mary wie ihr Schatten, raffen den Unglücklichen und all Jene, die mit ihm in Kontakt kamen, dahin. Trotz ihres Aussehens und ihrem mörderischen Wahn ist Mary im Grunde eine bemitleidenswerte Existenz. Geboren aus den unheiligen Experimenten der Alchemie hatte sie nie die Gelegenheit, ein normales Leben kennen zu lernen – zumal sie niemals wirklich lebendig gewesen war. Geschaffen wurde sie von Menschenhand als ein Seuchenbringer, und so zehren die Siechen, die sie in sich trägt, nicht nur an ihrem Körper, sondern auch an ihrer Seele. Und wer weiß, vielleicht ist ihr Blutdurst auch nur die Suche nach einem Wesen, das sie endlich von ihren unsagbaren Leiden erlösen kann?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Als ich das Kind erblickte – und das war sie, trotz allem was man ihr angetan hatten – sah ich plötzlich das ganze Ausmaß dieses Wahnsinns. Ich sah die deformierten, grünlichen Glieder, ich sah den klebrigen Schleim, der ihren Körper bedeckte, doch das Schlimmste: ich sah den grausam verzerrten Ausdruck auf ihrem Gesicht, während sie wieder und wieder aufschrie. Ich habe schon viele Dinge erlebt, doch noch nie hatte ich solche Qualen bei irgendeinem Wesen erblickt. Und in jeder Nacht, seit diesem Tag, bete ich zu den Göttern, sie mögen den Schleier des Vergessens über meinen Erinnerungen ausbreiten. -- Vilys Meer, Hebamme</German>
		<Italian>We were at the gates, we were almost there. Everything was going so well. The Citadel lay within our grasp, the battle would soon be over. Then we heard it. A death rattle of a cough that froze the blood to ice. No one had told us Mary was here. No one had warned us...And then the horrible screech, and she was on us, tearing into the men in front of me, a cloud of pestilence following her like an aura. She...I...I'm sorry, Master. We failed Junil. She was too much.-Dying words of Truls Dagrend, 1st. Order Shield Troops, recorded at Crusader Plague Hospital.[PARAGRAPH:1] Mary is like a dread creature from some fevered nightmare. Pale as death and twisted into a crippled and deformed shadow of a human being, her appearance reveals the madness within. She is surprisingly dangerous, biting and slashing with her clawlike nails. Even those who survive initial contacts often succumb to the insidious plague she carries-but not before they spread it to those unfortunate enough to come in contact with them. Despite her appearance and homicidal fury, Mary's story is a pitiful one. Born of unholy experiments in alchemy, she has never lived a normal life-in fact, she has never truly "lived" at all. She is a human biological weapon, twisted and permanently tortured by her man-made disease. Perhaps her bloodlust is a hunt to find someone who can finally kill her and give her release?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As I beheld the child, for a child she was despite everything, the true horror of what they were doing to her, what they had done to her, suddenly struck me. I beheld her deformed limbs, the green sticky filth her body was soiled in, but most of all the expression on her face as she screamed. I don't think I've ever seen a being in such agony, and every night since that horrible day, I've prayed in vain for the gods to strike me with amnesia.-Vilys Meer, Midwife</Italian>
		<Spanish>We were at the gates, we were almost there. Everything was going so well. The Citadel lay within our grasp, the battle would soon be over. Then we heard it. A death rattle of a cough that froze the blood to ice. No one had told us Mary was here. No one had warned us...And then the horrible screech, and she was on us, tearing into the men in front of me, a cloud of pestilence following her like an aura. She...I...I'm sorry, Master. We failed Junil. She was too much.-Dying words of Truls Dagrend, 1st. Order Shield Troops, recorded at Crusader Plague Hospital.[PARAGRAPH:1] Mary is like a dread creature from some fevered nightmare. Pale as death and twisted into a crippled and deformed shadow of a human being, her appearance reveals the madness within. She is surprisingly dangerous, biting and slashing with her clawlike nails. Even those who survive initial contacts often succumb to the insidious plague she carries-but not before they spread it to those unfortunate enough to come in contact with them. Despite her appearance and homicidal fury, Mary's story is a pitiful one. Born of unholy experiments in alchemy, she has never lived a normal life-in fact, she has never truly "lived" at all. She is a human biological weapon, twisted and permanently tortured by her man-made disease. Perhaps her bloodlust is a hunt to find someone who can finally kill her and give her release?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As I beheld the child, for a child she was despite everything, the true horror of what they were doing to her, what they had done to her, suddenly struck me. I beheld her deformed limbs, the green sticky filth her body was soiled in, but most of all the expression on her face as she screamed. I don't think I've ever seen a being in such agony, and every night since that horrible day, I've prayed in vain for the gods to strike me with amnesia.-Vilys Meer, Midwife</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MARY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Bearer of the Plague. Mary transmits the Plague to stacks she attacks. She is the only unit that can transmit the plague but the negative heal rate it gives will leave them vulnerable until they can reach a priest or source of sacred water.</English>
		<French>Bearer of the Plague. Mary transmits the Plague to stacks she attacks. She is the only unit that can transmit the plague but the negative heal rate it gives will leave them vulnerable until they can reach a priest or source of sacred water.</French>
		<German>Überträger der Pest. Die Pest Marie überträgt die Seuche an Armeen, die sie angreift. Sie ist die einzige Einheit, die die Seuche übertragen kann und die negative Heilungsrate kann Einheiten noch Runden nach ihrem Angriff dahinraffen.</German>
		<Italian>Bearer of the Plague. Mary transmits the Plague to stacks she attacks. She is the only unit that can transmit the plague but the negative heal rate it gives will leave them vulnerable until they can reach a priest or source of sacred water.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Bearer of the Plague. Mary transmits the Plague to stacks she attacks. She is the only unit that can transmit the plague but the negative heal rate it gives will leave them vulnerable until they can reach a priest or source of sacred water.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MARDERO</Tag>
		<English>Mardero</English>
		<French>Mardèro</French>
		<German>Erzdämon Mardero</German>
		<Italian>Mardero</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mardero</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MARDERO_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The basilica was flooded with screaming, a mob calling for the death of Lita. Long suspected of witchcraft, she was found with crow's blood on her forehead and eyelids, evidence of her attempts at clairvoyance through dark rites.[PARAGRAPH:1]The adjudicator listened to the guardsman's retelling of her capture. A neighbor claimed to have seen a cat walking backwards from her house and a pigeon handing upside down from the eaves like a bat. The guards had been called to check it out, not an uncommon occurrence for Lita. But this time she didn't open the door, and when the guardsman entered, they found her in her basement deep in a trance, with the crow's broken body beside her.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What are the names of these demons you say I follow?" Lita argued, "Hate, suspicion, fear, weakness, pride. Do you believe these are my demons or your own? You scream because I killed a bird, yet you will return to your mutton dinner tonight and see no hypocrisy. You claim that what I have done is evil, yet the temple diviners perform the same acts with oils and burnt incense."[PARAGRAPH:1]She shook with rage, her voice carried an authority far beyond her 24 years. She turned and glared at the townspeople, most she had known her entire life, and each one quieted under her gaze, but then picked the screaming back up when her eyes were off of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]The adjudicator was Goroff Grist and he had served in this role for nearly 30 years. He wasn't concerned with Lita's pagan ritual but he was very concerned with the effect she had on the city. This kind of disharmony could not be tolerated in a cultured society; she had been warned before about her questionable behavior and refused to become a good citizen. He had known the outcome of this trial the second she was dragged into the basilica.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goroff opened the large tome before him. The hall went quiet as he scribed Lita's name and the verdict. Everyone strained to gain some clue from the stroke of his quill as to the final decision. Goroff sprinkled find sand on the ink and blew on it, then he closed the tome.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The testimony has been heard and a just decision has been made. Lita of Alexandria will be exiled from the Empire. This exile will be initiated by throwing her from the Cliffs of Hastur. We will see if she will follow the crow's fate and have her body broken, or gain the crow's gift and be saved from the rocks below."[PARAGRAPH:1]The crowd cheered the decision, Lita screamed and attacked the guardsmen that held her. They wrestled her into submission and began the march to the edge of the cliffs. By the time they reached them, the crowd had grown and hundreds of townspeople were there to witness her death.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was an early spring day and the mists common to cliffs still hung around its base. Lita had stopped struggling and stood unmoving at the cliffs edge. She told herself that she would die without weakness and step over the edge on her own, but she found herself unable to do so. She sensed something much worse than death over the cliff's edge. Then the guardsman pushed her.[PARAGRAPH:1]She fell. Her life passed before her, pain inflicted by her and on her, actions performed both good and evil. She considered her own regret, had she become something she didn't intend? She pushed the thoughts from her mind, she was not the one at fault, but the people of Alexandria. She fed off of her own hate, wished only that they would suffer for what they had done to her.[PARAGRAPH:1]She passed into the mists and heard the snap of thick leather, like the crack of a whip all around her. A dark form slammed into her and at first she though it was the ground, but her direction changed and she felt herself being carried along the cliff's edge. A beast held her, and she struggled to see its face. It had thick hide wings and skin that felt like a serpents, but hard and warm. The face was a man's, horrible and beautiful, horns and smaller bones pierced his skin and thick iron pins were inserted into the inside curve of his eye, just where tears are formed.[PARAGRAPH:1]He took her to a dark place, Hell or some hidden cave, it was the same to Lita. She became his unwilling concubine, mother of his half-demonic children. His spells kept the many pregnancies from killing her, but they did nothing for the pain which was so intense that she wished for the times when she wasn't pregnant and had only to suffer the brutal rapes. And during the periods of the rapes she wished for the times she was pregnant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mardero was the last of these children. His birth was so traumatic that even his father's considerable power couldn't keep Lita alive through it. His first act in this world was to join his siblings in consuming his mothers flesh, the first of many human victims his father would bring them as they grew.[PARAGRAPH:1]Now Mardero roams the land, unbound by the Compact because of his human heritage but as destructive and loyal to the forces of Entropy as any demon.</English>
		<French>The basilica was flooded with screaming, a mob calling for the death of Lita. Long suspected of witchcraft, she was found with crow's blood on her forehead and eyelids, evidence of her attempts at clairvoyance through dark rites.[PARAGRAPH:1]The adjudicator listened to the guardsman's retelling of her capture. A neighbor claimed to have seen a cat walking backwards from her house and a pigeon handing upside down from the eaves like a bat. The guards had been called to check it out, not an uncommon occurrence for Lita. But this time she didn't open the door, and when the guardsman entered, they found her in her basement deep in a trance, with the crow's broken body beside her.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What are the names of these demons you say I follow?" Lita argued, "Hate, suspicion, fear, weakness, pride. Do you believe these are my demons or your own? You scream because I killed a bird, yet you will return to your mutton dinner tonight and see no hypocrisy. You claim that what I have done is evil, yet the temple diviners perform the same acts with oils and burnt incense."[PARAGRAPH:1]She shook with rage, her voice carried an authority far beyond her 24 years. She turned and glared at the townspeople, most she had known her entire life, and each one quieted under her gaze, but then picked the screaming back up when her eyes were off of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]The adjudicator was Goroff Grist and he had served in this role for nearly 30 years. He wasn't concerned with Lita's pagan ritual but he was very concerned with the effect she had on the city. This kind of disharmony could not be tolerated in a cultured society; she had been warned before about her questionable behavior and refused to become a good citizen. He had known the outcome of this trial the second she was dragged into the basilica.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goroff opened the large tome before him. The hall went quiet as he scribed Lita's name and the verdict. Everyone strained to gain some clue from the stroke of his quill as to the final decision. Goroff sprinkled find sand on the ink and blew on it, then he closed the tome.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The testimony has been heard and a just decision has been made. Lita of Alexandria will be exiled from the Empire. This exile will be initiated by throwing her from the Cliffs of Hastur. We will see if she will follow the crow's fate and have her body broken, or gain the crow's gift and be saved from the rocks below."[PARAGRAPH:1]The crowd cheered the decision, Lita screamed and attacked the guardsmen that held her. They wrestled her into submission and began the march to the edge of the cliffs. By the time they reached them, the crowd had grown and hundreds of townspeople were there to witness her death.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was an early spring day and the mists common to cliffs still hung around its base. Lita had stopped struggling and stood unmoving at the cliffs edge. She told herself that she would die without weakness and step over the edge on her own, but she found herself unable to do so. She sensed something much worse than death over the cliff's edge. Then the guardsman pushed her.[PARAGRAPH:1]She fell. Her life passed before her, pain inflicted by her and on her, actions performed both good and evil. She considered her own regret, had she become something she didn't intend? She pushed the thoughts from her mind, she was not the one at fault, but the people of Alexandria. She fed off of her own hate, wished only that they would suffer for what they had done to her.[PARAGRAPH:1]She passed into the mists and heard the snap of thick leather, like the crack of a whip all around her. A dark form slammed into her and at first she though it was the ground, but her direction changed and she felt herself being carried along the cliff's edge. A beast held her, and she struggled to see its face. It had thick hide wings and skin that felt like a serpents, but hard and warm. The face was a man's, horrible and beautiful, horns and smaller bones pierced his skin and thick iron pins were inserted into the inside curve of his eye, just where tears are formed.[PARAGRAPH:1]He took her to a dark place, Hell or some hidden cave, it was the same to Lita. She became his unwilling concubine, mother of his half-demonic children. His spells kept the many pregnancies from killing her, but they did nothing for the pain which was so intense that she wished for the times when she wasn't pregnant and had only to suffer the brutal rapes. And during the periods of the rapes she wished for the times she was pregnant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mardero was the last of these children. His birth was so traumatic that even his father's considerable power couldn't keep Lita alive through it. His first act in this world was to join his siblings in consuming his mothers flesh, the first of many human victims his father would bring them as they grew.[PARAGRAPH:1]Now Mardero roams the land, unbound by the Compact because of his human heritage but as destructive and loyal to the forces of Entropy as any demon.</French>
		<German>Die Basilika wurde von Schreien des Mobs erfüllt, der den Tod von Lita forderte. Lange Zeit der Hexerei beschuldigt, wurde sie mit Krähenblut auf ihrer Stirn und ihren Augenlidern vorgefunden, der Beweis ihrer hellseherischen Versuche durch dunkle Riten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Richter hörte den Bericht des Wachmannes von ihrer Gefangennahme an. Eine Nachbarin gab an, eine Katze gesehen zu haben, die rückwärts von ihrem Haus weglief, ebenfalls wolle sie eine Taube gesehen haben, die mit dem Kopf nach unten an einer Dachrinne hing, wie eine Feldmaus. Die Wächter wurden herbeigerufen, um der Sache nachzugehen, weil das Anzeichen für das Erscheinen von Lita sind. Aber dieses Mal öffnete sie nicht die Tür, und als die Wächter eintraten, fanden sie sie in ihrem Keller, tief in Trance, mit dem toten Körper einer Krähe neben ihr. [PARAGRAPH:1]"Wie lauten die Namen der Dämonen, denen ich folgen soll?" fragte Lita, "Hass, Argwohn, Angst, Schwäche, Stolz. Glaubt ihr, dass das meine Dämonen sind, oder eure? Ihr beschwert euch, weil ich eine Krähe getötet habe, doch heute Abend kehrt ihr an euren Hammelbraten zurück und entdeckt dabei keine Heuchelei? Ihr nehmt an, dass das was ich getan habe, böse ist, doch die Wahrsager des Tempels machen das gleiche mit Öl und Weihrauch."[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie zitterte vor Wut und ihre Stimme klang mächtiger, als es ihre 24 Jahre vermuten ließen. Sie drehte sich um und blickte die Stadtbewohner an, von denen sie die meisten ihr ganzes Leben lang kannte, doch jeder vermied ihren Blick, nur um sich dann wieder am allgemeinen Geschrei zu beteiligen, als sie wieder weg blickte.[PARAGRAPH:1] Der Richter hieß Goroff Grist und hatte diese Position seit fast 30 Jahren inne. Er hatte keine Bedenken bezüglich Litas heidnischen Ritualen, aber er machte sich Sorgen über ihre Wirkung auf die Stadt. Diese Art der Störung konnte nicht in einer kultivierten Stadt toleriert werden; sie wurde bereits vorher auf Grund ihres fragwürdigen Verhaltens verwarnt, aber sie weigerte sich, ein guter Bürger zu werden. Er wusste schon in der Sekunde den Ausgang der Verhandlung, als sie in der Basilika entdeckt wurde.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goroff öffnete die große Schriftrolle vor ihm. In der Halle wurde es still, als er Litas Namen und das Urteil verkündete. Jedermann bemühte sich, aus der Führung seiner Feder das endgültige Urteil zu erfahren. Goroff blies feinen Sand über die Tinte, dann schloss er die Schriftrolle.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Die Zeugenaussagen wurden gehört und eine Entscheidung wurde getroffen. Lita von Alexandria wird aus dem Imperium verbannt. Die Verbannung wird ausgeführt, indem sie von den Klippen von Hastur geworfen wird. Wir werden sehen, ob sie dem Schicksal der Krähe folgt und stirbt, oder ob sie das Geschenk der Krähe erwirbt und von den Felsen unter ihr verschont bleibt." [PARAGRAPH:1]Die Menge begrüßte die Entscheidung, Lita schrie und griff die Wachmänner an, die sie festhielten. Sie ringen sie nieder und brachten sie zum Rand der Klippe. Als sie ankamen, wuchs die Menge immer mehr an, hunderte Stadtbewohner wollten ihren Tod beiwohnen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Es war ein früher Frühlingstag, und der Nebel hing wie immer am Fuße der Klippen. Lita wehrte sich nicht mehr und stand steif am Rande der Klippen. Sie sagte sich selbst, dass sie ohne Schwäche zu zeigen sterben würde und aus eigener Kraft den Schritt in den Abgrund wagen würde, aber sie sah sich nicht dazu in der Lage. Sie spürte etwas viel schlimmeres als den Tod in den Klippen. Dann stieß sie der Wachmann. [PARAGRAPH:1]Sie fiel. Ihr Leben zog an ihr vorbei, Schmerz, der von ihr und an ihr zugefügt wurde, gute und schlechte Taten. Sie bemerkte ihr Bedauern, wurde sie zu etwas, dass sie gar nicht wollte? Sie schob die Gedanken beiseite, nicht sie machte den Fehler, sondern die Bürger von Alexandria. Ihre Wut verflog, sie wünschte sich nur, dass sie dafür leiden müssen für das, was sie ihr antaten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie fiel in den Nebel und hörte dickes Leder aneinander klatschen, als wenn um sie herum eine Peitsche brechen würde. Ein dunkles Objekt prallte an sie, und zuerst dachte sie, es wäre der Boden, aber ihre Richtung änderte sich und sie bemerkte, wie sie am Rande der Klippe festgehalten wurde. Ein Biest hielt sie, und sie traute sich nicht, es anzusehen. Es hatte dicke, zusammengefaltete Flügel und eine Haut wie die einer Schlange, aber hart und warm. Das Gesicht war männlich, abscheulich und schön, Hörner und kleinere Knochen ragten aus seiner Haut, und dicke eiserne Nieten waren an der Stelle seiner Augen angebracht, an der sich Tränen formten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er nahm sie mit zu einem dunklen Ort, die Hölle oder eine dunkle Höhle, es war das selbe für Lita. Sie wurde seine unfreiwillige Konkubine, Mutter seiner halbdämonischen Kinder. Seine Zauber verhinderten, dass sie an den vielen Schwangerschaften starb, aber sie änderten nichts an den Schmerzen, die sie erleiden musste und die so stark waren, dass sie sich nach den Zeiten sehnte, in denen sie nur die brutalen Vergewaltigungen erdulden musste. Und während den Vergewaltigungen wünschte sie sich, schwanger zu sein.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mardero war das letzte dieser Kinder. Seine Geburt war so traumatisch, dass nicht einmal die starken Zauber seines Vaters Lita am Leben halten konnten. Als seine erste Tat in dieser Welt schloss er sich seinen Geschwistern an und verspeiste das Fleisch seiner Mutter, die erste von vielen Menschen, die ihnen ihr Vater bringen würde, während sie aufwuchsen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Jetzt durchstreift Mardero das Land, ungebunden an den Vertrag auf Grund seines menschlichen Vermächtnisses, aber ebenso zerstörerisch und loyal zu den Kräften der Entropie wie jeder andere Dämon.</German>
		<Italian>The basilica was flooded with screaming, a mob calling for the death of Lita. Long suspected of witchcraft, she was found with crow's blood on her forehead and eyelids, evidence of her attempts at clairvoyance through dark rites.[PARAGRAPH:1]The adjudicator listened to the guardsman's retelling of her capture. A neighbor claimed to have seen a cat walking backwards from her house and a pigeon handing upside down from the eaves like a bat. The guards had been called to check it out, not an uncommon occurrence for Lita. But this time she didn't open the door, and when the guardsman entered, they found her in her basement deep in a trance, with the crow's broken body beside her.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What are the names of these demons you say I follow?" Lita argued, "Hate, suspicion, fear, weakness, pride. Do you believe these are my demons or your own? You scream because I killed a bird, yet you will return to your mutton dinner tonight and see no hypocrisy. You claim that what I have done is evil, yet the temple diviners perform the same acts with oils and burnt incense."[PARAGRAPH:1]She shook with rage, her voice carried an authority far beyond her 24 years. She turned and glared at the townspeople, most she had known her entire life, and each one quieted under her gaze, but then picked the screaming back up when her eyes were off of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]The adjudicator was Goroff Grist and he had served in this role for nearly 30 years. He wasn't concerned with Lita's pagan ritual but he was very concerned with the effect she had on the city. This kind of disharmony could not be tolerated in a cultured society; she had been warned before about her questionable behavior and refused to become a good citizen. He had known the outcome of this trial the second she was dragged into the basilica.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goroff opened the large tome before him. The hall went quiet as he scribed Lita's name and the verdict. Everyone strained to gain some clue from the stroke of his quill as to the final decision. Goroff sprinkled find sand on the ink and blew on it, then he closed the tome.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The testimony has been heard and a just decision has been made. Lita of Alexandria will be exiled from the Empire. This exile will be initiated by throwing her from the Cliffs of Hastur. We will see if she will follow the crow's fate and have her body broken, or gain the crow's gift and be saved from the rocks below."[PARAGRAPH:1]The crowd cheered the decision, Lita screamed and attacked the guardsmen that held her. They wrestled her into submission and began the march to the edge of the cliffs. By the time they reached them, the crowd had grown and hundreds of townspeople were there to witness her death.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was an early spring day and the mists common to cliffs still hung around its base. Lita had stopped struggling and stood unmoving at the cliffs edge. She told herself that she would die without weakness and step over the edge on her own, but she found herself unable to do so. She sensed something much worse than death over the cliff's edge. Then the guardsman pushed her.[PARAGRAPH:1]She fell. Her life passed before her, pain inflicted by her and on her, actions performed both good and evil. She considered her own regret, had she become something she didn't intend? She pushed the thoughts from her mind, she was not the one at fault, but the people of Alexandria. She fed off of her own hate, wished only that they would suffer for what they had done to her.[PARAGRAPH:1]She passed into the mists and heard the snap of thick leather, like the crack of a whip all around her. A dark form slammed into her and at first she though it was the ground, but her direction changed and she felt herself being carried along the cliff's edge. A beast held her, and she struggled to see its face. It had thick hide wings and skin that felt like a serpents, but hard and warm. The face was a man's, horrible and beautiful, horns and smaller bones pierced his skin and thick iron pins were inserted into the inside curve of his eye, just where tears are formed.[PARAGRAPH:1]He took her to a dark place, Hell or some hidden cave, it was the same to Lita. She became his unwilling concubine, mother of his half-demonic children. His spells kept the many pregnancies from killing her, but they did nothing for the pain which was so intense that she wished for the times when she wasn't pregnant and had only to suffer the brutal rapes. And during the periods of the rapes she wished for the times she was pregnant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mardero was the last of these children. His birth was so traumatic that even his father's considerable power couldn't keep Lita alive through it. His first act in this world was to join his siblings in consuming his mothers flesh, the first of many human victims his father would bring them as they grew.[PARAGRAPH:1]Now Mardero roams the land, unbound by the Compact because of his human heritage but as destructive and loyal to the forces of Entropy as any demon.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The basilica was flooded with screaming, a mob calling for the death of Lita. Long suspected of witchcraft, she was found with crow's blood on her forehead and eyelids, evidence of her attempts at clairvoyance through dark rites.[PARAGRAPH:1]The adjudicator listened to the guardsman's retelling of her capture. A neighbor claimed to have seen a cat walking backwards from her house and a pigeon handing upside down from the eaves like a bat. The guards had been called to check it out, not an uncommon occurrence for Lita. But this time she didn't open the door, and when the guardsman entered, they found her in her basement deep in a trance, with the crow's broken body beside her.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What are the names of these demons you say I follow?" Lita argued, "Hate, suspicion, fear, weakness, pride. Do you believe these are my demons or your own? You scream because I killed a bird, yet you will return to your mutton dinner tonight and see no hypocrisy. You claim that what I have done is evil, yet the temple diviners perform the same acts with oils and burnt incense."[PARAGRAPH:1]She shook with rage, her voice carried an authority far beyond her 24 years. She turned and glared at the townspeople, most she had known her entire life, and each one quieted under her gaze, but then picked the screaming back up when her eyes were off of them.[PARAGRAPH:1]The adjudicator was Goroff Grist and he had served in this role for nearly 30 years. He wasn't concerned with Lita's pagan ritual but he was very concerned with the effect she had on the city. This kind of disharmony could not be tolerated in a cultured society; she had been warned before about her questionable behavior and refused to become a good citizen. He had known the outcome of this trial the second she was dragged into the basilica.[PARAGRAPH:1]Goroff opened the large tome before him. The hall went quiet as he scribed Lita's name and the verdict. Everyone strained to gain some clue from the stroke of his quill as to the final decision. Goroff sprinkled find sand on the ink and blew on it, then he closed the tome.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The testimony has been heard and a just decision has been made. Lita of Alexandria will be exiled from the Empire. This exile will be initiated by throwing her from the Cliffs of Hastur. We will see if she will follow the crow's fate and have her body broken, or gain the crow's gift and be saved from the rocks below."[PARAGRAPH:1]The crowd cheered the decision, Lita screamed and attacked the guardsmen that held her. They wrestled her into submission and began the march to the edge of the cliffs. By the time they reached them, the crowd had grown and hundreds of townspeople were there to witness her death.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was an early spring day and the mists common to cliffs still hung around its base. Lita had stopped struggling and stood unmoving at the cliffs edge. She told herself that she would die without weakness and step over the edge on her own, but she found herself unable to do so. She sensed something much worse than death over the cliff's edge. Then the guardsman pushed her.[PARAGRAPH:1]She fell. Her life passed before her, pain inflicted by her and on her, actions performed both good and evil. She considered her own regret, had she become something she didn't intend? She pushed the thoughts from her mind, she was not the one at fault, but the people of Alexandria. She fed off of her own hate, wished only that they would suffer for what they had done to her.[PARAGRAPH:1]She passed into the mists and heard the snap of thick leather, like the crack of a whip all around her. A dark form slammed into her and at first she though it was the ground, but her direction changed and she felt herself being carried along the cliff's edge. A beast held her, and she struggled to see its face. It had thick hide wings and skin that felt like a serpents, but hard and warm. The face was a man's, horrible and beautiful, horns and smaller bones pierced his skin and thick iron pins were inserted into the inside curve of his eye, just where tears are formed.[PARAGRAPH:1]He took her to a dark place, Hell or some hidden cave, it was the same to Lita. She became his unwilling concubine, mother of his half-demonic children. His spells kept the many pregnancies from killing her, but they did nothing for the pain which was so intense that she wished for the times when she wasn't pregnant and had only to suffer the brutal rapes. And during the periods of the rapes she wished for the times she was pregnant.[PARAGRAPH:1]Mardero was the last of these children. His birth was so traumatic that even his father's considerable power couldn't keep Lita alive through it. His first act in this world was to join his siblings in consuming his mothers flesh, the first of many human victims his father would bring them as they grew.[PARAGRAPH:1]Now Mardero roams the land, unbound by the Compact because of his human heritage but as destructive and loyal to the forces of Entropy as any demon.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MARDERO_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Mardero will only join the Ashen Veil civilizations. Mardero and his rival Sphener are the latest and most powerful heroes in the game. Mardero has a bonus against disciples and makes short work of paladins, priests, and monks.</English>
		<French>Mardèro ne rejoindra que les civilisations du Voile Cendré. Mardéro et son rival Sphener sont les derniers et les plus puissants héros du jeu. Mardéro a un bonus contre les disciples et ne fait qu'une bouchée des paladins, prêtres et moines.</French>
		<German>Der Erzdämon Mardero schliesst sich nur Zivilisationen des Aschfahlen Schleiers an. Er und sein Rivale, Erzengel Sphener, sind die letzten und mächtigsten Helden im Spiel. Mardero besitzt einen speziellen Bonus gegen Geweihte und macht kurzen Prozess mit Paladinen, Priestern und Mönchen.</German>
		<Italian>Mardero will only join the Ashen Veil civilizations. Mardero and his rival Sphener are the latest and most powerful heroes in the game. Mardero has a bonus against disciples and makes short work of paladins, priests, and monks.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mardero will only join the Ashen Veil civilizations. Mardero and his rival Sphener are the latest and most powerful heroes in the game. Mardero has a bonus against disciples and makes short work of paladins, priests, and monks.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KITHRA</Tag>
		<English>Kithra Kyriel</English>
		<French>Kithra Kyriel</French>
		<German>Kithra Kyriel</German>
		<Italian>Kithra Kyriel</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kithra Kyriel</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KITHRA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Kithra's father was an elven hunter and his mother was a human, a merchant's daughter. Their families were accepting of the relationship, and Kithra's father left his people to move into the small human village. They got married and seemed to defy the belief that these relationships would always end tragically.[PARAGRAPH:1]The villagers were very tolerant, even happy, to have an elf living in their village. But though the humans may have accepted him, their diseases didn't. After just 3 years spent in the village, he caught a stomach flu that had been going around the village, and, unaccustomed to such illnesses, it killed him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra was raised by his mother. Still accepted and loved by the village, he grew into a quiet and friendly half-elven young man. He worked in the inn stables and seemed to have a knack for calming and caring for the horses that travelers would stable there. That was all he thought he would ever do.[PARAGRAPH:1]A soldier was staying at the inn for a few weeks, and he had asked Kithra to exercise his horse at least once a day. It was a magnificent horse, and Kithra looked forward to riding it each day. He was running it in the small pasture by the inn when a new guest arrived, a mage named Hemah.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hemah watched the young half-elf ride before going inside. Kithra tried to ride up and talk to him, but the mage waved him off, tired from his travels. The caravan Hemah was traveling with had been attacked by orcs, many were killed and all of the travelers were exhausted.[PARAGRAPH:1]That night the orcs attacked again, but strange dark versions of orcs. Some ran through the walls of buildings like ghosts, other fought battles in the streets with guards who had been killed earlier that day. Yells and the sounds of battle echoed in the air, as if it was nothing more than a vision, but this was real. The orcs turned on the village guard, killing them. The soldier from the inn commanded Kithra to get his horse ready and grabbed his sword to keep the orcs back. By the time Kithra had saddled the horse, the soldier was already dead and the orcs were breaking into the inn.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra saw himself ride through the orcs, bow in hand, firing deadly arrow after arrow into the orc horde. He heard the orcs dying before he remembered ever performing the act. He was confused and then he was on the horse, but the horse had changed, it was stronger and faster than it was that day. The tail was untied and combed out, hooves were polished, and it was fearless. The horse charged through the orcs, trampling any that got in his way. Kithra was terrified, silent witness to his own hands as they used the bow and arrows he had never seen before to fight off the orcs.[PARAGRAPH:1]An orc broke into his mother's house and she ran out into the street. Kithra stopped being a puppet and grabbed the reins, forcing the horse to turn toward her and the orc bearing down on her. If she was shocked and terrified by the orc attack, she was even more so by the sight of her gentle quiet son slaughtering the orcs and turning to charge toward her.[PARAGRAPH:1]He aimed at the orc, and his arrow caught him in the chest. A second quickly followed and a third sunk into the orc's head. No longer a puppet, Kithra still had no idea what was going on, but there were many more orcs to kill. He told his mother to hide by the well while he then turned back towards the orcs; there was more fighting to be done before morning.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra still doesn't know what happened that night. The orcs' bodies simply disappeared, but the effects of their presence didn't. Some of the villagers were killed, as was the soldier who owned the horse. Evidence of the attack was everywhere, broken doors, tracks, the orcs had even eaten some of the livestock. But the orcs themselves, along with their weapons and gear, were gone.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra's bow remained and the horse kept the changes that had occurred during the night. Kithra had changed too, his sandy blond hair was now golden blond, his eyes were greener, he seemed taller and more fit. Thinking that his elven heritage may have done this to him, he left the village and traveled to his father's former home where he asked for advice from the priest of the Temple of Leaves.[PARAGRAPH:1]They weren't able to answer his questions about that night, but they did tell him that he was a hero now, and had an amazing gift bestowed upon him. He stayed and trained and learned at the temple, adopting the elven traditions and the worship of Cernunnos. He has been one of the Fellowship's most powerful heroes ever since.</English>
		<French>Kithra's father was an elven hunter and his mother was a human, a merchant's daughter. Their families were accepting of the relationship, and Kithra's father left his people to move into the small human village. They got married and seemed to defy the belief that these relationships would always end tragically.[PARAGRAPH:1]The villagers were very tolerant, even happy, to have an elf living in their village. But though the humans may have accepted him, their diseases didn't. After just 3 years spent in the village, he caught a stomach flu that had been going around the village, and, unaccustomed to such illnesses, it killed him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra was raised by his mother. Still accepted and loved by the village, he grew into a quiet and friendly half-elven young man. He worked in the inn stables and seemed to have a knack for calming and caring for the horses that travelers would stable there. That was all he thought he would ever do.[PARAGRAPH:1]A soldier was staying at the inn for a few weeks, and he had asked Kithra to exercise his horse at least once a day. It was a magnificent horse, and Kithra looked forward to riding it each day. He was running it in the small pasture by the inn when a new guest arrived, a mage named Hemah.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hemah watched the young half-elf ride before going inside. Kithra tried to ride up and talk to him, but the mage waved him off, tired from his travels. The caravan Hemah was traveling with had been attacked by orcs, many were killed and all of the travelers were exhausted.[PARAGRAPH:1]That night the orcs attacked again, but strange dark versions of orcs. Some ran through the walls of buildings like ghosts, other fought battles in the streets with guards who had been killed earlier that day. Yells and the sounds of battle echoed in the air, as if it was nothing more than a vision, but this was real. The orcs turned on the village guard, killing them. The soldier from the inn commanded Kithra to get his horse ready and grabbed his sword to keep the orcs back. By the time Kithra had saddled the horse, the soldier was already dead and the orcs were breaking into the inn.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra saw himself ride through the orcs, bow in hand, firing deadly arrow after arrow into the orc horde. He heard the orcs dying before he remembered ever performing the act. He was confused and then he was on the horse, but the horse had changed, it was stronger and faster than it was that day. The tail was untied and combed out, hooves were polished, and it was fearless. The horse charged through the orcs, trampling any that got in his way. Kithra was terrified, silent witness to his own hands as they used the bow and arrows he had never seen before to fight off the orcs.[PARAGRAPH:1]An orc broke into his mother's house and she ran out into the street. Kithra stopped being a puppet and grabbed the reins, forcing the horse to turn toward her and the orc bearing down on her. If she was shocked and terrified by the orc attack, she was even more so by the sight of her gentle quiet son slaughtering the orcs and turning to charge toward her.[PARAGRAPH:1]He aimed at the orc, and his arrow caught him in the chest. A second quickly followed and a third sunk into the orc's head. No longer a puppet, Kithra still had no idea what was going on, but there were many more orcs to kill. He told his mother to hide by the well while he then turned back towards the orcs; there was more fighting to be done before morning.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra still doesn't know what happened that night. The orcs' bodies simply disappeared, but the effects of their presence didn't. Some of the villagers were killed, as was the soldier who owned the horse. Evidence of the attack was everywhere, broken doors, tracks, the orcs had even eaten some of the livestock. But the orcs themselves, along with their weapons and gear, were gone.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra's bow remained and the horse kept the changes that had occurred during the night. Kithra had changed too, his sandy blond hair was now golden blond, his eyes were greener, he seemed taller and more fit. Thinking that his elven heritage may have done this to him, he left the village and traveled to his father's former home where he asked for advice from the priest of the Temple of Leaves.[PARAGRAPH:1]They weren't able to answer his questions about that night, but they did tell him that he was a hero now, and had an amazing gift bestowed upon him. He stayed and trained and learned at the temple, adopting the elven traditions and the worship of Cernunnos. He has been one of the Fellowship's most powerful heroes ever since.</French>
		<German>Kithras Vater war ein elfischer Jäger und seine Mutter war ein Mensch, die Tochter eines Händlers. Ihr Familien akzeptieren ihre Beziehung und Kithras Vater verlies sein Volk und zog in ein kleines Menschendorf. Sie heirateten und schienen zu widerlegen, dass solche Beziehungen immer tragisch endeten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Dorfbewohner waren sehr tolerant, und auch ein wenig glücklich, dass ein Elf in ihrem Dorf lebt. Aber obwohl die Menschen ihn akzeptiert hatten, hatten ihre Krankheiten dies nicht. Nach nur 3 Jahren die er in dem Dorf verbrachte, steckte er sich mit einer Darmgrippe an, die im Dorf kursierte, und, weil er an solche Krankheiten nicht gewohnt war, so starb er daran. [PARAGRAPH:1] Kithra wurde von seiner Mutter erzogen. Noch immer akzeptiert und vom Dorf geliebt, wuchs er zu einem stillen und freundlichen Halbelfenmann heran. Er arbeitete in den Ställen des Gasthofs und schien die Gabe zu haben, die Pferde, die Reisende dort rasten ließen, zu beruhigen und kümmerte sich um sie. Das war alles was er dachte dass er in seinem Leben tun würde.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Soldat verbrachte einige Wochen im Gasthof, und er bat Kithra darum, sein Pferd wenigstens einmal pro Tag auszuführen. Es war ein wunderbares Pferd und Kithra freute sich jeden Tag darauf es zu reiten. Er lies es auf der Weide neben dem Gasthaus laufen, als ein neuer Gast ankam, ein Magier namens Hemah.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hemah sah dem jungen Halbelfen beim Reiten zu, bevor er das Gasthaus betrat. Kithra versuchte ihn einzuholen und mit ihm zu sprechen, doch der Magier wimmelte ihn ab, denn er war müde von der Reise. Die Karawane mit der Hemah reiste wurde von Orks angegriffen und dabei starben viele und die überlebenden Reisenden waren erschöpft. [PARAGRAPH:1]In der Nacht griffen die Orks erneut an, jedoch seltsame dunkle Arten von Orks. Einige rannten durch die Mauern der Gebäude, als ob sie Gespenster wären, andere kämpfen in den Straßen mit Wachen, die bereits beim ersten Angriff starben. Schreie und Kampfeslärm erfüllte die Luft, so als ob all das nur eine Vision wäre, doch es war real. Die Orks wandten sich den Dorfwachen zu und töteten diese. Der Soldat aus dem Gasthaus befahl Kithra sein Pferd zu satteln und griff nach seinem Schwert um die Orks zurückzuschlagen. Zur Zeit als Kithra das Pferd gesattelt hatte, war der Soldat bereits tot und die Orks waren dabei das Gasthaus zu erstürmen. [PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra sah sich selbst, wie er, mit dem Bogen in der Hand, durch die Reihen der Orks ritt und einen tödlichen Pfeil nach dem anderen in die Orkhorde feuerte. Er hörte die Orks sterben, noch bevor er die Tat ausführte. Er war verwirrt und dann befand er sich auf dem Pferd, aber das Pferd hatte sich verändert. Es war stärker und schneller als am vorherigen Tag. Die Mähne war nicht gebunden und nach außen gekämmt, die Hufe waren poliert und das Pferd war furchtlos. Das Pferd fegte durch die Orks und trampelte jeden nieder der ihm in den Weg kam. Kithra war vom Schrecken erfüllt, als er stiller Zeuge seiner eigenen Hände wurde, wie sie Pfeil und Bogen benutzten und die Orks damit bekämpften, obwohl er sie noch nie zuvor gesehen hatte. [PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Ork drang in das Haus seiner Mutter ein und so rannte sie auf die Straße. Kithra beendete sein Dasein als Puppe, griff nach den Zügeln und zwang das Pferd sich dem Ork zuzuwenden, der seine Mutter verfolgte. Auch wenn der Orkangriff ihr sehr zusetzte, so schockierte es sie doch umso mehr,  ihren lieben und stillen Sohn zu sehen, wie er ein Schlachtfest mit den Orks veranstaltete und sich ihr zuwandte um den Ork anzugreifen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Er zielte auf den Ork und sein Pfeil traf ihn in die Brust. Ein zweiter folgte sofort und ein dritter Pfeil traf ihn in den Schädel. Obwohl nicht länger eine Puppe, hatte Kithra noch immer keine Ahnung was los war, aber es waren noch immer genügend Orks übrig die zu töten waren. Er sagte seiner Mutter, dass sie sich beim Brunnen verstecken sollte, während er sich wieder den Orks zuwandte; es gab noch viele Kämpfe zu führen bevor der Morgen anbrach. [PARAGRAPH:1] Kithra weiss noch immer nicht was in jener Nacht geschah. Die Körper der Orks verschwanden einfach, aber die Spuren ihrer Anwesenheit nicht. Einige der Dorfbewohner wurden getötet, wie auch der Soldat dem das Pferd gehörte. Spuren des Angriffs waren überall, zerstörte Türen, Pfade, die Orks hatten sogar Teile des Viehs gefressen. Aber die Orks selbst, ebenso wie ihre Waffen und Ausrüstung, waren verschwunden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithras Bogen war noch immer da und auch das Pferd behielt die Veränderungen die es in der Nacht erfuhr. Kithra selbst hatte sich auch verändert: Sein sandblondes Haar war nun goldblond, seine Augen waren grüner und er schien größer und fitter. Weil er dachte, dass sein elfisches Erbe dafür verantwortlich war, reiste er in das ehemalige Heim seines Vaters und suchte Rat beim Priester im Tempel des Laubes. [PARAGRAPH:1]Sie waren nicht in der Lage seine Fragen über diese Nacht zu beantworten, aber sie sagten ihm, dass er nun ein Held war und dass ihm eine unglaubliche Gabe gegeben war. Er blieb, trainierte und lernte im Tempel, übernahm elfische Traditionen und die Anbetung Cernunnos. Er wurde einer der mächtigsten Helden die die Gemeinschaft jemals sah.</German>
		<Italian>Kithra's father was an elven hunter and his mother was a human, a merchant's daughter. Their families were accepting of the relationship, and Kithra's father left his people to move into the small human village. They got married and seemed to defy the belief that these relationships would always end tragically.[PARAGRAPH:1]The villagers were very tolerant, even happy, to have an elf living in their village. But though the humans may have accepted him, their diseases didn't. After just 3 years spent in the village, he caught a stomach flu that had been going around the village, and, unaccustomed to such illnesses, it killed him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra was raised by his mother. Still accepted and loved by the village, he grew into a quiet and friendly half-elven young man. He worked in the inn stables and seemed to have a knack for calming and caring for the horses that travelers would stable there. That was all he thought he would ever do.[PARAGRAPH:1]A soldier was staying at the inn for a few weeks, and he had asked Kithra to exercise his horse at least once a day. It was a magnificent horse, and Kithra looked forward to riding it each day. He was running it in the small pasture by the inn when a new guest arrived, a mage named Hemah.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hemah watched the young half-elf ride before going inside. Kithra tried to ride up and talk to him, but the mage waved him off, tired from his travels. The caravan Hemah was traveling with had been attacked by orcs, many were killed and all of the travelers were exhausted.[PARAGRAPH:1]That night the orcs attacked again, but strange dark versions of orcs. Some ran through the walls of buildings like ghosts, other fought battles in the streets with guards who had been killed earlier that day. Yells and the sounds of battle echoed in the air, as if it was nothing more than a vision, but this was real. The orcs turned on the village guard, killing them. The soldier from the inn commanded Kithra to get his horse ready and grabbed his sword to keep the orcs back. By the time Kithra had saddled the horse, the soldier was already dead and the orcs were breaking into the inn.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra saw himself ride through the orcs, bow in hand, firing deadly arrow after arrow into the orc horde. He heard the orcs dying before he remembered ever performing the act. He was confused and then he was on the horse, but the horse had changed, it was stronger and faster than it was that day. The tail was untied and combed out, hooves were polished, and it was fearless. The horse charged through the orcs, trampling any that got in his way. Kithra was terrified, silent witness to his own hands as they used the bow and arrows he had never seen before to fight off the orcs.[PARAGRAPH:1]An orc broke into his mother's house and she ran out into the street. Kithra stopped being a puppet and grabbed the reins, forcing the horse to turn toward her and the orc bearing down on her. If she was shocked and terrified by the orc attack, she was even more so by the sight of her gentle quiet son slaughtering the orcs and turning to charge toward her.[PARAGRAPH:1]He aimed at the orc, and his arrow caught him in the chest. A second quickly followed and a third sunk into the orc's head. No longer a puppet, Kithra still had no idea what was going on, but there were many more orcs to kill. He told his mother to hide by the well while he then turned back towards the orcs; there was more fighting to be done before morning.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra still doesn't know what happened that night. The orcs' bodies simply disappeared, but the effects of their presence didn't. Some of the villagers were killed, as was the soldier who owned the horse. Evidence of the attack was everywhere, broken doors, tracks, the orcs had even eaten some of the livestock. But the orcs themselves, along with their weapons and gear, were gone.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra's bow remained and the horse kept the changes that had occurred during the night. Kithra had changed too, his sandy blond hair was now golden blond, his eyes were greener, he seemed taller and more fit. Thinking that his elven heritage may have done this to him, he left the village and traveled to his father's former home where he asked for advice from the priest of the Temple of Leaves.[PARAGRAPH:1]They weren't able to answer his questions about that night, but they did tell him that he was a hero now, and had an amazing gift bestowed upon him. He stayed and trained and learned at the temple, adopting the elven traditions and the worship of Cernunnos. He has been one of the Fellowship's most powerful heroes ever since.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kithra's father was an elven hunter and his mother was a human, a merchant's daughter. Their families were accepting of the relationship, and Kithra's father left his people to move into the small human village. They got married and seemed to defy the belief that these relationships would always end tragically.[PARAGRAPH:1]The villagers were very tolerant, even happy, to have an elf living in their village. But though the humans may have accepted him, their diseases didn't. After just 3 years spent in the village, he caught a stomach flu that had been going around the village, and, unaccustomed to such illnesses, it killed him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra was raised by his mother. Still accepted and loved by the village, he grew into a quiet and friendly half-elven young man. He worked in the inn stables and seemed to have a knack for calming and caring for the horses that travelers would stable there. That was all he thought he would ever do.[PARAGRAPH:1]A soldier was staying at the inn for a few weeks, and he had asked Kithra to exercise his horse at least once a day. It was a magnificent horse, and Kithra looked forward to riding it each day. He was running it in the small pasture by the inn when a new guest arrived, a mage named Hemah.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hemah watched the young half-elf ride before going inside. Kithra tried to ride up and talk to him, but the mage waved him off, tired from his travels. The caravan Hemah was traveling with had been attacked by orcs, many were killed and all of the travelers were exhausted.[PARAGRAPH:1]That night the orcs attacked again, but strange dark versions of orcs. Some ran through the walls of buildings like ghosts, other fought battles in the streets with guards who had been killed earlier that day. Yells and the sounds of battle echoed in the air, as if it was nothing more than a vision, but this was real. The orcs turned on the village guard, killing them. The soldier from the inn commanded Kithra to get his horse ready and grabbed his sword to keep the orcs back. By the time Kithra had saddled the horse, the soldier was already dead and the orcs were breaking into the inn.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra saw himself ride through the orcs, bow in hand, firing deadly arrow after arrow into the orc horde. He heard the orcs dying before he remembered ever performing the act. He was confused and then he was on the horse, but the horse had changed, it was stronger and faster than it was that day. The tail was untied and combed out, hooves were polished, and it was fearless. The horse charged through the orcs, trampling any that got in his way. Kithra was terrified, silent witness to his own hands as they used the bow and arrows he had never seen before to fight off the orcs.[PARAGRAPH:1]An orc broke into his mother's house and she ran out into the street. Kithra stopped being a puppet and grabbed the reins, forcing the horse to turn toward her and the orc bearing down on her. If she was shocked and terrified by the orc attack, she was even more so by the sight of her gentle quiet son slaughtering the orcs and turning to charge toward her.[PARAGRAPH:1]He aimed at the orc, and his arrow caught him in the chest. A second quickly followed and a third sunk into the orc's head. No longer a puppet, Kithra still had no idea what was going on, but there were many more orcs to kill. He told his mother to hide by the well while he then turned back towards the orcs; there was more fighting to be done before morning.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra still doesn't know what happened that night. The orcs' bodies simply disappeared, but the effects of their presence didn't. Some of the villagers were killed, as was the soldier who owned the horse. Evidence of the attack was everywhere, broken doors, tracks, the orcs had even eaten some of the livestock. But the orcs themselves, along with their weapons and gear, were gone.[PARAGRAPH:1]Kithra's bow remained and the horse kept the changes that had occurred during the night. Kithra had changed too, his sandy blond hair was now golden blond, his eyes were greener, he seemed taller and more fit. Thinking that his elven heritage may have done this to him, he left the village and traveled to his father's former home where he asked for advice from the priest of the Temple of Leaves.[PARAGRAPH:1]They weren't able to answer his questions about that night, but they did tell him that he was a hero now, and had an amazing gift bestowed upon him. He stayed and trained and learned at the temple, adopting the elven traditions and the worship of Cernunnos. He has been one of the Fellowship's most powerful heroes ever since.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KITHRA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Kithra will only join Fellowship of the Leaves civilizations. Kithra is a very mobile horse archer combining a high move rate and the powerful Hero promotion.</English>
		<French>Kithra ne rejoindra que les civilisations de la Communauté des Feuilles.  Kithra est un archer monté très mobile combinant un grand nombre de points de mouvement et la promotion Forestier II avec la puissante promotion Héros.</French>
		<German>Kithra schließt sich nur Zivilisationen mit der Religion Gefährten des Laubes an. Kithra ist ein sehr mobiler berittener Bogenschütze mit einer hohen Bewegungsrate, kombiniert mit der mächtigen Beförderung "Held"</German>
		<Italian>Kithra will only join Fellowship of the Leaves civilizations. Kithra is a very mobile horse archer combining a high move rate and the powerful Hero promotion.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Kithra will only join Fellowship of the Leaves civilizations. Kithra is a very mobile horse archer combining a high move rate and the powerful Hero promotion.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GIBBON</Tag>
		<English>Gibbon Goetia</English>
		<French>Gibbon Goetia</French>
		<German>Gibbon Goetia</German>
		<Italian>Gibbon Goetia</Italian>
		<Spanish>Gibbon Goetia</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GIBBON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]How many roles have I played? They blur together in my mind.[PARAGRAPH:1]I was a victim from the moment my life began. An attacker came for my mother even as she gave birth to me. He possessed Garrus, a simple stable boy and used him to sneak up through the inn to my parents room. He tried to get close to my mother, to attack her at her most vulnerable. My father fought to stop him. The details are unknown except that a battle occurred in the room and my father was struck a mortal blow. With his last breath he uttered a holy word that destroyed the spirit possessing Garrus and collapsed the entire inn.[PARAGRAPH:1]My mother died in the collapse, my father died from the attack. The stable boy was pulled from the rubble, one arm was crushed but he appeared otherwise healthy. My soul fled the dying infants form and took home in his newly evacuated body. I was born into the body of a teenage boy.[PARAGRAPH:1]The innkeeper raised me, teaching me as if I had simply forgotten my life and in a few years I served him well. He raised me as he rebuilt the inn. But I always knew that Garrus wasn't my name and I listened intently when those that survived the collapse retold the story.[PARAGRAPH:1]We didn't know much about my parents. But my father wore the yellow robes of a priest of the Empyrean. There was a small temple to the god in our city and when I was ready I joined their ranks as a disciple. Within the clergy my identity didn't matter, I was simply a child of Lugus. My superiors praised my empathy, questioned my maturity and laughed when I said that I thought I was the son of a priest. They claimed no such priest had visited the city and considered my thoughts the wishful thoughts of boy with too much imagination.[PARAGRAPH:1]My right arm was still crushed, by this point it was shriveled and permanently wrapped against my side. When I asked if it could be healed the priests prayed over it, but it never got better. Others came and received healing, nobles, merchants, beggars, soldiers. But I remained maimed.[PARAGRAPH:1]One day in early Aedrini the temple was in an uproar. Priests barked orders, disciples scurried about trying to look busy, no one had thought to wake me. After many questions a priest finally gave me my answer.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Luridus Chalid is coming child, stay out of the way."[PARAGRAPH:1]I began to retreat to my chamber when he yelled after me, "And don't bother him when he arrives!"[PARAGRAPH:1]That next day a single man arrived on a dappled grey mare. He rode without an escort and though he needed no guards on the road, he could have used some outside of the temple. He was immediately mobbed by well meaning disciples, genuflecting priests and hordes of gawking townspeople. He wore the robes of a Luridus and I wondered if my father wore the same.[PARAGRAPH:1]He spent the next three days in our hastily constructed council chamber. The chamber was open for anyone to hear the deliberation and speak in an orderly manner. They discussed the towns role in the Overcouncil, local legislation and a problem with brigands in the area.[PARAGRAPH:1]The council meetings always went well into the night, and Chalid attended every dawn ceremony. He only had a few hours between to get some sleep. I was hurrying to the dawn service one morning when I found him standing alone in the refectory looking out the windows toward the east. The morning bell rung, signaling the dawn ceremony was about to start and Chalid turned to find me staring at him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Morning disciple, are you ready to receive our lords blessing?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I managed to stammer something unintelligible out. Despite that he smiled at me with true affection and clasp me on the shoulder. That was the first he noticed my withered arm.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do you have something to ask me?" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]He expected me to ask for healing, but that didn't matter to me. Instead I asked, "What sort of spirit attacked my mother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]He put his arm around me and we walked to the sanctuary together.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Let me pray about it" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]The service was exactly like all the others but I paid little attention. Instead I watched Chalid. He looked confused as he prayed, sometimes pained, sometimes resigned and I imagined that it had something to do with my question.[PARAGRAPH:1]I waited after the service. Chalid spoke briefly with the vicar who had performed the service and meet a few of the members. And then he left the sanctuary and went into the council chambers.[PARAGRAPH:1]I spent the day neglecting my duties and waiting outside the council chamber. But just past nightfall the towns warning bells rang out, guards ran through the streets yelling that brigands were attacking.[PARAGRAPH:1]Everyone flooded out of the temple. At the edge of the town shapes rushed through the darkness. Black tipped arrows cut guards down where they writhed screaming in pain. Guards brought torches and under the cover of shield men they retook the fortifications while the shadows simply moved to attack at another point.[PARAGRAPH:1]A voice from the darkness called, "What good is a god that abandons you every night?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid ignored the taunt and ordered the men back within the cities lantern light. He alone bounded over the wall and in to the darkness at the cities edge. His mace glowed faintly in the starlight and though we couldn't see any attackers on the open field we all knew they were moving in on him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid prayed and an aura of golden fire burst up around his head and dark men caught fire on the field, on the walls, and even a few that had snuck into the city. The holy fire consumed them and guards rushed in to beat or capture the men.[PARAGRAPH:1]But one was not distracted by the fire. It clung to his black armor and that of his steed but he rode soundlessly towards Chalid, like a shadow of a dark god stretching out to touch him. Chalid raised his mace up, and then back down and the field was lit up as if it was day. A pillar of golden fire, like the sun itself but full of righteous fury, crushed the rider. There was a horrific scream and then when the pillar retreated back up into the sky the rider was gone.[PARAGRAPH:1]I spent the night tending to the guardsmen wounded in the attack. Their wounds festered from poison and the men passed between fevered dreams and anguish when awake. There was little I could do but try to keep their wounds clean and try to make them comfortable. Chalid and the priests prayed over the men and some were healed, but too many were injured.[PARAGRAPH:1]That next morning I returned to my chambers to wash up and change into fresh clothes, as did most of the temple. I headed again to the dawn ceremony and found Chalid alone again in the refectory looking out towards the east.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You saved the town." It sounded hollow when I said it. Unsuited to the miracle I had witnessed.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I only had faith that Lugus would protect me, he did everything else."[PARAGRAPH:1]I smiled, the warmth Chalid had shared with me yesterday was gone now. He looked troubled but I assumed it was just the events of the long night. I know he hadn't slept either.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Did you find out anything about my mother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid looked at the floor, the morning bells rang though neither of us moved.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I should lie to you" Chalid said, "the mandate of truth is sometimes painful. I am sorry. I won't lie but I will warn you, it would be better if you did not know."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I want to know" I argued with more passion than I intended, "Knowledge, truth, revelation are the precepts of Lugus. I should know my own past."[PARAGRAPH:1]"The woman's name was Magda de'Vala" Chalid started, "The man wasn't her husband but her guardian, though he was a priest of the Empyrean. The child was prophesied to be a great hero, which is why many sought to kill Magda and her baby."[PARAGRAPH:1]He paused, but I only waited for him to continue.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The stable boy Garrus died three days before the attack. That which killed Garras, that which killed Magda's guardian and caused the collapse that killed Magda and her baby. That was you."[PARAGRAPH:1]I was furious and I rushed out of the refectory. Chalid watched me go then headed into the sanctuary. My thoughts went back to those early days, I never felt like I was the stable boy. And for the first time I questioned my origin. Would a babies spirit in a boy's body be able to adapt that quickly? Could even a possessed stable boy be able to overcome a priest of Lugus, or was that creature something darker? And was I that creature?[PARAGRAPH:1]I stopped in the temples infirmary. Except for the wounded it was empty, everyone in the temple was in the dawn ceremony despite those laying here near death. There was only one man awake, a bandage covered his left thigh. I knelt at his bedside. When I saw the torment he was in I forgot a bit of my own.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What is your name?" I asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Abin," he said, "I'm a jeweler who pretended to be a city guard."[PARAGRAPH:1]That wasn't unusual. Our city was too small to maintain full time guardsmen so most were volunteers with other jobs.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Either you are too good at pretending, or not good enough."[PARAGRAPH:1]He gave me a weak smile.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Can I pray for you?" I asked. He nodded.[PARAGRAPH:1]I placed my hand on him and closed my eyes. I have seen many healed but I had never performed a miracle myself. If I could do this, if I could heal this man and channel the power of Lugus then I couldn't be whatever creature Chalid thought I was. Maybe I was the holy child, maybe the attack on Magda de'Vala failed.[PARAGRAPH:1]I could feel his labored breath. I could feel his pain, feel his love for his large family of nieces and nephews. His quiet store and hours spent working on small intricate jewelry. And I felt him die.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then I felt the poison strike, it burnt through my body focused on the wound in my left thigh. I stepped away from the bed in shock. I was taller and my robes, which were big on me, were now tight. And my formerly withered arm was now trapped uncomfortably in its folds.[PARAGRAPH:1]I loosened the robe and held out my full, strong arm. But it didn't look like my arm, it was the jewelers arm. And as I looked at myself I realized that I was identical to the dead body of the jeweler that lay in the bed in front of me. And then the poison struck again and sent me to my knees. I picked myself up and fled the temple in pain and confusion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Pain will drive you mad and it only took a few hours of suffering like this before I found a farmer out working in his field.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Blind goats Abin!" he said, "what is wrong with you? Why are you wearing a disciples robes?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I threw him to the ground and held him, smashing him once in the face when he tried to fight back. I felt for that closeness, I reached out to find everything that he was, and the pain drifted away. When I opened my eyes I saw him staring up at his own reflection in horror. The last I saw him he was running toward his farmhouse, I started running as well. I don't think I have ever stopped.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]I still don't know what I am. All the roles that I've played since then blur together in my mind. I've gotten better at reading people and worked for a time for an assassins guild, simply for reading people I touch. During other times I steal the lives of those I wish to share. I tried the lavish extravagance of princes and wealthy merchants, but there is little to envy them for once you understand how they truly live. The best stolen lives come from the simple fathers of large families, those that have the love and respect of everyone in their lives. Dump the body of one of those in a shallow grave and I have a few good weeks of fun before I become bored and move on to something else.[PARAGRAPH:1]Maybe Chalid was right, maybe I am a monster.</English>
		<French>[TAB]How many roles have I played? They blur together in my mind.[PARAGRAPH:1]I was a victim from the moment my life began. An attacker came for my mother even as she gave birth to me. He possessed Garrus, a simple stable boy and used him to sneak up through the inn to my parents room. He tried to get close to my mother, to attack her at her most vulnerable. My father fought to stop him. The details are unknown except that a battle occurred in the room and my father was struck a mortal blow. With his last breath he uttered a holy word that destroyed the spirit possessing Garrus and collapsed the entire inn.[PARAGRAPH:1]My mother died in the collapse, my father died from the attack. The stable boy was pulled from the rubble, one arm was crushed but he appeared otherwise healthy. My soul fled the dying infants form and took home in his newly evacuated body. I was born into the body of a teenage boy.[PARAGRAPH:1]The innkeeper raised me, teaching me as if I had simply forgotten my life and in a few years I served him well. He raised me as he rebuilt the inn. But I always knew that Garrus wasn't my name and I listened intently when those that survived the collapse retold the story.[PARAGRAPH:1]We didn't know much about my parents. But my father wore the yellow robes of a priest of the Empyrean. There was a small temple to the god in our city and when I was ready I joined their ranks as a disciple. Within the clergy my identity didn't matter, I was simply a child of Lugus. My superiors praised my empathy, questioned my maturity and laughed when I said that I thought I was the son of a priest. They claimed no such priest had visited the city and considered my thoughts the wishful thoughts of boy with too much imagination.[PARAGRAPH:1]My right arm was still crushed, by this point it was shriveled and permanently wrapped against my side. When I asked if it could be healed the priests prayed over it, but it never got better. Others came and received healing, nobles, merchants, beggars, soldiers. But I remained maimed.[PARAGRAPH:1]One day in early Aedrini the temple was in an uproar. Priests barked orders, disciples scurried about trying to look busy, no one had thought to wake me. After many questions a priest finally gave me my answer.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Luridus Chalid is coming child, stay out of the way."[PARAGRAPH:1]I began to retreat to my chamber when he yelled after me, "And don't bother him when he arrives!"[PARAGRAPH:1]That next day a single man arrived on a dappled grey mare. He rode without an escort and though he needed no guards on the road, he could have used some outside of the temple. He was immediately mobbed by well meaning disciples, genuflecting priests and hordes of gawking townspeople. He wore the robes of a Luridus and I wondered if my father wore the same.[PARAGRAPH:1]He spent the next three days in our hastily constructed council chamber. The chamber was open for anyone to hear the deliberation and speak in an orderly manner. They discussed the towns role in the Overcouncil, local legislation and a problem with brigands in the area.[PARAGRAPH:1]The council meetings always went well into the night, and Chalid attended every dawn ceremony. He only had a few hours between to get some sleep. I was hurrying to the dawn service one morning when I found him standing alone in the refectory looking out the windows toward the east. The morning bell rung, signaling the dawn ceremony was about to start and Chalid turned to find me staring at him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Morning disciple, are you ready to receive our lords blessing?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I managed to stammer something unintelligible out. Despite that he smiled at me with true affection and clasp me on the shoulder. That was the first he noticed my withered arm.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do you have something to ask me?" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]He expected me to ask for healing, but that didn't matter to me. Instead I asked, "What sort of spirit attacked my mother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]He put his arm around me and we walked to the sanctuary together.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Let me pray about it" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]The service was exactly like all the others but I paid little attention. Instead I watched Chalid. He looked confused as he prayed, sometimes pained, sometimes resigned and I imagined that it had something to do with my question.[PARAGRAPH:1]I waited after the service. Chalid spoke briefly with the vicar who had performed the service and meet a few of the members. And then he left the sanctuary and went into the council chambers.[PARAGRAPH:1]I spent the day neglecting my duties and waiting outside the council chamber. But just past nightfall the towns warning bells rang out, guards ran through the streets yelling that brigands were attacking.[PARAGRAPH:1]Everyone flooded out of the temple. At the edge of the town shapes rushed through the darkness. Black tipped arrows cut guards down where they writhed screaming in pain. Guards brought torches and under the cover of shield men they retook the fortifications while the shadows simply moved to attack at another point.[PARAGRAPH:1]A voice from the darkness called, "What good is a god that abandons you every night?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid ignored the taunt and ordered the men back within the cities lantern light. He alone bounded over the wall and in to the darkness at the cities edge. His mace glowed faintly in the starlight and though we couldn't see any attackers on the open field we all knew they were moving in on him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid prayed and an aura of golden fire burst up around his head and dark men caught fire on the field, on the walls, and even a few that had snuck into the city. The holy fire consumed them and guards rushed in to beat or capture the men.[PARAGRAPH:1]But one was not distracted by the fire. It clung to his black armor and that of his steed but he rode soundlessly towards Chalid, like a shadow of a dark god stretching out to touch him. Chalid raised his mace up, and then back down and the field was lit up as if it was day. A pillar of golden fire, like the sun itself but full of righteous fury, crushed the rider. There was a horrific scream and then when the pillar retreated back up into the sky the rider was gone.[PARAGRAPH:1]I spent the night tending to the guardsmen wounded in the attack. Their wounds festered from poison and the men passed between fevered dreams and anguish when awake. There was little I could do but try to keep their wounds clean and try to make them comfortable. Chalid and the priests prayed over the men and some were healed, but too many were injured.[PARAGRAPH:1]That next morning I returned to my chambers to wash up and change into fresh clothes, as did most of the temple. I headed again to the dawn ceremony and found Chalid alone again in the refectory looking out towards the east.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You saved the town." It sounded hollow when I said it. Unsuited to the miracle I had witnessed.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I only had faith that Lugus would protect me, he did everything else."[PARAGRAPH:1]I smiled, the warmth Chalid had shared with me yesterday was gone now. He looked troubled but I assumed it was just the events of the long night. I know he hadn't slept either.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Did you find out anything about my mother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid looked at the floor, the morning bells rang though neither of us moved.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I should lie to you" Chalid said, "the mandate of truth is sometimes painful. I am sorry. I won't lie but I will warn you, it would be better if you did not know."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I want to know" I argued with more passion than I intended, "Knowledge, truth, revelation are the precepts of Lugus. I should know my own past."[PARAGRAPH:1]"The woman's name was Magda de'Vala" Chalid started, "The man wasn't her husband but her guardian, though he was a priest of the Empyrean. The child was prophesied to be a great hero, which is why many sought to kill Magda and her baby."[PARAGRAPH:1]He paused, but I only waited for him to continue.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The stable boy Garrus died three days before the attack. That which killed Garras, that which killed Magda's guardian and caused the collapse that killed Magda and her baby. That was you."[PARAGRAPH:1]I was furious and I rushed out of the refectory. Chalid watched me go then headed into the sanctuary. My thoughts went back to those early days, I never felt like I was the stable boy. And for the first time I questioned my origin. Would a babies spirit in a boy's body be able to adapt that quickly? Could even a possessed stable boy be able to overcome a priest of Lugus, or was that creature something darker? And was I that creature?[PARAGRAPH:1]I stopped in the temples infirmary. Except for the wounded it was empty, everyone in the temple was in the dawn ceremony despite those laying here near death. There was only one man awake, a bandage covered his left thigh. I knelt at his bedside. When I saw the torment he was in I forgot a bit of my own.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What is your name?" I asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Abin," he said, "I'm a jeweler who pretended to be a city guard."[PARAGRAPH:1]That wasn't unusual. Our city was too small to maintain full time guardsmen so most were volunteers with other jobs.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Either you are too good at pretending, or not good enough."[PARAGRAPH:1]He gave me a weak smile.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Can I pray for you?" I asked. He nodded.[PARAGRAPH:1]I placed my hand on him and closed my eyes. I have seen many healed but I had never performed a miracle myself. If I could do this, if I could heal this man and channel the power of Lugus then I couldn't be whatever creature Chalid thought I was. Maybe I was the holy child, maybe the attack on Magda de'Vala failed.[PARAGRAPH:1]I could feel his labored breath. I could feel his pain, feel his love for his large family of nieces and nephews. His quiet store and hours spent working on small intricate jewelry. And I felt him die.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then I felt the poison strike, it burnt through my body focused on the wound in my left thigh. I stepped away from the bed in shock. I was taller and my robes, which were big on me, were now tight. And my formerly withered arm was now trapped uncomfortably in its folds.[PARAGRAPH:1]I loosened the robe and held out my full, strong arm. But it didn't look like my arm, it was the jewelers arm. And as I looked at myself I realized that I was identical to the dead body of the jeweler that lay in the bed in front of me. And then the poison struck again and sent me to my knees. I picked myself up and fled the temple in pain and confusion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Pain will drive you mad and it only took a few hours of suffering like this before I found a farmer out working in his field.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Blind goats Abin!" he said, "what is wrong with you? Why are you wearing a disciples robes?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I threw him to the ground and held him, smashing him once in the face when he tried to fight back. I felt for that closeness, I reached out to find everything that he was, and the pain drifted away. When I opened my eyes I saw him staring up at his own reflection in horror. The last I saw him he was running toward his farmhouse, I started running as well. I don't think I have ever stopped.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]I still don't know what I am. All the roles that I've played since then blur together in my mind. I've gotten better at reading people and worked for a time for an assassins guild, simply for reading people I touch. During other times I steal the lives of those I wish to share. I tried the lavish extravagance of princes and wealthy merchants, but there is little to envy them for once you understand how they truly live. The best stolen lives come from the simple fathers of large families, those that have the love and respect of everyone in their lives. Dump the body of one of those in a shallow grave and I have a few good weeks of fun before I become bored and move on to something else.[PARAGRAPH:1]Maybe Chalid was right, maybe I am a monster.</French>
		<German>[TAB]How many roles have I played? They blur together in my mind.[PARAGRAPH:1]I was a victim from the moment my life began. An attacker came for my mother even as she gave birth to me. He possessed Garrus, a simple stable boy and used him to sneak up through the inn to my parents room. He tried to get close to my mother, to attack her at her most vulnerable. My father fought to stop him. The details are unknown except that a battle occurred in the room and my father was struck a mortal blow. With his last breath he uttered a holy word that destroyed the spirit possessing Garrus and collapsed the entire inn.[PARAGRAPH:1]My mother died in the collapse, my father died from the attack. The stable boy was pulled from the rubble, one arm was crushed but he appeared otherwise healthy. My soul fled the dying infants form and took home in his newly evacuated body. I was born into the body of a teenage boy.[PARAGRAPH:1]The innkeeper raised me, teaching me as if I had simply forgotten my life and in a few years I served him well. He raised me as he rebuilt the inn. But I always knew that Garrus wasn't my name and I listened intently when those that survived the collapse retold the story.[PARAGRAPH:1]We didn't know much about my parents. But my father wore the yellow robes of a priest of the Empyrean. There was a small temple to the god in our city and when I was ready I joined their ranks as a disciple. Within the clergy my identity didn't matter, I was simply a child of Lugus. My superiors praised my empathy, questioned my maturity and laughed when I said that I thought I was the son of a priest. They claimed no such priest had visited the city and considered my thoughts the wishful thoughts of boy with too much imagination.[PARAGRAPH:1]My right arm was still crushed, by this point it was shriveled and permanently wrapped against my side. When I asked if it could be healed the priests prayed over it, but it never got better. Others came and received healing, nobles, merchants, beggars, soldiers. But I remained maimed.[PARAGRAPH:1]One day in early Aedrini the temple was in an uproar. Priests barked orders, disciples scurried about trying to look busy, no one had thought to wake me. After many questions a priest finally gave me my answer.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Luridus Chalid is coming child, stay out of the way."[PARAGRAPH:1]I began to retreat to my chamber when he yelled after me, "And don't bother him when he arrives!"[PARAGRAPH:1]That next day a single man arrived on a dappled grey mare. He rode without an escort and though he needed no guards on the road, he could have used some outside of the temple. He was immediately mobbed by well meaning disciples, genuflecting priests and hordes of gawking townspeople. He wore the robes of a Luridus and I wondered if my father wore the same.[PARAGRAPH:1]He spent the next three days in our hastily constructed council chamber. The chamber was open for anyone to hear the deliberation and speak in an orderly manner. They discussed the towns role in the Overcouncil, local legislation and a problem with brigands in the area.[PARAGRAPH:1]The council meetings always went well into the night, and Chalid attended every dawn ceremony. He only had a few hours between to get some sleep. I was hurrying to the dawn service one morning when I found him standing alone in the refectory looking out the windows toward the east. The morning bell rung, signaling the dawn ceremony was about to start and Chalid turned to find me staring at him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Morning disciple, are you ready to receive our lords blessing?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I managed to stammer something unintelligible out. Despite that he smiled at me with true affection and clasp me on the shoulder. That was the first he noticed my withered arm.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do you have something to ask me?" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]He expected me to ask for healing, but that didn't matter to me. Instead I asked, "What sort of spirit attacked my mother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]He put his arm around me and we walked to the sanctuary together.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Let me pray about it" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]The service was exactly like all the others but I paid little attention. Instead I watched Chalid. He looked confused as he prayed, sometimes pained, sometimes resigned and I imagined that it had something to do with my question.[PARAGRAPH:1]I waited after the service. Chalid spoke briefly with the vicar who had performed the service and meet a few of the members. And then he left the sanctuary and went into the council chambers.[PARAGRAPH:1]I spent the day neglecting my duties and waiting outside the council chamber. But just past nightfall the towns warning bells rang out, guards ran through the streets yelling that brigands were attacking.[PARAGRAPH:1]Everyone flooded out of the temple. At the edge of the town shapes rushed through the darkness. Black tipped arrows cut guards down where they writhed screaming in pain. Guards brought torches and under the cover of shield men they retook the fortifications while the shadows simply moved to attack at another point.[PARAGRAPH:1]A voice from the darkness called, "What good is a god that abandons you every night?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid ignored the taunt and ordered the men back within the cities lantern light. He alone bounded over the wall and in to the darkness at the cities edge. His mace glowed faintly in the starlight and though we couldn't see any attackers on the open field we all knew they were moving in on him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid prayed and an aura of golden fire burst up around his head and dark men caught fire on the field, on the walls, and even a few that had snuck into the city. The holy fire consumed them and guards rushed in to beat or capture the men.[PARAGRAPH:1]But one was not distracted by the fire. It clung to his black armor and that of his steed but he rode soundlessly towards Chalid, like a shadow of a dark god stretching out to touch him. Chalid raised his mace up, and then back down and the field was lit up as if it was day. A pillar of golden fire, like the sun itself but full of righteous fury, crushed the rider. There was a horrific scream and then when the pillar retreated back up into the sky the rider was gone.[PARAGRAPH:1]I spent the night tending to the guardsmen wounded in the attack. Their wounds festered from poison and the men passed between fevered dreams and anguish when awake. There was little I could do but try to keep their wounds clean and try to make them comfortable. Chalid and the priests prayed over the men and some were healed, but too many were injured.[PARAGRAPH:1]That next morning I returned to my chambers to wash up and change into fresh clothes, as did most of the temple. I headed again to the dawn ceremony and found Chalid alone again in the refectory looking out towards the east.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You saved the town." It sounded hollow when I said it. Unsuited to the miracle I had witnessed.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I only had faith that Lugus would protect me, he did everything else."[PARAGRAPH:1]I smiled, the warmth Chalid had shared with me yesterday was gone now. He looked troubled but I assumed it was just the events of the long night. I know he hadn't slept either.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Did you find out anything about my mother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid looked at the floor, the morning bells rang though neither of us moved.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I should lie to you" Chalid said, "the mandate of truth is sometimes painful. I am sorry. I won't lie but I will warn you, it would be better if you did not know."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I want to know" I argued with more passion than I intended, "Knowledge, truth, revelation are the precepts of Lugus. I should know my own past."[PARAGRAPH:1]"The woman's name was Magda de'Vala" Chalid started, "The man wasn't her husband but her guardian, though he was a priest of the Empyrean. The child was prophesied to be a great hero, which is why many sought to kill Magda and her baby."[PARAGRAPH:1]He paused, but I only waited for him to continue.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The stable boy Garrus died three days before the attack. That which killed Garras, that which killed Magda's guardian and caused the collapse that killed Magda and her baby. That was you."[PARAGRAPH:1]I was furious and I rushed out of the refectory. Chalid watched me go then headed into the sanctuary. My thoughts went back to those early days, I never felt like I was the stable boy. And for the first time I questioned my origin. Would a babies spirit in a boy's body be able to adapt that quickly? Could even a possessed stable boy be able to overcome a priest of Lugus, or was that creature something darker? And was I that creature?[PARAGRAPH:1]I stopped in the temples infirmary. Except for the wounded it was empty, everyone in the temple was in the dawn ceremony despite those laying here near death. There was only one man awake, a bandage covered his left thigh. I knelt at his bedside. When I saw the torment he was in I forgot a bit of my own.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What is your name?" I asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Abin," he said, "I'm a jeweler who pretended to be a city guard."[PARAGRAPH:1]That wasn't unusual. Our city was too small to maintain full time guardsmen so most were volunteers with other jobs.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Either you are too good at pretending, or not good enough."[PARAGRAPH:1]He gave me a weak smile.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Can I pray for you?" I asked. He nodded.[PARAGRAPH:1]I placed my hand on him and closed my eyes. I have seen many healed but I had never performed a miracle myself. If I could do this, if I could heal this man and channel the power of Lugus then I couldn't be whatever creature Chalid thought I was. Maybe I was the holy child, maybe the attack on Magda de'Vala failed.[PARAGRAPH:1]I could feel his labored breath. I could feel his pain, feel his love for his large family of nieces and nephews. His quiet store and hours spent working on small intricate jewelry. And I felt him die.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then I felt the poison strike, it burnt through my body focused on the wound in my left thigh. I stepped away from the bed in shock. I was taller and my robes, which were big on me, were now tight. And my formerly withered arm was now trapped uncomfortably in its folds.[PARAGRAPH:1]I loosened the robe and held out my full, strong arm. But it didn't look like my arm, it was the jewelers arm. And as I looked at myself I realized that I was identical to the dead body of the jeweler that lay in the bed in front of me. And then the poison struck again and sent me to my knees. I picked myself up and fled the temple in pain and confusion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Pain will drive you mad and it only took a few hours of suffering like this before I found a farmer out working in his field.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Blind goats Abin!" he said, "what is wrong with you? Why are you wearing a disciples robes?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I threw him to the ground and held him, smashing him once in the face when he tried to fight back. I felt for that closeness, I reached out to find everything that he was, and the pain drifted away. When I opened my eyes I saw him staring up at his own reflection in horror. The last I saw him he was running toward his farmhouse, I started running as well. I don't think I have ever stopped.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]I still don't know what I am. All the roles that I've played since then blur together in my mind. I've gotten better at reading people and worked for a time for an assassins guild, simply for reading people I touch. During other times I steal the lives of those I wish to share. I tried the lavish extravagance of princes and wealthy merchants, but there is little to envy them for once you understand how they truly live. The best stolen lives come from the simple fathers of large families, those that have the love and respect of everyone in their lives. Dump the body of one of those in a shallow grave and I have a few good weeks of fun before I become bored and move on to something else.[PARAGRAPH:1]Maybe Chalid was right, maybe I am a monster.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]How many roles have I played? They blur together in my mind.[PARAGRAPH:1]I was a victim from the moment my life began. An attacker came for my mother even as she gave birth to me. He possessed Garrus, a simple stable boy and used him to sneak up through the inn to my parents room. He tried to get close to my mother, to attack her at her most vulnerable. My father fought to stop him. The details are unknown except that a battle occurred in the room and my father was struck a mortal blow. With his last breath he uttered a holy word that destroyed the spirit possessing Garrus and collapsed the entire inn.[PARAGRAPH:1]My mother died in the collapse, my father died from the attack. The stable boy was pulled from the rubble, one arm was crushed but he appeared otherwise healthy. My soul fled the dying infants form and took home in his newly evacuated body. I was born into the body of a teenage boy.[PARAGRAPH:1]The innkeeper raised me, teaching me as if I had simply forgotten my life and in a few years I served him well. He raised me as he rebuilt the inn. But I always knew that Garrus wasn't my name and I listened intently when those that survived the collapse retold the story.[PARAGRAPH:1]We didn't know much about my parents. But my father wore the yellow robes of a priest of the Empyrean. There was a small temple to the god in our city and when I was ready I joined their ranks as a disciple. Within the clergy my identity didn't matter, I was simply a child of Lugus. My superiors praised my empathy, questioned my maturity and laughed when I said that I thought I was the son of a priest. They claimed no such priest had visited the city and considered my thoughts the wishful thoughts of boy with too much imagination.[PARAGRAPH:1]My right arm was still crushed, by this point it was shriveled and permanently wrapped against my side. When I asked if it could be healed the priests prayed over it, but it never got better. Others came and received healing, nobles, merchants, beggars, soldiers. But I remained maimed.[PARAGRAPH:1]One day in early Aedrini the temple was in an uproar. Priests barked orders, disciples scurried about trying to look busy, no one had thought to wake me. After many questions a priest finally gave me my answer.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Luridus Chalid is coming child, stay out of the way."[PARAGRAPH:1]I began to retreat to my chamber when he yelled after me, "And don't bother him when he arrives!"[PARAGRAPH:1]That next day a single man arrived on a dappled grey mare. He rode without an escort and though he needed no guards on the road, he could have used some outside of the temple. He was immediately mobbed by well meaning disciples, genuflecting priests and hordes of gawking townspeople. He wore the robes of a Luridus and I wondered if my father wore the same.[PARAGRAPH:1]He spent the next three days in our hastily constructed council chamber. The chamber was open for anyone to hear the deliberation and speak in an orderly manner. They discussed the towns role in the Overcouncil, local legislation and a problem with brigands in the area.[PARAGRAPH:1]The council meetings always went well into the night, and Chalid attended every dawn ceremony. He only had a few hours between to get some sleep. I was hurrying to the dawn service one morning when I found him standing alone in the refectory looking out the windows toward the east. The morning bell rung, signaling the dawn ceremony was about to start and Chalid turned to find me staring at him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Morning disciple, are you ready to receive our lords blessing?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I managed to stammer something unintelligible out. Despite that he smiled at me with true affection and clasp me on the shoulder. That was the first he noticed my withered arm.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do you have something to ask me?" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]He expected me to ask for healing, but that didn't matter to me. Instead I asked, "What sort of spirit attacked my mother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]He put his arm around me and we walked to the sanctuary together.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Let me pray about it" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]The service was exactly like all the others but I paid little attention. Instead I watched Chalid. He looked confused as he prayed, sometimes pained, sometimes resigned and I imagined that it had something to do with my question.[PARAGRAPH:1]I waited after the service. Chalid spoke briefly with the vicar who had performed the service and meet a few of the members. And then he left the sanctuary and went into the council chambers.[PARAGRAPH:1]I spent the day neglecting my duties and waiting outside the council chamber. But just past nightfall the towns warning bells rang out, guards ran through the streets yelling that brigands were attacking.[PARAGRAPH:1]Everyone flooded out of the temple. At the edge of the town shapes rushed through the darkness. Black tipped arrows cut guards down where they writhed screaming in pain. Guards brought torches and under the cover of shield men they retook the fortifications while the shadows simply moved to attack at another point.[PARAGRAPH:1]A voice from the darkness called, "What good is a god that abandons you every night?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid ignored the taunt and ordered the men back within the cities lantern light. He alone bounded over the wall and in to the darkness at the cities edge. His mace glowed faintly in the starlight and though we couldn't see any attackers on the open field we all knew they were moving in on him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid prayed and an aura of golden fire burst up around his head and dark men caught fire on the field, on the walls, and even a few that had snuck into the city. The holy fire consumed them and guards rushed in to beat or capture the men.[PARAGRAPH:1]But one was not distracted by the fire. It clung to his black armor and that of his steed but he rode soundlessly towards Chalid, like a shadow of a dark god stretching out to touch him. Chalid raised his mace up, and then back down and the field was lit up as if it was day. A pillar of golden fire, like the sun itself but full of righteous fury, crushed the rider. There was a horrific scream and then when the pillar retreated back up into the sky the rider was gone.[PARAGRAPH:1]I spent the night tending to the guardsmen wounded in the attack. Their wounds festered from poison and the men passed between fevered dreams and anguish when awake. There was little I could do but try to keep their wounds clean and try to make them comfortable. Chalid and the priests prayed over the men and some were healed, but too many were injured.[PARAGRAPH:1]That next morning I returned to my chambers to wash up and change into fresh clothes, as did most of the temple. I headed again to the dawn ceremony and found Chalid alone again in the refectory looking out towards the east.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You saved the town." It sounded hollow when I said it. Unsuited to the miracle I had witnessed.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I only had faith that Lugus would protect me, he did everything else."[PARAGRAPH:1]I smiled, the warmth Chalid had shared with me yesterday was gone now. He looked troubled but I assumed it was just the events of the long night. I know he hadn't slept either.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Did you find out anything about my mother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid looked at the floor, the morning bells rang though neither of us moved.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I should lie to you" Chalid said, "the mandate of truth is sometimes painful. I am sorry. I won't lie but I will warn you, it would be better if you did not know."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I want to know" I argued with more passion than I intended, "Knowledge, truth, revelation are the precepts of Lugus. I should know my own past."[PARAGRAPH:1]"The woman's name was Magda de'Vala" Chalid started, "The man wasn't her husband but her guardian, though he was a priest of the Empyrean. The child was prophesied to be a great hero, which is why many sought to kill Magda and her baby."[PARAGRAPH:1]He paused, but I only waited for him to continue.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The stable boy Garrus died three days before the attack. That which killed Garras, that which killed Magda's guardian and caused the collapse that killed Magda and her baby. That was you."[PARAGRAPH:1]I was furious and I rushed out of the refectory. Chalid watched me go then headed into the sanctuary. My thoughts went back to those early days, I never felt like I was the stable boy. And for the first time I questioned my origin. Would a babies spirit in a boy's body be able to adapt that quickly? Could even a possessed stable boy be able to overcome a priest of Lugus, or was that creature something darker? And was I that creature?[PARAGRAPH:1]I stopped in the temples infirmary. Except for the wounded it was empty, everyone in the temple was in the dawn ceremony despite those laying here near death. There was only one man awake, a bandage covered his left thigh. I knelt at his bedside. When I saw the torment he was in I forgot a bit of my own.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What is your name?" I asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Abin," he said, "I'm a jeweler who pretended to be a city guard."[PARAGRAPH:1]That wasn't unusual. Our city was too small to maintain full time guardsmen so most were volunteers with other jobs.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Either you are too good at pretending, or not good enough."[PARAGRAPH:1]He gave me a weak smile.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Can I pray for you?" I asked. He nodded.[PARAGRAPH:1]I placed my hand on him and closed my eyes. I have seen many healed but I had never performed a miracle myself. If I could do this, if I could heal this man and channel the power of Lugus then I couldn't be whatever creature Chalid thought I was. Maybe I was the holy child, maybe the attack on Magda de'Vala failed.[PARAGRAPH:1]I could feel his labored breath. I could feel his pain, feel his love for his large family of nieces and nephews. His quiet store and hours spent working on small intricate jewelry. And I felt him die.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then I felt the poison strike, it burnt through my body focused on the wound in my left thigh. I stepped away from the bed in shock. I was taller and my robes, which were big on me, were now tight. And my formerly withered arm was now trapped uncomfortably in its folds.[PARAGRAPH:1]I loosened the robe and held out my full, strong arm. But it didn't look like my arm, it was the jewelers arm. And as I looked at myself I realized that I was identical to the dead body of the jeweler that lay in the bed in front of me. And then the poison struck again and sent me to my knees. I picked myself up and fled the temple in pain and confusion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Pain will drive you mad and it only took a few hours of suffering like this before I found a farmer out working in his field.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Blind goats Abin!" he said, "what is wrong with you? Why are you wearing a disciples robes?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I threw him to the ground and held him, smashing him once in the face when he tried to fight back. I felt for that closeness, I reached out to find everything that he was, and the pain drifted away. When I opened my eyes I saw him staring up at his own reflection in horror. The last I saw him he was running toward his farmhouse, I started running as well. I don't think I have ever stopped.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]I still don't know what I am. All the roles that I've played since then blur together in my mind. I've gotten better at reading people and worked for a time for an assassins guild, simply for reading people I touch. During other times I steal the lives of those I wish to share. I tried the lavish extravagance of princes and wealthy merchants, but there is little to envy them for once you understand how they truly live. The best stolen lives come from the simple fathers of large families, those that have the love and respect of everyone in their lives. Dump the body of one of those in a shallow grave and I have a few good weeks of fun before I become bored and move on to something else.[PARAGRAPH:1]Maybe Chalid was right, maybe I am a monster.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]How many roles have I played? They blur together in my mind.[PARAGRAPH:1]I was a victim from the moment my life began. An attacker came for my mother even as she gave birth to me. He possessed Garrus, a simple stable boy and used him to sneak up through the inn to my parents room. He tried to get close to my mother, to attack her at her most vulnerable. My father fought to stop him. The details are unknown except that a battle occurred in the room and my father was struck a mortal blow. With his last breath he uttered a holy word that destroyed the spirit possessing Garrus and collapsed the entire inn.[PARAGRAPH:1]My mother died in the collapse, my father died from the attack. The stable boy was pulled from the rubble, one arm was crushed but he appeared otherwise healthy. My soul fled the dying infants form and took home in his newly evacuated body. I was born into the body of a teenage boy.[PARAGRAPH:1]The innkeeper raised me, teaching me as if I had simply forgotten my life and in a few years I served him well. He raised me as he rebuilt the inn. But I always knew that Garrus wasn't my name and I listened intently when those that survived the collapse retold the story.[PARAGRAPH:1]We didn't know much about my parents. But my father wore the yellow robes of a priest of the Empyrean. There was a small temple to the god in our city and when I was ready I joined their ranks as a disciple. Within the clergy my identity didn't matter, I was simply a child of Lugus. My superiors praised my empathy, questioned my maturity and laughed when I said that I thought I was the son of a priest. They claimed no such priest had visited the city and considered my thoughts the wishful thoughts of boy with too much imagination.[PARAGRAPH:1]My right arm was still crushed, by this point it was shriveled and permanently wrapped against my side. When I asked if it could be healed the priests prayed over it, but it never got better. Others came and received healing, nobles, merchants, beggars, soldiers. But I remained maimed.[PARAGRAPH:1]One day in early Aedrini the temple was in an uproar. Priests barked orders, disciples scurried about trying to look busy, no one had thought to wake me. After many questions a priest finally gave me my answer.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Luridus Chalid is coming child, stay out of the way."[PARAGRAPH:1]I began to retreat to my chamber when he yelled after me, "And don't bother him when he arrives!"[PARAGRAPH:1]That next day a single man arrived on a dappled grey mare. He rode without an escort and though he needed no guards on the road, he could have used some outside of the temple. He was immediately mobbed by well meaning disciples, genuflecting priests and hordes of gawking townspeople. He wore the robes of a Luridus and I wondered if my father wore the same.[PARAGRAPH:1]He spent the next three days in our hastily constructed council chamber. The chamber was open for anyone to hear the deliberation and speak in an orderly manner. They discussed the towns role in the Overcouncil, local legislation and a problem with brigands in the area.[PARAGRAPH:1]The council meetings always went well into the night, and Chalid attended every dawn ceremony. He only had a few hours between to get some sleep. I was hurrying to the dawn service one morning when I found him standing alone in the refectory looking out the windows toward the east. The morning bell rung, signaling the dawn ceremony was about to start and Chalid turned to find me staring at him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Morning disciple, are you ready to receive our lords blessing?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I managed to stammer something unintelligible out. Despite that he smiled at me with true affection and clasp me on the shoulder. That was the first he noticed my withered arm.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do you have something to ask me?" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]He expected me to ask for healing, but that didn't matter to me. Instead I asked, "What sort of spirit attacked my mother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]He put his arm around me and we walked to the sanctuary together.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Let me pray about it" he said.[PARAGRAPH:1]The service was exactly like all the others but I paid little attention. Instead I watched Chalid. He looked confused as he prayed, sometimes pained, sometimes resigned and I imagined that it had something to do with my question.[PARAGRAPH:1]I waited after the service. Chalid spoke briefly with the vicar who had performed the service and meet a few of the members. And then he left the sanctuary and went into the council chambers.[PARAGRAPH:1]I spent the day neglecting my duties and waiting outside the council chamber. But just past nightfall the towns warning bells rang out, guards ran through the streets yelling that brigands were attacking.[PARAGRAPH:1]Everyone flooded out of the temple. At the edge of the town shapes rushed through the darkness. Black tipped arrows cut guards down where they writhed screaming in pain. Guards brought torches and under the cover of shield men they retook the fortifications while the shadows simply moved to attack at another point.[PARAGRAPH:1]A voice from the darkness called, "What good is a god that abandons you every night?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid ignored the taunt and ordered the men back within the cities lantern light. He alone bounded over the wall and in to the darkness at the cities edge. His mace glowed faintly in the starlight and though we couldn't see any attackers on the open field we all knew they were moving in on him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid prayed and an aura of golden fire burst up around his head and dark men caught fire on the field, on the walls, and even a few that had snuck into the city. The holy fire consumed them and guards rushed in to beat or capture the men.[PARAGRAPH:1]But one was not distracted by the fire. It clung to his black armor and that of his steed but he rode soundlessly towards Chalid, like a shadow of a dark god stretching out to touch him. Chalid raised his mace up, and then back down and the field was lit up as if it was day. A pillar of golden fire, like the sun itself but full of righteous fury, crushed the rider. There was a horrific scream and then when the pillar retreated back up into the sky the rider was gone.[PARAGRAPH:1]I spent the night tending to the guardsmen wounded in the attack. Their wounds festered from poison and the men passed between fevered dreams and anguish when awake. There was little I could do but try to keep their wounds clean and try to make them comfortable. Chalid and the priests prayed over the men and some were healed, but too many were injured.[PARAGRAPH:1]That next morning I returned to my chambers to wash up and change into fresh clothes, as did most of the temple. I headed again to the dawn ceremony and found Chalid alone again in the refectory looking out towards the east.[PARAGRAPH:1]"You saved the town." It sounded hollow when I said it. Unsuited to the miracle I had witnessed.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I only had faith that Lugus would protect me, he did everything else."[PARAGRAPH:1]I smiled, the warmth Chalid had shared with me yesterday was gone now. He looked troubled but I assumed it was just the events of the long night. I know he hadn't slept either.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Did you find out anything about my mother?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Chalid looked at the floor, the morning bells rang though neither of us moved.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I should lie to you" Chalid said, "the mandate of truth is sometimes painful. I am sorry. I won't lie but I will warn you, it would be better if you did not know."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I want to know" I argued with more passion than I intended, "Knowledge, truth, revelation are the precepts of Lugus. I should know my own past."[PARAGRAPH:1]"The woman's name was Magda de'Vala" Chalid started, "The man wasn't her husband but her guardian, though he was a priest of the Empyrean. The child was prophesied to be a great hero, which is why many sought to kill Magda and her baby."[PARAGRAPH:1]He paused, but I only waited for him to continue.[PARAGRAPH:1]"The stable boy Garrus died three days before the attack. That which killed Garras, that which killed Magda's guardian and caused the collapse that killed Magda and her baby. That was you."[PARAGRAPH:1]I was furious and I rushed out of the refectory. Chalid watched me go then headed into the sanctuary. My thoughts went back to those early days, I never felt like I was the stable boy. And for the first time I questioned my origin. Would a babies spirit in a boy's body be able to adapt that quickly? Could even a possessed stable boy be able to overcome a priest of Lugus, or was that creature something darker? And was I that creature?[PARAGRAPH:1]I stopped in the temples infirmary. Except for the wounded it was empty, everyone in the temple was in the dawn ceremony despite those laying here near death. There was only one man awake, a bandage covered his left thigh. I knelt at his bedside. When I saw the torment he was in I forgot a bit of my own.[PARAGRAPH:1]"What is your name?" I asked.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Abin," he said, "I'm a jeweler who pretended to be a city guard."[PARAGRAPH:1]That wasn't unusual. Our city was too small to maintain full time guardsmen so most were volunteers with other jobs.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Either you are too good at pretending, or not good enough."[PARAGRAPH:1]He gave me a weak smile.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Can I pray for you?" I asked. He nodded.[PARAGRAPH:1]I placed my hand on him and closed my eyes. I have seen many healed but I had never performed a miracle myself. If I could do this, if I could heal this man and channel the power of Lugus then I couldn't be whatever creature Chalid thought I was. Maybe I was the holy child, maybe the attack on Magda de'Vala failed.[PARAGRAPH:1]I could feel his labored breath. I could feel his pain, feel his love for his large family of nieces and nephews. His quiet store and hours spent working on small intricate jewelry. And I felt him die.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then I felt the poison strike, it burnt through my body focused on the wound in my left thigh. I stepped away from the bed in shock. I was taller and my robes, which were big on me, were now tight. And my formerly withered arm was now trapped uncomfortably in its folds.[PARAGRAPH:1]I loosened the robe and held out my full, strong arm. But it didn't look like my arm, it was the jewelers arm. And as I looked at myself I realized that I was identical to the dead body of the jeweler that lay in the bed in front of me. And then the poison struck again and sent me to my knees. I picked myself up and fled the temple in pain and confusion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Pain will drive you mad and it only took a few hours of suffering like this before I found a farmer out working in his field.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Blind goats Abin!" he said, "what is wrong with you? Why are you wearing a disciples robes?"[PARAGRAPH:1]I threw him to the ground and held him, smashing him once in the face when he tried to fight back. I felt for that closeness, I reached out to find everything that he was, and the pain drifted away. When I opened my eyes I saw him staring up at his own reflection in horror. The last I saw him he was running toward his farmhouse, I started running as well. I don't think I have ever stopped.[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1]I still don't know what I am. All the roles that I've played since then blur together in my mind. I've gotten better at reading people and worked for a time for an assassins guild, simply for reading people I touch. During other times I steal the lives of those I wish to share. I tried the lavish extravagance of princes and wealthy merchants, but there is little to envy them for once you understand how they truly live. The best stolen lives come from the simple fathers of large families, those that have the love and respect of everyone in their lives. Dump the body of one of those in a shallow grave and I have a few good weeks of fun before I become bored and move on to something else.[PARAGRAPH:1]Maybe Chalid was right, maybe I am a monster.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DUIN</Tag>
		<English>Baron Duin Halfmorn</English>
		<French>Baron Duin Halfmorn</French>
		<German>Baron Duin Halfmorn</German>
		<Italian>Baron Duin Halfmorn</Italian>
		<Spanish>Baron Duin Halfmorn</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DUIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Duin was a fearsome warlord during the Age of Magic. He hosted lavish banquets after his victories, where he and his generals feasted on the bodies of the captured opponents. His generals' ambition grew to match his own and they turned on him in a bloody civil war. Duin won the war but lost his empire; in the end, he sat alone, feasting on his generals' bodies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Like all mortals, even the horrific Duin passed away, but he would not be allowed to sleep forever. In time of dire need, desperate mages performed rites to bring back the greatest, most feared general of history. But it was not without price: the gods knew of Duin's character, and would not suffer him to be raised back to life without an appropriate form.[PARAGRAPH:1]Werewolves had not been seen in the world since the Age of Ice. Hardly possessed with the same mental faculties as vampires, the werewolves truly were hunted to extinction by the human survivors. But in Duin Halfmorn, these dark creatures will witness a terrible rebirth, and the free peoples would do right to tremble in fear.</English>
		<French>Duin was a fearsome warlord during the Age of Magic. He hosted lavish banquets after his victories, where he and his generals feasted on the bodies of the captured opponents. His generals' ambition grew to match his own and they turned on him in a bloody civil war. Duin won the war but lost his empire; in the end, he sat alone, feasting on his generals' bodies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Like all mortals, even the horrific Duin passed away, but he would not be allowed to sleep forever. In time of dire need, desperate mages performed rites to bring back the greatest, most feared general of history. But it was not without price: the gods knew of Duin's character, and would not suffer him to be raised back to life without an appropriate form.[PARAGRAPH:1]Werewolves had not been seen in the world since the Age of Ice. Hardly possessed with the same mental faculties as vampires, the werewolves truly were hunted to extinction by the human survivors. But in Duin Halfmorn, these dark creatures will witness a terrible rebirth, and the free peoples would do right to tremble in fear.</French>
		<German>Duin brachte es im Zeitalter der Magie zu einem furchterregenden Kriegsherrn. Nach jedem Sieg richtete er verschwenderische Bankette aus, bei denen er und seine Generäle die Körper der Gefangenen verspeisten. Es kam die Zeit, da sie ihm in Macht und Ehrgeiz gleichen wollten und sie wandten sich in einem blutigen Bürgerkrieg gegen ihn. Duin gewann den Krieg, aber verlor sein Reich und am Ende saß er allein zu Tisch vor den Körpern seiner Generäle.[PARAGRAPH:1]Wie alle Sterblichen, musste auch er dahin scheiden, doch nicht für ewig. Denn in einer Zeit grösster Not führten verzweifelte Magier Rituale zur Wiederbelebung des meist gefürchteten Generals der Geschichte durch. Erst die Götter verliehen dem Zauber seine Kraft, aber sie liessen Duin wohlwissend um sein wahres Wesen die Gestalt eines Werwolfes annehmen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Werwölfe wurden seit dem Zeitalter des Eises nicht mehr gesehen. Den Vampiren in geistigen Fähigkeiten unterlegen, waren sie von der Menschheit bis zur Ausrottung gejagt worden. Doch durch Duin Halfmorn werden diese dunklen Geschöpfe ihre grausame Wiedergeburt erleben und alle freien Völker in Furcht erzittern lassen.</German>
		<Italian>Duin was a fearsome warlord during the Age of Magic. He hosted lavish banquets after his victories, where he and his generals feasted on the bodies of the captured opponents. His generals' ambition grew to match his own and they turned on him in a bloody civil war. Duin won the war but lost his empire; in the end, he sat alone, feasting on his generals' bodies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Like all mortals, even the horrific Duin passed away, but he would not be allowed to sleep forever. In time of dire need, desperate mages performed rites to bring back the greatest, most feared general of history. But it was not without price: the gods knew of Duin's character, and would not suffer him to be raised back to life without an appropriate form.[PARAGRAPH:1]Werewolves had not been seen in the world since the Age of Ice. Hardly possessed with the same mental faculties as vampires, the werewolves truly were hunted to extinction by the human survivors. But in Duin Halfmorn, these dark creatures will witness a terrible rebirth, and the free peoples would do right to tremble in fear.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Duin was a fearsome warlord during the Age of Magic. He hosted lavish banquets after his victories, where he and his generals feasted on the bodies of the captured opponents. His generals' ambition grew to match his own and they turned on him in a bloody civil war. Duin won the war but lost his empire; in the end, he sat alone, feasting on his generals' bodies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Like all mortals, even the horrific Duin passed away, but he would not be allowed to sleep forever. In time of dire need, desperate mages performed rites to bring back the greatest, most feared general of history. But it was not without price: the gods knew of Duin's character, and would not suffer him to be raised back to life without an appropriate form.[PARAGRAPH:1]Werewolves had not been seen in the world since the Age of Ice. Hardly possessed with the same mental faculties as vampires, the werewolves truly were hunted to extinction by the human survivors. But in Duin Halfmorn, these dark creatures will witness a terrible rebirth, and the free peoples would do right to tremble in fear.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_DUIN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Reborn in the land by unknown means, Duin has been cursed with Lycanthropy: every living unit he slays becomes a Ravenous Werewolf that will follow him.</English>
		<French>Ressuscité de façon inexpliquée, Duin a été affecté par la Lycanthropie, toute unité vivante qu'il capture devient un Loup-Garou vorace qui va le suivre.</French>
		<German>Wiedererweckt von den Toten ist Duin mit Lykanthropie verflucht: jede lebende von ihm besiegte Einheit verwandelt sich in einen Lechzenden Werwolf und unterwirft sich seinem Willen.</German>
		<Italian>Reborn in the land by unknown means, Duin has been cursed with Lycanthropy: every living unit he slays becomes a Ravenous Werewolf that will follow him.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Reborn in the land by unknown means, Duin has been cursed with Lycanthropy: every living unit he slays becomes a Ravenous Werewolf that will follow him.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FIACRA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]"Awake my noble pet."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mulcarn undid the bindings that had been in place since the time of the Compact.  The chains were only a physical manifestation of the magic that bound the great eagle, that kept Fiacra from leaving his prison, and contained the blizzards that always followed him.[PARAGRAPH:1]Fiacra focused on his master's voice, eager to sail over creation again, to taste meat and hunt the pets of lesser gods.  Once freed, he lept to Mulcarn's arm and let out a shriek that echoed even above the roar of the storm that surrounded them.[PARAGRAPH:1]"It is your time again. Go hunt the wilds and devour those men that have not sworn loyalty to me.  Bhall has fallen and I have destroyed the lord of summer.  This age is mine, and it will be eternal."[PARAGRAPH:1]With that Mulcarn raised his arm and Fiacra's wings spread to catch the winds of the blizzard.  The eagle was quickly lifted into the air and turned south, towards the sparse civilizations of man.</English>
		<French>[TAB]"Réveille-toi, noble animal."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mulcarn défit les liens en place depuis l'époque du pacte. Les cha&#238;nes n'étaient qu'une manifestation de cette magie qui retenait le grand aigle, emp&#234;chait Fiacra de quitter sa prison, et contenait le blizzard qui l'avait toujours suivi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Fiacra se concentra sur la voix de son ma&#238;tre, impatient d'aller voler au-dessus de la terre, de go&#251;ter la viande et de chasser les animaux des dieux inférieurs. Une fois libéré, il vola jusqu'au bras de Mulcarn et laissa échapper un cri qui résonna au-delà m&#234;me des grondements de la temp&#234;te autour d'eux.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Notre temps est à nouveau venu ! Va chasser et dévore ces hommes qui ne m'ont pas juré fidélité. Bhall est tombée et j'ai détruit le Seigneur de l'été. Cet âge est le mien et il sera éternel."[PARAGRAPH:1]Sur ce, Mulcarn leva son bras. Les ailes de Fiacra se déployèrent pour profiter du blizzard. L'aigle s'envola rapidement vers le sud, vers les tribus humaines éparses.</French>
		<German>[TAB]"Hinweg, mein edles Schoßtier."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mulcarn löste die Bande, die seit der Zeit des Paktes bestanden. Die Ketten waren nur eine Manifestation der Magie, die den großen Adler band, die verhinderte, dass Fiacra sein Gefängnis verließ, und die die Schneestürme verursachte, die ihm stets folgten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Fiacra konzentrierte sich auf die Stimme seines Herrn, begierig darauf, wieder über die Schöpfung zu segeln, Fleisch zu schmecken und die Tiere der niederen Götter zu jagen. Freigelassen schwang er sich auf Mulcarns Arm und stieß einen Schrei aus, der sogar den Sturm übertönte, der sie umgab.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Deine Zeit ist erneut gekommen. Jage in der Wildnis und verschlinge diejenigen, die mir keinen Gehorsam geschworen haben. Bhall ist gefallen und ich habe den Herrn des Sommers vernichtet. Dieses Zeitalter ist mein, und es wird auf ewig andauern."[PARAGRAPH:1]Damit hob Mulcarn den Arm und Fiacra spreizte die Schwingen, um den Wind des Schneesturms einzufangen. Der Adler erhob sich geschwind in die Luft und wandte sich gen Süden, zu den spärlichen Zivilisationen der Menschheit.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]"Sveglia, mio nobile animale."[PARAGRAPH:1]Mulcarn sciolse i legami che esistevano dal tempo del patto. Le catene erano solo una manifestazione fisica della magia che legava la grande aquila, che teneva Fiacra in prigione e conteneva le tempeste che lo seguivano.[PARAGRAPH:1]Fiacra si concentr&#242; sulla voce del padrone, ansioso di veleggiare ancora nel creato, di gustare la carne e cacciare gli animali di dei inferiori. Una volta liberato, salt&#242; sul braccio di Mulcarn e fece uno strillo che riecheggi&#242; anche sul rombo della tempesta che li circondava.[PARAGRAPH:1]"&#200; di nuovo la tua ora. Torna a cacciare nelle lande desolate e divora gli uomini che non mi hanno giurato fedeltà. Bhall è caduta e ho distrutto il signore dell'estate. Questa era è mia, e durerà in eterno."[PARAGRAPH:1]Cos&#236; dicendo Mulcarn sollev&#242; il braccio e le ali di Fiacra si spiegarono per catturare i venti della tempesta. L'aquila si alz&#242; rapidamente e si diresse a sud, verso le rade civiltà degli uomini.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]"Despierta, mi noble mascota". [PARAGRAPH:1]Mulcarn deshizo las ataduras que hab&#237;an estado all&#237; desde tiempos del pacto.  Las cadenas eran solo una manifestaci&#243;n f&#237;sica de la magia que manten&#237;a cautiva a la gran &#225;guila, imped&#237;a que Fiacra dejara la prisi&#243;n y conten&#237;a las ventiscas que siempre la segu&#237;an.[PARAGRAPH:1]Fiacra, impaciente por sobrevolar de nuevo la creaci&#243;n, probar la carne y cazar las mascotas de los dioses menores, se concentr&#243; en la voz de su amo y se&#241;or.  Una vez libre, subi&#243; al brazo de Mulcarn y solt&#243; un chillido que reson&#243; incluso por encima del rugido de la tormenta que los rodeaba.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ha llegado tu hora una vez m&#225;s. Ve a las tierras salvajes y da caza a los hombres que no me hayan jurado lealtad.  Bhall ha ca&#237;do, y he destruido al se&#241;or del verano.  Esta edad es m&#237;a, y haré que sea eterna". [PARAGRAPH:1]Dicho esto, Mulcarn levant&#243; el brazo y Fiacra despleg&#243; las alas para atrapar los vientos de la tormenta.  El &#225;guila se elev&#243; r&#225;pidamente en el aire y se dirigi&#243; al sur, hacia las modestas ciudades de los hombres.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_FIACRA</Tag>
		<English>Fiacra the North Wind</English>
		<French>Fiacra le Vent Septentrional</French>
		<German>
			<Text>Fiacra der Nordwind</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0</Plural>
		</German>
		<Italian>Fiacra, il Vento del nord</Italian>
		<Spanish>Fiacra, el viento del Norte</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ORTHUS</Tag>
		<English>Orthus</English>
		<French>Orthus</French>
		<German>Orthus</German>
		<Italian>Orthus</Italian>
		<Spanish>Orthus</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_ORTHUS_CREATION</Tag>
		<English>Orthus, the Barbarian King, has entered the lands. This powerful hero is responsible for the deaths of more empires than anyone in creation. But the unit that defeats Orthus gains his powerful axe.</English>
		<French>Orthus, le Chef Barbare, arrive. Ce puissant héros est responsable de la chute de bien plus d'empires que quiconque. Mais celui qui vaincra Orthus gagnera sa puissante hache.</French>
		<German>Orthus der Barbarenkönig betritt das Land. Im Schatten dieses mächtigen Kriegers schleicht der Tod, denn er hat schon unzähligen Zivilisationen ein Ende gemacht. Derjenige aber, der ihn bezwingt, wird für seine Mühen mit Orthus' legendärer Axt belohnt.</German>
		<Italian>Orthus, the Barbarian King, has entered the lands. This powerful hero is responsible for the deaths of more empires than anyone in creation. But the unit that defeats Orthus gains his powerful axe.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Orthus, the Barbarian King, has entered the lands. This powerful hero is responsible for the deaths of more empires than anyone in creation. But the unit that defeats Orthus gains his powerful axe.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ORTHUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Leader of the Barbarian hordes. More civilizations have died under Orthus's legendary axe than by any other means.</English>
		<French>Le Chef des Hordes Barbares. Ce puissant héros et sa [LINK=PROMOTION_ORTHUSS_AXE]hache légendaire[\LINK] sont responsables de la chute de bien plus d'empires que quiconque.</French>
		<German>Anführer der Barbarischen Horden. Orthus' Legendäre Axt hat mehr Zivilisationen dahingerafft als andere bedeutende Waffen</German>
		<Italian>Leader of the Barbarian hordes. More civilizations have died under Orthus's legendary axe than by any other means.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Leader of the Barbarian hordes. More civilizations have died under Orthus's legendary axe than by any other means.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HEMAH</Tag>
		<English>Hemah</English>
		<French>Hemah</French>
		<German>Hemah</German>
		<Italian>Hemah</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hemah</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HEMAH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>They called him an affective dreamer. It was a horrible attunement with magic that few were cursed with; what he dreamed became real.[PARAGRAPH:1]When he was 12, Hemah saw salamanders playing on the wet stones. They were like living pieces of painted mercury, tiny dragons who had an entire primordial world underneath the dock behind his home. They hissed at Hemah, as if confidence alone would keep him from squashing them.[PARAGRAPH:1]That night the hisses came again, but lower, echoing through the small stone house. Slick painted demons broke through the walls. With forked tongues, they scuttled through the shadows and grabbed Hemah's parents, dragging them from the house.[PARAGRAPH:1]He slept through it all. In the morning, the neighbors' screams woke him. Most of the house had collapsed, only his room remained standing. The neighbor's wife was a round woman with a voice so high she seemed to squeal like the pigs she and her husband raised. She rushed in and threw herself on Hemah, checking to make sure he was okay. They told him to close his eyes before they led him out of his room, but he looked.[PARAGRAPH:1]Claw marks, blood, everything was broken...and his parents were missing. They searched everywhere for them, but couldn't find them, but Hemah knew where they were. He led the pig farmer and his wife to the river behind their home and looked beneath the dock. That's where they found Hemah's parents' broken bodies, their mouths stuffed with so much mud their throats had exploded.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since then, everyone who has gotten close to Hemah has died, not that those who don't know him do much better. One morning, he awoke to find the entire population of the small village he was passing through was simply gone. Sometimes creatures are created that live well after he awakes. People are killed, women are raped. Men are made into puppets for the night, forced to play out scenes from Hemah's subconscious over and over again.[PARAGRAPH:1]Some say Hemah isn't a mage, he only dreamt he was once and he hasn't forgotten the dream. Others wonder if the Overlords found Hemah and caused his dreams, or if Hemah dreamt of the Overlords and created them. What is known is that as dangerous as Hemah is awake, he is even more dangerous asleep.</English>
		<French>They called him an affective dreamer. It was a horrible attunement with magic that few were cursed with; what he dreamed became real.[PARAGRAPH:1]When he was 12, Hemah saw salamanders playing on the wet stones. They were like living pieces of painted mercury, tiny dragons who had an entire primordial world underneath the dock behind his home. They hissed at Hemah, as if confidence alone would keep him from squashing them.[PARAGRAPH:1]That night the hisses came again, but lower, echoing through the small stone house. Slick painted demons broke through the walls. With forked tongues, they scuttled through the shadows and grabbed Hemah's parents, dragging them from the house.[PARAGRAPH:1]He slept through it all. In the morning, the neighbors' screams woke him. Most of the house had collapsed, only his room remained standing. The neighbor's wife was a round woman with a voice so high she seemed to squeal like the pigs she and her husband raised. She rushed in and threw herself on Hemah, checking to make sure he was okay. They told him to close his eyes before they led him out of his room, but he looked.[PARAGRAPH:1]Claw marks, blood, everything was broken...and his parents were missing. They searched everywhere for them, but couldn't find them, but Hemah knew where they were. He led the pig farmer and his wife to the river behind their home and looked beneath the dock. That's where they found Hemah's parents' broken bodies, their mouths stuffed with so much mud their throats had exploded.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since then, everyone who has gotten close to Hemah has died, not that those who don't know him do much better. One morning, he awoke to find the entire population of the small village he was passing through was simply gone. Sometimes creatures are created that live well after he awakes. People are killed, women are raped. Men are made into puppets for the night, forced to play out scenes from Hemah's subconscious over and over again.[PARAGRAPH:1]Some say Hemah isn't a mage, he only dreamt he was once and he hasn't forgotten the dream. Others wonder if the Overlords found Hemah and caused his dreams, or if Hemah dreamt of the Overlords and created them. What is known is that as dangerous as Hemah is awake, he is even more dangerous asleep.</French>
		<German>Sie nannten ihn einen emotionalen Träumer. Es war eine schreckliche Verbundenheit mit Magie mit der nur sehr wenige verflucht waren, denn was er träumte wurde real.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als er 12 war, sah Hemah Salamander auf den nassen Steinen spielen. Sie sahen aus wie lebende und bemalte Quecksilberstücke, winzige Drachen die zu einer primitiven Welt unter dem Hafen hinter seinem Haus gehören. Sie zischten Hemah an, als ob seine Zufriedenheit allein ihn davon abhielt sie zu zerquetschen.[PARAGRAPH:1]In dieser Nacht ertönte das zischen erneut, aber es klang tiefer und hallte durch das steinerne Haus. Glänzend farbige Dämonen durchbrachen die Mauern. Mit gespaltenen Zungen eilten sie durch die Dunkelheit und schnappten sich Hemahs Eltern und verschleppten sie aus dem Haus.[PARAGRAPH:1]All das verschlief er. Am Morgen weckten ihn die Schreie der Nachbarn. Der größte Teil des Hauses war zusammengebrochen, nur sein Zimmer war stehen geblieben. Die Frau des Nachbarn war eine dicke Frau und hatte eine Stimme, die so hoch war, wie die Schweine die sie und ihr Mann aufzogen. Sie eilte herein und warf sich auf Hemah um zu prüfen ob es ihm gut ging. Sie sagte ihm er solle seine Augen schließen bevor er das Zimmer verließ, doch er blinzelte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Klauenabdrücke, Blut, alles war zerstört... und seine Eltern wurden vermisst. Sie suchten überall nach ihnen, doch niemand konnte sie finden. Hemah wusste wo sie waren. Er führte den Schweinezüchter und seine Frau zum Fluss hinter ihren Häusern und sahen sich unterhalb des Hafens um. Dort war es, wo sie die zerfetzten Leiber von Hemahs Eltern fanden, ihre Münder so mit Schlamm vollgestopft, dass ihr Hals zerriss.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ab da starben alle in Hemahs näheren Umfeld, doch denen die er nicht kannte, ging es nicht besser. Eines Morgens wachte er auf und stellte fest, dass die gesamte Bevölkerung des Dorfes, dass er passierte verschwunden war. Manchmal wurden Wesen erschaffen, die selbst nach seinem Erwachen noch lebten. Menschen wurden getötet, Frauen vergewaltigt. Männer wurden zu Puppen gemacht, die gezwungen wurden, Szenen aus Hemahs Unterbewusstsein immer und immer wieder nachzuspielen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Manche sagen, dass Hemah kein Magier ist, sondern nur einmal geträumt hatte einer zu sein und er diesen Traum nicht vergessen hat. Andere fragen sich, ob die Schatten Hemah fanden und seine Träume beeinflussten, oder ob Hemah von den Schatten träumte und sie so erschuf. Was bekannt ist, ist dass Hemah gefährlich ist wenn er wach ist, doch ist er noch gefährlicher wenn er schläft.</German>
		<Italian>They called him an affective dreamer. It was a horrible attunement with magic that few were cursed with; what he dreamed became real.[PARAGRAPH:1]When he was 12, Hemah saw salamanders playing on the wet stones. They were like living pieces of painted mercury, tiny dragons who had an entire primordial world underneath the dock behind his home. They hissed at Hemah, as if confidence alone would keep him from squashing them.[PARAGRAPH:1]That night the hisses came again, but lower, echoing through the small stone house. Slick painted demons broke through the walls. With forked tongues, they scuttled through the shadows and grabbed Hemah's parents, dragging them from the house.[PARAGRAPH:1]He slept through it all. In the morning, the neighbors' screams woke him. Most of the house had collapsed, only his room remained standing. The neighbor's wife was a round woman with a voice so high she seemed to squeal like the pigs she and her husband raised. She rushed in and threw herself on Hemah, checking to make sure he was okay. They told him to close his eyes before they led him out of his room, but he looked.[PARAGRAPH:1]Claw marks, blood, everything was broken...and his parents were missing. They searched everywhere for them, but couldn't find them, but Hemah knew where they were. He led the pig farmer and his wife to the river behind their home and looked beneath the dock. That's where they found Hemah's parents' broken bodies, their mouths stuffed with so much mud their throats had exploded.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since then, everyone who has gotten close to Hemah has died, not that those who don't know him do much better. One morning, he awoke to find the entire population of the small village he was passing through was simply gone. Sometimes creatures are created that live well after he awakes. People are killed, women are raped. Men are made into puppets for the night, forced to play out scenes from Hemah's subconscious over and over again.[PARAGRAPH:1]Some say Hemah isn't a mage, he only dreamt he was once and he hasn't forgotten the dream. Others wonder if the Overlords found Hemah and caused his dreams, or if Hemah dreamt of the Overlords and created them. What is known is that as dangerous as Hemah is awake, he is even more dangerous asleep.</Italian>
		<Spanish>They called him an affective dreamer. It was a horrible attunement with magic that few were cursed with; what he dreamed became real.[PARAGRAPH:1]When he was 12, Hemah saw salamanders playing on the wet stones. They were like living pieces of painted mercury, tiny dragons who had an entire primordial world underneath the dock behind his home. They hissed at Hemah, as if confidence alone would keep him from squashing them.[PARAGRAPH:1]That night the hisses came again, but lower, echoing through the small stone house. Slick painted demons broke through the walls. With forked tongues, they scuttled through the shadows and grabbed Hemah's parents, dragging them from the house.[PARAGRAPH:1]He slept through it all. In the morning, the neighbors' screams woke him. Most of the house had collapsed, only his room remained standing. The neighbor's wife was a round woman with a voice so high she seemed to squeal like the pigs she and her husband raised. She rushed in and threw herself on Hemah, checking to make sure he was okay. They told him to close his eyes before they led him out of his room, but he looked.[PARAGRAPH:1]Claw marks, blood, everything was broken...and his parents were missing. They searched everywhere for them, but couldn't find them, but Hemah knew where they were. He led the pig farmer and his wife to the river behind their home and looked beneath the dock. That's where they found Hemah's parents' broken bodies, their mouths stuffed with so much mud their throats had exploded.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since then, everyone who has gotten close to Hemah has died, not that those who don't know him do much better. One morning, he awoke to find the entire population of the small village he was passing through was simply gone. Sometimes creatures are created that live well after he awakes. People are killed, women are raped. Men are made into puppets for the night, forced to play out scenes from Hemah's subconscious over and over again.[PARAGRAPH:1]Some say Hemah isn't a mage, he only dreamt he was once and he hasn't forgotten the dream. Others wonder if the Overlords found Hemah and caused his dreams, or if Hemah dreamt of the Overlords and created them. What is known is that as dangerous as Hemah is awake, he is even more dangerous asleep.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HEMAH_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Hemah is an excellent spell caster available to Octopus Overlords followers only. He can take Archmage spells even though he only requires the Arcane Lore technology, giving you a head start on your rivals, and like other heroic spell casters, can take the powerful twincast promotion.</English>
		<French>Hemah is an excellent spell caster available to Octopus Overlords followers only. He can take Archmage spells even though he only requires the Arcane Lore technology, giving you a head start on your rivals, and like other heroic spell casters, can take the powerful twincast promotion.</French>
		<German>Hemah ist ein hervorragender Zauberer, der nur Anhängern des Schattens der Tiefe zur Verfügung steht. Ihm stehen die Zaubersprüche der Erzmagier zur Verfügung, obwohl er nur die Technologie "Hohe Lehre der Magie" als Voraussetzung mitbringt. Dies gibt dem Spieler, der ihn kontrolliert, einen Vorsprung gegenüber allen anderen Gegnern, und wie alle magischen Helden kann er auch die Zwillingszauber-Beförderung erhalten.</German>
		<Italian>Hemah is an excellent spell caster available to Octopus Overlords followers only. He can take Archmage spells even though he only requires the Arcane Lore technology, giving you a head start on your rivals, and like other heroic spell casters, can take the powerful twincast promotion.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hemah is an excellent spell caster available to Octopus Overlords followers only. He can take Archmage spells even though he only requires the Arcane Lore technology, giving you a head start on your rivals, and like other heroic spell casters, can take the powerful twincast promotion.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
