<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Created with the FfH editor by Kael -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LANUN_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Lanun</English>
		<French>lanouniste:lanouniste:lanounistes:lanounistes</French>
		<German>Lanunisch</German>
		<Italian>Lanun</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lanun</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LANUN_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Lanun</English>
		<French>Lanoun</French>
		<German>Reich der Lanun</German>
		<Italian>Lanun</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lanun</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LANUN_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Lanun</English>
		<French>Lanounistes</French>
		<German>Lanun</German>
		<Italian>Lanun</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lanun</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LANUN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Lanun gain more food from every water tile, and their ships move farther. Once on land they must rely on the same units as everyone else, but the oceans hold no obstacle to them.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the ferocious monsters were removed from the seas with the signing of the Compact, man expanded into them, and these first explorers were the ancestors of the Lanun. There were still beasts such as leviathans and giant turtles to contend with, but these were not insurmountable obstacles to the brave men on those early, leaky galleys and later triremes. Danalin offered these men his guidance, and they formed friendships with the otherwise elusive Aifons, those men most close to the sea god who lived in underwater cities. Island communities of Lanun developed, each with their own customs, but sharing most of the values of the mainland coastal Lanun cities, a love of freedom and adventure, guile, and a flexible sense of honor. When Kylorin solidified his rule of Patria and began to incorporate neighboring kingdoms into his empire, by force if needed, the distant Lanun freely pledged. They only bothered to enforce those laws they agreed with, however, and allowed fugitives to flee aboard ship and seek their fortunes on the waves. Occasionally a Lanun city would be punished for this, though their trade routes made them too valuable to make an example of. Patria soon collapsed, as wars broke out between the wicked mages and those seeking redemption for the world of men. The Lanun happily aided both sides, taking fleeing mages across the waves and then selling ships to the Patrian fire priests seeking them down. Then their world was shaken by the gods, as Bhall's rain of fire and Mulcarn's conquest brought civilizations crashing down. The seas were made more hazardous by huge icebergs that could tear a ship to pieces before being seen, and some Lanun communities were in fact completely isolated by encroaching ice. Further imperiling Lanun seafarers during this time, their priests lost all contact with Danalin, and their rituals began to behave in unexpected ways. Those Lanun crews who were still willing to brave the seas found great fame and wealth trading between distant tribes, though this often made them a target of the blizzards and many crews were never heard from again, including the ship captained by Malus which carried an artifact from Cassiel into Amurite lands.[PARAGRAPH:1] Eventually the ice receded, and the Lanun were reunited. They found they barely knew their kin, as crew in different locations had evolved quite different outlooks and values. This wasn't a problem for the Lanun, though, for each captain rules his own ship in the manner he sees fit. The sea captains are where the real power in Lanun territory lies, for captains outrank provincial governors and can conscript any person for any reason. The only authority a Lanun captain acknowledges over him is another captain to whom he has given his word, though as always the word of a Lanun is somewhat fleeting. The real problem is that the ocean is no longer quite as welcoming as it once was, and whereas they could before seek the aid the God of Water, those petitions are unheeded now, or worse, answered by strange creatures that emerge from the depths. [PARAGRAPH:1]Some Lanun captains retain the carefree spirit of their people despite this new challenge, while others, like Hannah the Irin, embrace the darker nature the seas have taken. Falamar sees himself as a dashing rogue. He tends not to kill the victims of his raids (claiming that would keep them from bringing him more loot), and he is an excellent swordsman and charming leader. Hannah is everything he isn't. She is the storm personified, temperamental and powerful. She has had entire cities razed for a perceived insult, and rules not by charm, but by fear. Which view will prove more effective in the new age is yet to be seen, but as always there is room in the Lanun for each captain to choose his or her own path.</English>
		<French>[TAB]The Lanun gain more food from every water tile, and their ships move farther. Once on land they must rely on the same units as everyone else, but the oceans hold no obstacle to them.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the ferocious monsters were removed from the seas with the signing of the Compact, man expanded into them, and these first explorers were the ancestors of the Lanun. There were still beasts such as leviathans and giant turtles to contend with, but these were not insurmountable obstacles to the brave men on those early, leaky galleys and later triremes. Danalin offered these men his guidance, and they formed friendships with the otherwise elusive Aifons, those men most close to the sea god who lived in underwater cities. Island communities of Lanun developed, each with their own customs, but sharing most of the values of the mainland coastal Lanun cities, a love of freedom and adventure, guile, and a flexible sense of honor. When Kylorin solidified his rule of Patria and began to incorporate neighboring kingdoms into his empire, by force if needed, the distant Lanun freely pledged. They only bothered to enforce those laws they agreed with, however, and allowed fugitives to flee aboard ship and seek their fortunes on the waves. Occasionally a Lanun city would be punished for this, though their trade routes made them too valuable to make an example of. Patria soon collapsed, as wars broke out between the wicked mages and those seeking redemption for the world of men. The Lanun happily aided both sides, taking fleeing mages across the waves and then selling ships to the Patrian fire priests seeking them down. Then their world was shaken by the gods, as Bhall's rain of fire and Mulcarn's conquest brought civilizations crashing down. The seas were made more hazardous by huge icebergs that could tear a ship to pieces before being seen, and some Lanun communities were in fact completely isolated by encroaching ice. Further imperiling Lanun seafarers during this time, their priests lost all contact with Danalin, and their rituals began to behave in unexpected ways. Those Lanun crews who were still willing to brave the seas found great fame and wealth trading between distant tribes, though this often made them a target of the blizzards and many crews were never heard from again, including the ship captained by Malus which carried an artifact from Cassiel into Amurite lands.[PARAGRAPH:1] Eventually the ice receded, and the Lanun were reunited. They found they barely knew their kin, as crew in different locations had evolved quite different outlooks and values. This wasn't a problem for the Lanun, though, for each captain rules his own ship in the manner he sees fit. The sea captains are where the real power in Lanun territory lies, for captains outrank provincial governors and can conscript any person for any reason. The only authority a Lanun captain acknowledges over him is another captain to whom he has given his word, though as always the word of a Lanun is somewhat fleeting. The real problem is that the ocean is no longer quite as welcoming as it once was, and whereas they could before seek the aid the God of Water, those petitions are unheeded now, or worse, answered by strange creatures that emerge from the depths. [PARAGRAPH:1]Some Lanun captains retain the carefree spirit of their people despite this new challenge, while others, like Hannah the Irin, embrace the darker nature the seas have taken. Falamar sees himself as a dashing rogue. He tends not to kill the victims of his raids (claiming that would keep them from bringing him more loot), and he is an excellent swordsman and charming leader. Hannah is everything he isn't. She is the storm personified, temperamental and powerful. She has had entire cities razed for a perceived insult, and rules not by charm, but by fear. Which view will prove more effective in the new age is yet to be seen, but as always there is room in the Lanun for each captain to choose his or her own path.</French>
		<German>[Tab]Die Lanun bekommen von Wasserfeldern mehr Nahrung, und ihre Schiffe können sich weiter bewegen. An Land müssen sie auf die selben Einheiten zurückgreifen wie die anderen Völker auch, aber der Ozean stellt für sie kein Hindernis dar.[PARAGRAPH:1]Als die wilden Monster infolge der Unterzeichnung des Vertrags von den Meeren verschwanden, begannen die Menschen, sie zu erforschen. Diese ersten Abenteurer waren die Vorfahren der Lanun. Es gab zwar immer noch Monster wie die Leviathane und Riesenschildkröten, gegen die sie sich behaupten mussten, aber dies waren keine unbezwingbaren Hindernisse für die verwegenen Kerlen der frühen, heruntergekommenen Galeeren und Triremen. Danalin bot diesem Volk seinen Schutz an, und sie schlossen Freundschaft mit den sonst eher unzugänglichen Aifons, diesem Volk, das dem Meeresgott am nächsten stand, und in Unterwasserstädten wohnte. Es entstanden Gemeinden auf verschiedenen Inseln, jede für sich eine eigene Welt, aber sie teilten doch die meisten Werte der lanunischen Küstenstädte auf dem Festland, nämlich die Liebe zu Freiheit und Abenteuern, Arglist, und ein sehr anpassbares Ehrgefühl. Als Kyrolin seinen Machtanspruch über Patria gefestigt hatte, und begann, sich die benachbarten Königreiche einzuverleiben, falls nötig auch mit Gewalt, schlossen die entfernten Lanun sich freiwillig an. Aber sie zögerten damit, die Gesetze, denen sie sich unterworfen hatten, Folge zu leisten, und erlaubten es den Verfolgten, zu flüchten und ihr Heil in den Wellen zu suchen. Gelegentlich wurde eine lanunische Stadt dafür bestraft, obwohl die Handelswege sie eigentlich viel zu wertvoll dafür machten. Bald aber brach Patria zusammen, infolge des Bürgerkriegs, der zwischen den Magiern der Dunkelheit und des Lichts ausbrach. Die Lanun unterstützten gern beide Seiten, halfen fliehenden Magiern das Meer zu überwinden, und verkauften dann Schiffe an deren Verfolger, die patrianischen Feuerpriester. Dann wurde ihre Welt von den Göttern erschüttert, als Bhalls Feuerregen und Mulcarns Angriffe die Zivilisation zusammenbrechen ließ. Die Ozeane wurden noch unsicherer, vor allem durch Eisberge, die ein Schiff in seine Einzelteile zerlegen konnten, bevor man sie überhaupt sah, und einige lanunische Gemeinschaften wurden durch die anschwellenden Eismassen vollkommen isoliert. Es gab auch noch eine zusätzliche Gefahr für die Seefahrer der Lanun während dieser Zeitt, denn ihre Priester verloren den Kontakt zu Danalin, und ihre Rituale verliefen in unerwartete Richtungen. Die Lanun, die immer noch gewillt waren, die Meere zu bezwingen, fanden großen Ruhm und Reichtum darin, mit den versprengten Stämmen zu handeln, wobei sie aber dabei oft das Opfer von Eisstürmen wurden, und von vielen Schiffen hat man nie wieder etwas gehört, auch vom Schiff des Kapitän Malus, welches ein Artefakt von Cassiel in das Land der Amuriten bringen sollte. [PARAGRAPH:1] Schließlich zog sich das Eis zurück, und die Lanun wurden wieder vereint. Aber sie mussten erkennen, dass sie so gut wie nichts mehr voneinander wussten, dass die verschiedenen Gruppen an den verschiedenen Orten andere Werte und Einstellungen entwickelt hatten. Das war allerdings kein Problem für die Lanun, weil jeder Kapitän sein Schiff in der rauen See so führt, wie er es für richtig hält. Die eigentliche Macht im Reich der Lanun lag bei den Kapitänen, die den Rang eines Provinzgouverneurs inne hatten, und jeden ohne jeden Grund zwangsrekrutieren konnten. Die einzige Person, die ein Lanun-Kapitän als höher gestellt anerkannte, war ein anderer Kapitän, dem er sein Wort gegeben hatte, auch wenn das Wort eines Lanun nicht besonders viel zählt. Das wirkliche Problem ist nun, dass der Ozean nicht mehr so ruhig und einladend ist wie einst, und die Gebete, mit denen sie früher die Hilfe des Meeresgottes erbitten konnte, bleiben nun ungehört, oder noch schlimmer, werden von seltsamen Kreaturen der Tiefe beantwortet.[PARAGRAPH:1]Einige Kapitäne bewahren sich den freizügigen Geist ihres Volkes trotz dieser neuen Herausforderung, während andere wie Hannah die Irin, die dunkle Natur der Ozeane willkommen heißen...[TAB]Falamar sieht sich selbst als ein schneidiger Schurke. Meist tötet er die Opfer seiner Raubzüge nicht (weil sie dann davon abgehalten würden, ihm noch mehr Beute zu bringen). Er ist ein ausgezeichneter Schwertkämpfer und ein galanter Verführer. Hannah ist dagegen das komplette Gegenteil dessen. Sie ist der personifizierte Sturm, temperamentvoll und stark. Sie hat schon wegen einer lächerlichen Beleidigung ganze Städte niedergerissen. Hannah herrscht nicht durch Charme, sondern durch Angst. Was sich davon in den neuen Zeiten als effektiver erweist, wird sich erst noch herausstellen müssen, aber bei den Lanun ist immer Platz für Kapitäne, die ihren eigenen Weg wählen.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]I Lanun ottengono più cibo del normale dalle caselle d'acqua, e le loro navi hanno un movimento maggiore. Una volta sulla terraferma devono affidarsi alle stesse unità delle altre civiltà, ma sugli oceani non hanno limiti.[PARAGRAPH:1]Quando i mostri feroci furono rimossi dai mari in seguito alla firma del Patto gli uomini li esplorarono, questi primi esploratori sono gli antenati dei Lanun. Vi erano ancora delle bestie feroci presenti, come i leviatani e le tartarughe giganti, con cui fare i conti, ma non erano ostacoli cosi insormontabili per quei coraggiosi uomini su quelle antiche galee e in seguito triremi. Danalin offrì a quegli uomini la sua guida e cosi strinsero amicizia con gli altrimenti elusivi Aifon, gli uomini cosi vicini al dio dei mari che vivevano in città sott'acqua. Comunità insulari di Lanun si svilupparono, ognuna con le proprie tradizioni, ma condividendo la maggior parte dei valori con le città costiere Lanun del continente, un'amore per la libertà e l'avventura, l'astuzia, e un flessibile senso dell'onore. Quando Kylorin solidificò il suo potere su Patria e iniziò a incorporare i regni vicini nel suo impero, anche con la forza se necessario, i distanti Lanun gli si unirono volontariamente. Si preoccupavano solo di far rispettare le leggi su cui erano d'accordo però, e permettevano ai fuggitivi di salire sulle loro navi e cercare fortuna sui mari. Occasionalmente una città Lanun veniva punita per questo, sebbene le loro rotte commerciali le rendevano troppo preziose per punirle in modo esemplare. Poi Patria collassò, quando la guerra scoppiò tra i malvagi maghi e coloro che cercavano la redenzione per il mondo degli uomini. I Lanun aiutarono felicemente entrambi gli schieramenti, trasportando maghi in fuga attraverso i mari e poi vendendo navi ai sacerdoti del fuoco di Patria che li stavano inseguendo. Poi il loro mondo fu scosso dagli dei mentre la pioggia di fuoco di Bhall e le conquiste di Mulcarn distruggevano intere civiltà. I mari divennerò sempre più pericolosi per via di enormi iceberg che potevano fare a pezzi una nave ancor prima di essere visti, e alcune comunità Lanun rimaserò di fatto isolate dal ghiaccio. A mettere ancor più in pericolo i navigatori Lanun fù il fatto che i loro sacerdoti perserò ogni contatto con Danalin, e i loro rituali iniziarono ad avere risultati imprevedibili. Quegli equipaggi Lanun che ancora volevano affrontare i mari trovarono grande fama e ricchezza commerciando tra tribù distanti, anche se spesso venivano colpiti dalle tempeste e cosi non si seppe più nulla di molti di loro, incluso l'equipaggio della nave capitanata da Malus, che trasportava un'artefatto da Cassiel alle terre degli Amurite.[PARAGRAPH:1] Alla fine il ghiaccio sparì, e i Lanun furono riuniti. Scoprirono di essere parecchio diversi, in quanto ogni equipaggio si era sviluppato in ambienti differenti ognuno con diversi aspetti e valori. Questo non era un problema per i Lanun, in quanto ogni capitano governa la sua nave come meglio preferisce. I capitani del mare sono coloro che detengono veramente il potere nei territori Lanun, visto che i capitani sono di grado superiore ai governatori provinciali e possono coscrivere chiunque per qualsiasi ragione. L'unica autorità che un capitano Lanun riconosce sopra la sua è quella di un'altro capitano a cui ha dato la sua parola, anche se come sempre la parola di un Lanun è alquanto fugace. Il vero problema è che l'oceano non è più accogliente come un tempo, e mentre prima potevano chiedere aiuto al Dio dell'Acqua, ora quelle richeste rimangono inascoltate, o peggio si ottiene risposta da strane creature che emergono dalle profondità. [PARAGRAPH:1]Alcuni capitani Lanun conservano lo spirito spensierato del loro popolo nonostante questa nuova sfida, mentre altri, come Hannah la Irin, accolgono la natura più oscura che i mari stanno prendendo. Falamar si vede come un furfante affascinante. Tende a non uccidere le vittime delle sue incursioni (sostenendo che farlo gli impedirebbe di portargli altro bottino), ed è un eccellente spadaccino e un leader affascinante. Hannah è tutto quello che lui non è. Lei è la tempesta personificata, temperamentale e potente. Ha fatto radere al suolo intere città per via di un insulto da lei presunto, e comanda non attraverso il fascino ma attraverso la paura. Che ritiene si dimostrerà più efficace nella nuova era che deve arrivare, ma come sempre c'è sempre spazio tra i Lanun per far scegliere a ogni capitano la sua strada.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Lanun gain more food from every water tile, and their ships move farther. Once on land they must rely on the same units as everyone else, but the oceans hold no obstacle to them.[PARAGRAPH:1]As the ferocious monsters were removed from the seas with the signing of the Compact, man expanded into them, and these first explorers were the ancestors of the Lanun. There were still beasts such as leviathans and giant turtles to contend with, but these were not insurmountable obstacles to the brave men on those early, leaky galleys and later triremes. Danalin offered these men his guidance, and they formed friendships with the otherwise elusive Aifons, those men most close to the sea god who lived in underwater cities. Island communities of Lanun developed, each with their own customs, but sharing most of the values of the mainland coastal Lanun cities, a love of freedom and adventure, guile, and a flexible sense of honor. When Kylorin solidified his rule of Patria and began to incorporate neighboring kingdoms into his empire, by force if needed, the distant Lanun freely pledged. They only bothered to enforce those laws they agreed with, however, and allowed fugitives to flee aboard ship and seek their fortunes on the waves. Occasionally a Lanun city would be punished for this, though their trade routes made them too valuable to make an example of. Patria soon collapsed, as wars broke out between the wicked mages and those seeking redemption for the world of men. The Lanun happily aided both sides, taking fleeing mages across the waves and then selling ships to the Patrian fire priests seeking them down. Then their world was shaken by the gods, as Bhall's rain of fire and Mulcarn's conquest brought civilizations crashing down. The seas were made more hazardous by huge icebergs that could tear a ship to pieces before being seen, and some Lanun communities were in fact completely isolated by encroaching ice. Further imperiling Lanun seafarers during this time, their priests lost all contact with Danalin, and their rituals began to behave in unexpected ways. Those Lanun crews who were still willing to brave the seas found great fame and wealth trading between distant tribes, though this often made them a target of the blizzards and many crews were never heard from again, including the ship captained by Malus which carried an artifact from Cassiel into Amurite lands.[PARAGRAPH:1] Eventually the ice receded, and the Lanun were reunited. They found they barely knew their kin, as crew in different locations had evolved quite different outlooks and values. This wasn't a problem for the Lanun, though, for each captain rules his own ship in the manner he sees fit. The sea captains are where the real power in Lanun territory lies, for captains outrank provincial governors and can conscript any person for any reason. The only authority a Lanun captain acknowledges over him is another captain to whom he has given his word, though as always the word of a Lanun is somewhat fleeting. The real problem is that the ocean is no longer quite as welcoming as it once was, and whereas they could before seek the aid the God of Water, those petitions are unheeded now, or worse, answered by strange creatures that emerge from the depths. [PARAGRAPH:1]Some Lanun captains retain the carefree spirit of their people despite this new challenge, while others, like Hannah the Irin, embrace the darker nature the seas have taken. Falamar sees himself as a dashing rogue. He tends not to kill the victims of his raids (claiming that would keep them from bringing him more loot), and he is an excellent swordsman and charming leader. Hannah is everything he isn't. She is the storm personified, temperamental and powerful. She has had entire cities razed for a perceived insult, and rules not by charm, but by fear. Which view will prove more effective in the new age is yet to be seen, but as always there is room in the Lanun for each captain to choose his or her own path.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_LANUN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategy: The Lanun are a sea people, capable of dominating the seas in any map with water present. They gain extra food from sea tiles, losing food from farms in exchange. The Lanun capital gets increased ship production, so it better be built on the coast. Though they're somewhat more oriented towards warmongering, they also have viable hybrid strategies. Led by Falamar they'll grow quickly thanks to rapid border expansion and cheaper lighthouses. Led by Hannah coastal tiles with their three food and commerce will be incredibly profitable for them, not to mention their extra income from pillaging.</English>
		<French>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Les Lanounistes sont le peuple des mers, capable de dominer les océans sur toute carte où l'eau est présente. Ils gagnent un bonus en nourriture pour les cases d'eau, perdant de la nourriture des fermes en contre-partie. La capitale lanouniste a un bonus pour la production de navires, de fait il est conseillé de la fonder sur une côte. Bien qu'ils soient plutôt orientés vers un style de jeu belliqueux, ils sont aussi viables avec des stratégies hybrides.[NEWLINE]Conduits par Falamar, ils grandiront rapidement grâce à une rapide extension des frontières et des phares moins chers.[NEWLINE]Dirigés par Hannah, les cases de côtes avec trois[ICON_FOOD] et trois [ICON_COMMERCE] leur seront incroyablement profitables, sans compter les revenus supplémentaires du pillage.</French>
		<German>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategie: Die Lanun sind ein Seevolk, fähig die Meere in jeder Karte mit Wasser zu dominieren. Sie erlangen zusätzliche Nahrung von Meeresfeldern, und dafür weniger von Farmen. Die Hauptstadt der Lanun hat eine höhere Produktionsrate bei Schiffen, darum sollte sie besser an einer Küste gebaut werden. Obwohl sie etwas mehr zu Kriegstreiberei tendieren, machen sie dennoch praktikable gemischte Strategien möglich. Wenn sie von Falamar geführt werden, werden sie sich schnell vermehren, dank schnellerer Grenzerweiterung und billigeren Leuchttürmen. Wenn sie von Hannah geführt werden, werden Küstenfelder mit ihren drei Einheiten Nahrung und Gold für sie unglaublich profitabel sein, nicht zu vergessen ihr zusätzliches Einkommen bei Plünderungen.</German>
		<Italian>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Strategia: I Lanun sono il popolo del mare, capaci di dominare i mari in ogni mappa che li ha. Ottengono più cibo del normale dalle casella d'acqua, ottenendone meno dalle fattorie in cambio. La capitale Lanun ha un bonus alla produzione di navi, pertanto è meglio fondarla sulla costa. Sebbene siano leggermente più orientati a guerreggiare, possono anche percorrere strategie ibride. Guidati da Falamar crescono in fretta grazie ad una espansione rapida dei confini e da fari più economici. Guidati da Hannah le caselle costiere con i tre di cibo e di commercio sono incredibilmente remunerative per loro, senza parlare del loro guadagno extra dal saccheggio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Estrategia: Los Lanun son gente de mar, capaces de dominar los mares en cualquier mapa con agua presente. Ganan comida extra de las casillas de agua, y tienen penalización de comida de las granjas. La capital Lanun tiene una producción de navíos aumentada, por lo que es más conveniente levantarla en la costa. Aunque de alguna forma están más orientados al belicismo, también disponen de estrategias híbridas válidas. Dirigidos por Falamar crecerán rápido gracias a su rápida expansión de bordes y baratos faros. Liderados por Hannah las casillas de costa serán increiblemente beneficiosas con sus tres de comida y comercio, por no mencionar su ingresos extra por pillaje.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_BLACKHEART</Tag>
		<English>Captain Blackheart</English>
		<French>Capitaine C&#156;urnoir</French>
		<German>Kapitän Schwarzherz</German>
		<Italian>Capitan Blackheart</Italian>
		<Spanish>Captain Blackheart</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_BLACKHEART_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Blackheart's terms had been clear enough. The town would surrender half of its treasury, or every man, woman, and child in it would be put to the sword, and every building looted and razed to the ground. The town could not hope to resist his fleet; why did they dare resist? He had proven his willingness to slaughter those who did not submit to his demands time and time again. Those who surrendered were spared, those who did not were butchered. This was the way of the world. Nobody had stood before Blackheart; he chose his targets well, and his men were unmatched in ferocity, willing to kill even mewling babes without the slightest hesitation.
			What could this town possibly have to oppose him? He said, "Alright men, we'll have the people of this wretched town for our pleasure by nightfall! Open fire, and let the legend of Blackheart spread once more!" The cannons roared, the walls began to crumble... and then, one of his henchmen, the one who'd drawn the short straw, appeared before him. "Cap'n, trouble!" The man pointed out to sea, where a fleet was approaching. A massive fleet, openly flying the Lanun flag. Only one person on all of Erebus could possibly assemble such a fleet.
			"Hannah the Irin!" a lookout screamed, confirming what Blackheart had feared. Falamar, that dandy, was too busy saving the world, but Hannah... she would not tolerate anyone on the open seas being feared more than she. Of course, if Hannah was upon him...
			He screamed, "Man the harpoons! Ready your blades! We'll be matching steel with krakens and the undead! Hannah won't be taking prisoners, unless they're to be sacrificed! Oh, and get that accursed cultist; we'll need him!" As he finished speaking, a massive shape arose from the depths. Whose Kraken was it? As he looked closer, he realized it was neither; two of them, one presumably his, were locked in combat. He couldn't tell them apart, and decided to let them have at each other in peace.
			The waves began to heave and writhe as Hannah's cultists began calling forth the powers of the Overlords. Blackheart's man clambered up from below decks, took one look at the situation, and immediately began to do all he could to counter their incantations. Of course, one rum-scented cultist stood no chance of defeating whatever hardened priests Hannah had rounded up to remove Blackheart from the seas. Waves as tall as a man emmentated from Hannah's flagship and threatened to capsize Blackheart's; he knew they'd have been worse if he didn't have a cultist of his own defending him.
			He heard rattling below decks, and a man, some new recruit, came up screaming, "The dead! They're tearing our ship apart from underneath us!" That wretched woman... he knew he couldn't win this fight. His fleet was being decimated, ship by ship, torn apart by Stygian Guard, assaulted by boarding parties, or shattered by the ocean's unnatural ferocity. He watched as his cultist leapt overboard to join his gods. Or...
			Blackheart followed the cultist, diving into the water and catching one of the rear tentacles of the kraken. His kraken. He desperately tried to hold his breath, hoping the cultist's plan involved seeing land. But he couldn't, and soon water filled his lungs...
			He awoke upon a strange shore, his cultist peering over him. "You survived," he muttered. "Clearly the overlords favor you." Blackheart crawled to his feet, and said, "Aye." He took a good look around himself; he appeared to be on an uninhabited island, one of the many across the great seas of Erebus. "So," he said. "I got me a sword, a cultist, a kraken, and an island. Now what?" It was then he realized what he needed to do. He had a sword a cultist, a kraken and an island, and that was all he needed to rebuild, to get vengeance upon that wretched Hannah of Irin, and to take his rightful place as champion of the Overlords. "If ye see any boats," he instructed the cultist, "crash 'em right into this island. We'll be needing the lumber. And the passengers... ye know how to do the drowning ritual, aye?" </English>
		<French>Blackheart's terms had been clear enough. The town would surrender half of its treasury, or every man, woman, and child in it would be put to the sword, and every building looted and razed to the ground. The town could not hope to resist his fleet; why did they dare resist? He had proven his willingness to slaughter those who did not submit to his demands time and time again. Those who surrendered were spared, those who did not were butchered. This was the way of the world. Nobody had stood before Blackheart; he chose his targets well, and his men were unmatched in ferocity, willing to kill even mewling babes without the slightest hesitation.
			What could this town possibly have to oppose him? He said, "Alright men, we'll have the people of this wretched town for our pleasure by nightfall! Open fire, and let the legend of Blackheart spread once more!" The cannons roared, the walls began to crumble... and then, one of his henchmen, the one who'd drawn the short straw, appeared before him. "Cap'n, trouble!" The man pointed out to sea, where a fleet was approaching. A massive fleet, openly flying the Lanun flag. Only one person on all of Erebus could possibly assemble such a fleet.
			"Hannah the Irin!" a lookout screamed, confirming what Blackheart had feared. Falamar, that dandy, was too busy saving the world, but Hannah... she would not tolerate anyone on the open seas being feared more than she. Of course, if Hannah was upon him...
			He screamed, "Man the harpoons! Ready your blades! We'll be matching steel with krakens and the undead! Hannah won't be taking prisoners, unless they're to be sacrificed! Oh, and get that accursed cultist; we'll need him!" As he finished speaking, a massive shape arose from the depths. Whose Kraken was it? As he looked closer, he realized it was neither; two of them, one presumably his, were locked in combat. He couldn't tell them apart, and decided to let them have at each other in peace.
			The waves began to heave and writhe as Hannah's cultists began calling forth the powers of the Overlords. Blackheart's man clambered up from below decks, took one look at the situation, and immediately began to do all he could to counter their incantations. Of course, one rum-scented cultist stood no chance of defeating whatever hardened priests Hannah had rounded up to remove Blackheart from the seas. Waves as tall as a man emmentated from Hannah's flagship and threatened to capsize Blackheart's; he knew they'd have been worse if he didn't have a cultist of his own defending him.
			He heard rattling below decks, and a man, some new recruit, came up screaming, "The dead! They're tearing our ship apart from underneath us!" That wretched woman... he knew he couldn't win this fight. His fleet was being decimated, ship by ship, torn apart by Stygian Guard, assaulted by boarding parties, or shattered by the ocean's unnatural ferocity. He watched as his cultist leapt overboard to join his gods. Or...
			Blackheart followed the cultist, diving into the water and catching one of the rear tentacles of the kraken. His kraken. He desperately tried to hold his breath, hoping the cultist's plan involved seeing land. But he couldn't, and soon water filled his lungs...
			He awoke upon a strange shore, his cultist peering over him. "You survived," he muttered. "Clearly the overlords favor you." Blackheart crawled to his feet, and said, "aye." He took a good look around himself; he appeared to be on an uninhabited island, one of the many across the great seas of Erebus. "So," he said. "I got me a sword, a cultist, a kraken, and an island. Now what?" It was then he realized what he needed to do. He had a sword a cultist, a kraken and an island, and that was all he needed to rebuild, to get vengeance upon that wretched Hannah of Irin, and to take his rightful place as champion of the Overlords. "If ye see any boats," he instructed the cultist, "crash 'em right into this island. We'll be needing the lumber. And the passengers... ye know how to do the drowning ritual, aye?" </French>
		<German>Blackheart's terms had been clear enough. The town would surrender half of its treasury, or every man, woman, and child in it would be put to the sword, and every building looted and razed to the ground. The town could not hope to resist his fleet; why did they dare resist? He had proven his willingness to slaughter those who did not submit to his demands time and time again. Those who surrendered were spared, those who did not were butchered. This was the way of the world. Nobody had stood before Blackheart; he chose his targets well, and his men were unmatched in ferocity, willing to kill even mewling babes without the slightest hesitation.
			What could this town possibly have to oppose him? He said, "Alright men, we'll have the people of this wretched town for our pleasure by nightfall! Open fire, and let the legend of Blackheart spread once more!" The cannons roared, the walls began to crumble... and then, one of his henchmen, the one who'd drawn the short straw, appeared before him. "Cap'n, trouble!" The man pointed out to sea, where a fleet was approaching. A massive fleet, openly flying the Lanun flag. Only one person on all of Erebus could possibly assemble such a fleet.
			"Hannah the Irin!" a lookout screamed, confirming what Blackheart had feared. Falamar, that dandy, was too busy saving the world, but Hannah... she would not tolerate anyone on the open seas being feared more than she. Of course, if Hannah was upon him...
			He screamed, "Man the harpoons! Ready your blades! We'll be matching steel with krakens and the undead! Hannah won't be taking prisoners, unless they're to be sacrificed! Oh, and get that accursed cultist; we'll need him!" As he finished speaking, a massive shape arose from the depths. Whose Kraken was it? As he looked closer, he realized it was neither; two of them, one presumably his, were locked in combat. He couldn't tell them apart, and decided to let them have at each other in peace.
			The waves began to heave and writhe as Hannah's cultists began calling forth the powers of the Overlords. Blackheart's man clambered up from below decks, took one look at the situation, and immediately began to do all he could to counter their incantations. Of course, one rum-scented cultist stood no chance of defeating whatever hardened priests Hannah had rounded up to remove Blackheart from the seas. Waves as tall as a man emmentated from Hannah's flagship and threatened to capsize Blackheart's; he knew they'd have been worse if he didn't have a cultist of his own defending him.
			He heard rattling below decks, and a man, some new recruit, came up screaming, "The dead! They're tearing our ship apart from underneath us!" That wretched woman... he knew he couldn't win this fight. His fleet was being decimated, ship by ship, torn apart by Stygian Guard, assaulted by boarding parties, or shattered by the ocean's unnatural ferocity. He watched as his cultist leapt overboard to join his gods. Or...
			Blackheart followed the cultist, diving into the water and catching one of the rear tentacles of the kraken. His kraken. He desperately tried to hold his breath, hoping the cultist's plan involved seeing land. But he couldn't, and soon water filled his lungs...
			He awoke upon a strange shore, his cultist peering over him. "You survived," he muttered. "Clearly the overlords favor you." Blackheart crawled to his feet, and said, "aye." He took a good look around himself; he appeared to be on an uninhabited island, one of the many across the great seas of Erebus. "So," he said. "I got me a sword, a cultist, a kraken, and an island. Now what?" It was then he realized what he needed to do. He had a sword a cultist, a kraken and an island, and that was all he needed to rebuild, to get vengeance upon that wretched Hannah of Irin, and to take his rightful place as champion of the Overlords. "If ye see any boats," he instructed the cultist, "crash 'em right into this island. We'll be needing the lumber. And the passengers... ye know how to do the drowning ritual, aye?" </German>
		<Italian>I termini di Blackheart erano stati abbastanza chiari. La città avrebbe consegnato metà della sua tesoreria, altrimenti ogni uomo, donna e bambino al suo interno sarebbe stato passato a fil di spada, ed ogni edificio sarebbe stato saccheggiato e raso al suolo. La città non poteva sperare di resistere alla sua flotta; perche continuavano a resistergli? Aveva dimostrato la sua disponibilità a massacrare chi non acconsentiva alle sue richieste più e più volte. Coloro che si arrendevano venivano risparmiati, coloro che non lo facevano venivano uccisi. Cosi andava il mondo. Nessuno si era mai opposto a Blackheart; sceglieva bene i suoi bersagli, e i suoi uomini erano senza rivali per ferocia, disposti ad uccidere perfino neonati senza alcuna esitazione.
			Cosa poteva avere questa cittadina per opporsi? Disse, "Va bene, uomini, avremo la popolazione di questa misera cittadina a nostra disposizione per il calare della notte! Aprite il fuoco, e lasciate che la leggenda di Blackheart si sparga un'altra volta!" I cannoni tuonarono, e le mura iniziarono a crollare... e poi, uno dei suoi uomini, quello che aveva estratto la pagliuzza più corta, gli si parò davanti. "Capitano, problemi!" L'uomo disse indicando il mare, da dove si stava avvicinando una flotta. Una flotta enorme, che mostrava apertamente la bandiera Lanun. Solo una persona su tutto Erebus poteva radunare una tale flotta.
			"Hannah la Irin!" una vedetta urlò, confermando quello che Blackheart temeva. Falamar, quel damerino, era troppo occupato a salvare il mondo, ma Hannah... lei non avrebbe mai tollerato che qualcuno fosse più temuto di lei sul mare aperto. Ovviamente, se Hannah gli era addosso...
			Lui urlò, "Usate gli arpioni! Preparate le lame! Affronteremo kraken e non morti con l'acciaio! Hannah non farà prigionieri, se non per sacrificarli in seguito! Oh, e prendete quel maledetto cultista; avremo bisogno di lui!" Mentre finiva di parlare, una enorme sagoma sorse dalle profondità. Di chi era quel Kraken? Guardando attentamente capì che non era solo uno; erano due, presumibilmente uno era suo, che stavano combattendo. Non riusciva a distinguerli, e decise di lasciarli stare in pace.
			Le onde iniziarono a ingrossarsi quando i cultisti di Hannah iniziarono a invocare il potere dei Padroni. L'uomo di Blackheart salì sul ponte, dette uno sguardo alla situazione e si mise subito a fare quello che poteva per contrastare le loro invocazioni. Ovviamente un cultista che puzzava di rum non poteva sperare di sconfiggere alcun sacerdote esperto che Hannah aveva radunato per eliminare Blackheart dai mari. Onde alte quanto un'uomo venivano emanate dalla ammiraglia di Hannah che rischiavano di far capovolgere quella di Blackheart; lui sapeva che sarebbe stato peggio se non avesse avuto un cultista dalla sua a difenderlo.
			Sentii anche dei rumori sotto coperta, e un'uomo ed alcune nuove reclute salirono sul ponte urlando, "I morti! Stanno facendo a pezzi la nostra nave da sotto!" Quella maledetta donna... lui sapeva che non poteva vincere questo combattimento. La sua flotta stava venendo decimata, nave dopo nave, fatte a pezzi dalla Guardia Stigea, assalite da squadre d'abbordaggio, o distrutte dalla ferocia innaturale dell'oceano. Vide il suo cultista saltare fuori bordo per unirsi ai suoi dei. Oppure...
			Blackheart seguì il cultista, tuffandosi in acqua e afferrando uno dei tentacoli posteriori del kraken. Il suo kraken. Cercò disperatamente di trattenere il fiato, sperando che il piano del cultista comprendesse raggiungere la terraferma. Ma non ci riuscì, e poco dopo l'acqua riempì i suoi polmoni...
			Si svegliò su una strana spiaggia, con il suo cultista che lo scrutava da sopra di lui. "Sei sopravvissuto," borbottò. "Chiaramente i Padroni ti sono favorevoli." Blackheart si rimise in piedi e disse, "già". Poi diede un'occhiata in giro; sembrava essere su un'isola disabitata, una delle tante sparse per i grandi mari di Erebus. "Quindi," disse. "Ho una spada, un cultista, un kraken e un'isola. Che cosa faccio ora?" A quel punto realizzò che cosa avrebbe dovuto fare. Aveva una spada, un cultista, un kraken e un'isola e quello era tutto ciò di cui aveva bisogno per ricostruire, per ottenere vendetta su quella maledetta Hannah la Irin, e prendere il suo posto di diritto come campione dei Padroni. "Se vedi qualsiasi barca," istruì il cultista, "falla schiantare su quest'isola. Avremo bisogno del legno. E i passeggeri... tu sai come eseguire il rituale d'affogamento, vero?" </Italian>
		<Spanish>Blackheart's terms had been clear enough. The town would surrender half of its treasury, or every man, woman, and child in it would be put to the sword, and every building looted and razed to the ground. The town could not hope to resist his fleet; why did they dare resist? He had proven his willingness to slaughter those who did not submit to his demands time and time again. Those who surrendered were spared, those who did not were butchered. This was the way of the world. Nobody had stood before Blackheart; he chose his targets well, and his men were unmatched in ferocity, willing to kill even mewling babes without the slightest hesitation.
			What could this town possibly have to oppose him? He said, "Alright men, we'll have the people of this wretched town for our pleasure by nightfall! Open fire, and let the legend of Blackheart spread once more!" The cannons roared, the walls began to crumble... and then, one of his henchmen, the one who'd drawn the short straw, appeared before him. "Cap'n, trouble!" The man pointed out to sea, where a fleet was approaching. A massive fleet, openly flying the Lanun flag. Only one person on all of Erebus could possibly assemble such a fleet.
			"Hannah the Irin!" a lookout screamed, confirming what Blackheart had feared. Falamar, that dandy, was too busy saving the world, but Hannah... she would not tolerate anyone on the open seas being feared more than she. Of course, if Hannah was upon him...
			He screamed, "Man the harpoons! Ready your blades! We'll be matching steel with krakens and the undead! Hannah won't be taking prisoners, unless they're to be sacrificed! Oh, and get that accursed cultist; we'll need him!" As he finished speaking, a massive shape arose from the depths. Whose Kraken was it? As he looked closer, he realized it was neither; two of them, one presumably his, were locked in combat. He couldn't tell them apart, and decided to let them have at each other in peace.
			The waves began to heave and writhe as Hannah's cultists began calling forth the powers of the Overlords. Blackheart's man clambered up from below decks, took one look at the situation, and immediately began to do all he could to counter their incantations. Of course, one rum-scented cultist stood no chance of defeating whatever hardened priests Hannah had rounded up to remove Blackheart from the seas. Waves as tall as a man emmentated from Hannah's flagship and threatened to capsize Blackheart's; he knew they'd have been worse if he didn't have a cultist of his own defending him.
			He heard rattling below decks, and a man, some new recruit, came up screaming, "The dead! They're tearing our ship apart from underneath us!" That wretched woman... he knew he couldn't win this fight. His fleet was being decimated, ship by ship, torn apart by Stygian Guard, assaulted by boarding parties, or shattered by the ocean's unnatural ferocity. He watched as his cultist leapt overboard to join his gods. Or...
			Blackheart followed the cultist, diving into the water and catching one of the rear tentacles of the kraken. His kraken. He desperately tried to hold his breath, hoping the cultist's plan involved seeing land. But he couldn't, and soon water filled his lungs...
			He awoke upon a strange shore, his cultist peering over him. "You survived," he muttered. "Clearly the overlords favor you." Blackheart crawled to his feet, and said, "aye." He took a good look around himself; he appeared to be on an uninhabited island, one of the many across the great seas of Erebus. "So," he said. "I got me a sword, a cultist, a kraken, and an island. Now what?" It was then he realized what he needed to do. He had a sword a cultist, a kraken and an island, and that was all he needed to rebuild, to get vengeance upon that wretched Hannah of Irin, and to take his rightful place as champion of the Overlords. "If ye see any boats," he instructed the cultist, "crash 'em right into this island. We'll be needing the lumber. And the passengers... ye know how to do the drowning ritual, aye?" </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CASIN</Tag>
		<English>Casin Loveless</English>
		<French>Casin Loveless</French>
		<German>Casin Lieblos</German>
		<Italian>Casin Loveless</Italian>
		<Spanish>Casin Loveless</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CASIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Most men would have been terrified in his position, but Septimus was merely annoyed. His ship had been overtaken by some Lanun raiders, who had easily overpowered him and his men and were now dividing up the treasure. One Lanun, a large man who seemed to assume he could intimidate Septimus with his size, glared down at Septimus and said, "You. The captain wants to see you." He motioned for Septimus to follow him, and having no better alternative, Septimus did.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He wasn't sure what he'd expected the Captain's quarters to look like; aside from the bed, what he saw seemed more like a library. The centerpiece of the room was a large desk, but books were everywhere, scattered about with no immediately obvious system. He grabbed one at random; it was Cassiel's "Discourse on Gods and Worship in the Age of Magic." This was, in his Bannor homelands, an incredibly heretical book, but most who read it often confessed they didn't really understand it anyways. He opened it to a bookmarked page and found a description of the changes to the rites of the Illian people in the time leading up to the Age of Ice. It was terribly dry, although another hand had underlined certain passages, and written scholarly-looking notes in the side margins.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A red-headed woman entered the room, and sat down at the desk, motioning for Septimus to take a seat. She carried herself with authority and intellect, and her large henchman shrank in her presence. She was clearly the captain, but Septimus couldn't resist a cheap jibe. He remained standing, and said, "seems whoever runs this boat has a fine taste in whores." She grinned. "Whore? Maybe according to some, but I'm also the captain, and capable of gutting you like a fish six different ways." She pulled out a knife and caressed it for emphasis. Septimus noticed she didn't really seem offended by being called a whore; what sort of strange woman was she?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Quite the library, Miss..." "Loveless. Casin Loveless." "Quite the library, Miss Loveless. Did you know you can read these things, instead of selling or burning them?" She grinned. "Very much so; reading is one of my favorite hobbies. Gutting idiots is another. And the third..." Septimus cut her off with his guess: "Bedding men? Women? Both?" "Men. But only interesting ones. Falamar was fun for a while, but he couldn't quite keep up with me, mentally or physically. I could have forgiven one, but not both. Charadon had natural gifts, but not much else. Now, Amelanchier..." "Miss Loveless, I think I've heard enough on that topic. Care to tell me why I'm here? And if it's what I think it is, you might as well toss me to the sharks now. I am sure the number of interesting men you've bedded is matched only by the number of interesting, and no doubt painful, diseases you've collected." "I have an excellent healer, Dural trained, who makes certain that's not a problem. Tolerating her pitiable attempts at flirting with me is a small price to pay. But that isn't why you're here. I've been following your exploits for quite a while, Captain Septimus, so I'm not going to waste effort trying to seduce you. I have more than enough evidence that you prefer to share your bed with men."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Septimus fell into the seat Casin had pulled out for him, and stared at her with horror. Casin lay back in her chair, and said, "Your arrogant confidence seems to have disappeared. Excellent. Now maybe you'll shut up and listen. Your hobbies aside, Captain Septimus, my records make it quite clear you are among the most courageous and, more importantly, competent men to ever sail the seas of Erebus. I've been hunting you down, specifically, to make you an offer. I've already sent anonymous but irrefutable evidence of your activities to the Bannor admiralty. Now, you have three choices. I can drop you off in Bannor lands, and trust you to their gentle mercies. Alternatively, I can kill you, far more quickly and painlessly than your Bannor kin would. One stroke of my blade, and you go forth to the afterlife. You're a good and noble man; if you're lucky, Sirona or Lugus will take you in. If you're not, you could end up haunted for eternity by what you consider to be your sins in Arwan's realm. Some clever demon might even take advantage of your meaningless guilt and drag you to Hell." Septimus nodded, still recovering from shock. "So, Septimus, care to guess your third option?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He said, "I join your crew, and in doing so, betray my fellow Bannor, betray my god, betray everything I ever held dear." Casin said, "nay. Your nation betrayed you long ago. As for the 'everything I ever held dear,' I'll have you know, you'll realize in time what you truly hold dear among my crew. I can offer you the freedom to be your own man. The opprotunity to be judged for your actions, not the insane whims of a merciless priesthood." "They serve Junil's will; I would sooner face their punishment than betray the God of Order." Casin opened her desk, and slid a thick tome to Septimus. "It's 'The Great Bannor Corruption;' a compilation of essays by Dural, Elohim, Kuriotate, and Malakim theologians which demonstrates, quite well in my opinion, that the Bannor priesthood has strayed worryingly far from the true nature of the Order, possibly due to corruption by Mammon, Aeron, or perhaps just the human ambition to rule over one's fellows." "I've heard of this book. It's been called heresy of the greatest degree, and is said to make a mockery of everything the Order holds dear." Casin rolled her eyes, then said, "well, it's not my personal copy, just in case you fail to resist the temptation to burn it or carry it into the watery depths. Just a bit of light reading for you to peruse while you consider my little offer." Septimus left, holding the tome as though he expected it to bite him.Once Septimus had left, the man who'd escorted Septimus in asked Loveless, "weren't you complaining that book was... how'd you put it?" "I believe I said the book was built on theologically shaky grounds, and that any well trained Bannor Confessor could probably pen a thorough refutation if they bothered to read the damn thing instead of torching it on sight. Although, who knows, maybe the book's authors could refute the Bannor refutations, if they got the chance. But, fascinating as they are, the Order's internal divisions do not really concern me. Septimus is not a Confessor, just a tormented soul who'd make a great new First Mate. Now then, tell the crew we're sailing to Aylesbury. Falamar and Arturus are having a diplomatic summit. I can never resist a chance to mess with Falamar's head, and I'm wondering if it's true what they say about dwarves." "What do they say about dwarves?" She pulled out a text on comparative biology and said, "evidently, not everything's shorter."</English>
		<French>Most men would have been terrified in his position, but Septimus was merely annoyed. His ship had been overtaken by some Lanun raiders, who had easily overpowered him and his men and were now dividing up the treasure. One Lanun, a large man who seemed to assume he could intimidate Septimus with his size, glared down at Septimus and said, "You. The captain wants to see you." He motioned for Septimus to follow him, and having no better alternative, Septimus did.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He wasn't sure what he'd expected the Captain's quarters to look like; aside from the bed, what he saw seemed more like a library. The centerpiece of the room was a large desk, but books were everywhere, scattered about with no immediately obvious system. He grabbed one at random; it was Cassiel's "Discourse on Gods and Worship in the Age of Magic." This was, in his Bannor homelands, an incredibly heretical book, but most who read it often confessed they didn't really understand it anyways. He opened it to a bookmarked page and found a description of the changes to the rites of the Illian people in the time leading up to the Age of Ice. It was terribly dry, although another hand had underlined certain passages, and written scholarly-looking notes in the side margins.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A red-headed woman entered the room, and sat down at the desk, motioning for Septimus to take a seat. She carried herself with authority and intellect, and her large henchman shrank in her presence. She was clearly the captain, but Septimus couldn't resist a cheap jibe. He remained standing, and said, "seems whoever runs this boat has a fine taste in whores." She grinned. "Whore? Maybe according to some, but I'm also the captain, and capable of gutting you like a fish six different ways." She pulled out a knife and caressed it for emphasis. Septimus noticed she didn't really seem offended by being called a whore; what sort of strange woman was she?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Quite the library, Miss..." "Loveless. Casin Loveless." "Quite the library, Miss Loveless. Did you know you can read these things, instead of selling or burning them?" She grinned. "Very much so; reading is one of my favorite hobbies. Gutting idiots is another. And the third..." Septimus cut her off with his guess: "Bedding men? Women? Both?" "Men. But only interesting ones. Falamar was fun for a while, but he couldn't quite keep up with me, mentally or physically. I could have forgiven one, but not both. Charadon had natural gifts, but not much else. Now, Amelanchier..." "Miss Loveless, I think I've heard enough on that topic. Care to tell me why I'm here? And if it's what I think it is, you might as well toss me to the sharks now. I am sure the number of interesting men you've bedded is matched only by the number of interesting, and no doubt painful, diseases you've collected." "I have an excellent healer, Dural trained, who makes certain that's not a problem. Tolerating her pitiable attempts at flirting with me is a small price to pay. But that isn't why you're here. I've been following your exploits for quite a while, Captain Septimus, so I'm not going to waste effort trying to seduce you. I have more than enough evidence that you prefer to share your bed with men."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Septimus fell into the seat Casin had pulled out for him, and stared at her with horror. Casin lay back in her chair, and said, "Your arrogant confidence seems to have disappeared. Excellent. Now maybe you'll shut up and listen. Your hobbies aside, Captain Septimus, my records make it quite clear you are among the most courageous and, more importantly, competent men to ever sail the seas of Erebus. I've been hunting you down, specifically, to make you an offer. I've already sent anonymous but irrefutable evidence of your activities to the Bannor admiralty. Now, you have three choices. I can drop you off in Bannor lands, and trust you to their gentle mercies. Alternatively, I can kill you, far more quickly and painlessly than your Bannor kin would. One stroke of my blade, and you go forth to the afterlife. You're a good and noble man; if you're lucky, Sirona or Lugus will take you in. If you're not, you could end up haunted for eternity by what you consider to be your sins in Arwan's realm. Some clever demon might even take advantage of your meaningless guilt and drag you to Hell." Septimus nodded, still recovering from shock. "So, Septimus, care to guess your third option?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He said, "I join your crew, and in doing so, betray my fellow Bannor, betray my god, betray everything I ever held dear." Casin said, "nay. Your nation betrayed you long ago. As for the 'everything I ever held dear,' I'll have you know, you'll realize in time what you truly hold dear among my crew. I can offer you the freedom to be your own man. The opprotunity to be judged for your actions, not the insane whims of a merciless priesthood." "They serve Junil's will; I would sooner face their punishment than betray the God of Order." Casin opened her desk, and slid a thick tome to Septimus. "It's 'The Great Bannor Corruption;' a compilation of essays by Dural, Elohim, Kuriotate, and Malakim theologians which demonstrates, quite well in my opinion, that the Bannor priesthood has strayed worryingly far from the true nature of the Order, possibly due to corruption by Mammon, Aeron, or perhaps just the human ambition to rule over one's fellows." "I've heard of this book. It's been called heresy of the greatest degree, and is said to make a mockery of everything the Order holds dear." Casin rolled her eyes, then said, "well, it's not my personal copy, just in case you fail to resist the temptation to burn it or carry it into the watery depths. Just a bit of light reading for you to peruse while you consider my little offer." Septimus left, holding the tome as though he expected it to bite him.Once Septimus had left, the man who'd escorted Septimus in asked Loveless, "weren't you complaining that book was... how'd you put it?" "I believe I said the book was built on theologically shaky grounds, and that any well trained Bannor Confessor could probably pen a thorough refutation if they bothered to read the damn thing instead of torching it on sight. Although, who knows, maybe the book's authors could refute the Bannor refutations, if they got the chance. But, fascinating as they are, the Order's internal divisions do not really concern me. Septimus is not a Confessor, just a tormented soul who'd make a great new First Mate. Now then, tell the crew we're sailing to Aylesbury. Falamar and Arturus are having a diplomatic summit. I can never resist a chance to mess with Falamar's head, and I'm wondering if it's true what they say about dwarves." "What do they say about dwarves?" She pulled out a text on comparative biology and said, "evidently, not everything's shorter."</French>
		<German>Most men would have been terrified in his position, but Septimus was merely annoyed. His ship had been overtaken by some Lanun raiders, who had easily overpowered him and his men and were now dividing up the treasure. One Lanun, a large man who seemed to assume he could intimidate Septimus with his size, glared down at Septimus and said, "You. The captain wants to see you." He motioned for Septimus to follow him, and having no better alternative, Septimus did.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He wasn't sure what he'd expected the Captain's quarters to look like; aside from the bed, what he saw seemed more like a library. The centerpiece of the room was a large desk, but books were everywhere, scattered about with no immediately obvious system. He grabbed one at random; it was Cassiel's "Discourse on Gods and Worship in the Age of Magic." This was, in his Bannor homelands, an incredibly heretical book, but most who read it often confessed they didn't really understand it anyways. He opened it to a bookmarked page and found a description of the changes to the rites of the Illian people in the time leading up to the Age of Ice. It was terribly dry, although another hand had underlined certain passages, and written scholarly-looking notes in the side margins.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A red-headed woman entered the room, and sat down at the desk, motioning for Septimus to take a seat. She carried herself with authority and intellect, and her large henchman shrank in her presence. She was clearly the captain, but Septimus couldn't resist a cheap jibe. He remained standing, and said, "seems whoever runs this boat has a fine taste in whores." She grinned. "Whore? Maybe according to some, but I'm also the captain, and capable of gutting you like a fish six different ways." She pulled out a knife and caressed it for emphasis. Septimus noticed she didn't really seem offended by being called a whore; what sort of strange woman was she?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Quite the library, Miss..." "Loveless. Casin Loveless." "Quite the library, Miss Loveless. Did you know you can read these things, instead of selling or burning them?" She grinned. "Very much so; reading is one of my favorite hobbies. Gutting idiots is another. And the third..." Septimus cut her off with his guess: "Bedding men? Women? Both?" "Men. But only interesting ones. Falamar was fun for a while, but he couldn't quite keep up with me, mentally or physically. I could have forgiven one, but not both. Charadon had natural gifts, but not much else. Now, Amelanchier..." "Miss Loveless, I think I've heard enough on that topic. Care to tell me why I'm here? And if it's what I think it is, you might as well toss me to the sharks now. I am sure the number of interesting men you've bedded is matched only by the number of interesting, and no doubt painful, diseases you've collected." "I have an excellent healer, Dural trained, who makes certain that's not a problem. Tolerating her pitiable attempts at flirting with me is a small price to pay. But that isn't why you're here. I've been following your exploits for quite a while, Captain Septimus, so I'm not going to waste effort trying to seduce you. I have more than enough evidence that you prefer to share your bed with men."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Septimus fell into the seat Casin had pulled out for him, and stared at her with horror. Casin lay back in her chair, and said, "Your arrogant confidence seems to have disappeared. Excellent. Now maybe you'll shut up and listen. Your hobbies aside, Captain Septimus, my records make it quite clear you are among the most courageous and, more importantly, competent men to ever sail the seas of Erebus. I've been hunting you down, specifically, to make you an offer. I've already sent anonymous but irrefutable evidence of your activities to the Bannor admiralty. Now, you have three choices. I can drop you off in Bannor lands, and trust you to their gentle mercies. Alternatively, I can kill you, far more quickly and painlessly than your Bannor kin would. One stroke of my blade, and you go forth to the afterlife. You're a good and noble man; if you're lucky, Sirona or Lugus will take you in. If you're not, you could end up haunted for eternity by what you consider to be your sins in Arwan's realm. Some clever demon might even take advantage of your meaningless guilt and drag you to Hell." Septimus nodded, still recovering from shock. "So, Septimus, care to guess your third option?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He said, "I join your crew, and in doing so, betray my fellow Bannor, betray my god, betray everything I ever held dear." Casin said, "nay. Your nation betrayed you long ago. As for the 'everything I ever held dear,' I'll have you know, you'll realize in time what you truly hold dear among my crew. I can offer you the freedom to be your own man. The opprotunity to be judged for your actions, not the insane whims of a merciless priesthood." "They serve Junil's will; I would sooner face their punishment than betray the God of Order." Casin opened her desk, and slid a thick tome to Septimus. "It's 'The Great Bannor Corruption;' a compilation of essays by Dural, Elohim, Kuriotate, and Malakim theologians which demonstrates, quite well in my opinion, that the Bannor priesthood has strayed worryingly far from the true nature of the Order, possibly due to corruption by Mammon, Aeron, or perhaps just the human ambition to rule over one's fellows." "I've heard of this book. It's been called heresy of the greatest degree, and is said to make a mockery of everything the Order holds dear." Casin rolled her eyes, then said, "well, it's not my personal copy, just in case you fail to resist the temptation to burn it or carry it into the watery depths. Just a bit of light reading for you to peruse while you consider my little offer." Septimus left, holding the tome as though he expected it to bite him.Once Septimus had left, the man who'd escorted Septimus in asked Loveless, "weren't you complaining that book was... how'd you put it?" "I believe I said the book was built on theologically shaky grounds, and that any well trained Bannor Confessor could probably pen a thorough refutation if they bothered to read the damn thing instead of torching it on sight. Although, who knows, maybe the book's authors could refute the Bannor refutations, if they got the chance. But, fascinating as they are, the Order's internal divisions do not really concern me. Septimus is not a Confessor, just a tormented soul who'd make a great new First Mate. Now then, tell the crew we're sailing to Aylesbury. Falamar and Arturus are having a diplomatic summit. I can never resist a chance to mess with Falamar's head, and I'm wondering if it's true what they say about dwarves." "What do they say about dwarves?" She pulled out a text on comparative biology and said, "evidently, not everything's shorter."</German>
		<Italian>La maggior parte degli uomini sarebbero rimasti terrorizzati nella sua posizione, ma Septimus era semplicemente infastidito. La sua nave era stata assalita da qualche razziatore Lanun, che avevano facilmente sopraffatto lui e i suoi uomini e si stavano dividendo ora il bottino. Un Lanun, un uomo largo che sembrava presumere di poter intimidire Septimus con la sua stazza, guardò verso Septimus e disse, "Tu. Il capitano ti vuole vedere". Fece cenno a Septimus di seguirlo, and quest'ultimo, non avendo un'alternativa migliore, lo seguì.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Non sapeva cosa aspettarsi dalla cabina del capitano; a parte un letto quello che vedeva assomigliava più a una libreria. Il fulcro della stanza era una grande scrivania, ma i libri erano dappertutto, sparsi senza alcun ordine apparente. Ne prese uno a caso; era quello scritto da Cassiel "Discorso sugli Dei e l'Adorazione nell'Erà della Magia". Questo libro era, nella sua patria Bannor, assolutamente eretico, ma la maggior parte di quelli che l'avevano letto spesso confessavano di non averlo veramente compreso. Lo aprì sulla pagina con il segnalibro e vi trovò una descrizione dei cambi dei riti del popolo Illian sino all'arrivo dell'Era del Ghiaccio. Era terribilmente secco, anche se un'altra mano aveva sottolineato alcuni passaggi, e scritto delle note dall'aspetto accademico ai margini laterali.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Una donna dai capelli rossi entrò nella stanza, e si sedette alla scrivania, facendo cenno a Septimus di sedersi. Lei si muoveva con autorità e intelligenza, e il suo grosso scagnozzo si rimpicciolì in sua presenza. Lei era chiaramente il capitano, ma Septimus non riuscì a trattenere uno scherno. Rimase in piedi e disse, "Sembra che chiunque governi questa barca abbia buon gusto per le puttane". Lei sorrise. "Puttane? Forse secondo alcuni, ma io sono anche il capitano e capace di sventrarti come un pesce in sei modi diversi". Lei disse estraendo un coltello e accarezzandolo per dare enfasi. Septimus notò che non sembrava essersi offesa dall'essere chiamata puttana; che strano tipo di donna era?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Una bella libreria, Signora..." "Loveless. Casin Loveless." "Una bella libreria, Signora Loveless. Sapete che potete leggere questi cosi, invece di venderli o bruciarli?" Lei sorrise. "Lo so; leggere è uno dei miei hobby preferiti. Un'altro è sventrare idioti. E il terzo..." Septimus la interruppe con la sua ipotesi: "Scopare uomini? Donne? Entrambi?" "Uomini. Ma solo quelli interessanti. Falamar è stato divertente per un pò, ma non riusciva a tenere il mio passo, mentalmente e fisicamente. Avrei potuto ignorarne uno, ma non entrambi. Charadon aveva doti naturali, ma non molto altro. Ora, Amelanchier..." "Signora Loveless, penso di aver sentito abbastanza su questo argomento. Vi va di dirmi perchè sono qui? E se è per quello che penso che sia, potete anche buttarmi in pasto agli squali adesso. Sono certo che il numero di uomini interessanti con cui siete stata è pari soltanto al numero di interessanti, e senza dubbio dolorose, malattie che avete collezionato". "Ho una eccellente guaritrice, istruita dai Dural, chi si assicura che non siano un problema. Tollerare i suoi pietosi tentativi di flirtare con me è un piccolo prezzo da pagare. Ma questo non è il motivo per cui siete qui. Sto seguendo le vostre imprese da un pò, Capitano Septimus, quindi non mi dilungherò cercando di sedurti. Ho prove più che sufficienti per sapere che preferisci condividere il tuo letto con gli uomini."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Septimus cascò nella sedia che Casin gli aveva messo a disposizione, e la fissava con orrore. Casin si rilassò sulla sua sedia e disse, "Sembra che la tua arrogante sicurezza sia sparita. Eccellente. Forse ora starai zitto e ascolterai. Messi da parte i tuoi hobby, Capitano Septimus, le mie informazioni sono chiare sul fatto che voi siete tra i più coraggiosi e, ancor più importante, competenti uomini che hanno mai solcato i mari di Erebus. Ti stavo dando la caccia, specificatamente, per farti un'offerta. Ho già mandato in via anonima delle prove inconfutabili delle tue attività all'ammiragliato Bannor. Ora, hai tre scelte. Posso farti sbarcare nei territori Bannor, e affidarti alle loro gentili cure. In alternativa, posso ucciderti, molto più rapidamente e indolore di quanto i tuoi simili Bannor farebbero. Un colpo della mia lama, e tu finisci nell'aldilà. Sei un uomo buono e nobile; se sei fortunato, Sirona o Lugus ti accoglieranno. Se non lo sei, potresti finire perseguitato per l'eternità da ciò che tu consideri i tuoi peccati nel reame di Arwan. Qualche astuto demone potrebbe persino trarre vantaggio del tuo senso di colpa immotivato e trascinarti all'Inferno." Septimus annuì mentre si stava ancora riprendendo dallo shock. "Quindi, Septimus, ti va di indovinare la tua terza opzione?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Lui disse, "Mi unisco al tuo equipaggio, e nel farlo, tradirei i miei compagni Bannor, tradirei il mio dio e tradirei tutto quello a cui ho mai tenuto". Casin disse, "No. La tua nazione ti ha tradito molto tempo fa. Per quanto riguarda 'tutto quello a cui ho tenuto,' farò in modo che tu sappia, che tu capisca nel tempo a cosa tu tenga veramente tra il mio equipaggio. Io posso offrirti la libertà di essere te stesso. L'opportunità di essere giudicato per le tue azioni, non per i capricci di un clero senza pietà". "Loro servono la volontà di Junil; Preferisco affrontare la loro punizione piuttosto che tradire il Dio dell'Ordine." Casin aprì la sua scrivania, e poi fece scorrere un libro spesso verso Septimus. "È 'La Grande Corruzione Bannor;' una raccolta di saggi di teologi Dural, Elohim, Kuriotate e Malakim che dimostra, abbastanza bene secondo me, che il clero Bannor si è allontanto in maniera preoccupante dalla vera natura dell'Ordine, probabilmente a causa dell'influenza di Mammon, Aeron o forse semplicemente l'ambizione umana di governare sompra i propri simili". "Ho sentito parlare di questo libro. È considerato un'eresia di altissimo grado, e si dice che derida ogni cosa che l'Ordine ha a cuore". Casin alzò gli occhi al cielo, poi disse, "Bene, non è la mia copia personale, nel caso fallisci a resistere alla tentazione di bruciarlo o portarlo con te nelle profondità oceaniche. Semplicemente una lettura leggera per te da esaminare mentre consideri la mia piccola offerta". Septimus se ne andò tenendo il tomo come se si aspettasse che lo avrebbe morso. Una volta che Septimus fù uscito, l'uomo che lo aveva scortato chiese a Loveless, "Non ti stavi lamentando che il libro era... com'è che avevi detto?" "Penso di aver detto che il libro si fonda su deboli fondamenta teologiche, e che qualsiasi ben istruito Confessore Bannor avrebbe potuto scrivere una completa confutazione se soltanto si preoccupassero di leggerlo invece di bruciarlo a vista. Anche se, chi sà, forse gli autori del libro possono confutare le confutazioni Bannor, se ne avessero la possibilità. Ma, per quanto siano interessanti, le divisioni interne dell'Ordine non mi preoccupano. Septimus non è un Confessore, ma soltanto un'anima tormentata che sarebbe un grande nuovo Primo Ufficiale. Quindi ora di all'equipaggio che stiamo salpando per Aylesbury. Falamar e Arturus stanno avendo un incontro diplomatico. Non riesco a resistere alla possibilità di incasinare la testa a Falamar, e mi sto chiedendo se sia vero quello che si dice dei nani". "Cosa si dice dei nani?" Lei prese un libro di biologia comparativa e disse, "evidentemente, non tutto è più corto".</Italian>
		<Spanish>Most men would have been terrified in his position, but Septimus was merely annoyed. His ship had been overtaken by some Lanun raiders, who had easily overpowered him and his men and were now dividing up the treasure. One Lanun, a large man who seemed to assume he could intimidate Septimus with his size, glared down at Septimus and said, "You. The captain wants to see you." He motioned for Septimus to follow him, and having no better alternative, Septimus did.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He wasn't sure what he'd expected the Captain's quarters to look like; aside from the bed, what he saw seemed more like a library. The centerpiece of the room was a large desk, but books were everywhere, scattered about with no immediately obvious system. He grabbed one at random; it was Cassiel's "Discourse on Gods and Worship in the Age of Magic." This was, in his Bannor homelands, an incredibly heretical book, but most who read it often confessed they didn't really understand it anyways. He opened it to a bookmarked page and found a description of the changes to the rites of the Illian people in the time leading up to the Age of Ice. It was terribly dry, although another hand had underlined certain passages, and written scholarly-looking notes in the side margins.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A red-headed woman entered the room, and sat down at the desk, motioning for Septimus to take a seat. She carried herself with authority and intellect, and her large henchman shrank in her presence. She was clearly the captain, but Septimus couldn't resist a cheap jibe. He remained standing, and said, "seems whoever runs this boat has a fine taste in whores." She grinned. "Whore? Maybe according to some, but I'm also the captain, and capable of gutting you like a fish six different ways." She pulled out a knife and caressed it for emphasis. Septimus noticed she didn't really seem offended by being called a whore; what sort of strange woman was she?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"Quite the library, Miss..." "Loveless. Casin Loveless." "Quite the library, Miss Loveless. Did you know you can read these things, instead of selling or burning them?" She grinned. "Very much so; reading is one of my favorite hobbies. Gutting idiots is another. And the third..." Septimus cut her off with his guess: "Bedding men? Women? Both?" "Men. But only interesting ones. Falamar was fun for a while, but he couldn't quite keep up with me, mentally or physically. I could have forgiven one, but not both. Charadon had natural gifts, but not much else. Now, Amelanchier..." "Miss Loveless, I think I've heard enough on that topic. Care to tell me why I'm here? And if it's what I think it is, you might as well toss me to the sharks now. I am sure the number of interesting men you've bedded is matched only by the number of interesting, and no doubt painful, diseases you've collected." "I have an excellent healer, Dural trained, who makes certain that's not a problem. Tolerating her pitiable attempts at flirting with me is a small price to pay. But that isn't why you're here. I've been following your exploits for quite a while, Captain Septimus, so I'm not going to waste effort trying to seduce you. I have more than enough evidence that you prefer to share your bed with men."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Septimus fell into the seat Casin had pulled out for him, and stared at her with horror. Casin lay back in her chair, and said, "Your arrogant confidence seems to have disappeared. Excellent. Now maybe you'll shut up and listen. Your hobbies aside, Captain Septimus, my records make it quite clear you are among the most courageous and, more importantly, competent men to ever sail the seas of Erebus. I've been hunting you down, specifically, to make you an offer. I've already sent anonymous but irrefutable evidence of your activities to the Bannor admiralty. Now, you have three choices. I can drop you off in Bannor lands, and trust you to their gentle mercies. Alternatively, I can kill you, far more quickly and painlessly than your Bannor kin would. One stroke of my blade, and you go forth to the afterlife. You're a good and noble man; if you're lucky, Sirona or Lugus will take you in. If you're not, you could end up haunted for eternity by what you consider to be your sins in Arwan's realm. Some clever demon might even take advantage of your meaningless guilt and drag you to Hell." Septimus nodded, still recovering from shock. "So, Septimus, care to guess your third option?"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He said, "I join your crew, and in doing so, betray my fellow Bannor, betray my god, betray everything I ever held dear." Casin said, "nay. Your nation betrayed you long ago. As for the 'everything I ever held dear,' I'll have you know, you'll realize in time what you truly hold dear among my crew. I can offer you the freedom to be your own man. The opprotunity to be judged for your actions, not the insane whims of a merciless priesthood." "They serve Junil's will; I would sooner face their punishment than betray the God of Order." Casin opened her desk, and slid a thick tome to Septimus. "It's 'The Great Bannor Corruption;' a compilation of essays by Dural, Elohim, Kuriotate, and Malakim theologians which demonstrates, quite well in my opinion, that the Bannor priesthood has strayed worryingly far from the true nature of the Order, possibly due to corruption by Mammon, Aeron, or perhaps just the human ambition to rule over one's fellows." "I've heard of this book. It's been called heresy of the greatest degree, and is said to make a mockery of everything the Order holds dear." Casin rolled her eyes, then said, "well, it's not my personal copy, just in case you fail to resist the temptation to burn it or carry it into the watery depths. Just a bit of light reading for you to peruse while you consider my little offer." Septimus left, holding the tome as though he expected it to bite him.Once Septimus had left, the man who'd escorted Septimus in asked Loveless, "weren't you complaining that book was... how'd you put it?" "I believe I said the book was built on theologically shaky grounds, and that any well trained Bannor Confessor could probably pen a thorough refutation if they bothered to read the damn thing instead of torching it on sight. Although, who knows, maybe the book's authors could refute the Bannor refutations, if they got the chance. But, fascinating as they are, the Order's internal divisions do not really concern me. Septimus is not a Confessor, just a tormented soul who'd make a great new First Mate. Now then, tell the crew we're sailing to Aylesbury. Falamar and Arturus are having a diplomatic summit. I can never resist a chance to mess with Falamar's head, and I'm wondering if it's true what they say about dwarves." "What do they say about dwarves?" She pulled out a text on comparative biology and said, "evidently, not everything's shorter."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_FALAMAR</Tag>
		<English>Falamar</English>
		<French>Falamar</French>
		<German>Falamar</German>
		<Italian>Falamar</Italian>
		<Spanish>Falamar</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_FALAMAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]"Release me at once or taste steel, cur!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Falamar gazed at Rhoanna in mock anguish. "Milady is displeased by the accommodations? You are welcome to leave at any time, of course, and I'm injured by the insinuation that you are anything but a guest."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I have business too urgent to put up with your pranks." The lady paced about the Captain's quarters, armor clanking with every step. "Return me to my vessel, or I am as good as your prisoner," she said, glaring at the waves. "Or did you expect me to walk?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"You know, I've seen that done, and it isn't all that impressive." The Lanun picked up one of two goblets on the heavy wooden table and took a delicate sip. "The magic helps, sure. But the real trick is to not look down."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do not-" Rhoanna paused and clenched a fist tightly as the ship swayed on the waves. "Dragons take you and your seas! Don't change the subject! I need to be aboard my own vessel on my own course."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ah, well, it seems that one just can't buy good help these days. No sooner had we brought you--and that delightful Air conjurer-aboard, than they headed for the horizon. Without telling me where they were going! Although, I do suspect I'll see them again, the captain is my brother-in-law."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Is there no honor on the seas?" the Hippus Queen moaned, as she slumped into the chair across from Falamar.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do try the wine, my dear; our fall 157 vintage takes the edge off the sea pangs. As for honor, I'd wager mine against any sell-sword from the steppes... present company excluded of course. We have our own rules on the waves, 'tis true," Falamar rose and walked around the cabin, picking up a large bottle which contained a replica of the Maiden's Delight, his flagship. "But I think you'll find them to contain a certain measure of honor. A captain's word is law on his ship, but a crewman is free to leave at any port. We may have a wife in every port, but our mistress, the sea, is eternal. A man makes his fate with his own two hands, but we all wind up in the drink eventually. A Lady's virtue remains sacrosanct-unless she can be persuaded to set it aside like a suit of armor, soon to be made worthless by the sea air."[PARAGRAPH:1]Rhoanna pulled out a dagger from a sheath hidden in the plates of her armor. "Fascinating. Pray tell, what are the rules of the sea with regard to eunuchs?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Galley slaves, usually, and it's good to see the sea hasn't robbed you of all your spirit. Speaking of robbery, you did want to return to land, did you not?"[PARAGRAPH:1]She glared at him for a minute, then sighed, and said "Name your price, Sea-King. I need to reach my company at the Grigori border. Our contract has been... renegotiated, and if I don't inform my sergeants, the honor of the Hippus will indeed be worth little more than that of sea thieves."[PARAGRAPH:1]"There are a few trade contracts which could only draw us closer... as nations, of course. Awaiting just your signature here, dear lady." Rhoanna looked them over, muttering about extortion but made her mark.[PARAGRAPH:2]Falamar watched as Rhoanna and her companion bounded down the harbor, away from the Maiden's Delight and towards her duty. "Where to now, captain?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Not just yet, Sharwin." He kept watching, eventually a frown playing on his normally implacable visage. She was almost out of his sight. He began to reach for his spyglass.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rhoanna slowed at the edge of town. Slowed then stopped, and almost against her will, certainly against her better judgment, turned around. She gazed at the Lanun ship for several minutes, the wind pulling her hair towards the sea. Then she returned to her quest.[PARAGRAPH:1]Falamar smiled. "They always look back. Always. Sharwin, head for Balseraph waters. They have a vintage that should be ripening now."</English>
		<French>[TAB]"Release me at once or taste steel, cur!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Falamar gazed at Rhoanna in mock anguish. "Milady is displeased by the accommodations? You are welcome to leave at any time, of course, and I'm injured by the insinuation that you are anything but a guest."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I have business too urgent to put up with your pranks." The lady paced about the Captain's quarters, armor clanking with every step. "Return me to my vessel, or I am as good as your prisoner," she said, glaring at the waves. "Or did you expect me to walk?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"You know, I've seen that done, and it isn't all that impressive." The Lanun picked up one of two goblets on the heavy wooden table and took a delicate sip. "The magic helps, sure. But the real trick is to not look down."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do not-" Rhoanna paused and clenched a fist tightly as the ship swayed on the waves. "Dragons take you and your seas! Don't change the subject! I need to be aboard my own vessel on my own course."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ah, well, it seems that one just can't buy good help these days. No sooner had we brought you--and that delightful Air conjurer-aboard, than they headed for the horizon. Without telling me where they were going! Although, I do suspect I'll see them again, the captain is my brother-in-law."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Is there no honor on the seas?" the Hippus Queen moaned, as she slumped into the chair across from Falamar.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do try the wine, my dear; our fall 157 vintage takes the edge off the sea pangs. As for honor, I'd wager mine against any sell-sword from the steppes... present company excluded of course. We have our own rules on the waves, 'tis true," Falamar rose and walked around the cabin, picking up a large bottle which contained a replica of the Maiden's Delight, his flagship. "But I think you'll find them to contain a certain measure of honor. A captain's word is law on his ship, but a crewman is free to leave at any port. We may have a wife in every port, but our mistress, the sea, is eternal. A man makes his fate with his own two hands, but we all wind up in the drink eventually. A Lady's virtue remains sacrosanct-unless she can be persuaded to set it aside like a suit of armor, soon to be made worthless by the sea air."[PARAGRAPH:1]Rhoanna pulled out a dagger from a sheath hidden in the plates of her armor. "Fascinating. Pray tell, what are the rules of the sea with regard to eunuchs?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Galley slaves, usually, and it's good to see the sea hasn't robbed you of all your spirit. Speaking of robbery, you did want to return to land, did you not?"[PARAGRAPH:1]She glared at him for a minute, then sighed, and said "Name your price, Sea-King. I need to reach my company at the Grigori border. Our contract has been... renegotiated, and if I don't inform my sergeants, the honor of the Hippus will indeed be worth little more than that of sea thieves."[PARAGRAPH:1]"There are a few trade contracts which could only draw us closer... as nations, of course. Awaiting just your signature here, dear lady." Rhoanna looked them over, muttering about extortion but made her mark.[PARAGRAPH:2]Falamar watched as Rhoanna and her companion bounded down the harbor, away from the Maiden's Delight and towards her duty. "Where to now, captain?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Not just yet, Sharwin." He kept watching, eventually a frown playing on his normally implacable visage. She was almost out of his sight. He began to reach for his spyglass.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rhoanna slowed at the edge of town. Slowed then stopped, and almost against her will, certainly against her better judgment, turned around. She gazed at the Lanun ship for several minutes, the wind pulling her hair towards the sea. Then she returned to her quest.[PARAGRAPH:1]Falamar smiled. "They always look back. Always. Sharwin, head for Balseraph waters. They have a vintage that should be ripening now."</French>
		<German>[TAB]"Lasst mich sofort gehen, oder schmeckt Stahl, Köter!"[PARAGRAPH:1] Falamar starrte Rhoanna in gespieltem Entsetzen an. "Mylady ist mit ihrer Unterkunft unzufrieden? Ihr seid frei, uns jederzeit zu verlassen, selbstverständlich, und ich bin getroffen von der Unterstellung, Ihr wärt irgendetwas anderes als ein Gast."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ich habe zu wichtige Geschäfte zu erledigen, als dass ich mich mit Euren Scherzen aufhalten könnte." Die Herrin schritt durch das Quartier des Kapitäns, Rüstung schepperte mit jedem Schritt. "Leitet mich zu meinem Schiff zurück, sonst bin ich nichts besseres, als Eure Gefangene", sagte sie, während sie auf die Wellen blickte. "Oder erwartet Ihr, dass ich über das Meer gehe?"[PARAGRAPH:1] "Wisst Ihr, das habe ich schon gesehen, und es ist gar nicht so beeindruckend." Der Lanun nahm einen der zwei Kelche von dem schweren Holztisch, und nahm einen genüsslichen Schluck. "Die Magie hilft dabei, sicher. Aber der Trick dabei ist, nicht nach unten zu sehen."[PARAGRAPH:1] "Lasst nicht...", Rhoanna hielt inne, und ballte ihre Faust stark, als sich das Schiff auf den Wellen wog. "Die Drachen sollen Euch und Eure Meere hohlen! Hört auf, das Thema zu wechseln! Ich muss auf meinem eigenem Schiff, auf meinem eigenen Kurs sein."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ah, seht, es scheint, als ob niemand mehr gute Hilfe dieser Tage kaufen könnte. Kaum hatten wir Euch - und diesen wunderbaren Luftbeschwörer an Bord gebracht, da fuhren sie schon wieder dem Horizont entgegen. Ohne mir zu sagen, wohin sie unterwegs waren! Obwohl, ich glaube, dass ich sie wieder sehen werde, der Kapitän ist mein Schwager."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Gibt es keine Ehre auf dem Meer?", stieß die Königin der Hippus aus, als sie sich in den Sessel gegenüber von Falamar sinken ließ.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Versucht doch den Wein, meine Liebe; unsere Herbstlese von 157 nimmt der Seekrankheit das Unangenehme. Was die Ehre betrifft, ich würde meine jederzeit mit der eines jeden Söldners aus den Steppen messen können... vorhandene Personen natürlich ausgeschlossen. Wir haben unsere eigenen Regeln auf den Wellen, das wohl." Falamar erhob sich, ging durch die Kabine, und nahm eine große Flasche auf, die ein Replikat der "Jungfrauenwonne", seines Flaggschiffes, enthielt. "Aber ich glaube, ihr werdet feststellen, dass sie eine gewisse Art von Ehre enthalten. Das Wort des Kapitäns ist auf seinem Schiff Gesetz, aber ein Mannschaftsmitglied ist frei, in jedem Hafen abzuheuern. Wir haben vielleicht in jedem Hafen eine Frau, aber unsere Geliebte, die See, ist ewig. Ein Mann schafft sein Schicksal mit seinen beiden Händen, aber irgendwann enden wir wahrscheinlich alle in den Fluten. Die Tugend einer Dame ist uns heilig - außer, sie kann überzeugt werden, diese abzulegen, wie eine Rüstung, die bald durch die Seeluft wertlos werden würde."[PARAGRAPH:1]Rhoanna zog einen Dolch aus einer Scheide, die in den Platten ihrer Rüstung verborgen war. "Faszinierend. Bitte, erzählt doch, was sagen eure Regeln der See zu Eunuchen?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Galeerensklaven, normalerweise, und es ist schön zu sehen, dass die See Euch nicht all Euren Geist geraubt hat. Wo wir von Rauben sprechen, Ihr wolltet doch an Land zurückkehren, oder nicht?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie starrte ihn noch eine Minute lang an, dann seufzte sie, und sprach: "Nennt Euern Preis, Seekönig. Ich muss meine Gesandtschaft an den Grenzen zu den Grigori erreichen. Unser Vertrag ist... neu verhandelt worden, und wenn ich meine Rittmeister nicht informiere, wird die Ehre der Hippus tatsächlich nicht mehr viel mehr Wert sein, als die von Seeräubern."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Es gibt ein paar Handelsverträge, die uns nur einander näher bringen können... als Völker, natürlich. Ich warte nur noch auf Eure Unterschrift hier, liebste Dame." Rhoanna überflog sie, murmelte etwas über Ausbeutung, aber machte ihr Zeichen. [PARAGRAPH:2] Falamar sah zu, als Rhoanna und ihr Begleiter aus dem Hafen fuhren, fort von der Jungfrauenwonne, und ihrer Pflicht entgegen. "Wohin jetzt, Kapitän?" [PARAGRAPH:1]"Noch nicht, Sharwin." Er beobachtete sie weiter, hin und wieder mit einem Stirnrunzeln in seinem normalerweise ausdruckslosen Gesicht. Sie war schon fast nicht mehr zu sehen. Er begann, nach seinem Fernglas zu suchen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rhoanna wurde am Rand der Stadt langsamer. Langsamer, dann hielt sie ganz an, und dann, fast gegen ihren Willen, und sicher gegen ihr besseres Wissen, drehte sie sich um. Sie blickte auf das Schiff der Lanun für mehrere Minuten, während der Wind ihr Haar in Richtung des Meeres wehte.[PARAGRAPH:1]Falamar lächelte. "Sie schauen immer zurück. Immer. Sharwin, bring uns in Balseraph-Gewässer. Dort haben sie eine Lese, die jetzt gerade reifen sollte."</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]"Lasciami andare subito o assaggierai l'acciaio, cane!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Falamar guardò Rhoanna con finta angoscia. "Milady è dispiaciuta della sistemazione? Siete libera di andare quando volete, ovviamente, e sono ferito dall'insinuazione che non siete che un ospite."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ho affari troppo urgenti per sopportare i tuoi giochi". Rhoanna camminava su e giù per la cabina del capitano, con l'armatura che tintinnava a ogni passo. "Riportatemi al mio vascello, altrimenti non sono altro che vostra prigioniera," lei disse, osservando le onde. "O vi aspettate che ci arrivi camminando?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Sapete, lo ho visto fare, e non è poi così impressionante." Il Lanun prese uno dei due calici dal robusto tavolo di legno e sorseggiò delicatamente. "La magia aiuta, certo. Ma il vero segreto è non guardare in basso."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non-" Rhoanna fece una pausa e strinse una mano a pugno mentre la nave ondeggiava. "Che i draghi prendano te e i tuoi mari! Non cambiare discorso! Devo essere a bordo della mia nave sulla mia rotta."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ah, beh, sembra che non si possa comprare un buon aiuto in questi giorni. Non appena abbiamo portato te, e quel fantastico mago dell'aria, a bordo loro sono corsi via. Senza neppure dirmi dove stavano andando! Anche se sospetto che li rivedrò di nuovo, il capitano è il mio fratellastro."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non vi è onore sui mari?" la regina Hippus disse mentre si accasciava sulla sedia di fronte a Falamar.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Provate il vino, mia cara; la nostra annata autunnale 157 toglie il mal di mare. Per quanto riguarda l'onore, scommetterei il mio contro quello di qualsiasi mercenario delle steppe... con la compagnia attuale esclusa ovviamente. Abbiamo le nostre regole sui mari, questo è vero" Falamar si alzò e ando a prendere una grossa bottiglia, al cui interno vi era una replica della Maiden's Delight, la sua ammiraglia. "Ma penso che vi troverete in esse un certo quantitativo di onore. La parola di un capitano è legge sulla sua nave, ma un membro dell'equipaggio è libero di andarsene ad ogni porto. Potremmo avere una moglie in ogni porto, ma il nostro amore, il mare, è eterno. Un'uomo crea il suo destino con le sue mani, ma alla fine finiamo tutti a bere. La virtù di una donna rimane sacrosanta, a meno che lei non possa essere persuasa a metterla da parte come fosse un'armatura, a breve rovinata dall'aria di mare."[PARAGRAPH:1]Rhoanna estrasse un pugnale da un fodero nascosto sotto le piastre dell'armatura. "Affascinante. Di grazia dimmi, quali sono le regole del mare riguardanti gli eonuchi?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Schiavi rematori, di solito, ed è bello vedere che il mare non vi ha privato del vostro temperamento. A proposito di rapinare, volete tornare sulla terraferma, non è vero?"[PARAGRAPH:1]Lei lo fissò per un minuto, poi sospiro e disse "Dite il vostro prezzo, Re del Mare. Devo raggiungere la mia compagnia al confine Grigori. Il nostro contratto è stato... rinegoziato, e se non informo i miei sergenti l'onore degli Hippus varrà veramente poco più di quello dei ladri del mare".[PARAGRAPH:1]"Vi sono alcuni trattati commerciali che potrebberò soltanto avvicinarci... come nazioni, ovviamente. Attendono solo la vostra firma qui, gentil dama". Rhoanna li lessè, borbottando come fossero un'estorsione, ma li firmò.[PARAGRAPH:2]Falamar rimase ad osservare Rhoanna e il suo compagno mentre scendevano al porto e si allontanavano dalla Maiden's Delight diretti verso i loro doveri. "Dove si va ora, capitano?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Non ancora, Sharwin." Disse Falamar rimanendo a guardare, aggrottando la fronte normalmente rilassata. Lei era quasi fuori dalla sua vista e lui iniziò a prendere il cannocchiale.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rhoanna rallentò ai margini della città. Poi si fermò, e quasi contro la sua volontà e di sicuro contro il suo giudizio, si voltò. Guardò la nave Lanun per diversi minuti con il vento che spingeva i suoi capelli verso il mare. Poi tornò alla sua missione.[PARAGRAPH:1]Falamar sorrise. "Si voltano sempre. Sempre. Sharwin, fai rotta verso le acque dei Balseraph. Hanno una vendemmia che dovrebbe star maturando".</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]"Release me at once or taste steel, cur!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Falamar gazed at Rhoanna in mock anguish. "Milady is displeased by the accommodations? You are welcome to leave at any time, of course, and I'm injured by the insinuation that you are anything but a guest."[PARAGRAPH:1]"I have business too urgent to put up with your pranks." The lady paced about the Captain's quarters, armor clanking with every step. "Return me to my vessel, or I am as good as your prisoner," she said, glaring at the waves. "Or did you expect me to walk?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"You know, I've seen that done, and it isn't all that impressive." The Lanun picked up one of two goblets on the heavy wooden table and took a delicate sip. "The magic helps, sure. But the real trick is to not look down."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do not-" Rhoanna paused and clenched a fist tightly as the ship swayed on the waves. "Dragons take you and your seas! Don't change the subject! I need to be aboard my own vessel on my own course."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Ah, well, it seems that one just can't buy good help these days. No sooner had we brought you--and that delightful Air conjurer-aboard, than they headed for the horizon. Without telling me where they were going! Although, I do suspect I'll see them again, the captain is my brother-in-law."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Is there no honor on the seas?" the Hippus Queen moaned, as she slumped into the chair across from Falamar.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Do try the wine, my dear; our fall 157 vintage takes the edge off the sea pangs. As for honor, I'd wager mine against any sell-sword from the steppes... present company excluded of course. We have our own rules on the waves, 'tis true," Falamar rose and walked around the cabin, picking up a large bottle which contained a replica of the Maiden's Delight, his flagship. "But I think you'll find them to contain a certain measure of honor. A captain's word is law on his ship, but a crewman is free to leave at any port. We may have a wife in every port, but our mistress, the sea, is eternal. A man makes his fate with his own two hands, but we all wind up in the drink eventually. A Lady's virtue remains sacrosanct-unless she can be persuaded to set it aside like a suit of armor, soon to be made worthless by the sea air."[PARAGRAPH:1]Rhoanna pulled out a dagger from a sheath hidden in the plates of her armor. "Fascinating. Pray tell, what are the rules of the sea with regard to eunuchs?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Galley slaves, usually, and it's good to see the sea hasn't robbed you of all your spirit. Speaking of robbery, you did want to return to land, did you not?"[PARAGRAPH:1]She glared at him for a minute, then sighed, and said "Name your price, Sea-King. I need to reach my company at the Grigori border. Our contract has been... renegotiated, and if I don't inform my sergeants, the honor of the Hippus will indeed be worth little more than that of sea thieves."[PARAGRAPH:1]"There are a few trade contracts which could only draw us closer... as nations, of course. Awaiting just your signature here, dear lady." Rhoanna looked them over, muttering about extortion but made her mark.[PARAGRAPH:2]Falamar watched as Rhoanna and her companion bounded down the harbor, away from the Maiden's Delight and towards her duty. "Where to now, captain?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Not just yet, Sharwin." He kept watching, eventually a frown playing on his normally implacable visage. She was almost out of his sight. He began to reach for his spyglass.[PARAGRAPH:1]Rhoanna slowed at the edge of town. Slowed then stopped, and almost against her will, certainly against her better judgment, turned around. She gazed at the Lanun ship for several minutes, the wind pulling her hair towards the sea. Then she returned to her quest.[PARAGRAPH:1]Falamar smiled. "They always look back. Always. Sharwin, head for Balseraph waters. They have a vintage that should be ripening now."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HANNAH</Tag>
		<English>Hannah the Irin</English>
		<French>Hannah l'Irin</French>
		<German>Hannah die Irin</German>
		<Italian>Hannah la Irin</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hannah the Irin</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HANNAH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Dreamers, worthless vagrants whose only use was receiving the visions of the Overlords, surrounded the chamber. Each lay in a shallow recess, and 27 thin bone needles pierced them in different places. The needles were hollow and filled with wax from whale fat and unholy religious oils, while in each a wick burned. As the wax melted, it seeped down the needle into the dreamers' blood, this was what induced the visions.[PARAGRAPH:1]Most of what they said was gibberish, nightmares and twisted memories. They repeated verses to old lullabies, held conversations with imaginary people, and talked in languages no one could recognize. But occasionally it was more than that.[PARAGRAPH:1]These dreams were always preceded by the Dreamers screaming. New Zealots always considered opening themselves up to receive the dreams directly, to speak directly with the Overlords, until they heard the screams.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then the voice came, a variety of voices but never that of the Dreamer. The message was given, the Cultists would faithfully record it and worship at the sides of the recess. The Dreamer was always mentally scarred by the contact, most were only good for 2 or 3 visions before they were replaced.[PARAGRAPH:1]But there were rules to dealing with the dreamers, they were sacred objects. Their food was specially prepared, they were kept clean and groomed and they weren't exposed to any sound or sight that could distress them, until Cinnia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Cinnia was a favored dreamer of the Overlords, having received 7 visions and all the Cultists except Koun of the Ninth Ring agreed she was fit to receive more. Her 8th vision was her last, the Overlords spoke through her in three voices. One yelled in outrage threatening a great wave would destroy the city if atonement was not met. Another spoke of the future, of a human terror that would lead and destroy men, the "Kraken of Fields". The last voice screamed in pain, it was broken and the Cultists were never able to decipher its message, for it was cut off halfway through the messages of the other two.[PARAGRAPH:1]For weeks the Cultists debated the meanings of the visions. Koun argued that Cinnia should be killed, that her sacrifice was the atonement the Overlords demanded. Each day they watched the sea, fearful of a coming wave. Then the Cultists noticed that the sea was beginning to recede, to pull away from the city. The water was gathering somewhere distant, the wave was coming.[PARAGRAPH:1]They rushed to the chamber, worshipped beside Cinnia, asked for guidance on how to appease their masters. They stayed there until one of them noticed Cinnia's stomach had expanded slightly. A sorcerer confirmed it, she was pregnant.[PARAGRAPH:1]The rest of the day was chaos. A dreamer had been befouled, and only Cultists had access to them. Under threat and coercion they found who had done it: Koun of the Ninth Ring.[PARAGRAPH:1]Koun was sacrificed at the beach and the wave never came. Cinnia was taken from the chamber and tended to. She died in childbirth, but gave birth two girls, one was stillborn, the other survived.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Cultists decided that the child was too dangerous to be kept in the temple, so she was given to a Lanun ship captain to raise. He named her Hannah the Irin, after being told she was a twin whose mother and sister died in childbirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hannah became as temperamental and powerful as the sea itself. She left her fathers ship at 15 and led a mutiny against her next ship's captain to take it from him. That ship, which she renamed the 'Desecrated Vessel' became feared by military and merchant ships alike. When the time for war came, pirates flocked to her flag. Unaccustomed to central rule, the Lanun follow Hannah, too afraid to do otherwise.</English>
		<French>[TAB]Dreamers, worthless vagrants whose only use was receiving the visions of the Overlords, surrounded the chamber. Each lay in a shallow recess, and 27 thin bone needles pierced them in different places. The needles were hollow and filled with wax from whale fat and unholy religious oils, while in each a wick burned. As the wax melted, it seeped down the needle into the dreamers' blood, this was what induced the visions.[PARAGRAPH:1]Most of what they said was gibberish, nightmares and twisted memories. They repeated verses to old lullabies, held conversations with imaginary people, and talked in languages no one could recognize. But occasionally it was more than that.[PARAGRAPH:1]These dreams were always preceded by the Dreamers screaming. New Zealots always considered opening themselves up to receive the dreams directly, to speak directly with the Overlords, until they heard the screams.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then the voice came, a variety of voices but never that of the Dreamer. The message was given, the Cultists would faithfully record it and worship at the sides of the recess. The Dreamer was always mentally scarred by the contact, most were only good for 2 or 3 visions before they were replaced.[PARAGRAPH:1]But there were rules to dealing with the dreamers, they were sacred objects. Their food was specially prepared, they were kept clean and groomed and they weren't exposed to any sound or sight that could distress them, until Cinnia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Cinnia was a favored dreamer of the Overlords, having received 7 visions and all the Cultists except Koun of the Ninth Ring agreed she was fit to receive more. Her 8th vision was her last, the Overlords spoke through her in three voices. One yelled in outrage threatening a great wave would destroy the city if atonement was not met. Another spoke of the future, of a human terror that would lead and destroy men, the "Kraken of Fields". The last voice screamed in pain, it was broken and the Cultists were never able to decipher its message, for it was cut off halfway through the messages of the other two.[PARAGRAPH:1]For weeks the Cultists debated the meanings of the visions. Koun argued that Cinnia should be killed, that her sacrifice was the atonement the Overlords demanded. Each day they watched the sea, fearful of a coming wave. Then the Cultists noticed that the sea was beginning to recede, to pull away from the city. The water was gathering somewhere distant, the wave was coming.[PARAGRAPH:1]They rushed to the chamber, worshipped beside Cinnia, asked for guidance on how to appease their masters. They stayed there until one of them noticed Cinnia's stomach had expanded slightly. A sorcerer confirmed it, she was pregnant.[PARAGRAPH:1]The rest of the day was chaos. A dreamer had been befouled, and only Cultists had access to them. Under threat and coercion they found who had done it: Koun of the Ninth Ring.[PARAGRAPH:1]Koun was sacrificed at the beach and the wave never came. Cinnia was taken from the chamber and tended to. She died in childbirth, but gave birth two girls, one was stillborn, the other survived.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Cultists decided that the child was too dangerous to be kept in the temple, so she was given to a Lanun ship captain to raise. He named her Hannah the Irin, after being told she was a twin whose mother and sister died in childbirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hannah became as temperamental and powerful as the sea itself. She left her fathers ship at 15 and led a mutiny against her next ship's captain to take it from him. That ship, which she renamed the 'Desecrated Vessel' became feared by military and merchant ships alike. When the time for war came, pirates flocked to her flag. Unaccustomed to central rule, the Lanun follow Hannah, too afraid to do otherwise.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Träumer, wertlose Landstreicher, deren einziger Zweck darin bestand, die Visionen der Schatten zu empfangen, umgaben die Kammer. Ein jeder lag in einer flachen Nische, 27 dünne Knochennadeln hielten sie an verschiedenen Orten fest. Diese Nadeln waren hohl und mit Wachs aus Waltran und unheiligen Ölen gefüllt, in einer jeden brannte ein Docht. Wenn das Wachs schmolz, tropfte es durch die Nadeln in das Blut der Träumer, so entstanden in ihnen die Visionen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Das meiste von dem Gesagten war Unfug, Alpträume und verworrene Erinnerungen. Sie wiederholten alte Kinderreime, sprachen mit unsichtbaren Leuten und redeten in unerkennbaren Sprachen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Aber gelegentlich war es mehr.[PARAGRAPH:1] Diese Träume wurden vorangekündigt durch die Schreie der Träumenden. Neue Fanatiker beabsichtigten immer, sich direkt den Schatten zu öffnen, bis sie die Schreie hörten.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dann kam die Stimme, eine Vielzahl von Stimmen, aber niemals jene des Träumers. Die Botschaft wurde überbracht, die Priester zeichneten sie ehrfürchtig auf und verehrten sie an den Seiten der Nischen. Die Träumer wurden immer geistig beansprucht, viele waren nur für zwei bis drei Visionen zu gebrauchen bevor sie ersetzt wurden.[PARAGRAPH:1] Es gab jedoch Regeln über den Umgang mit Träumern, sie waren heilige Objekte. Ihre Nahrung wurde speziell zubereitet, sie wurden gesäubert und gepflegt und auch keinem Geräusch oder Anblick ausgesetzt, der sie stören könnte. Bis auf Cinnia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Cinnia war eine bevorzugte Träumerin der Schatten, sie hatte schon sieben Visionen und alle Priester außer Koun von neunten Ring hielten sie für geeignet für noch mehr. Die letzte Vision war ihre achte, die Schatten sprachen durch sie mit drei Stimmen. Eine schrie voll Empörung und drohte, daß eine große Woge die Stadt zerstören werde, wenn keine Buße erfolgt. Eine andere sprach von der Zukunft, von einem menschlichen Schrecken, der die Menschheit zerstören würde, dem "Kraken der Felder". Die letzte Stimme schrie vor Schmerz, die Priester waren unfähig, diese Botschaft zu verstehen, sie war ab der Hälfte abgeschnitten worden durch die beiden anderen Botschaften.[PARAGRAPH:1] Wochenlang diskutierten die Priester die Bedeutung der Visionen. Koun schlug vor, Cinnia zu töten, ihr Opfer wäre die geforderte Buße. Jeden Tag beobachteten sie das Meer aus Furcht vor der Woge. Dann bemerkten die Priester, daß sich das Meer von der Stadt zurückzog. Das Wasser sammelte sich anderswo, die Woge war im kommen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie liefen zur Kammer, knieten neben Cinnia und flehten um Anleitung, wie sie ihre Meister besänftigen sollen. Sie blieben dort bis sie feststellten, daß sich Cinnias Bauch leicht gewölbt hatte. Ein Zauberer bestätigte es, sie war schwanger.[PARAGRAPH:1]Der Rest des Tages war Chaos. Ein Träumer war entweiht worden und ausschließlich Priester hatten Zugang. Unter Gewalt und Drohungen fanden sie den Täter: Koun vom neunten Ring.[PARAGRAPH:1]Koun wurde am Strand geopfert und die Woge blieb aus. Cinnia wurde aus der Kammer geholt und gepflegt. Sie gebar zwei Mädchen, eines tot, das andere lebte und starb selbst im Kindbett.[PARAGRAPH:1]Die Priester entschieden, daß es zu gefährlich war, dieses Kind im Tempel zu behalten. Sie gaben es daher einem Lanun Schiffskapitän zum Aufziehen. Er nannte sie Hannah die Irin, nachdem er erfahren hatte, daß ihre Mutter und ihre Schwester bei der Geburt gestorben waren.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hannah wurde launisch und kräftig wie die See selbst. Mit 15 verließ sie das Schiff ihres Vaters und führte eine Meuterei gegen den Kapitän des nächsten Schiffs an. So kam sie zu ihrem eigenen Schiff, der "Entweihten", die bald von allen Kriegs- und Handelsschiffen gefürchtet war. Zur Kriegszeit versammelten sich die Lanun unter ihrer Flagge, nicht an eine zentrale Führung gewohnt und ängstlich, anderes zu tun, folgten die Lanun Hannah.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Sognatori, vagabondi senza valore il cui unico scopo era ricevere le visioni dei Padroni, contornavano la stanza. Ognuno giaceva in una nicchia poco profonda, e 27 sottili aghi d'osso li perforavano in diversi punti. Gli aghi erano cavi e riempiti con cera di grasso di balena e empi oli religiosi mentre in ognuno uno stoppino bruciava. Quando la cera si scioglieva scendeva nell'ago e entrava nel flusso sanguigno del sognatore, era questo a indurre le visioni.[PARAGRAPH:1]La maggior parte di quello che dicevano erano parole incomprensibili, incubi e ricordi distorti. Ripetevano versi di vecchie ninne nanne, conversavano con persone immaginarie e parlavano linguaggi che nessuno riusciva a riconoscere. Ma a volte dicevano altro.[PARAGRAPH:1]Questi sogni erano sempre preceduti dall'urlo del sognatore. I nuovi Zeloti contemplavano sempre la possibilità di aprire loro stessi per ricevere i sogni direttamente, per pralare direttamente con i Padroni, solo fino a quando non sentivano le urla.[PARAGRAPH:1]Poi la voce giungeva, in realtà una varietà di voci ma mai quella del sognatore. Il messaggio veniva consegnato, e i Cultisti lo avrebbero trascritto e venerato ai bordi della nicchia. Il sognatore rimaneva sempre segnato dal contatto, la maggior parte erano buoni solo per 2 o 3 visioni prima di dover venire sostituiti.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ma vi erano delle regole per avere a che fare con i sognatori, loro erano oggetti sacri. Il loro cibo era preparato appositamente per loro, venivano mantenuti puliti e curati e non venivano esposti ad alcun suono o vista che potesse influenzarli, fino a Cinnia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Cinnia era una sognatrice favorita dai Padroni, avendo ricevuto 7 visioni e tutti i cultisti, tranne Koun del Nono Anello, erano concordi che era capace di riceverne altre. La sua 8° visione fu l'ultima, i Padroni parlarono attraverso di lei con tre voci. Una urlava adirata minacciando di distruggere la città con una grande onda se non si espiava qualcosa. Un'altra parlava del futuro, di un terrore umano che avrebbe guidato e distrutto gli uomini, il "Kraken dei Campi". L'ultima voce urlava di dolore, era frammentaria e i Cultisti non erano riusciti a decifrare il messaggio, in quanto fu interrotta a metà strada dai messaggi delle altre due.[PARAGRAPH:1]Per settimane i Cultisti discusserò del significato delle visioni. Koun sosteneva che Cinnia doveva essere uccisa, che il suo sacrificio era l'espiazione che i Padroni esigevano. Ogni giorno guardavano il mare, timorosi dell'onda. Poi i Cultisti notarono che il mare stava iniziando a ritrarsi, allontanandosi dalla città. L'acqua stava ammassandosi da qualche parte lontano, l'onda stava arrivando.[PARAGRAPH:1]Corserò nella stanza, pregando vicino a Cinnia chiesero indicazioni su come placare i loro padroni. Rimasero li fino a quando uno di loro notò che lo stomaco di Cinnia si era leggermente mosso. Un incantatore lo confermò, lei era incinta.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il resto del giorno fù il caos. Una sognatrice era stata profanata, e solo i Cultisti avevano accesso a loro. Con minaccie e coercizioni scoprirono chi era stato: Koun del Nono Anello.[PARAGRAPH:1]Koun fù sacrificato sulla spiaggia e l'onda non arrivò mai. Cinnia fù rimossa dalla stanza e accudita. Lei morì di parto, ma diede alla luce due bambine, una era nata morta, ma l'altra sopravvissè.[PARAGRAPH:1]I Cultisti decisero che la bambina era troppo pericolosa per rimanere nel tempio, quindi fù affidata a un capitano Lanun per farla crescere. Lui la chiamò Hannah la Irin, dopo che gli fù detto che lei era una gemella la cui madre e sorella erano morte durante il parto.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hannah divenne volubile e potente come il mare stesso. Abbandonò la nave del padre a 15 anni e guidò un'ammutinamento contro il capitano della seconda nave in cui era salita. Tale nave, che lei rinominò 'Desecrated Vessel' divenne temuta sia dalle navi militari che mercantili. Quando la guerra arrivò, i pirati andarono da lei. Non abituati a un controllo centrale, i Lanun seguono Hannah in quanto troppo spaventati per fare diversamente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]Dreamers, worthless vagrants whose only use was receiving the visions of the Overlords, surrounded the chamber. Each lay in a shallow recess, and 27 thin bone needles pierced them in different places. The needles were hollow and filled with wax from whale fat and unholy religious oils, while in each a wick burned. As the wax melted, it seeped down the needle into the dreamers' blood, this was what induced the visions.[PARAGRAPH:1]Most of what they said was gibberish, nightmares and twisted memories. They repeated verses to old lullabies, held conversations with imaginary people, and talked in languages no one could recognize. But occasionally it was more than that.[PARAGRAPH:1]These dreams were always preceded by the Dreamers screaming. New Zealots always considered opening themselves up to receive the dreams directly, to speak directly with the Overlords, until they heard the screams.[PARAGRAPH:1]Then the voice came, a variety of voices but never that of the Dreamer. The message was given, the Cultists would faithfully record it and worship at the sides of the recess. The Dreamer was always mentally scarred by the contact, most were only good for 2 or 3 visions before they were replaced.[PARAGRAPH:1]But there were rules to dealing with the dreamers, they were sacred objects. Their food was specially prepared, they were kept clean and groomed and they weren't exposed to any sound or sight that could distress them, until Cinnia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Cinnia was a favored dreamer of the Overlords, having received 7 visions and all the Cultists except Koun of the Ninth Ring agreed she was fit to receive more. Her 8th vision was her last, the Overlords spoke through her in three voices. One yelled in outrage threatening a great wave would destroy the city if atonement was not met. Another spoke of the future, of a human terror that would lead and destroy men, the "Kraken of Fields". The last voice screamed in pain, it was broken and the Cultists were never able to decipher its message, for it was cut off halfway through the messages of the other two.[PARAGRAPH:1]For weeks the Cultists debated the meanings of the visions. Koun argued that Cinnia should be killed, that her sacrifice was the atonement the Overlords demanded. Each day they watched the sea, fearful of a coming wave. Then the Cultists noticed that the sea was beginning to recede, to pull away from the city. The water was gathering somewhere distant, the wave was coming.[PARAGRAPH:1]They rushed to the chamber, worshipped beside Cinnia, asked for guidance on how to appease their masters. They stayed there until one of them noticed Cinnia's stomach had expanded slightly. A sorcerer confirmed it, she was pregnant.[PARAGRAPH:1]The rest of the day was chaos. A dreamer had been befouled, and only Cultists had access to them. Under threat and coercion they found who had done it: Koun of the Ninth Ring.[PARAGRAPH:1]Koun was sacrificed at the beach and the wave never came. Cinnia was taken from the chamber and tended to. She died in childbirth, but gave birth two girls, one was stillborn, the other survived.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Cultists decided that the child was too dangerous to be kept in the temple, so she was given to a Lanun ship captain to raise. He named her Hannah the Irin, after being told she was a twin whose mother and sister died in childbirth.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hannah became as temperamental and powerful as the sea itself. She left her fathers ship at 15 and led a mutiny against her next ship's captain to take it from him. That ship, which she renamed the 'Desecrated Vessel' became feared by military and merchant ships alike. When the time for war came, pirates flocked to her flag. Unaccustomed to central rule, the Lanun follow Hannah, too afraid to do otherwise.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MORDMORGAN</Tag>
		<English>Mordmorgan</English>
		<French>Mordmorgan</French>
		<German>Mordmorgan</German>
		<Italian>Mordmorgan</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mordmorgan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MORDMORGAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Elohim merchant vessel had been almost too easy to capture. The pirate vessel had snuck up on them silently in the mist, wrecking their mast with the first broadside before the merchants even knew they where in danger. Pirates grinned as they drew alongside and readied grappling hooks; the merchant crew screamed and ran into their cabins in senseless terror.[PARAGRAPH:1]The captain came on board personally with the first wave. A woman had been spotted fleeing into the main cabin, and the captain liked to claim such prizes personally. His crew dispersed below decks to ferret out the fleeing merchant cowards that had abandoned their posts. The captain kicked down the door with a fearsome and bellowing laugh that he reserved for inspire terror in his prisoners. Stretched out on the desk of the main cabin was, indeed, a woman's dress, but it was empty. Just then a call came out from behind him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Captain! The mast!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"What about it?" He bellowed.[PARAGRAPH:1]"It's armor plated! It only fell over because it's on a hinge!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The captain's heart fell at those words. Courage turned to fear as he suddenly noticed that none of his men had yet returned from the lower decks. He opened his mouth to call for a retreat, but was silenced by the feel of cold steel against his throat. He turned his head, slowly and carefully, and saw the man who had hidden in the rafters above the door. His hair was long and grey, but he moved with a grace unusual for his age. He spoke with a dignified and cultured accent, gained from the years he had spent as a spice trader on the mainland.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am Captain Mordmorgan. Your men appear to be trespassing, a crime that bears serious penalties on the high seas. I do hope you and your crew know how to swim... it is two miles to the nearest island."[PARAGRAPH:2]Mordmorgan was a kind man, at least in comparison to others in his chosen profession: he left the pirates with enough barrels to stay afloat until land. He watched them recede into the mist for a moment, then turned to his first mate.[PARAGRAPH:1]"How many were willing to swear off a life of crime and commit to penance?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Only four, captain, this was a rough lot we caught today."[PARAGRAPH:1]"All the better that they are off the seas, then. How is my ship?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"The Stolen Thunder has a few dings on her, but nothing serious. We picked up more than enough scrap to repair her before we scuttled the pirates. That mast plating took a direct hit, but there's nary a scratch on it. How you talked the dwarves out of it I'll never know."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Trade secret, my friend, you know that. Were there any serious injuries among the crew?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"One man took a nasty blow to his arm, but the doctor has him patched up just fine. Everyone else is ready to go."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bring up the Malakim flag next; there's a fleet five days to the north heading for one of their colonies. We'll play the straggler and see who bites." </English>
		<French>[TAB]The Elohim merchant vessel had been almost too easy to capture. The pirate vessel had snuck up on them silently in the mist, wrecking their mast with the first broadside before the merchants even knew they where in danger. Pirates grinned as they drew alongside and readied grappling hooks; the merchant crew screamed and ran into their cabins in senseless terror.[PARAGRAPH:1]The captain came on board personally with the first wave. A woman had been spotted fleeing into the main cabin, and the captain liked to claim such prizes personally. His crew dispersed below decks to ferret out the fleeing merchant cowards that had abandoned their posts. The captain kicked down the door with a fearsome and bellowing laugh that he reserved for inspire terror in his prisoners. Stretched out on the desk of the main cabin was, indeed, a woman's dress, but it was empty. Just then a call came out from behind him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Captain! The mast!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"What about it?" He bellowed.[PARAGRAPH:1]"It's armor plated! It only fell over because it's on a hinge!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The captain's heart fell at those words. Courage turned to fear as he suddenly noticed that none of his men had yet returned from the lower decks. He opened his mouth to call for a retreat, but was silenced by the feel of cold steel against his throat. He turned his head, slowly and carefully, and saw the man who had hidden in the rafters above the door. His hair was long and grey, but he moved with a grace unusual for his age. He spoke with a dignified and cultured accent, gained from the years he had spent as a spice trader on the mainland.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am Captain Mordmorgan. Your men appear to be trespassing, a crime that bears serious penalties on the high seas. I do hope you and your crew know how to swim; it is two miles to the nearest island."[PARAGRAPH:2]Mordmorgan was a kind man, at least in comparison to others in his chosen profession; he left the pirates with enough barrels to stay afloat until land. He watched them recede into the mist for a moment, then turned to his first mate.[PARAGRAPH:1]"How many were willing to swear off a life of crime and commit to penance?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Only four, captain, this was a rough lot we caught today."[PARAGRAPH:1]"All the better that they are off the seas, then. How is my ship?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"The Stolen Thunder has a few dings on her, but nothing serious. We picked up more than enough scrap to repair her before we scuttled the pirates. That mast plating took a direct hit, but there's nary a scratch on it. How you talked the dwarves out of it I'll never know."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Trade secret, my friend, you know that. Were there any serious injuries among the crew?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"One man took a nasty blow to his arm, but the doctor has him patched up just fine. Everyone else is ready to go."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bring up the Malakim flag next; there's a fleet five days to the north heading for one of their colonies. We'll play the straggler and see who bites." </French>
		<German>[TAB]The Elohim merchant vessel had been almost too easy to capture. The pirate vessel had snuck up on them silently in the mist, wrecking their mast with the first broadside before the merchants even knew they where in danger. Pirates grinned as they drew alongside and readied grappling hooks; the merchant crew screamed and ran into their cabins in senseless terror.[PARAGRAPH:1]The captain came on board personally with the first wave. A woman had been spotted fleeing into the main cabin, and the captain liked to claim such prizes personally. His crew dispersed below decks to ferret out the fleeing merchant cowards that had abandoned their posts. The captain kicked down the door with a fearsome and bellowing laugh that he reserved for inspire terror in his prisoners. Stretched out on the desk of the main cabin was, indeed, a woman's dress, but it was empty. Just then a call came out from behind him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Captain! The mast!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"What about it?" He bellowed.[PARAGRAPH:1]"It's armor plated! It only fell over because it's on a hinge!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The captain's heart fell at those words. Courage turned to fear as he suddenly noticed that none of his men had yet returned from the lower decks. He opened his mouth to call for a retreat, but was silenced by the feel of cold steel against his throat. He turned his head, slowly and carefully, and saw the man who had hidden in the rafters above the door. His hair was long and grey, but he moved with a grace unusual for his age. He spoke with a dignified and cultured accent, gained from the years he had spent as a spice trader on the mainland.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am Captain Mordmorgan. Your men appear to be trespassing, a crime that bears serious penalties on the high seas. I do hope you and your crew know how to swim; it is two miles to the nearest island."[PARAGRAPH:2]Mordmorgan was a kind man, at least in comparison to others in his chosen profession; he left the pirates with enough barrels to stay afloat until land. He watched them recede into the mist for a moment, then turned to his first mate.[PARAGRAPH:1]"How many were willing to swear off a life of crime and commit to penance?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Only four, captain, this was a rough lot we caught today."[PARAGRAPH:1]"All the better that they are off the seas, then. How is my ship?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"The Stolen Thunder has a few dings on her, but nothing serious. We picked up more than enough scrap to repair her before we scuttled the pirates. That mast plating took a direct hit, but there's nary a scratch on it. How you talked the dwarves out of it I'll never know."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Trade secret, my friend, you know that. Were there any serious injuries among the crew?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"One man took a nasty blow to his arm, but the doctor has him patched up just fine. Everyone else is ready to go."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bring up the Malakim flag next; there's a fleet five days to the north heading for one of their colonies. We'll play the straggler and see who bites." </German>
		<Italian>[TAB]Il vascello mercantile Elohim era stato quasi troppo facile da catturare. Il vascello pirata si era nascosto in silenzio nella nebbia, distruggendo il loro albero maestro con la prima bordata prima ancora che i mercanti realizzassero che erano in pericolo. I pirati sorrisero mentre preparavano i rampini per l'arrembraggio; l'equipaggio del mercantile invece correva urlando nelle loro cabine in preda al terrore.[PARAGRAPH:1]Il capitano salì a bordo del mercantile con la prima ondata. Una donna era stata vista correre nella cabina principale, e al capitano piaceva rivendicare tali bottini di persona. Il suo equipaggio si sparpagliò per i ponti inferiori per recuperare i codardi del mercantile che avevano abbandonato i loro posti. Il capitano sfondò la porta della cabina con un calcio mentre nello stesso tempo rideva in maniera da inspirare terrore nei suoi prigionieri. Steso sulla scrivania della cabina vi era, in effetti, un vestito da donna, ma era vuoto. Proprio in quel momento qualcuno lo chaimava da dietro.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Capitano! L'albero!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Cosa c'è?" rispose urlando.[PARAGRAPH:1]"È corazzato! È caduto solo perche è su un cardine!"[PARAGRAPH:1]Il cuore del capitano sprofondò a quelle parole. Il coraggio si trasformò in paura e improvvisamente notò che nessuno dei suoi uomini era tornato dai ponti inferiori. Fece per aprire la bocca per ordinare la ritirata, ma fù bloccato dalla sensazione del freddo acciaio sulla sua gola. Voltò la testa, lentamente e cautamente, e vide l'uomo che si era nascosto tra le travi sopra la porta. I suoi capelli erano lunghi e grigi, ma si muoveva con una grazia innaturale per la sua età. Parlò con un'accento colto e solenne, sviluppato negli anni che aveva passato a commerciare spezie sulla terraferma.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Io sono il Capitano Mordmorgan. Sembra che i vostri uomini stiano sconfinando, un crimine che comporta serie conseguenze in alto mare. Spero che voi e i vostri uomini sappiate nuotare; sono due miglia da qui all'isola più vicina."[PARAGRAPH:2]Mordmorgan era un'uomo gentile, almeno in confronto ai suoi colleghi; abbandonò i pirati con abbastanza barili per farli galleggiare sino alla terraferma. Li osservò svanire nella nebbia per un momento, poi si voltò verso il suo primo ufficiale.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Quanti sono disposti ad abbandonare una vita di crimini e fare penitenza?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Solo quattro, capitano, il gruppo che abbiamo catturato oggi era particolarmente violento".[PARAGRAPH:1]"Tanto meglio che non sono più sui mari allora. Come sta la mia nave?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"La Stolen Thunder ha qualche ammaccatura, ma nulla di serio. Abbiamo preso abbastanza pezzi per ripararla prima di affondare quella dei pirati. La corazza dell'albero è stata colpita duramente, ma vi è a malapena un graffio. Come hai fatto a convincere i nani a fartela non lo capirò mai".[PARAGRAPH:1]"Segreto professionale, amico mio, lo sai. Vi sono stati feriti gravi tra l'equipaggio?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Uno ha preso un brutto taglio sul braccio, ma il dottore lo ha rappezzato bene. Tutti gli altri sono pronti a partire".[PARAGRAPH:1]"Issa la bandiera Malakim; vi è una loro flotta a cinque giorni più a nord diretta verso una delle loro colonie. Giocheremo al ritardatario e vedremo chi abbocca".</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]The Elohim merchant vessel had been almost too easy to capture. The pirate vessel had snuck up on them silently in the mist, wrecking their mast with the first broadside before the merchants even knew they where in danger. Pirates grinned as they drew alongside and readied grappling hooks; the merchant crew screamed and ran into their cabins in senseless terror.[PARAGRAPH:1]The captain came on board personally with the first wave. A woman had been spotted fleeing into the main cabin, and the captain liked to claim such prizes personally. His crew dispersed below decks to ferret out the fleeing merchant cowards that had abandoned their posts. The captain kicked down the door with a fearsome and bellowing laugh that he reserved for inspire terror in his prisoners. Stretched out on the desk of the main cabin was, indeed, a woman's dress, but it was empty. Just then a call came out from behind him.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Captain! The mast!"[PARAGRAPH:1]"What about it?" He bellowed.[PARAGRAPH:1]"It's armor plated! It only fell over because it's on a hinge!"[PARAGRAPH:1]The captain's heart fell at those words. Courage turned to fear as he suddenly noticed that none of his men had yet returned from the lower decks. He opened his mouth to call for a retreat, but was silenced by the feel of cold steel against his throat. He turned his head, slowly and carefully, and saw the man who had hidden in the rafters above the door. His hair was long and grey, but he moved with a grace unusual for his age. He spoke with a dignified and cultured accent, gained from the years he had spent as a spice trader on the mainland.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am Captain Mordmorgan. Your men appear to be trespassing, a crime that bears serious penalties on the high seas. I do hope you and your crew know how to swim; it is two miles to the nearest island."[PARAGRAPH:2]Mordmorgan was a kind man, at least in comparison to others in his chosen profession; he left the pirates with enough barrels to stay afloat until land. He watched them recede into the mist for a moment, then turned to his first mate.[PARAGRAPH:1]"How many were willing to swear off a life of crime and commit to penance?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"Only four, captain, this was a rough lot we caught today."[PARAGRAPH:1]"All the better that they are off the seas, then. How is my ship?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"The Stolen Thunder has a few dings on her, but nothing serious. We picked up more than enough scrap to repair her before we scuttled the pirates. That mast plating took a direct hit, but there's nary a scratch on it. How you talked the dwarves out of it I'll never know."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Trade secret, my friend, you know that. Were there any serious injuries among the crew?"[PARAGRAPH:1]"One man took a nasty blow to his arm, but the doctor has him patched up just fine. Everyone else is ready to go."[PARAGRAPH:1]"Bring up the Malakim flag next; there's a fleet five days to the north heading for one of their colonies. We'll play the straggler and see who bites." </Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RAGING_SEAS</Tag>
		<English>Raging Seas</English>
		<French>Océans Déchainés</French>
		<German>Tobende See</German>
		<Italian>Mari Furiosi</Italian>
		<Spanish>Raging Seas</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_SPELL_RAGING_SEAS_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Does damage to all non-Lanun units that are near oceans and has a chance to destroy enemy improvements</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Endommage toutes les unités non-Lanun proches des océans</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Beschädigt alle Einheiten außer die der Lanun, wenn sich sich in Ozeannähe aufhalten</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Danneggia tutte le unità non Lanun vicino ai mari e ha una probabilità di distruggere i miglioramenti nemici</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Does damage to all non-Lanun units that are near oceans</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HARBOR_LANUN</Tag>
		<English>Sea Haven</English>
		<French>Port lanouniste</French>
		<German>Seehafen</German>
		<Italian>Porto Lanun</Italian>
		<Spanish>Puerto Lanun</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_LANUN</Tag>
		<English>Lanun Palace</English>
		<French>Palais lanouniste</French>
		<German>Palast der Lanun</German>
		<Italian>Palazzo dei Lanun</Italian>
		<Spanish>Palacio Lanun</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BLACK_WIND</Tag>
		<English>The Black Wind</English>
		<French>Le Vent Noir</French>
		<German>Schwarzer Wind</German>
		<Italian>La Vento Nero</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Black Wind</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BLACK_WIND_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Listen me hearties an' I'll sing ye the tale,[NEWLINE]of the a fearsome ship, aye, Hell did send [NEWLINE]out of the depths, in a midnight gale.[NEWLINE]The fabled vessel name o' Black Wind.[NEWLINE]Cunning was the captain[NEWLINE]Of this dauntless vessel fair,[NEWLINE]Though they never plundered but a coin,[NEWLINE]'twas always 'nough to share![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The boat herself was a sturdy old gel,[NEWLINE]Nigh invincible they'll tell you,[NEWLINE]Her hull was strong, and the mast as well,[NEWLINE]She could take whatever you'd do.[NEWLINE]Why they say she rammed a Queen O' the line[NEWLINE]Cloaked in the fog, dead a-winter[NEWLINE]You think that stopped a ship this fine?[NEWLINE]Well-least they had a carpenter![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The crew was brave, the terror o' the seas,[NEWLINE]Hardened men of every stripe,[NEWLINE]The bounty on them could have pleased[NEWLINE]Even the greediest type.[NEWLINE]O'l Black Wind 's crew was the boldest lot,[NEWLINE]That's why they're in our chantey's,[NEWLINE]This verse goes out to their wildest plot,[NEWLINE]When they stole ol' Hannah's panties![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navies![NEWLINE][NEWLINE][TAB]-Lanun Pirate Chantey</English>
		<French>Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Listen me hearties an' I'll sing ye the tale,[NEWLINE]of the a fearsome ship, aye, Hell did send [NEWLINE]out of the depths, in a midnight gale.[NEWLINE]The fabled vessel name o' Black Wind.[NEWLINE]Cunning was the captain[NEWLINE]Of this dauntless vessel fair,[NEWLINE]Though they never plundered but a coin,[NEWLINE]'twas always 'nough to share![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The boat herself was a sturdy old gel,[NEWLINE]Nigh invincible they'll tell you,[NEWLINE]Her hull was strong, and the mast as well,[NEWLINE]She could take whatever you'd do.[NEWLINE]Why they say she rammed a Queen O' the line[NEWLINE]Cloaked in the fog, dead a-winter[NEWLINE]You think that stopped a ship this fine?[NEWLINE]Well-least they had a carpenter![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The crew was brave, the terror o' the seas,[NEWLINE]Hardened men of every stripe,[NEWLINE]The bounty on them could have pleased[NEWLINE]Even the greediest type.[NEWLINE]O'l Black Wind 's crew was the boldest lot,[NEWLINE]That's why they're in our chantey's,[NEWLINE]This verse goes out to their wildest plot,[NEWLINE]When they stole ol' Hannah's panties![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navies![NEWLINE][NEWLINE][TAB]-Lanun Pirate Chantey</French>
		<German>Und hebt, und hoch, und nichts wie los, schneller als du sie wirst sehn![NEWLINE]Und hebt, und hoch, und nichts wie los, schneller als die Marine kann gehn![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ich werd Euch singen ne Geschicht, so hört mir zu, ihr Süßen,[NEWLINE]von nem furchtbarn Schiff, aus der Höll' gesandt [NEWLINE]im Mitternachts Sturm, aus ihren Tiefen.[NEWLINE]Schwarzer Wind ward die Legend genannt.[NEWLINE]Listig der Kaptain war[NEWLINE]diesem furchtlosen Schiff angemessen,[NEWLINE]Obwohl sie niemals raubten n Salar,[NEWLINE]haben sie doch immer genug zum Teilen besesssen![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Und hebt, und hoch, und nichts wie los, schneller als du sie wirst sehn![NEWLINE]Und hebt, und hoch, und nichts wie los, schneller als die Marine kann gehn![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Das Schiff selbst war ein strammes altes Mädel,[NEWLINE]Fast unüberwindlich werden sie Dir sagen,[NEWLINE]Ihr Rumpf war stark und auch der Mast ward ohne Tadel,[NEWLINE]Sie konnt ertragen was immer Du wolltst wagen.[NEWLINE]Weshalb sie sagen, dass sie rammte der Linienschiffe Königin.[NEWLINE]Verborgen im Nebel, Tod im Winter.[NEWLINE]Du denkst dies stoppte ein Schiff wie dies so fein?[NEWLINE]Nun Gut - sie hatten zumindest einen Zimmerer![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Und hebt, und hoch, und nichts wie los, schneller als du sie wirst sehn![NEWLINE]Und hebt, und hoch, und nichts wie los, schneller als die Marine kann gehn![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Die Mannschaft war mutig, der Meere Schrecken,[NEWLINE]Abgehärtete Kerle von jeglicher Couleur,[NEWLINE]Das Kopfgeld von ihnen hätt könn beglücken[NEWLINE]Selbst den habgierigsten Gauner.[NEWLINE]Der altn Schwarzen Wind Crew ward der kühnste Trupp,[NEWLINE]Deswegen sind sie in unserem Gesang,[NEWLINE]Dieser Vers endet mit ihrem wildesten Komplott,[NEWLINE]Als sie stahl'n alt Hannahs Höschen.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Und hebt, und hoch, und nichts wie los, schneller als du sie wirst sehn![NEWLINE]Und hebt, und hoch, und nichts wie los, schneller als die Marine kann gehn![NEWLINE][NEWLINE][TAB] - Lanunisches Piratenlied</German>
		<Italian>Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Listen me hearties an' I'll sing ye the tale,[NEWLINE]of the a fearsome ship, aye, Hell did send [NEWLINE]out of the depths, in a midnight gale.[NEWLINE]The fabled vessel name o' Black Wind.[NEWLINE]Cunning was the captain[NEWLINE]Of this dauntless vessel fair,[NEWLINE]Though they never plundered but a coin,[NEWLINE]'twas always 'nough to share![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The boat herself was a sturdy old gel,[NEWLINE]Nigh invincible they'll tell you,[NEWLINE]Her hull was strong, and the mast as well,[NEWLINE]She could take whatever you'd do.[NEWLINE]Why they say she rammed a Queen O' the line[NEWLINE]Cloaked in the fog, dead a-winter[NEWLINE]You think that stopped a ship this fine?[NEWLINE]Well-least they had a carpenter![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The crew was brave, the terror o' the seas,[NEWLINE]Hardened men of every stripe,[NEWLINE]The bounty on them could have pleased[NEWLINE]Even the greediest type.[NEWLINE]O'l Black Wind 's crew was the boldest lot,[NEWLINE]That's why they're in our chantey's,[NEWLINE]This verse goes out to their wildest plot,[NEWLINE]When they stole ol' Hannah's panties![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navies![NEWLINE][NEWLINE][TAB]-Canto marinaresco dei pirati Lanun</Italian>
		<Spanish>Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Listen me hearties an' I'll sing ye the tale,[NEWLINE]of the a fearsome ship, aye, Hell did send [NEWLINE]out of the depths, in a midnight gale.[NEWLINE]The fabled vessel name o' Black Wind.[NEWLINE]Cunning was the captain[NEWLINE]Of this dauntless vessel fair,[NEWLINE]Though they never plundered but a coin,[NEWLINE]'twas always 'nough to share![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The boat herself was a sturdy old gel,[NEWLINE]Nigh invincible they'll tell you,[NEWLINE]Her hull was strong, and the mast as well,[NEWLINE]She could take whatever you'd do.[NEWLINE]Why they say she rammed a Queen O' the line[NEWLINE]Cloaked in the fog, dead a-winter[NEWLINE]You think that stopped a ship this fine?[NEWLINE]Well-least they had a carpenter![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navy![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The crew was brave, the terror o' the seas,[NEWLINE]Hardened men of every stripe,[NEWLINE]The bounty on them could have pleased[NEWLINE]Even the greediest type.[NEWLINE]O'l Black Wind 's crew was the boldest lot,[NEWLINE]That's why they're in our chantey's,[NEWLINE]This verse goes out to their wildest plot,[NEWLINE]When they stole ol' Hannah's panties![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than you'll e'er see![NEWLINE]Oh, heave and ho, and away we go, faster than the navies![NEWLINE][NEWLINE][TAB]-Lanun Pirate Chantey</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BLACK_WIND_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Starting with hidden nationality and hero allows the Black Wind to become the terror of the seas, regardless of any landlubber "treaties."</English>
		<French>Commençant avec la promotion Nationalité Cachée et Héros, le Vent Noir peut devenir la terreur des mers, indépendamment de tout traité terrien.</French>
		<German>Mit der Beförderung Held und versteckter Nationalität beginnend, erlaubt es der Schwarzwasserwind zum Terror der Meere zu werden, unabhängig von jeglichen Verträgen der Landratten.</German>
		<Italian>Iniziare con Nazionalità Nascosta ed Eroe permette alla Vento Nero di diventare il terrore dei mari, indipendentemente da qualsiasi "trattato" della terraferma.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Starting with hidden nationality and hero allows the Black Wind to become the terror of the seas, regardless of any landlubber "treaties."</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOARDING_PARTY</Tag>
		<English>Boarding Party</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Escouade d'Abordage:Escouades d'Abordage</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Entermannschaft</German>
		<Italian>Squadra d'Abbordaggio</Italian>
		<Spanish>Boarding Party</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOARDING_PARTY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Most of the Lanun army is conscripted to serve as deckhands at one time or another. Those that show aptitude at sea are trained to be boarding parties, fearless (after enough grog) and deadly (at least on sea) these sea monkeys are ever eager to swing to an enemy vessel and dispatch the crew, claiming the prize for themselves.</English>
		<French>Most of the Lanun army is conscripted to serve as deckhands at one time or another. Those that show aptitude at sea are trained to be boarding parties, fearless (after enough grog) and deadly (at least on sea) these sea monkeys are ever eager to swing to an enemy vessel and dispatch the crew, claiming the prize for themselves.</French>
		<German>Die meisten aus der Lanun Armee sind verpflichtet mindestens einmal als Matrosen zu dienen. Diejenigen, die eine Eignung fürs Meer zeigen, werden ausgebildet um Entermannschafften zu werden. Furchtlos (nach genug Grog) und tödlich (wenigstesns auf See) sind diese Seeaffen immer begierig darauf sich hinüber zu einem feindlichen Schiff zu schwingen, um Mannschafften zu erledigen und die Schätze für sich in Besitz zu nehmen.</German>
		<Italian>La maggior parte dell'esercito Lanun è composto da coscritti che servono come marinai prima o poi. Coloro che dimostrano un'attitudine per il mare vengono addestrati come squadre d'abbordaggio, impavidi (dopo abbastanza grog) e letali (almeno in mare) queste scimmie di mare sono sempre pronti ad assaltare un vascello nemico ed eliminarne l'equipaggio, reclamando la nave per se stessi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Most of the Lanun army is conscripted to serve as deckhands at one time or another. Those that show aptitude at sea are trained to be boarding parties, fearless (after enough grog) and deadly (at least on sea) these sea monkeys are ever eager to swing to an enemy vessel and dispatch the crew, claiming the prize for themselves.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BOARDING_PARTY_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Although capable fighters on their own, Boarding parties are also able to attack naval units. And if they win, the naval unit comes under their control. They require a harbor to train and gain strength from metal resources as with other melee units.</English>
		<French>Although capable fighters on their own, Boarding parties are also able to attack naval units. And if they win, the naval unit comes under their control. They require a harbor to train and gain strength from metal resources as with other melee units.</French>
		<German>Obwohl sie alleine schon fähige Kämpfer sind, können Entermannschaften auch Wassereinheiten angreifen. Und falls sie gewinnen, gerät die Wassereinheit unter ihre Kontrolle. Sie benötigen einen Hafen um ausgebildet zu werden und gewinnen, wie andere Nahkampfeinheiten auch, durch Metallressourcen an Stärke.</German>
		<Italian>Sebbene siano dei combattenti capaci di per se, la loro peculiarità è quella di poter attaccare unità navali. E se vincono, l'unità navale sconfitta passa sotto il loro controllo. Richiedono un porto per essere create e ottengono i bonus al pari delle altre unità da combattimento ravvicinato.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Although capable fighters on their own, Boarding parties are also able to attack naval units. And if they win, the naval unit comes under their control. They require a harbor to train and gain strength from metal resources as with other melee units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GUYBRUSH</Tag>
		<English>Guybrush Threepwood</English>
		<French>Guybrush Threepwood</French>
		<German>Guybrush Threepwood</German>
		<Italian>Guybrush Threepwood</Italian>
		<Spanish>Guybrush Threepwood</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GUYBRUSH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Out of work since Lucasarts isn't making any more Monkey Island games (please please make another Lucasarts!), Guybrush has accepted work in our mod. According to his resume he is "Pirate Extraordinaire", captain of numerous vessels and master of the art of insult sword fighting.[PARAGRAPH:1]Guybrush was quickly adopted into the Lanun ranks where he found Falamar to be a kindred spirit. He described Hannah as a cross between LeChuck and Lemonhead of Skull Island. We aren't really sure what he was talking about.</English>
		<French>Out of work since Lucasarts isn't making any more Monkey Island games (please please make another Lucasarts!), Guybrush has accepted work in our mod. According to his resume he is "Pirate Extraordinaire", captain of numerous vessels and master of the art of insult sword fighting.[PARAGRAPH:1]Guybrush was quickly adopted into the Lanun ranks where he found Falamar to be a kindred spirit. He described Hannah as a cross between LeChuck and Lemonhead of Skull Island. We aren't really sure what he was talking about.</French>
		<German>Arbeitslos seit LucasArts keine Monkey Island Spiele mehr produziert (bitte, bitte macht noch eins LucasArts!) hat sich Guybrush bereiterklärt, in unserem Mod mitzuarbeiten. Sein Lebenslauf besagt er sei "Außerordentlicher Pirat", Kapitän von zahlreichen Schiffen und ein Meister der Kunst des beleidigenden Schwertkampfes.[PARAGRAPH:1]Guybrush wurde schnell in die Reihen der Lanun aufgenommen, wo er in Falamar eine verwandte Seele kennenlernte. Er beschrieb Hannah als eine Kreuzung aus LeChuck und Lemonhead von Skull Island. Wir sind uns nicht ganz sicher, was er uns damit sagen wollte.</German>
		<Italian>Senza lavoro da quando la Lucasarts non ha fatto altri giochi Monkey Island (per favore Lucasarts fanne un'altro!), Guybrush ha accettato di lavorare nel nostro mod. Secondo il suo curriculum lui è un "Pirata Straordianrio", capitano di numerosi vascelli e maestro dell'arte dell'insulto combattiento con spade.[PARAGRAPH:1]Guybrush è stato rapidamente adottato dai Lanun nei cui ranghi ha incontrato uno spirito affine in Falamar. Ha descritto Hannah come un mix tra LeChuck e Lemonhead dell'Isola Teschio. Non siamo esattamente certi di cosa stesse parlando.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Out of work since Lucasarts isn't making any more Monkey Island games (please please make another Lucasarts!), Guybrush has accepted work in our mod. According to his resume he is "Pirate Extraordinaire", captain of numerous vessels and master of the art of insult sword fighting.[PARAGRAPH:1]Guybrush was quickly adopted into the Lanun ranks where he found Falamar to be a kindred spirit. He described Hannah as a cross between LeChuck and Lemonhead of Skull Island. We aren't really sure what he was talking about.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GUYBRUSH_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Guybrush starts with Hero and Boarders promotions, making him excellent at capturing opponents' naval units.</English>
		<French>Guybrush entre en jeu avec les promotions Héros et Abordage, ce qui le rend particulèrement apte à capturer les unités navales ennemies.</French>
		<German>Guybrush startet mit "Entern", und durch die weiteren Beförderungen, die er als Held erhält, ist er wunderbar dazu einsetzbar, gegnerische Schiffe zu kapern.</German>
		<Italian>Guybrush inizia con le promozioni Eroe e Abbordaggio, rendendolo eccellente nel catturare unità navali avversarie.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Guybrush starts with Hero and Boarders promotions, making him excellent at capturing opponents' naval units.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PIRATE</Tag>
		<English>Pirate</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Pirate:Pirates</Text>
			<Gender>Male</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Pirat</German>
		<Italian>Pirata</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pirate</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PIRATE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Pirates are the scourge of the seas. Fast, nimble, and totally heartless, they attack without warning and leave nothing alive. These less-than-admirable qualities make them excellent weapons to counter the naval ambitions of one's enemies. Privateers are mercenary pirates, chartered by a civilization with one goal: attack everything not flying the right flag. Used efficiently, pirates can completely disrupt an enemy's naval trade and coastal industry.</English>
		<French>Pirates are the scourge of the seas. Fast, nimble, and totally heartless, they attack without warning and leave nothing alive. These less-than-admirable qualities make them excellent weapons to counter the naval ambitions of one's enemies. Privateers are mercenary pirates, chartered by a civilization with one goal: attack everything not flying the right flag. Used efficiently, pirates can completely disrupt an enemy's naval trade and coastal industry.</French>
		<German>Wenn die schnellen, geschickten und herzlosen Piraten Angreifen, zeigt sich wieder einmal, warum man sie den Schrecken der Meere nennt: Sie greifen lautlos aus dem Hinterhalt an, Versenken alle Schiffe und töten alle, die sich zuvor ergaben. Oft lassen sie sich von einer bestimmten Zivilisation dafür bezahlen, alles mit einer anderen als der eigenen Flagge zu versenken, sie eignen sich also gut, um die Konkurrenz vom Wasser fernzuhalten. Wenn sie richtig eingesetzt werden, können Piraten die Marine Wirtschaft des Feindes komplett einbrechen lassen.</German>
		<Italian>I Pirati sono la piaga dei mari. Veloci, agili e completamente senza cuore, attaccano senza preavviso e non lasciano nessuno in vita. Queste qualità non proprio ammirevoli li rendono armi eccellenti per contrastare le ambizioni marittime dei nemici di qualcuno. I corsari sono pirati mercenari, alle dipendenze di una civiltà con un solo obiettivo: attaccare qualsiasi cosa non abbia la bandiera giusta. Usati correttamente, i pirati possono completamente distruggere il commercio e l'industria costiera del nemico.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pirates are the scourge of the seas. Fast, nimble, and totally heartless, they attack without warning and leave nothing alive. These less-than-admirable qualities make them excellent weapons to counter the naval ambitions of one's enemies. Privateers are mercenary pirates, chartered by a civilization with one goal: attack everything not flying the right flag. Used efficiently, pirates can completely disrupt an enemy's naval trade and coastal industry.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PIRATE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Pirates and Privateers are useful units for weakening rivals without declaring war. They can blockade cities, eliminating traderoutes and stealing a small amount of gold, and they can attack any ships without declaring war. Even though they have cargo space, remember that they can only carry other Hidden Nationality units, such as Council of Esus units, unless they declare nationality.</English>
		<French>Pirates and Privateers are useful units for weakening rivals without declaring war. They can blockade cities, eliminating traderoutes and stealing a small amount of gold, and they can attack any ships without declaring war. Even though they have cargo space, remember that they can only carry other Hidden Nationality units, such as Council of Esus units, unless they declare nationality.</French>
		<German>Piraten und Freibeuter sind nützlich um Gegner zu schwächen ohne Krieg zu erklären. Sie können Häfen blockieren wodurch Handelsrouten ausgeschaltet werden und eine kleine Menge Gold gestohlen wird. Außerdem können sie Schiffe angreifen ohne Krieg erklärt zu haben. Auch wenn sie Einheiten transportieren können solltet Ihr daran denken, dass nur Einheiten mit Verborgener Nationalität, z.B. Einheiten des Rats des Esus, transportieren können es sei denn sie geben ihre Nationalität bekannt.</German>
		<Italian>I Pirati e i Corsari sono unità utili per indebolire gli avversari senza dovergli dichiarare guerra. Possono bloccare gli sbocchi sul mare delle città, eliminando le rotte commerciali e rubando una piccola quantita di denaro, e possono attaccare qualsiasi nave senza dover dichiarare guerra. Anche se hanno uno spazio di carico ricorda che possono trasportare solo altre unità con la Nazionalità Nascosta, come le unità del Concilio di Esus, a meno che non dichiarino la loro nazionalità.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pirates and Privateers are useful units for weakening rivals without declaring war. They can blockade cities, eliminating traderoutes and stealing a small amount of gold, and they can attack any ships without declaring war. Even though they have cargo space, remember that they can only carry other Hidden Nationality units, such as Council of Esus units, unless they declare nationality.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WAR_TORTOISE</Tag>
		<English>War Tortoise</English>
		<French>
			<Text>Tortue de Guerre:Tortues de Guerre</Text>
			<Gender>Female</Gender>
			<Plural>0:1</Plural>
		</French>
		<German>Kriegsschildkröte</German>
		<Italian>Tartaruga da Guerra</Italian>
		<Spanish>War Tortoise</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WORK_BOAT_LANUN</Tag>
		<English>Fishing Fleet</English>
		<French>Flotte de Pêche </French>
		<German>Fischerflotte</German>
		<Italian>Flotta di Perscherecci</Italian>
		<Spanish>Fishing Fleet</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WORK_BOAT_LANUN_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>Lanun Workboat</English>
		<French>Bateau-Atelier lanouniste</French>
		<German>Lanun Arbeitsboot</German>
		<Italian>Chiatta Lanun</Italian>
		<Spanish>Lanun Workboat</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_PARROT_PERCH</Tag>
		<English>Parrot Perch</English>
		<French>Perche à Perroquet</French>
		<German>Parrot Perch</German>
		<Italian>Parrot Perch</Italian>
		<Spanish>Parrot Perch</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
